<doc ID="COP25_UAE1" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 12, 2019 Thursday"source="ConstructionWeekOnline.com" >
The United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) Secretariat has chosen Dubai to host the MENA Climate Week 2020 in a first-of-its-kind climate event to be held in the Middle East and North Africa (MENA) region during the Expo 2020 Dubai. The chairman of the World Green Economy Organization (WGEO), HE Saeed Mohammed Al Tayer, made the announcement on the sidelines of the 2019 United Nations Climate Change Conference ( COP25 ) being held in Madrid, Spain, until 13 December, 2019. Al Tayer is heading a high-level delegation representing the Dubai Supreme Council of Energy, WGEO, and the Dubai Electricity and Water Authority (DEWA) at COP 25 . The chairman of WGEO also held a meeting with executive secretary of the UNFCCC, HE Patricia Espinosa, to discuss key areas of cooperation, and exchange best practices and global experiences in green economy. HYPERLINK http://imgs.syndigate.info/264/898/45/157620492230.jpg http://imgs.syndigate.info/264/898/45/157620492230.jpg Dubai to host first MENA Climate Week during Expo 2020 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE2" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 11, 2019 Wednesday"source="ArabianBusiness.com" >
Saeed Mohammed Al Tayer, chairman of the World Green Economy Organisation (WGEO), has announced that the Dubai has been picked to host the MENA Climate Week 2020. The United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) Secretariat has chosen the emirate to host the first of its kind climate event to be held in the Middle East and North Africa (MENA) which will coincide with Expo 2020 Dubai. The announcement came on the sidelines of the 2019 United Nations Climate Change Conference ( COP25 Al Tayer is heading a high level delegation from the Dubai Supreme Council of Energy and Dubai Electricity and Water Authority to participate at COP 25 . "The UNFCCC-WGEO Regional Collaboration Center's Steering Committee will be organizing the MENA Climate Week 2020 in Dubai next year during Expo 2020 Dubai, with more than 10000 participants. WGEO is delighted to be among the co-partners of the Regional Climate Weeks, which will be organizing the first MENA Climate Week in the second half of 2020, as part of our collaboration with the UNFCCC," said Al Tayer. "This important event aims to foster and speed up the shift towards a new model of sustainable growth and highlight the importance of simultaneously addressing climate change and meeting global development challenges," added Al Tayer. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE3" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 11, 2019 Wednesday 6:30 AM EST"source="UAE Government News" >
Dec. 11 -- Dubai Electricity and Water Authority issued the following news release: HE Saeed Mohammed Al Tayer, Chairman of the World Green Economy Organization (WGEO) has announced that the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) Secretariat has chosen Dubai, the United Arab Emirates to host the MENA Climate Week 2020, the first of its kind climate event to be held in the Middle East and North Africa (MENA) and will coincide with Expo 2020 Dubai. The announcement came during a press conference for the Regional Climate Weeks, which took place on the sidelines of the 2019 United Nations Climate Change Conference ( COP25 ), which is being held in Madrid, Spain until 13 December 2019. HE Al Tayer is heading a high level delegation from the Dubai Supreme Council of Energy, WGEO and Dubai Electricity and Water Authority to participate at COP 25 . The press conference was attended by HE Majed Hassan Al Suwaidi, the UAE Ambassador to Spain ;HE Fahad Al Hammadi, acting assistant undersecretary for Green Development and Climate Change at the UAE Ministry of Climate Change and the Environment; Ovais Sarmad Deputy Executive Secretary of the United Nations Climate Change Executive Secretary;Waleed Salman, Vice Chairman of WGEO; HE Ahmed Buti Al Muhairbi, WGEO Board Member; and Abdul Rahim Sultan, Director-General of WGEO. "I am honored to congratulate His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan, President of the UAE; His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai and His Highness Sheikh Mohamed Bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi and Deputy Supreme Commander of the UAE Armed Forces, for the selection of Dubai to host first-ever MENA Climate Week 2020 coinciding with Expo 2020 Dubai". "The UNFCCC-WGEO Regional Collaboration Center's Steering Committee will be organizing the MENA Climate Week 2020 in Dubai next year during Expo 2020 Dubai, with more than 10000 participants. WGEO is delighted to be among the co-partners of the Regional Climate Weeks, which will be organizing the first MENA Climate Week in the second half of 2020, as part of our collaboration with the UNFCCC," said Al Tayer. "This important event aims to foster and speed up the shift towards a new model of sustainable growth and highlight the importance of simultaneously addressing climate change and meeting global development challenges. WGEO is always keen to support such initiatives and we will be providing the highest level of support for MENA Climate Week 2020. This event is an important platform for various nations in the region to participate, as countries, next year would be reviewing their efforts and achievements in their national climate action plans to support the Paris Agreement and the Sustainable Development Goals of the UN 2030," noted Al Tayer. "With Dubai's long-standing experience in hosting regional and global events and its firm commitment to promote green economy, we are confident that participants will have the ideal platform to take part in the MENA Climate Week 2020 and highlight the successes as well as the key efforts that still need to be addressed to mitigate and adapt to climate change. We look forward to meeting you all in the UAE in 2020 at this event," Al Tayer added. HE Saeed Al Tayer, Chairman of WGEO earlier held a meeting with HE Patricia Espinosa to discuss key areas of cooperation and exchanged best practices and global experiences in green economy and addressing climate change. Al Tayer attended COP 25 High Level Segments which included the UAE national statement. Source: Dubai Electricity and Water Authority \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE4" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 11, 2019 Wednesday 6:30 AM EST"source="UAE Government News" >
Dec. 11 -- Media Office, Government of Dubai, UAE issued the following news release: HE Saeed Mohammed Al Tayer, Chairman of the World Green Economy Organization (WGEO) has announced that the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) Secretariat has chosen Dubai, the United Arab Emirates to host the MENA Climate Week 2020, the first of its kind climate event to be held in the Middle East and North Africa (MENA) and will coincide with Expo 2020 Dubai. The announcement came during a press conference for the Regional Climate Weeks, which took place on the sidelines of the 2019 United Nations Climate Change Conference ( COP25 ), which is being held in Madrid, Spain until 13 December 2019. HE Al Tayer is heading a high level delegation from the Dubai Supreme Council of Energy, WGEO and Dubai Electricity and Water Authority to participate at COP 25 . The press conference was attended by HE Majed Hassan Al Suwaidi, the UAE Ambassador to Spain ;HE Fahad Al Hammadi, acting assistant undersecretary for Green Development and Climate Change at the UAE Ministry of Climate Change and the Environment; Ovais Sarmad Deputy Executive Secretary of the United Nations Climate Change Executive Secretary;Waleed Salman, Vice Chairman of WGEO; HE Ahmed Buti Al Muhairbi, WGEO Board Member; and Abdul Rahim Sultan, Director-General of WGEO. "I am honored to congratulate His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan, President of the UAE; His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai and His Highness Sheikh Mohamed Bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi and Deputy Supreme Commander of the UAE Armed Forces, for the selection of Dubai to host first-ever MENA Climate Week 2020 coinciding with Expo 2020 Dubai". "The UNFCCC-WGEO Regional Collaboration Center's Steering Committee will be organizing the MENA Climate Week 2020 in Dubai next year during Expo 2020 Dubai, with more than 10000 participants. WGEO is delighted to be among the co-partners of the Regional Climate Weeks, which will be organizing the first MENA Climate Week in the second half of 2020, as part of our collaboration with the UNFCCC," said Al Tayer. "This important event aims to foster and speed up the shift towards a new model of sustainable growth and highlight the importance of simultaneously addressing climate change and meeting global development challenges. WGEO is always keen to support such initiatives and we will be providing the highest level of support for MENA Climate Week 2020. This event is an important platform for various nations in the region to participate, as countries, next year would be reviewing their efforts and achievements in their national climate action plans to support the Paris Agreement and the Sustainable Development Goals of the UN 2030," noted Al Tayer. "With Dubai's long-standing experience in hosting regional and global events and its firm commitment to promote green economy, we are confident that participants will have the ideal platform to take part in the MENA Climate Week 2020 and highlight the successes as well as the key efforts that still need to be addressed to mitigate and adapt to climate change. We look forward to meeting you all in the UAE in 2020 at this event," Al Tayer added. HE Saeed Al Tayer, Chairman of WGEO earlier held a meeting with HE Patricia Espinosa to discuss key areas of cooperation and exchanged best practices and global experiences in green economy and addressing climate change. Al Tayer attended COP 25 High Level Segments which included the UAE national statement. Source: Media Office, Government of Dubai, UAE \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE5" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="November 27, 2019 Wednesday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
Ministry of Climate Change / COP25 / UAE's participation ABU DHABI, 27th November, 2019 (WAM) -- The Ministry of Climate Change and Environment, MOCCAE, in collaboration with the Embassies of Spain and Chile in the UAE, today hosted a media roundtable on the upcoming 25th session of the Conference of the Parties, COP25 , to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, UNFCCC. Set to take place under the presidency of the Government of Chile in Madrid, Spain, from 2nd to 13th December, 2019, COP25 seeks to underline the next crucial steps to be taken in advancing the UN climate action agenda. It is expected to draw the participation of 25,000 stakeholders, including representatives of world governments, NGOs and businesses from the UNFCCC's 198 member countries. Eng. Fahed Al Hammadi, Acting Assistant Under-Secretary for the Green Development and Climate Change Sector at the MOCCAE; Antonio Alvarez Barthe, Ambassador of Spain to the UAE; and Jorge Daccarett, Ambassador of Chile to the UAE, headlined the roundtable and highlighted the roles of their countries in ensuring the successful outcome of the conference. Al Hammadi said, "The UAE delegation to COP25 will comprise 80 members from the public and private sector and academia, and will aim to underscore the global urgency to expedite the implementation of climate adaptation measures as the only viable solution at this stage to protect the lives of millions of people in climate-vulnerable communities. The delegation will also showcase the UAE's leading experience in this area through the National Climate Change Adaptation Programme." Barthe said, "Getting ready to host the COP25 in one month is a huge challenge, but Spain is willing to make every effort that goes into combating climate change and saving our planet." "Chile assumes the presidency of COP25 with the conviction that climate change is a collective task that must, therefore, be resolved not only by the Parties of the Convention but with the cooperation of the private sector, civil society, the scientific community, and academia," Daccarett said. "We hope that at the end of COP25 , we can agree on practical steps that take us a little closer to a future that is safe for the next generations. We do not have time to lose. The time for action is now," he added. COP25 paves the way for more ambitious climate commitments from members, ahead of the Paris Agreement entering into force in 2020. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE6" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 8, 2019 Sunday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
MOCCAE / Climate Change / UNFCCC / COP25 MADRID, 8th December, 2019 (WAM) -- Dr. Thani bin Ahmed Al Zeyoudi, Minister of Climate Change and Environment, is leading a UAE delegation to the 25th Conference of the Parties, COP25 , to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, UNFCCC, running from 2nd to 13th December 2019 in the Spanish capital, Madrid. The UAE delegation comprises 87 members, including 46 representatives of public and private sectors, including the Ministry of Climate Change and Environment, Ministry of Energy and Industry, Ministry of Infrastructure Development, Environment Agency - Abu Dhabi, Dubai Electricity and Water Authority, Dubai Carbon Centre of Excellence, National Centre of Meteorology, Emirates Diplomatic Academy, Abu Dhabi Future Energy Company - Masdar, Abu Dhabi National Oil Company, ADNOC, and Majid Al Futtaim, as well as 41 youth delegates. Delegates are highlighting the UAE's climate action efforts to date, with specific emphasis on the deliverables of the National Climate Change Adaptation Programme, which monitors climate trends and assesses their impacts on key sectors: energy, infrastructure, health, and the environment, in order to identify the climate risks that demand urgent action as well as the measures to counter them. The UAE delegates are also presenting an overview of the Climate Change Law draft, which is expected to come into effect in 2020, while emphasizing the importance of involving the private sector and youth in the wider climate conversation. Dr. Al Zeyoudi is participating in multiple events, including the Climate Adaptation Summit, the press conference to announce the launch of Regional Climate Weeks 2020, the Ministerial Roundtable for the Climate and Clean Air Coalition, and the high-level Forum on Climate Finance Strategies for NDC Implementation. In addition, he is scheduled to share insights on the UAE's climate action efforts at a lecture at the Polytechnic University of Madrid, and participate in a Ghaf tree planting ceremony at the city's Royal Botanical Garden. COP25 paves the way for more ambitious climate commitments from members, ahead of the Paris Agreement's entering into force in 2020. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE7" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 4, 2019 Wednesday"source="Khaleej Times (United Arab Emirates)" >
To secure a livable future on this planet, we also must commit to funding nature-based solutions. When world leaders gather at the 25th United Nations Climate Change Conference ( COP25 ) in Madrid from December 2-13, they will discuss concrete steps for meeting and increasing national emissions-reduction targets. But equally important, COP25 offers an opportunity to elevate one of the most powerful tools we have to address climate change: nature. Nature-based solutions (also known as natural climate solutions) leverage the world's forests, grasslands, wetlands, and soils to reduce greenhouse-gas emissions. Healthy ecosystems absorb and store carbon on their own. And if they are protected, restored, managed sustainably, they can provide one-third of the emissions reductions needed to meet the Paris agreement's goal for 2030. In other words, nature is offering us an opportunity that we cannot afford to miss. Reducing fossil-fuel emissions is crucial, but it will not be enough to keep global warming below 2\'b0C, let alone 1.5\'b0C, relative to pre-industrial levels. To secure a livable future on this planet, we also must commit to funding nature-based solutions. All countries need to start incorporating nature-based solutions into their national climate pledges, and begin investing accordingly. Two years ago, scientists from The Nature Conservancy and its partners published new research showcasing nature-based solutions' potential to fight climate change. Yet natural climate solutions have continued to attract relatively little attention - and even less funding. Fortunately, this may be starting to change. In September, nature-based solutions featured prominently at UN Climate Week in New York City. Although that event did not live up to UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres's call for "clear steps to enhance nationally determined contributions by 2020," it did offer a platform to a new generation of climate and nature advocates. From the Youth4Nature coalition to the Swedish activist Greta Thunberg, young people were on hand to demand that today's leaders account for the challenges they will inherit. Climate Week also produced an announcement from a coalition led by China and New Zealand, focused on encouraging nature-based solutions in both national climate plans and the corporate sector. And the private sector itself has made new commitments, with a group of 230 international investors (representing $16.2 trillion in assets under management) calling on firms to take immediate action to address deforestation in their supply chains. Political leaders now must maintain this momentum, by taking a closer look at what nature can do to help mitigate and build resilience to climate change. For example, one promising solution is sustainable agroforestry, in which food crops are grown alongside native trees. Expanding this practice can bolster food security and boost incomes in rural communities and simultaneously restore soil health, sequester carbon, and nurture critical wildlife. Another nature-based solution is being pioneered in Australia, where massive bushfires are putting people and wildlife at risk - and releasing enormous amounts of greenhouse gases into the atmosphere. The Nature Conservancy is cooperating with indigenous communities to improve grassland health, sequester carbon, and reduce the risk of catastrophic wildfires. Drawing on traditional knowledge dating back thousands of years, indigenous rangers set smaller, controlled burns to prevent the buildup of dry grass that contributes to larger, hotter wildfires. This programme contributes to healthier grasslands while generating income for communities through the sale of carbon credits. These kinds of programmes benefit people and the environment; but much more investment is urgently needed. Although natural systems play a critical role in regulating the climate, nature-based solutions still receive under 4 per cent of total public funding for climate action. France, Sweden, South Korea, the UK, and a few other countries have pledged to increase funding for international preservation and restoration efforts, and finalising the details of these programmes is now on the COP25 docket. But unless more countries make similar commitments, natural climate solutions will not achieve the scale. Worse, natural systems that could be part of the solution to climate change are facing increasingly severe threats. We have all seen the recent images of fires raging through the Amazon rainforest, which plays a major role in regulating the world's climate. Record-high temperatures, environmental crimes, weak oversight, ineffective firefighting, and other factors have increased the vulnerability of systems that store a disproportionate share of the planet's carbon. And the Amazon is just one example. The conversion and degradation of natural land and marine habitats is ongoing around the world. Such practices undermine our ability to adapt to climate effects like rising sea levels, and directly threaten our food security by wiping out species that pollinate crops, contribute to soil health, and provide habitats for fish and other marine life. Nature, climate, and human wellbeing are intimately connected; none can be addressed in isolation. COP25 offers an opportunity for world leaders to seize on these connections in the run up to 2020, which will be a veritable "environmental super year." In addition to finalising an international high-seas treaty and establishing a new framework for the UN Convention on Biological Diversity, governments will also revisit their climate commitments at COP26 in Glasgow, Scotland. But any commitments that countries make at these meetings will mean little without concrete plans to back them up. We have the science, and we have the solutions. What we need now is action to leverage the power of nature. Our shared existence on this planet depends on it. - Project Syndicate Sally Jewell is Interim CEO of The Nature Conservancy \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE8" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 10, 2019 Tuesday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
Al Zeyoudi highlights country's experience in climate change adaptation at COP25 MADRID, 10th December, 2019 (WAM) -- On the sidelines of the 25th Conference of the Parties, COP25 , to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, Dr. Thani bin Ahmed Al Zeyoudi, UAE Minister of Climate Change and Environment, today participated in the high-level forum of the Global Commission on Adaptation convening countries, where he highlighted the country's climate change adaptation and efficient cooling initiatives. The Netherlands government hosted the event under the theme, "Raising Ambition Ahead of the 2020 Climate Adaptation Summit". Addressing the forum, Dr. Al Zeyoudi said, "We recognise the urgency of climate change adaptation and acknowledge that it is our collective duty to help others, especially the most vulnerable communities of the world, achieve this objective. And while many countries have been working hard to meet the goals of the Paris Agreement, the fact remains that global temperatures are still rising, and we are rapidly depleting our carbon budget to ensure they do not surge above 1.5 degrees Celsius." Speaking on the UAE's approach to climate change adaptation, he said, "The changing weather patterns prompted the launch of our National Climate Change Adaptation Programme in 2017 that aims to assess climate risks in four critical sectors: health, energy, infrastructure, and the environment. In addition, we are taking steps to enhance the monitoring of the impact of climate change on the UAE, and working closely with academic and research institutions to understand it better." The minister also attended the Efficient Cooling Initiative side event, organised by the Climate and Clean Air Coalition, a voluntary cross-sectoral partnership committed to improving air quality and protecting the climate by reducing short-lived climate pollutants. Given that temperatures in the UAE soar to over 45 degrees Celsius in the summer and that cooling is one of the country's most energy-intensive sectors, Dr. Al Zeyoudi provided an overview of the UAE's experience in the area. He also attended the press conference announcing the launch of Regional Climate Weeks 2020. As the leading convener of global public and private sector actors on climate change, the UAE was selected to host the first Regional Climate Week in the MENA region during Expo 2020 Dubai. Dubbed MENA Climate Week, it will bring together governments, the private sector, and civil society from the region to discuss the serious threat of climate change and collaborate on swift, bold actions to address this challenge. Dr. Al Zeyoudi is leading the UAE delegation to COP25 being held from 2nd to 13th December, 2019, in the Spanish capital of Madrid. The delegation comprises 87 members, including representatives of the public and private sectors, as well as the youth. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE9" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 11, 2019 Wednesday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
COP25 / SUSTAINABILITY / MOCCAE / UAE MADRID, 11th December, 2019 (WAM) -- The UAE has highlighted the importance behind prioritising climate adaptation to assist vulnerable countries. On the sidelines of the 25th Conference of the Parties, COP25 , to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, UNFCCC, Dr Thani bin Ahmed Al Zeyoudi, Minister of Climate Change and Environment, delivered the UAE national statement where he emphasised the importance of prioritising efforts to help vulnerable countries in the developing world adapt to the impacts of climate change. Dr Al Zeyoudi said, "The international community must join forces and work seamlessly to provide the technologies, scientific research, and capacity building needed to address the climate emergency. COP25 comes at a time when tragic extreme weather events in various regions dominate the news, and with the deadline for countries to strengthen their nationally determined contributions, NDCs, under the Paris Agreement just around the corner. "At this stage, expediting and intensifying adaptation measures seems to be the only viable way of protecting the future of all mankind." The Minister added, "Prioritising adaptation measures can save millions of lives worldwide through establishing a climate-resilient infrastructure. It can also facilitate economic growth through expanding sectors such as clean and renewable energy and green building, thus creating new jobs." He also noted that the UAE has a proven track record of working towards securing a climate-safe future, and has always fulfilled its commitments under the Paris Agreement regarding drafting as well as upgrading its NDCs. Al Zeyoudi presented an overview of the country's achievements in this area in the past year. Globally, these included hosting the Abu Dhabi Climate Meeting as a precursor to the UN Climate Action Summit 2019, and upgrading its NDCs to achieve a target of 50 percent clean energy in its total energy mix by 2050, generated from renewable and nuclear power sources. Locally, the country commenced operations at the 1.1GW Noor Abu Dhabi solar plant, announced a new venture in the capital with a capacity of 2GW that is already in the works, and continues to work on the Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum Solar Park that will add 5GW to the grid upon completion. Al Zeyoudi also pointed out that the fifth phase of the Solar Park received the world's lowest bid of 1.69 US cents per kW/h for 900 MW. And as part of diversifying its energy mix, the UAE established the Barakah Nuclear Energy Plant, the first in the Arab world, to supply up to 25 percent of the country's electricity needs, once fully operational. Highlighting the integral role of the private sector in the UAE's climate efforts, the Minister of Climate Change referred to some of the recent projects of the country's flagship renewable energy company, Masdar. These included its investment in the UK's electric vehicle charging infrastructure in partnership with Her Majesty's Treasury and the Infrastructure and Projects Authority, Saudi Arabia's Dumat Al Jandal 400 MW wind farm project, and Cibuk 1, the largest wind farm in the Western Balkans. Al Zeyoudi toured Acciona, and met with its Executive Director, Jose Manuel Entrecanales, to learn more about the latest technologies used by the Spanish company, and explore opportunities for cooperation and experience sharing. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE10" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 11, 2019 Wednesday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
Dubai / WGEO / Expo 2020 / Sustainability MADRID, 11th December, 2019 (WAM) -- The United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, UNFCCC, Secretariat has selected Dubai to host the inaugural MENA Climate Week 2020. The first of its kind climate event to be held in the region will coincide with Expo 2020 Dubai. The announcement came during a press conference for the Regional Climate Weeks, which took place on the sidelines of the 2019 United Nations Climate Change Conference , COP25 , taking place in Madrid, Spain until 13th December 2019. The UAE Minister of Climate Change and Environment Dr. Thani bin Ahmed Al Zeyoudi participated in the press conference, alongside of Saeed Mohammed Al Tayer, Chairman of the World Green Economy Organisation, WGEO. Dr. Al Zeyoudi highlighted in his speech the importance of hosting the event and the UAE's relentless efforts in addressing climate change. The press conference was attended by Majed Hassan Al Suwaidi, UAE Ambassador to Spain; Fahad Al Hammadi, acting assistant undersecretary for Green Development and Climate Change at the UAE Ministry of Climate Change and the Environment; Ovais Sarmad Deputy Executive Secretary of the United Nations Climate Change Executive Secretary; Waleed Salman, Vice Chairman of WGEO; Ahmed Buti Al Muhairbi, WGEO Board Member, and Abdul Rahim Sultan, Director-General of WGEO. Al Tayer congratulated the UAE leadership on Dubai's selection as host of the MENA Climat Week 2020. "The UNFCCC-WGEO Regional Collaboration Centre's Steering Committee will be organising the MENA Climate Week 2020 in Dubai next year during Expo 2020 Dubai, with more than 10,000 participants. WGEO is delighted to be among the co-partners of the Regional Climate Weeks, which will be organising the first MENA Climate Week in the second half of 2020, as part of our collaboration with the UNFCCC," Al Tayer explained. "This important event," he added, "aims to foster and speed up the shift towards a new model of sustainable growth and highlight the importance of simultaneously addressing climate change and meeting global development challenges." Al Tayer continued, "WGEO is always keen to support such initiatives and we will be providing the highest level of support for MENA Climate Week 2020. This event is an important platform for various nations in the region to participate, as countries, next year would be reviewing their efforts and achievements in their national climate action plans to support the Paris Agreement and the Sustainable Development Goals of the UN 2030." "With Dubai's long-standing experience in hosting regional and global events and its firm commitment to promote green economy, we are confident that participants will have the ideal platform to take part in the MENA Climate Week 2020 and highlight the successes as well as the key efforts that still need to be addressed to mitigate and adapt to climate change. We look forward to meeting you all in the UAE in 2020 at this event," Al Tayer added. The WGEO Chairman also held a meeting with UNFCCC Executive Secretary Patricia Espinosa to discuss key areas of cooperation and exchanged best practices and global experiences in green economy and addressing climate change. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE11" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 13, 2019 Friday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
Al Zeyoudi / Environmental tolerance/ climate action MADRID, 13th December, 2019 (WAM) -- Dr. Thani bin Ahmed Al Zeyoudi, Minister of Climate Change and Environment, today pointed out that the best way to combat the environmental challenges the world faces today and create a better, more sustainable future for all is through nurturing tolerance and compassion towards the environment. Dr. Al Zeyoudi stated this at a Ghaf tree planting ceremony at the Royal Botanical Garden in the Spanish capital, Madrid. The ceremony was organised by the UAE Embassy in Spain and the Spanish National Research Council, the entity that manages the botanical garden, on the sidelines of the 25th Conference of the Parties, COP25 , to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change that concludes today in Madrid. The minister said, "The UAE is a beacon of solidarity and peaceful coexistence, with over 200 nationalities living together in harmony. Through such initiatives, we hope to increase public understanding that the value of tolerance is not limited to human interactions and includes in its scope the peaceful coexistence of people and their surrounding environment." He added, "The Ghaf tree is the national tree of the UAE. Ghaf trees received special attention from the founding father of the UAE, late Sheikh Zayed bin Sultan Al Nahyan, who planted thousands of them and issued legislation that made it illegal to cut them down. Selecting the Ghaf tree as the symbol of the Year of Tolerance adds greater momentum to our efforts to convey the message of tolerance towards the environment." Summarising the UAE participation at COP25 , Majed Hassan Al Suwaidi, UAE Ambassador to Spain, said, "The UAE adopted a can-do approach early on to tackling the most pressing challenges facing the world in its pursuit of ensuring prosperity for all. Climate change certainly tops the list of these challenges, and we are pleased to see that the UAE's participation in COP25 , under the leadership of Dr. Al Zeyoudi, has reinforced the vital message of collective climate action." He added, "The UAE presents an integrated, successful model for climate change mitigation and adaptation, and considers climate action a promising opportunity for growth across all sectors. Through their participation in COP25 's main and sideline events, the UAE delegates shared their insights on the key elements for successful climate action and urged members of the international community to expedite efforts to support developing countries and those most vulnerable to adapt to the impacts of climate change." The Ambassador said, "The Ghaf tree-planting ceremony was a gesture of goodwill that underlined the UAE's commitment to safeguarding biodiversity and promoting the value of tolerance, as the tree represents the symbol of the UAE's Year of Tolerance." Furthermore, he participated in a panel entitled "Reaching Net Zero: Learning from International Experiences with Climate Legislation". The panel discussion was aimed at increasing awareness of the importance of legislation in delivering energy transition goals and to share successful experiences in designing and implementing climate change laws. The session was jointly organised by ACCIONA, a leader in providing sustainable solutions for infrastructure and renewable energy projects around the world, and the Elcano Royal Institute, a think tank specializing in international and strategic studies conducted from a Spanish, European and global perspective. Speaking on the UAE's experience in drafting climate laws and strategies, Dr. Al Zeyoudi said, "The National Climate Change Plan 2050 and the UAE Energy Strategy 2050 guide our approach to reducing greenhouse gas emissions and driving a green, low-carbon economy. Besides, we are currently working on a climate change law that is expected to come into effect in 2020. The law will further increase our climate ambition and resilience by targeting all dimensions of climate action." Reaffirming the role of the youth in driving climate action, the minister mentioned two engagements with young people as part of his COP25 outing. The first was delivering a lecture to postgraduate and doctoral students of the Polytechnic University of Madrid, where he provided an overview of the UAE's integrated approach since its inception of tackling climate change and biodiversity loss. The second youth engagement was meeting with the UAE young delegates to COP25 , to reflect on their experience and takeaways from the event. On the sidelines of COP25 , Dr. Al Zeyoudi held multiple bilateral meetings with top officials, including Patricia Espinosa, Executive Secretary of UNFCCC, Zhao Yingmin, Vice Minister of Ecology and Environment of China, and Masagos Zulkifli, Minister for the Environment and Water Resources of Singapore. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE12" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 12, 2019 Thursday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
UAE / COP25 MADRID, 12th December, 2019 (WAM) -- Dr. Thani bin Ahmed Al Zeyoudi, Minister of Climate Change and Environment, has participated in the High-level Forum on Climate Finance Strategies for NDC Implementation, a key event organised by the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, UNFCCC, and the World Green Economy Organisation on the sidelines of the 25th Conference of the Parties, COP25 , to UNFCCC. The forum highlighted regional and national strategies to mobilise and access climate finance to meet the priorities of developing countries, as outlined in their nationally determined contributions, NDCs, under the Paris Agreement. Addressing the forum, Dr. Al Zeyoudi asked the international community to boost sustainability-driven investments and financing, thereby expediting the transition to a green economy to help step up climate action and create a better future for present and future generations. Showcasing the UAE's world-leading experiences in this area, the Minister said, "The country's wise leadership made critical and ambitious strides in the transition to a green economy through approving the UAE Green Growth Strategy. This initiative consolidates the UAE's environmental stewardship and its status as a hub for the export and re-export of green products and technologies. In doing so, it seeks to help support long-term economic growth." He added, "To meet our solid commitment to driving sustainability ventures, we unveiled the Dubai and Abu Dhabi Declarations on Sustainable Finance that commit UAE-based financial institutions to support the country's green economic agenda through financing sustainable projects. To date, both declarations have gained the endorsements of 57 signatories." The minister went on to highlight the launched of the Dubai Green Fund, with the goal of raising US$27 billion to fund green projects in the emirate. Dr. Al Zeyoudi also noted the First Abu Dhabi Bank as an example of best practice, where it financed US$10 billion for green businesses over the next several years, as well as its issuance of a US$587 million 5-year green bond in 2017. "Notably, HSBC Middle East and Emirates NBD have also introduced green auto loans to promote hybrid or electric vehicles," he added. The UAE Minister also participated in an informative meeting organised by the UAE Embassy in Spain for Spanish representatives of the public and private sectors and members of the diplomatic corps. In a presentation, Dr. Al Zeyoudi offered the participants insights into the UAE's long journey of environmental work and the country's efforts in tackling climate change and biodiversity loss at home and further afield. Dr. Al Zeyoudi is leading the UAE delegation to COP25 that is running from 2nd to 13th December, in the Spanish capital, Madrid. The delegation comprises 87 members, including representatives of the public and private sectors as well as the youth. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE13" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 13, 2019 Friday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
Editorial ABU DHABI, 13th December, 2019 (WAM) -- A UAE newspaper has said that protection of environment and sustainable development are key topics that receive great attention from the UAE government right from the beginning. "A clean and green environment will not only be beneficial for humanity, but also help protect endangered species, fish, and water from pollution, contributing to food security, and increasing the productivity of agricultural crops as a result of the elimination of chemical and gas contaminants," said The Gulf Today in an editorial on Friday. On the sidelines of the 25th Conference of the Parties, COP25 , to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, UNFCCC, Dr. Thani bin Ahmed Al Zeyoudi, Minister of Climate Change and Environment, convincingly emphasised the importance of prioritising efforts to help vulnerable countries in the developing world adapt to the impacts of climate change. He said that the international community must join forces and work seamlessly to provide the technologies, scientific research, and capacity building needed to address the climate emergency. COP25 comes at a time when tragic extreme weather events in various regions dominate the news, and with the deadline for countries to strengthen their nationally determined contributions, NDCs, under the Paris Agreement just around the corner. Expediting and intensifying adaptation measures undoubtedly seem to be the only viable way of protecting the future of all mankind. The UAE has a proven track record of working towards securing a climate-safe future, and has always fulfilled its commitments under the Paris Agreement regarding drafting as well as upgrading its NDCs. Al Zeyoudi well presented an overview of the country's achievements in this area in the past year. Globally, these included hosting the Abu Dhabi Climate Meeting as a precursor to the UN Climate Action Summit 2019, and upgrading its NDCs to achieve a target of 50 percent clean energy in its total energy mix by 2050, generated from renewable and nuclear power sources. Locally, the country commenced operations at the 1.1GW Noor Abu Dhabi solar plant, announced a new venture in the capital with a capacity of 2GW that is already in the works, and continues to work on the Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum Solar Park that will add 5GW to the grid upon completion. The need to boost sustainability-driven investments and financing should never by underestimated as it helps expedite the transition to a green economy and create a better future for present and future generations. Tackling sustainability-related challenges could save the global economy up to $30 trillion, as per estimates, and help prevent millions of people being displaced due to climate change. The UAE Energy Strategy 2050 seeks to bring the share of clean energy in the total energy mix to 50 percent, while the National Climate Change Plan of the UAE streamlines the concept of climate change mitigation and adaptation across the government and private sector. "The UAE is on right track having adopted a series of ambitious strategies, including the UAE Vision 2021, to promote sustainability," concluded the Sharjah-based daily. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE14" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="January 23, 2020"source="The Big Project Middle East" >
ACCIONA has been recognised for its climate action work throughout 2019 by global corporate climate information analyst CDP. ACCIONA is ranked in category A (CDP's Climate Change A List), placing it amongst the world's most pioneering companies in working towards a low-carbon economy. Only 179 of the more than 8,300 companies that were evaluated worldwide made it onto CDP's A List, noted ACCIONA in a statement. "ACCIONA has been a carbon-neutral company since 2016, reaching this landmark more than thirty years before it is forecast to happen at a global level. In this way, the company applies a carbon price to its operations worldwide, offsetting all the CO2 emissions it cannot reduce," the company further explained. "ACCIONA has also set increasingly ambitious specific targets for reducing emissions. The company has established new scientific-based emissions reduction targets through the Science Based Targets (SBTi) initiative. These targets are in alignment with the scenario set at COP25 that limits global warming to an increase of 1.5\'baC. These goals define a reduction of 60% of the greenhouse gas emissions generated by the company and a 47% reduction for the emissions of its suppliers, products and employees by 2030, in comparison to 2017 levels." CDP also reported that ACCIONA avoided the emission of 14.7 million tonnes of CO2 into the atmosphere in 2018, "thanks to its energy production activity exclusively from renewable sources." CDP works with more than 525 institutional investors managing US$96 trillion in assets. It is a non-profit organisation that aims to encourage institutions, companies and citizens to promote a low-carbon and environmentally friendly future economy. Its reports highlight solutions for global warming and the deterioration of natural resources, by channeling investment and consumption. The post ACCIONA joins exclusive A-list of world leaders in climate action appeared first on Middle East Construction News. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE15" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 1, 2019 Sunday"source="Khaleej Times (United Arab Emirates)" >
The lifetime health of a child born today will be profoundly affected by the decisions we make about climate change now and in the years to come. The climate crisis is also a health crisis. The same emissions that cause global warming are also largely responsible for polluting the air we breathe, causing heart disease, stroke, lung cancer, and infections, and affecting every organ in our bodies. Air pollution is the new tobacco, causing as many deaths as cigarettes do. And though it threatens us all, children, the elderly, pregnant women, and adults with weakened immune systems are the most at risk. It is now common knowledge that smoking tobacco severely harms you and those around you. That is why the tobacco industry's lobbying and advertising campaigns have been strictly regulated around the world. Globally, we have taken steps to safeguard existing health policies, and to force these companies to tell the truth: that their product kills. And yet, our reaction is very different when we learn that air pollution and fossil-fuel-driven climate change are just as deadly. Where are the policies to prevent the fossil-fuel industry from lobbying governments, or to end the $370 billion in subsidies lavished on coal, oil, and gas companies every year? Why are we still paying for a product that is killing us? As with the world's strong response to tobacco, ending harmful fossil-fuel use will require scaling up current policy interventions and social-mobilisation efforts. Fortunately, some multilateral financial organisations have already recognised the opportunity that such a change represents. Just recently, the European Investment Bank announced that it would end all of its funding for unabated fossil-fuel projects, and use its position to funnel public and private capital toward renewable energy. The choice between phasing out fossil fuels and continuing on the current path is black and white - it is a matter of life or death. We either will decide to prevent seven million premature deaths per year by cleaning up our air and providing people with clean energy sources, or we won't. We either will decide to prevent four million childhood asthma cases per year from traffic fumes, or we won't. In any case, the lifetime health of a child born today will be profoundly affected by the decisions we make about climate change now and in the years to come. That is why the World Health Organization has made climate change a top institutional priority. Climate change should be a priority for all businesses, governments, and multilateral organisations, too. Keeping the issue high on the agenda provides the necessary motivation to make difficult choices. By taking action now to reduce carbon dioxide emissions and limit global warming to no more than 1.5\'b0C relative to the pre-industrial level, we would not only ensure that our planet remains hospitable for future generations; we could also save at least one million lives per year, according to WHO's estimates. Moreover, in countries like the United States and the United Kingdom, eliminating air pollution would save the economy 4 per cent of GDP per year in averted health-care costs. In China and India, reducing emissions enough to limit global warming to 1.5\'b0C would more than pay for itself when accounting for the attendant health benefits. Likewise, transforming our food and transportation systems would save still more lives, by providing healthier diets and encouraging more physical activity - all while cleaning the air and stabilising the climate. The human right to a healthy life and a sustainable future is increasingly being enforced through legal systems, and officials that fail to uphold these rights are being held accountable. In France, for example, a court found that the government had failed to do enough to limit air pollution around Paris, and in Indonesia, Jakarta residents similarly took legal action against the government because of air pollution. At this year's United Nations General Assembly, many governments answered the WHO's call to achieve "air quality that is safe for citizens, and to align climate change and air pollution policies by 2030." This represents an encouraging first step. Now, many of the countries with the heaviest health burden from air pollution need to phase out their highest-pollution energy sources. At WHO, we will continue to push for action on these issues, while collaborating with others who are doing the same. On December 7, during the UN Climate Change Conference ( COP25 ) in Madrid, WHO and the Global Climate and Health Alliance will convene a one-day summit on climate and health, allowing representatives from civil society, the health sector, and all other stakeholders to shine a spotlight on this critical issue. Like the pollution that causes it, climate change does not observe national borders; it does not save its effects just for those who pollute. On the contrary, inequality is a key feature of the climate crisis: those least responsible for the problem - children, disadvantaged communities, and the Global South - must bear a disproportionate share of the health burden. WHO's new global survey, to be launched at COP25 , shows that many countries are highly exposed, vulnerable, and unsupported in dealing with health risks from climate change and air pollution. It is clear that we need an international and just response to this increasing strain on public health. Future efforts must reflect the real costs of our fossil-fuel based economy and aid those most affected. To achieve this, we will need all signatories to the Paris climate accord to strengthen their national climate plans by 2020. Beyond that, we need to establish new, robust mechanisms for protecting the most vulnerable and helping communities adapt to the realities of climate change. Health must be at the heart of our Paris commitments. The pollution that is choking our air and warming our planet has been accumulating for generations. We cannot afford to take that long to fix the problem. - Project Syndicate Maria Neira is Director of the Department of Public Health, Environmental and Social Determinants of Health at the World Health Organization \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE16" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="June 10, 2019 Monday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
Editorial ABU DHABI, 10th June, 2019 (WAM) -- A UAE newspaper has highlighted the important role that oceans play, noting that oceans are crucial to life on Earth, yet they frequently only feature in the ecological debate when plastic pollution or fish-stock declines are discussed. "As greenhouse gas levels in the atmosphere climb ever higher, so do sea levels; oceans currently encroach on the land around 3.3 millimetres (0.13 inches) a year, and the rate is accelerating," said The Gulf Today in an editorial on Monday. The United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, IPCC, which released a landmark report in October 2018 warning of the effects of global temperature rises, will this September publish its latest assessment on the state of oceans. The last IPCC assessment, in 2014, predicted that sea levels could rise as much as a metre (3.3 feet) by the end of the century. But more recent studies using more varied scenario planning have said that current warming trends could lift the seas as much as two metres by 2100. According to an IPCC official, the threats to the world's oceans include: surface warming, ocean heating, deoxygenation and acidification. Oceans absorb around a third of all manmade CO2, and 90 percent of the excess heat created by those emissions goes into the sea. In doing so, the ocean surface heats and becomes more acidic, something that has already decimated coral populations on reefs throughout the seas. Talking of the seas, tsunamis may become more frequent as global warming changes the earth's crust, scientists said at a meet nearly ten years ago in London. The 2004 tsunami wreaked unspeakable havoc in several countries. Already there is a lot of waste flooding the seas, and they are choking marine life. As part of World Oceans Day, people are doing their bit to clean up the sea waters. For instance, thousands of volunteers plucked plastic and other waste products from the rocks and beaches along Spain's Basque coast, while divers took to the sea to clear garbage from the water. Nearly 1,000 volunteers from a multinational firm teamed up with local authorities and NGOs in the UAE, Bahrain, Jordan, Kuwait, Lebanon, Saudi Arabia, and in North African countries to raise awareness and inspire responsible disposal of waste by cleaning up beaches. Chilean President Sebastian Pinera, whose country will host the COP25 UN climate summit in December, has dedicated the conference to oceans. Oceans contain 97 percent of all living space on Earth and, just like forests, they help keep the atmosphere breathable. But there is a limit to how much CO2 they can absorb. The Sharjah-based daily concluded by quoting Peter Thomson, UN special envoy for oceans, as saying, "Every second breath we take comes from oxygen produced by the ocean, so it's time for us to make some radical changes." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE17" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 4, 2019 Wednesday"source="Big News Network.com" >
Exceptional global heat driven by greenhouse gas emissions mean this decade will most likely go down as the warmest on record, according to the World Meteorological Organization (WMO) which released its provisional statement on the State of the Global Climate on Tuesday. The agency is also finding that 2019 is on track to be the second or third warmest year in history, with the global average temperature during January through October, roughly 1.1 degrees Celsius above the pre-industrial era. "If we do not take urgent climate action now, then we are heading for a temperature increase of more than 3C by the end of the century, with ever more harmful impacts on human wellbeing", WMO Secretary-General Petteri Taalas said Tuesday. "We are nowhere near on track to meet the Paris Agreement target," he added, referring to the 2015 international accord to limit global warming to 1.5C above pre-industrial levels. CO2 and sea levels on the rise The report finds that concentrations of carbon dioxide (CO2) in the atmosphere, which hit record levels last year, also continued to rise in 2019. Additionally, sea level rise has increased due to melting of the ice sheets in Greenland and Antarctica, while ocean heat is at record levels, with vital marine ecosystems being degraded. Several United Nations agencies provided input to the report, which also details how weather and climate have an impact on health, food security, migration, ecosystems and marine life. Climate variability and extreme weather events are among key drivers of the recent rise in global hunger, which now affects more than 820 million people. "On a day-to-day basis, the impacts of climate change play out through extreme and "abnormal" weather. And, once again in 2019, weather and climate related risks hit hard", said Mr Taalas. "Heatwaves and floods which used to be "once in a century" events are becoming more regular occurrences. Countries ranging from the Bahamas to Japan to Mozambique, suffered the effect of devastating tropical cyclones. Wildfires swept through the Arctic and Australia." Record-setting temperatures are increasingly putting health at risk, according to input provided by the World Health Organization (WHO). Major heatwaves in Japan in late July to early August caused more than 100 deaths and some 18,000 hospitalizations, for example. About half the global population is now threatened by dengue as changes in climatic conditions are making it easier for the Aedes mosquito species to transmit the dengue virus. Southern Africa has experienced extensive dry periods due to a delay in the start of the seasonal rains, the Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) reports. As cereal output is forecasted to be around eight per cent below the five-year average, some 12.5 million people in the region will face food insecurity. Climate-related disasters are also increasing displacement. Figures from the UN refugee agency, UNHCR, reveal more than 10 million new internal displacements were recorded during the first half of the year, with seven million forced to move as a result of disasters such as cyclones and flooding. New displacements associated with weather extremes could more than triple, to around 22 million by the end of the year. The provisional report was released as governments meet in Madrid for the UN climate change negotiations, known as COP25 . WMO will publish the final Statement on the State of the Climate, with complete 2019 data, in March. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE18" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="August 8, 2019 Thursday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
IPCC / report GENEVA, 8th August, 2019 (WAM) -- Land is already under growing human pressure and climate change is adding to these pressures. At the same time, keeping global warming to well below 2?C can be achieved only by reducing greenhouse gas emissions from all sectors including land and food, the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change,IPCC, said in its latest report on Thursday. The IPCC, the world body for assessing the state of scientific knowledge related to climate change, its impacts and potential future risks, and possible response options, saw the Summary for Policymakers of The Special Report on Climate Change and Land, SRCCL, approved by the world's governments on Wednesday in Geneva, Switzerland, will be a key scientific input into forthcoming climate and environment negotiations, such as the Conference of the Parties of the UN Convention to Combat Desertification,COP14, in New Delhi, India in September and the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change Conference, COP25 , in Santiago, Chile, in December. "Governments challenged the IPCC to take the first ever comprehensive look at the whole land-climate system. We did this through many contributions from experts and governments worldwide. This is the first time in IPCC report history that a majority of authors \- 53 percent \- are from developing countries," said Hoesung Lee, Chair of the IPCC. This report shows that better land management can contribute to tackling climate change, but is not the only solution. Reducing greenhouse gas emissions from all sectors is essential if global warming is to be kept to well below 2?C, if not 1.5oC. In 2015, governments backed the Paris Agreement goal of strengthening the global response to climate change by holding the increase in the global average temperature to well below 2?C above pre-industrial levels and to pursue efforts to limit the increase to 1.5?C. Land must remain productive to maintain food security as the population increases and the negative impacts of climate change on vegetation increase. This means there are limits to the contribution of land to addressing climate change, for instance through the cultivation of energy crops and afforestation. It also takes time for trees and soils to store carbon effectively. Bioenergy needs to be carefully managed to avoid risks to food security, biodiversity and land degradation. Desirable outcomes will depend on locally appropriate policies and governance systems. Climate Change and Land finds that the world is best placed to tackle climate change when there is an overall focus on sustainability. "Land plays an important role in the climate system," said Jim Skea, Co-Chair of IPCC Working Group III. "Agriculture, forestry and other types of land use account for 23 percent of human greenhouse gas emissions. At the same time natural land processes absorb carbon dioxide equivalent to almost a third of carbon dioxide emissions from fossil fuels and industry," he said. The report shows how managing land resources sustainably can help address climate change, said Hans-Otto P?rtner, Co-Chair of IPCC Working Group II. "Land already in use could feed the world in a changing climate and provide biomass for renewable energy, but early, far-reaching action across several areas is required" he said. "Also for the conservation and restoration of ecosystems and biodiversity." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE19" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="January 16, 2020 Thursday"source="ArabianBusiness.com" >
Saudi Arabia, the UAE, Oman, Jordan and Morocco are leading the transition to cleaner power sources in the Middle East & North Africa. Noor Abu Dhabi, currently the world's largest single-site solar park at nearly 1.2 gigawatts (GW), launched in 2019. Dubai will soon inaugurate the 800 megawatt (MW) third phase of its 5GW Mohammed Bin Rashid Al Maktoum Solar Park, a project Masdar has proudly delivered alongside Dubai Electricity and Water Authority (DEWA), EDF Renewables and our many other partners. Saudi Arabia's pledge to install nearly 60GW of solar and wind energy by 2030 will continue to dominate the renewable energy conversation regionally. Speaking at the Future Investment Initiative, HRH Prince Abdulaziz bin Salman, Saudi Arabia's Minister of Energy, confidently announced that the kingdom would become the world's most reliable provider of solar power, just as it is today its most dependable supplier of oil. Omani opportunities Similarly, Oman has launched an ambitious programme to both diversify its economy and strengthen its power infrastructure. Recent utility-scale solar PV tenders are evidence of this, with the Sultanate targeting a 30 percent share of its electricity mix for renewables by 2030. Masdar is already present in Oman through the Dhofar wind farm and actively pursuing more opportunities there. "As the first Arab world signatory to the Paris Agreement... the UAE is ideally positioned to reassert its credentials as a global sustainability leader" Encouragingly, the financial community is responding to the growing public demand for climate action, offering bonds and loans linked to the UN Sustainable Development Goals to encourage green projects. Incentive schemes, such as the IFC's Scaling Solar programme, are also emboldening investors to enter developing countries. As host of Abu Dhabi Sustainability Week (ADSW), Masdar is a keen supporter of the Abu Dhabi Sustainable Finance Forum and a signatory to its Sustainable Finance Declaration. Competing with coal Cheaper renewables are unlocking new markets. In 2019, Masdar announced its entry into Central Asia, with agreements to develop 400MW and 100MW of solar power projects in Armenia and Uzbekistan, respectively. Since 2008, Masdar City in Abu Dhabi has been a hub for innovation in sustainable urban development and cutting-edge pilot projects, including those in solar power, energy storage, green farming and biofuels. The wider adoption of smart metering, smart appliances and other smart city technologies will further integrate renewable sources into our energy systems. Distributed renewable energy sources will become more prevalent, with consumers supplied by smaller power plants and even their rooftop solar panels. Green energy Cheaper renewables sources will unlock new markets The UAE has announced 2020 as the year of preparations for its Golden Jubilee in 2021 and the coming 50 years. Welcoming tens of thousands of attendees from more than 170 countries, ADSW will be the ideal platform to seize the many opportunities, and to confront the many challenges, to build a more sustainable and prosperous future for all. There are only 10 years left to realise the Sustainable Development Goals. This year, all signatories to the Paris Agreement must produce their post-2020 climate actions, known as nationally determined contributions. COP25 ) concluded with other major economies reluctant to raise their targets. ADSW can help to address the missed opportunities of COP.\~ As the first Arab world signatory to the Paris Agreement, and the proud host of Expo 2020 in Dubai, which has sustainability as one of its core themes, the UAE is ideally positioned to reassert its credentials as a global sustainability leader. Mohamed Jameel Al Ramahi, Chief Executive Officer of Masdar 2020 ITP DIGITAL HYPERLINK http://imgs.syndigate.info/55/167/92/157966090224.jpg http://imgs.syndigate.info/55/167/92/157966090224.jpg \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE20" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 13, 2019 Friday"source="Khaleej Times (United Arab Emirates)" >
The Conference of Parties (CoP) this year in Madrid is a stepping stone to next year when the new commitments to climate action come in forc... The Conference of Parties (CoP) this year in Madrid is a stepping stone to next year when the new commitments to climate action come in force. The 2019 CoP aims at increasing ambitions to tackle climate change and completing processes related to the full operationalisation of the Paris Climate Change Agreement, before the 2020 climate summit. According to the UNFCCC, at COP 25 , "Crucial climate action work will be taken forward in areas including finance, the transparency of climate action, forests and agriculture, technology, capacity building, loss and damage, indigenous peoples, cities, oceans and gender." Among its highest priorities this year is the establishment of the rules for creating carbon markets among nations, cities and corporations to incentivise emission-reduction strategies. Longer heat waves, more intense rainstorms, seas eating into coastal cities, the disappearance of corals and crop production impacted negatively, putting pressure on food security - these are just some of the impacts if temperatures go up by 2 degrees Celsius. Keeping temperature increase to a 1.5 degree Celsius limit, versus a 2 degree Celsius increase, can reduce the intensity of climate change impact on society and natural biodiversity. Given that global temperature is currently rising by 0.2 degrees C (0.1 degrees C) per decade, human-induced warming has already reached 1 degrees C above pre-industrial levels around 2017. If this pace of warming continues, would reach 1.5 degrees C around 2040, notes a report by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). - Thewire.in \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE21" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="November 2, 2019 Saturday"source="Big News Network.com" >
WASHINGTON, DC - With his eye on the 2020 election, U.S. President Donald Trump is looking to capitalize on the signing of a partial trade deal with China. On Friday he was proposing the signing of the document detailing Phase-1 of the proposed deal take place in the state of Iowa. Iowa has worn the brunt of the trade war between the U.S. and China. It is also a key state in the 2020 election. The president on Friday it was important to get the deal done before a decision is made on the location for the signing. To dress it up even more, Mr Trump indicated he and the President of China Xi Jinping would be the signatories. It was a given, as far as he was concerned, that the signing would take place in the United States, "We're looking at a different couple of locations. It could even be in Iowa," he told reporters at a White House press conference. "We're discussing locations, but I like to get deals done first." It was expected a formal signing could have taken place at the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit in Santiago, Chile which was to have run from 14 to 17 November, however Chile has bowed out as the host country because of the accelerating protests there which have resulted in 18 deaths. "This has been a very difficult decision, a decision that causes us a lot of pain, because we fully understand the importance of APEC and COP-25 for Chile and for the world," President Sebastian Pinera said in a statement on Wednesday. "A president must always put his compatriots above all else," he said. "Our main concern is re-establishing public order, our citizens' safety and social peace along with pushing through a social agenda to respond to the main demands of our citizens." Trump said his preference anyway was for the signing to occur in the United States. "I would do it in the U.S.," he told reporters. Asked if Xi would too, Trump said: "He would too." (File photo). \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE22" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 10, 2019 Tuesday"source="ArabianBusiness.com" >
The United States and Saudi Arabia are among major polluters showing "hardly any signs" of reducing their greenhouse gas production, a global assessment of countries' emissions trajectories said Tuesday at United Nations climate talks. The Climate Change Performance Index (CCPI) measures the emissions, renewable energy share and climate policies of 57 countries and the European Union. It found the US ranks last, followed by Saudi Arabia and Australia, although several countries did report falls in emissions last year, largely due to an industry-wide fade out of coal. While climate performance varied greatly -- even within the EU, with Sweden leading the way -- the report found that none of the countries surveyed were currently on a path compatible with the Paris climate goals. US President Donald Trump says he plans to withdraw from the global plan to reduce emissions. China, the world's largest single emitter, was found to have taken "medium action" due to its high investment in renewables. However the index warned that Beijing could slump to the bottom rungs if it follows through on its plan to continue building coal-fired power plants. Ursula Hagen from the environmental watchdog Germanwatch, who co-authored the accompanying report, said both the US and China were "at a crossroads" on climate. "The index shows signs of a global turnaround in emissions, including declining coal consumption. However, several large countries are still trying to resist this trend -- above all the USA," she said. "Much will depend on further developments in China and the elections in the USA." Delegates are gathered at the COP 25 in Madrid to devise ways of putting the Paris plan in action, but key sticking points remain over emissions trading schemes and how the fight against climate change is funded. "This science based assessment shows again that in particular the large climate polluters do hardly anything for the transformational shift we need," said Stephan Singer from the Climate Action Network. He said nations need to implement "deep emissions reductions to curtail the run to potentially irreversible climate change". \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE23" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 26, 2019 Thursday"source="TechRadar" >
Consumers increasingly want to know how to reduce their environmental impact. Businesses that provide this information can help increase their sales. COP25 has brought with it even more pressure on governments and businesses to take climate change seriously. Consumers now demand that brands integrate sustainability or they risk extinction.&#xA0; Environmentally-aware consumers don&#x2019;t just want to make the world a better place; a survey by Futerra found that 96% of people believe behaviour and purchasing choices fuel real change. These consumers recognise they have a social responsibility to reduce their carbon footprint, and this is driving purchasing decisions. As consumers demand the demonstration of good corporate citizenship with a strong eco commitment, brands must strike a balance between what is right for their businesses with what is right for humanity and the environment. Already we&#x2019;re seeing reaction and response &#x2013; recently, John Lewis confirmed its first plastic-free bag trial in Oxford, while Vodafone has announced an initiative to sell more sustainable phones by the end of this year. But more needs to be done across the industry if brands are to remain in consumers&#x2019; shopping baskets. Products must tell sustainable stories across the supply chain, allowing consumers to track this from production to delivery. Creating clean supply chains In Denmark, for example, the government is working with supermarkets on creating labels that explain food products&#x2019; carbon footprints. While the idea of carbon labelling has been around for some time, there are very few brands that provide this level of visibility. In 2012, Tesco dropped a plan to label its product with its carbon footprint because of the amount of work involved in calculating the figure. However, nearly a decade on and this challenge is becoming less daunting. Sensors are now embedded into innocuous everyday objects. All of these items are now linked by the internet, sharing intelligence that can be used to deliver greater transparency into the provenance of individual products. Take small frequent buys that have a high environmental impact - such as perishable food or supermarket flowers. Sensors in the form of Radio Frequency Identification transmitters and GPS systems are used to track goods as they move from the production plant to storage facilities and are transported onto shop shelves. This intelligence can be used to give consumers an accurate view of where products have travelled. Brands can also capture the emissions produced by every vehicle or vessel involved in the transportation process and relay this back to customers. Interestingly, QR codes are providing the answer and meeting customers demand for more transparency. Using QR codes to access extra information might not be new exactly, but using spatial big data platforms, QR codes can read digital barcodes to provide deeper insights. Instead of simply enabling consumers to simply check brand credentials &#x2013; such as safety certificates and distribution licences &#x2013; QR codes can open apps that provide visualisations of product journeys. Route maps can even show precise movement of shipments from source to store and provide compelling proof of supply chain integrity through leveraging vast sets of data on a product&#x2019;s location and environment. &#xA0; IoT initiatives for a sustainable future Armed with greater intelligence, brands have an opportunity to optimise their operations to achieve greater efficiency and demonstrate their commitment to sustainability. The insight on the movement of goods can be combined with information such as temperature, humidity levels and shipping times. By combining the data sets available, brands can improve distribution models. For example, food with a short shelf life can be sent to a nearby destination with high-demand to limit food wastage. Brands can also streamline delivery services - something that&#x2019;s particularly important given the explosion in online shopping. Brands can use data from IoT-enabled devices such as connected cars, wearables and even the SIM cards that delivery drivers use. Each one represents a point of interest on the move, meaning its route can be accurately determined. Brands can analyse driver routes using fleet management software, calculate average drop times, dwell times, as well as distances between drops. Density analysis reveals when multiple drivers are operating in the same area at the same time, while additional data sets can reveal whether drops were successful or not. By leveraging IoT data, brands can evaluate driver routes against delivery data &#x2013; including pick-up windows and fulfilment times, and logistics tools such as ERP software. This information can then be combined with information on pollution levels, congestion areas and even weather forecasting, to define which routes will keep both costs and emissions low. Changing tides of sustainability With consumer having an unprecedented amount of information available to them, they are making carefully considered purchases. They research products and buy items that align with their values. To engage with a new generation of consumers, brands need to be authentic and integrate sustainability into the fabric of their brands. They need to help consumers make informed purchasing decisions through greater transparency. Going green not only attracts sustainably conscious consumers, but also helps reduce business costs. By harnessing and utilising data efficiently, tech can help brands optimise operations to reduce their carbon footprint and provide heightened visibility to consumers on product provenance. This will lead to increased innovation and more technology in this field. It&#x2019;s a small, incremental change that can ultimately help contribute to a greater cause. Protect against maleare with the best antivirus. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE24" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 12, 2019 Thursday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
WGEO / UNFCCC / NDC Implementation / climate change MADRID, 12th December, 2019 (WAM) -- The World Green Economy Organisation, WGEO, in cooperation with the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, UNFCCC, held a high-level forum that discussed climate finance strategies for the implementation of Nationally Determined Contributions, NDCs. During the conference, participants also reviewed the measures and actions taken by countries under the framework of the Paris Agreement. The forum, which was attended by ministers, officials and representatives from many countries, provided a key platform for participants to exchange knowledge on the most important practices and effective ways to develop and implement regional and national strategies. These efforts are aimed at facilitating countries' access to financing and help them meet their NDCs to mitigate the effects of climate change and achieve the long-term strategies of developing countries. WGEO reaffirmed its commitment to promoting the global transition towards a green economy and to supporting ambitious and innovative actions by countries to face climate change challenges worldwide. "It is my pleasure to welcome you to the High-level Forum on Climate Finance Strategies, a joint undertaking by the World Green Economy Organisation and UN Climate Change Secretariat. I congratulate the UN Climate Change Secretariat, and the governments of Chile and Spain, for their tremendous efforts to bring us all here in support of the global process to address climate change on the sideline of COP 25 ," said WGEO Chairman, Saeed Mohammed Al Tayer, during the forum. "Countries have, in their Nationally Determined Contributions and their National Adaptation Plans, laid out their commitments to reduce emissions and their climate-resilient development charted a course to deal with the impacts of climate change," he noted, adding that, "Financing these commitments and plans, enhancing access to the means to turn roadmaps into reality, is an immediate priority, especially for developing countries." "Working to create this change, to address climate change while leading towards a new economic system that is built upon green solutions is a mission that the World Green Economy Organisation (WGEO) is committed to," Al Tayer affirmed. WGEO and UNFCCC released a report titled, 'From Aspiration to Actual Action on Climate Change'. It provided insights and feedback about financing needs related to climate activities of some countries and regions based on discussions organised by the two parties during the five ministerial meetings, several high-level forums, and the Global Ministerial Conference on the Green Economy held this year. More than 300 participants took part in the forum, including ministers, senior executives and leading experts from international organisations and private institutions. The speakers presented their views on financing needs concerning the needs of some countries and regions, including the available instruments, initiatives and activities to support countries in the Arab, African, and Southeast Asian regions. The forum also shed light on the broader efforts currently being undertaken by some countries to mobilise climate finance such as the NBF project. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE25" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 27, 2019 Friday"source="Khaleej Times (United Arab Emirates)" >
China should aim to be not only a fully developed economy by 2050, but also a zero-carbon one. The 2010s may be remembered as the decade when the fight against harmful climate change was lost. In 2015, at the COP21 climate conference in Paris, 196 countries agreed to limit global warming to well below 2\'b0C above pre-industrial levels. But global greenhouse-gas (GHG) emissions have continued to increase, atmospheric concentrations of carbon dioxide are at their highest levels in 800,000 years, and current policies will likely result in warming of about 3\'b0C by 2100. Moreover, the recent COP25 negotiations in Madrid ended in failure, with governments squabbling over the value and allocation of "carbon credits" held over from a discredited previous policy regime. At the same time, however, stunning technological progress during the 2010s makes it possible to cut GHG emissions at a cost far lower than we dared hope a decade ago. The costs of solar and wind power have fallen more than 80% and 70%, respectively, while lithium-ion battery costs are down from $1,000 per kilowatt-hour in 2010 to $160 per kWh today. These and other breakthroughs guarantee that energy systems which are as much as 85% dependent on variable renewables could produce zero-carbon electricity at costs that are fully competitive with those of fossil-fuel-based systems. In addition, it is now clear that even the "harder-to-abate" sectors of the economy, such as heavy industry (including steel, cement, and chemicals) and long-distance transport (shipping, aviation, and trucking), can be decarbonized at costs which, although significant for any one company acting alone, are trivial in terms of the impact on people's living standards. In May 2019, the United Kingdom's Committee on Climate Change estimated that achieving a zero-carbon UK economy by 2050 would reduce GDP that year by no more than 1-2%. Back in 2008, the same committee, which I then chaired, had estimated a similar cost to achieve only an 80% reduction in emissions. Lower decarbonization costs and growing awareness of climate risks have in turn prompted an increasing focus on the possibility and necessity of meeting the zero-emissions goal by 2050. In July, the UK made a legally binding commitment to meet that objective, and the European Union agreed on the same goal earlier this month. Furthermore, Maersk, the world's largest container-shipping firm, the Swedish steel producer SSAB, and the Indian cement company Dalmia are among the growing number of leading businesses committed to being zero-carbon by 2050 or earlier. To achieve the Paris agreement's climate objective, all developed economies must become zero-carbon by around mid-century, and could do so at a minimal cost to living standards. And such efforts also must include China. Today, China seeks to negotiate at climate-change conferences as a "developing country" in view of its current GDP per capita (in purchasing-power-parity terms) of about $18,000, or around 40% of the EU average. But the government's stated ambition is for China to become "a fully developed rich economy" by 2050, with a higher GDP per capita than any European country today. And given the quality of China's workforce, infrastructure, and management, and its increasing technological leadership in many sectors, that objective is entirely achievable. How rapidly China reduces emissions is therefore crucial. The country currently accounts for almost 30% of global CO2 emissions, and its per capita emissions are due to overtake Europe's declining figure within a few years. So, if China does not dramatically cut emissions by 2050, whether Europe reduces them by 80% or 100% will have minimal impact on the rate of global warming. China should aim to be not only a fully developed economy by 2050, but also a zero-carbon one. Achieving this will of course require huge investments. The electricity production required to support rising living standards in China, and to achieve widespread electrification of transport, residential heating, and industry, could increase from 6,700 terawatt-hours today to 14-15,000 TWh by 2050. That implies a tripling of annual wind and solar investment in order to increase renewable capacity to almost 5,000 gigawatts by 2050, together with 230 GW of nuclear. But as a recent Energy Transitions Commission report points out, even this enormous capacity increase, along with additional investment in energy transmission, distribution, and storage, would require an overall increase in Chinese investment of less than 1% of GDP - and this in a country that saves and invests over 40% of it. Moreover, the total impact on China's GDP in 2050, and thus on consumer living standards, would be a similarly low 1% - and potentially far less, because the zero-carbon commitment would stimulate technological progress and improve productivity. Following the failure in Madrid, attention will now focus on prospects for the COP26 conference in Glasgow next year. Developed economies, plus rapidly developing China, should unilaterally commit to achieving zero emissions by 2050, confident that the cost to their economies will be very small. Emerging economies should commit to meeting the same target a decade later, confident that the technological progress involved in reducing emissions in developed countries will reduce the costs of decarbonization over time. In addition, both developed and developing countries should focus on the globally important question that the International Energy Agency highlighted in its latest World Energy Outlook: how to unleash massive investment in renewable electricity in low-income economies. That applies particularly to Africa, a continent with the world's best solar resources but currently less than 1% of its solar photovoltaic capacity. If next year's COP26 can successfully address these big opportunities and challenges, the 2020s might be the decade in which we start winning the climate-change battle. - Adair Turner, Chair of the Energy Transitions Commission, was Chair of the UK Financial Services Authority from 2008 to 2012. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE26" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 9, 2019 Monday"source="CommsMEA.com" >
At COP25 , Schneider Electric reaffirmed its ambition to be a role model in the fight against climate change, by delivering services & solutions that allow its customers to reduce more CO2 emissions than those induced by its activity and by seriously decarbonizing itself. This is reflected by the commitments made during Climate Week as part of the "Business Ambition for 1.5\'b0C - Our Only Future". The Group shared its plans for: (1) engaging with suppliers towards a net-zero supply chain by 2050 (2) achieving net-zero operational emissions and reduce scope 3 emissions by 35 per cent by 2030 (vs 2017) as part of its validated 1.5\'b0C SBT target (3) being carbon neutral in its operations by offsetting remaining emissions no later than 2025 (4) reaching by 2025 - five years in advance - its COP21 goal of carbon neutrality in its expanded ecosystem, by delivering more CO2 savings to its customers than its carbon footprint "Climate change is one of the greatest threats to the planet's health and to its people. We must work together to achieve this and stop the temperature rise," says Josu Ugarte, president of Schneider Electric Iberia. "Companies play a key role in reducing our carbon footprint. For this reason, the company has recently joined the group of early adopters that lead "Business Ambition for 1.5 \'ba C" with the aim of making this situation visible and try to add more leaders in the cause. In Spain, we are pursuing the implementation of new models for the purchase and sale of energy with PPAs (Power Purchase Agreements), which allow much more competitive prices to be set over a specific period of time. Thanks to the signing of these contracts, it is possible to invest in new renewable assets throughout the country." Schneider Electric has been a leading contributor to the fight against climate change for the past 15 years by implementing its own energy management and industrial automation offers across its operations, by supporting its clients in achieving their low-carbon and efficiency objectives and by allowing more than 24 million people to gain access to electricity. In 2019, programs in the Schneider Sustainability Impact's Climate pillar confirmed this ambition: more than 70 million tons of CO2 were saved on its clients' end, CO2 efficiency in transportation was improved by 8.8 per cent, the Group confirmed a 45 per cent renewable electricity consumption worldwide, and the consumption of over 77,000 tons of primary resources was avoided with circular offers. Schneider Electric accelerates innovation with new circular offers and business models, that enable products to be maintained, repaired, retrofitted for a longer lifetime, and reprocessed at the end of their life. Since 2015, our ecoDesign WayTM program is embedded into our R&D strategy to design new offers which are circular by design, and deliver additional environmental benefits to customers. 2020 Schneider Electric circular goals for 2020 include 75% of global sales under its new Green Premium programme 200 sites labeled toward zero waste to landfill 120,000 metric tons of avoided primary resources consumption through ECOFIT, recycling, and take-back programs Through Energy and Sustainability Services (ESS), Schneider Electric is advising clients in more than 100 countries on their carbon strategy and clean energy procurement, delivering efficiency in client facilities and sustaining results over time through long-term partnerships. In 2019, revenues from ESS increased by 20.2 per cent, demonstrating the acceleration of decarbonization. How these partnerships can impact on carbon is demonstrated with clients like Agrial. The French agricultural group with operations across Europe has embarked in 2015 on an efficiency program together with ESS, targeting a 10 per cent energy reduction for all of Agrial's sites. After demonstration of success with the pilot site, that even exceeded the guaranteed savings, 46 sites have joined the project to date, significantly reducing greenhouse gas emissions. Philippe Diez, ESS vice president EMEA comments "It's encouraging to see that most of our clients already have a lot of great actions in place. With our services, we try to connect all the internal departments working on clean energy procurement, energy efficiency programs or sustainability actions and make them move in the same direction, ideally toward a science-based carbon target that follows the 1,5-degree pathway." Acting today for a more Inclusive world Schneider Electric has developed for more than 10 years the Access to Energy program which will notably provide electricity to 80 million people by 2030 thanks to its offers and business models. Last week, two solutions, Villaya Community Emergency and Homaya PAYG solution have been awarded the Solar Impulse label. It is given by a team of independent scientific and financial experts led by Bertrand Piccard. The Solar Impulse label highlights solutions that are proven to be economically and environmentally attractive. These solutions are now part of the 1,000 solutions that can change the world for the better. "Access to energy is a basic human right, but it is also crucial that we are mindful of the effects of energy consumption on the environment," Gilles Vermot Desroches said. "We must find ways to bring energy-poor populations access to energy and allow them to develop in a sustainable way." Together, a net-zero future is possible Global Climate science is clear: public and private spheres must work together to reduce global carbon emissions and halt the rise in temperature. In line with TCFD recommendations, Schneider Electric launched two years earlier a prospective approach on climate change and energy transition, by setting up a dedicated organisation in charge. The Scenarios developed by Schneider Electric demonstrate that a net-zero carbon future, aligned with IPCC's 1.5\'b0C scenarios, is possible and the Group is uniquely positioned to embark its ecosystem into an inclusive, low-carbon transition. HYPERLINK http://imgs.syndigate.info/264/903/86/157594573754.jpg http://imgs.syndigate.info/264/903/86/157594573754.jpg Schneider electric commits to a carbon neutral future \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE27" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="January 7, 2020 Tuesday"source="Khaleej Times (United Arab Emirates)" >
Solidarity may take the form of direct financial transfers or a global agreement to vary national emissions targets or carbon taxes according to countri... There is an overwhelming consensus among scientists that this decade will be the last window for humanity to change the current global trajectory of carbon dioxide emissions so that the world can get close to zero net emissions by around 2050, and thus avoid potentially catastrophic climate risks. But although the massive technological and economic changes required to achieve this goal are well understood, their political implications are rarely discussed. While climate activists have built an impressive international movement, broadening their political support and crossing borders, the nationalist narrative has been gaining ground in domestic politics. Its central message - that the world consists of nation-states in relentless competition with one another - stands in sharp contrast to the climate movement's 'one planet' emphasis on human solidarity. These two trends are on a collision course. Although greenhouse-gas (GHG) emissions do not respect political borders, and climate change affects all parts of the planet, the impact of global warming is decidedly not uniform. An average global temperature increase of 2\'b0C will create extreme heat stress in India and Africa. Similarly, although rising sea levels will threaten lower-lying areas around the world, and more extreme weather events will affect almost everyone, already poor and vulnerable populations are especially at risk. Another inherently international aspect of the problem is carbon leakage as a result of trade. While GHGs are emitted in one country by the production of, say, steel, it is the use of that steel in importing countries that 'causes' the emissions in the exporting country. The net benefits for all countries of controlling global warming are clear, because the various tipping points (and the possibility of cascading effects) present huge global risks, and not just for future generations. Moreover, the green economy offers big medium-term opportunities. But, because climate mitigation is a global public good, and given the geographically varied impact of global warming and the transmission of emissions through trade, it is extremely difficult to make progress through multilateral negotiations. Every government tries to maximise its gains and minimise its losses according to a narrowly nationalist perspective - and often within very short-term political timeframes. The failure of the recent COP25 climate negotiations in Madrid reflects these difficulties only too well. The climate movement has thus correctly perceived that success will require a planetary ethics based on global solidarity and responsibility, with any credible solution necessarily including compensation for the temporary losers from green policies. Solidarity may take the form of direct financial transfers or a global agreement to vary national emissions targets or carbon taxes according to countries' income levels. For that reason, climate change poses a clear dilemma for the political right. The need to overcome short-term national interests in tackling global warming runs counter to the resurgent nationalist narrative. This is especially so in rich countries, which will have to compensate less developed economies either directly or by agreeing to differentiated rights and responsibilities. Raghuram G. Rajan, for example, recently proposed a formula whereby rich countries with per capita CO2 emissions above the world average would pay into a global fund that rewards low per capita emitters. However, under Rajan's proposal, the United States would pay about $36 billion per year into the fund. Would nationalist politicians in advanced economies ever agree to such a formula, or even to much less ambitious variants? Moreover, even governments that claim to be committed to the overall (and insufficiently ambitious) mitigation targets in the 2015 Paris climate agreement are dragging their feet when action requires substantial short-term sacrifice. Without robust solidarity, it seems, the tough measures and difficult compromises needed to protect the world from potentially devastating climate change are unlikely to come soon enough - if at all. Some climate advocates minimise the distributional issue, because they want to build as wide a political tent as possible and emphasise the long-term gains for all from tackling global warming. And as some centre-right political parties, notably in Europe, make climate protection part of their programmes, government coalitions comprising them and green parties appear increasingly possible. Globally, however, the inherent contradiction between the conservative nationalist and green internationalist narratives will remain. What China and India do is crucial, because they already account for about one-third of total global CO2 emissions. Further rapid increases in their share would fuel the nationalist reflex elsewhere, making any global climate agreement even harder to achieve. The EU's plans for a carbon border tax will be hotly contested, not least on equity grounds, unless developing countries are exempted. The EU's proposed tax also could trigger a negative reaction from the US, depending on the results of November's presidential election. The Nobel laureate economist Robert J. Shiller has argued that economies are driven more by popular 'narratives' than by technical policies. Given the centrality of the climate issue this decade, the conflict between climate activism and nationalism is likely to become more pronounced. In fact, this clash may become a defining feature of politics, with the nationalist right facing a coalition of climate-oriented voters comprising not only today's Greens, but also those from the social-democratic centre-left and the traditional centre-right. Moreover, other issues will be connected to this fault line, not least the need for domestic compensation of those groups that temporarily lose out as a result of ambitious climate mitigation efforts. If the dominant divide of the 2020s is between the nationalist narrative and green internationalism, then the climate debate may import global issues into national politics like never before. The outcome, of course, remains to be seen. -Project Syndicate Kemal Dervis is the former Minister of Economic Affairs of Turkey and former Administrator for the United Nations Development Program \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE28" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="November 29, 2019 Friday"source="Khaleej Times (United Arab Emirates)" >
Striking is not a choice we relish; we do it because we see no other options. For more than a year, children and young people from around the world have been striking for the climate. We launched a movement that defied all expectations, with millions of people lending their voices - and their bodies - to the cause. We did this not because it was our dream, but because we didn't see anyone else taking action to secure our future. And despite the vocal support we have received from many adults - including some of the world's most powerful leaders - we still don't. Striking is not a choice we relish; we do it because we see no other options. We have watched a string of United Nations climate conferences unfold. Countless negotiations have produced much-hyped but ultimately empty commitments from the world's governments - the same governments that allow fossil-fuel companies to drill for ever-more oil and gas, and burn away our futures for their profit. Politicians and fossil-fuel companies have known about climate change for decades. And yet the politicians let the profiteers continue to exploit our planet's resources and destroy its ecosystems in a quest for quick cash that threatens our very existence. Don't take our word for it: scientists are sounding the alarm. They warn that we have never been less likely to limit the rise in global temperatures to 1.5 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels - the threshold beyond which the most destructive effects of climate change would be triggered. Worse, recent research shows that we are on track to produce 120% more fossil fuels in 2030 than would be consistent with the 1.5\'b0C limit. The concentration of climate-heating greenhouse gases in our atmosphere has reached a record high, with no sign of a slowdown. Even if countries fulfill their current emissions-reduction pledges, we are headed for a 3.2\'b0C increase. Young people like us bear the brunt of our leaders' failures. Research shows that pollution from burning fossil fuels is the world's most significant threat to children's health. Just this month, five million masks were handed out at schools in New Delhi, India's capital, owing to toxic smog. Fossil fuels are literally choking the life from us. The science is crying out for urgent action, and still our leaders dare to ignore it. So we continue to fight. After a year of strikes, our voices are being heard. We are being invited to speak in the corridors of power. At the UN, we addressed a room filled with world leaders. At the World Economic Forum in Davos, we met with prime ministers, presidents, and even the pope. We have spent hundreds of hours participating in panels and speaking with journalists and filmmakers. We have been offered awards for our activism. Our efforts have helped to shift the wider conversation on climate change. People now increasingly discuss the crisis we face, not in whispers or as an afterthought, but publicly and with a sense of urgency. Polls confirm changing perceptions. One recent survey showed that, in seven of the eight countries included, climate breakdown is considered to be the most important issue facing the world. Another confirmed that schoolchildren have led the way in raising awareness. With public opinion shifting, world leaders, too, say that they have heard us. They say that they agree with our demand for urgent action to tackle the climate crisis. But they do nothing. As they head to Madrid for the 25th session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP25 ) to the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change, we call out this hypocrisy. On the next two Fridays, we will again take to the streets: worldwide on November 29, and in Madrid, Santiago, and many other places on December 6 during the UN climate conference. Schoolchildren, young people, and adults all over the world will stand together, demanding that our leaders take action - not because we want them to, but because the science demands it. That action must be powerful and wide-ranging. After all, the climate crisis is not just about the environment. It is a crisis of human rights, of justice, and of political will. Colonial, racist, and patriarchal systems of oppression have created and fueled it. We need to dismantle them all. Our political leaders can no longer shirk their responsibilities. Some say that the Madrid conference is not very important; the big decisions will be made at COP26 in Glasgow next year. We disagree. As the science makes clear, we don't have a single day to lose. We have learned that, if we do not step up, nobody will. So we will keep up a steady drumbeat of strikes, protests, and other actions. We will become louder and louder. We will do whatever it takes to persuade our leaders to unite behind science so clear that even children understand it. Collective action works; we have proved that. But to change everything, we need everyone. Each and every one of us must participate in the climate resistance movement. We cannot just say we care; we must show it. Join us. Participate in our upcoming climate strikes in Madrid or in your hometown. Show your community, the fossil-fuel industry, and your political leaders that you will not tolerate inaction on climate change anymore. With numbers on our side, we have a chance. And to the leaders who are headed to Madrid, our message is simple: the eyes of all future generations are upon you. Act accordingly. This commentary was also signed by Evan Meneses (Australia) and Hilda Flavia Nakabuye (Fridays for Future Uganda). Greta Thunberg is a Swedish climate activist. Luisa Neubauer is a German climate activist. Angela Valenzuela is a coordinator of Fridays for Future in Santiago. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE29" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 6, 2019 Friday"source="Forexpros" >
Investing.com - By Geoffrey Smith Investing.com -- It's been a tough week for the oil and gas sector. The price of its main commodity has risen by over $2 - nearly 4% - as the cartel that produces over 40% of the world's output has moved toward a significant tightening of its policy, but the share prices of Europe's big names are mostly down on the week, reflecting a growing number of longer-term concerns. The big four European majors are all down on the week, by between 0.6% and 2.6%. For one thing, there's the worry about whether the action agreed by OPEC and allies led by Russia will actually be enough to stop a fresh glut on world markets next year. The 'OPEC+' grouping has reportedly agreed to take another 500,000 barrels a day of oil off the market through the end of 2020, but whether that will be enough to offset rising production in Brazil, Norway and \- the big wild card \- U.S. shale is far from clear - especially if the U.S.'s attritional trade war with China continues to depress world oil demand. London-listed BP (LON:BP) and Royal Dutch Shell (LON:RDSa) can at least argue that some of their weakness is due to exchange rate effects: the pound has rallied strongly this week, reducing the value of their dollar-based income streams. But that doesn't explain away Total's and Eni's limp performance. The truth is \- the OPEC meeting in Vienna is not the only game in town. Across the continent in Madrid, the UN-sponsored COP 25 talks on climate change have sharpened the focus on the growing hostility to the very notion of oil and gas, even though there is currently no way of maintaining living standards in a world without the two sources that meet the overwhelming majority of the world's primary energy needs. The sector has been under siege from the growing might of the sustainable investing lobby for years, and now the authorities appear to be taking the ESG side too: incoming European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen has pledged to make the continent carbon-neutral by 2050, and Christine Lagarde is likely to throw the European Central Bank's considerable influence behind that push when she launches her strategic review of ECB policy, probably at her first governing council meeting next week. The ECB's action could include, for example, banning the sector's bonds from its asset purchase programs. It could also, as bank supervisor, apply higher capital charges on loans to the sector (ironically so, given that the majors in particular have rock-solid credit ratings). The central bank could also pull its own pension money from the sector's bonds and stocks. All three measures would raise the majors' cost of capital, the first two especially. The majors' stock prices have always been supported by the assumption that they are indispensable to the modern economy. That assumption is going to be tested with growing severity every year in future. Investing.com offers an extensive set of professional tools for the financial markets. Read more News on Investing.com and download the new Investing.com apps for Android and iOS! \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE30" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="November 27, 2019 Wednesday"source="Khaleej Times (United Arab Emirates)" >
Climate change is one of the most important environmental issues at the regional and international levels given its economic and social impact. (Supplied photo) The extreme rise in temperatures and high humidity are the biggest climate change challenges facing the GCC region and nations need to join hands to develop a unified model that can help protect the environment, a top UAE official has said. Fahed Al Hammad, acting assistant undersecretary for the Green Development and Climate Change at the Ministry of Climate Change and Environment (MoCCE), cautioned: "Temperatures in the UAE and the Gulf region were very high especially in the hot months, reaching highs of 50 degrees Celsius in the UAE during summer this year. "We must create a unified model for the GCC region to address the impacts of climate change and protect the environment from global warming." Al Hammad was speaking at a media briefing by the Ministry of Climate Change and Environment on UAE's preparations for the 25th session of the UN Climate Change Conference COP 25 , which will take place in Madrid, Spain, from December 2-13. He noted that at the forthcoming conference, the UAE, with a delegation of 80 members, including 40 students, will present its climate change study - the first-of-its-kind in the region - which is about oceans and the South Pole and how the oceans have been impacted by climate change. "Climate change is one of the most important environmental issues at the regional and international levels given its economic and social impact," said Al Hammadi. He added that the UAE has adopted key environment-friendly policies including economic diversification, energy sources diversification, while focusing on green economy and promoting renewable and clean energy as well as energy efficiency and sustainable transport. The UN annual Climate Change Conference is designated to take the next crucial steps in the UN climate change process. A key objective is to complete several matters with respect to the full implementation of the Paris Climate Change Agreement. The conference will take place under the presidency of the Government of Chile. Jorge Daccarett, Ambassadar of Chile to the UAE, said retaining the presidency is a decision based on conviction of the urgent need to continue mobilising the fight against climate change. "This trans-formative agenda points towards a more just, human and sustainable development," said Daccarett. He added: "Our high vulnerability and increase in the frequency and intensity of extreme weather events have generated higher demand for resources. Our planet is facing extreme weather phenomena such as severe droughts, more frequent extreme floods, large-scale wildfires, torrential rains and hailstorms, all of them affecting development capabilities and triggering social conflicts." The conference, which will attract more than 25,000 participants, will launch a platform of climate solutions for the oceans. It is the first climate change conference before the implementation of the Paris Agreement scheduled for 2020. Nations will use this platform to seek to boost the alliance for climate action, by incorporating new actors and new issues, especially highlighting the importance of governments and local companies. Among other issues to be highlighted is the importance of the cryosphere as a global climate regulator, the role of science, electromobility and renewable energies. HYPERLINK mailto:ismail@khaleejtimes.com ismail@khaleejtimes.com Ismail Sebugwaawo HYPERLINK http://imgs.syndigate.info/28/44/79/157487177628.jpeg http://imgs.syndigate.info/28/44/79/157487177628.jpeg \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_UAE31" COP="COP25" country="UAE" date="December 31, 2019"source="Law Update (UAE)" >
by Francis Patalong - Senior Associate - Corporate / Mergers & Acquisitions - HYPERLINK mailto:f.patalong@tamimi.com f.patalong@tamimi.com Mark Brown - Partner - Banking & Finance - HYPERLINK mailto:m.brown@tamimi.com m.brown@tamimi.com - Abu Dhabi Published: December 2019 \- January 2020 COP25 having taken place in Madrid it is time to take a fresh look at the prospects for renewable energy in Saudi Arabia. Before doing so, it is also worth revisiting our previous survey [1] of the geo-political context in which climate measures are being taken and examine the governance, risk and compliance framework which is reasonably foreseeable to be adopted in the short to medium term. Finally, we will look at concrete measures which are being taken in Saudi Arabia to address the challenge of climate change. Regulatory Stepping Stones The Extinction Rebellion protests which took place this summer in London and other major cities were hard to miss. Thousands of interested citizens, many of whom would previously not have contemplated participating in direct political action, drawn from the broadest spectrum of ideological backgrounds, were determined to engage in peaceful protest (and yet risk being arrested) in order to focus attention on the climate crisis. Basing their actions on the hard science of climate change, they have certainly succeeded in ratcheting the issue up political and corporate agendas. Although the rhetoric and tactics of the protests have drawn criticism, the direction of travel is clear. The protestors are however the tip of an iceberg \- the divestment movement, which seeks to encourage institutional investors (such as sovereign wealth funds, banks, global asset managers and insurance companies, cities, pension funds, health care organisations, universities, faith groups and foundations) to reconsider their portfolios on ethically green lines has had a profound impact. The value of portfolios committed to divestment have increased from US$52 billion in 2014 to more than US$11 trillion in 2019, an increase of 22,000 per cent. [2] Progress will however have to accelerate if the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change ('IPCC')'s warnings are to be heeded. The reality is stark: [3] implementing current unconditional Nationally Determined Contributions ('NDCs') would lead to a global mean temperature rise of between 2.9\'b0C and 3.4\'b0C by 2100 relative to pre-industrial levels, and continuing thereafter; and the current level of NDC ambition needs to be roughly tripled for emission reduction to be in line with the 2\'b0C goal and increased fivefold for the 1.5\'b0C goal. A temperature rise of more than 2\'b0C would be catastrophic. We have already breached the 1.1\'b0C threshold. Unsurprisingly, the requirement to report climate impacts on a regular basis is likely to become a fact of life for all corporates as part of their Governance, Risk and Compliance ('GRC') frameworks. The Task Force on Climate-related Financial Disclosures ('TFCFD'), led by former Mayor of New York, Michael Bloomberg, has been particularly active in this regard. The foreword to the June 2019 TFCFD [4] report bears repetition here: "Based on a recent report issued by the [United Nations'] Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change urgent and unprecedented changes are needed to meet the goals of the Paris Agreement." The report warns limiting the global average temperature to a maximum of 1.5\'b0C "require[s] rapid and far-reaching transitions in energy, land, urban and infrastructure [systems] (including transport and buildings), and industrial systems." In fact, according to a recent United Nations Environment Programme report on emissions, global greenhouse gas emissions have to peak by 2020 and decline rapidly thereafter to limit the increase in the global average temperature to no more than 1.5\'b0C above pre-industrial levels. However, based on current policies and commitments, "global emissions are not even estimated to peak by 2030 let alone by 2020." As a result, governments and private sector entities are considering a range of options for reducing global emissions, which could result in disruptive changes across economic sectors and regions in the near term." The World Economic Forum ('WEF'), famous for its Davos meetings of key leaders at the public/private interface, also continues to work with members of its Alliance of CEO Climate Leaders. WEF is also partnering with law firms to help corporate legal departments better understand climate-related risks. Climate governance principles have been promulgated for how corporate boards should address climate-related risk. Furthermore, in April 2019, S&P Global Ratings released its Environmental, Social, and Governance ('ESG') Evaluation Analytical Approach. [5] The ESG Evaluation "is a cross-sector, relative analysis of an entity's capacity to operate successfully in the future and is grounded in how ESG factors could affect stakeholders." The ESG will assess (at the request of an entity) whether and to what extent a company has complied with the TFCTF's 11 recommended disclosures related to climate change which include measures under governance, strategy, risk management and the setting of metrics and targets. Other ratings agencies (including Fitch and Moody's) are also active in this new market for tangible validation of sustainability measures. The reality of these measures and their perception in the market will become determinative of corporate success in the future. As Mark Carney, Governor of the Bank of England and recently appointed UN Special Envoy for Climate Action and Finance, has said: "There will be industries, sectors and firms that do very well during this process because they will be part of the solution but there will also be ones that lag behind and they will be punished." His core message is that: "Companies that don't adapt will go bankrupt without question." These are the considerations which will animate innovation for the foreseeable future. General Counsel in all sectors should be raising and discussing these issues with their commercial counterparts as a standing agenda item in all ESG/GRC meetings \- not just in terms of their own businesses but also as regards their supply chains. At a time when digitisation and innovation are key themes for business it also worth noting that the global energy burden of ICT could comprise 20 per cent of all the world's electricity demand by 2025. The fourth industrial revolution will therefore have to be very carefully calibrated to take account of its environmental footprint. The challenge is clear: "The situation is alarming," said [Anders] Andrae, who works for the Chinese communications technology firm Huawei. "We have a tsunami of data approaching. Everything which can be is being digitalised. It is a perfect storm. 5G [the fifth generation of mobile technology] is coming, IP [internet protocol] traffic is much higher than estimated, and all cars and machines, robots and artificial intelligence are being digitalised, producing huge amounts of data which is stored in data centres." [6] Moreover, the kinds of reporting requirements described above are likely to harden: Carney has warned major corporations that they have two years to agree rules for reporting climate risks before global regulators devise their own and make them compulsory. [7] The International Renewable Energy Agency ('IRENA') predicts that nearly US$148 billion will be required each year until 2050 to limit global temperature increases to 1.5 C above pre-industrial levels \- investment on this kind of scale will be subject to significant scrutiny and reporting requirements. Raising funds for significant projects or innovations that do not have auditable green credentials will be difficult if not impossible. If this is not easy reading for those engaged in oil and gas, it is deeply troubling for the shale industry which has, in recent years, operated as a kind of thermostat on the global oil price but remains a deeply polluting source of hydrocarbons. Moreover, businesses which do heed Carney's warning and accept the challenge of moving towards carbon neutrality will want to see that regulations are enforced locally and internationally. It's not just Mayor Bloomberg, Governor Carney and the WEF. The European Union has agreed (subject to EU Commission approval) a new set of rules governing which financial products can be called 'green' and 'sustainable'. [8] The initiative classifies products into three levels, and also requires full disclosure of all financial instruments, forcing funds without any sustainability claims to disclose that they are not assessed under the green criteria. Under the agreement, all financial products that claim to be green or sustainable will have to disclose exactly what proportion of their investments are environmentally friendly. "With credible and ambitious definitions for sustainable investment the EU will lead the world in sustainable finance now that we have credible definitions on which economic activities can be considered sustainable, the new Commission will have to start preparing to clearly identify environmentally harmful activities and the investments that currently support them" said EU lawmaker Bas Eickhout, lead negotiator on the matter. More Than Green Shoots In 2016 [9] Saudi Arabia's Vision 2030 development blueprint recognised that "the kingdom's impressive natural potential for solar and wind power generation remains largely untapped" and pledged to generate 9.5GW of renewable energy by 2030. 2016 now seems like a long time ago \- and initiatives have rapidly expanded in their ambition and scope. Commentator Jonathan Gornall observes: "Saudi Arabia, equipped with the motivation and the funds to carry out bold renewable-energy projects, has shown it can act fast. It is, after all, less than three years since the very first wind turbine was installed in the kingdom \- tellingly, to supply 2.75MW of electricity to a facility in Turaif belonging to Saudi Aramco, the world's largest oil and gas company." Much has been written about the short-term success of the recent Saudi Aramco IPO \- but perhaps the key determinant of its long term impact will be the ability to sustain and accelerate the kind of progress described above, and at a pace to maintain alignment with the kinds of international reporting benchmarks that are likely in future \- noting what is said above about the huge surge in data storage requirements. Aramco is not the only large industrial consumer of power in the Kingdom; where it leads others must follow. With a young population that is adept at adopting new technology, contributing to the tsunami of data indicated above, the imperative is clear. The opportunity is however significant, according to Michael Hayes [10], global head of renewables, KPMG International (reported in Arab News 20 November 2019): "The amount of capital required to support the energy transition is vast and it is for this reason that a whole new sector called green finance has emerged in recent years delivering new products such as green bonds and green insurance. Much of the expenditure in renewables over the next 20 years will be in emerging markets and so Saudi Arabia should concentrate on creating a centre for green finance for emerging markets". The Saudi government intends to attract between US$30 billion and US$50 billion in new investments into renewables by 2030, as it plans to tender around 9.5GW of solar and wind capacities by 2023. More broadly, the government has embarked on a series of initiatives that are squarely aimed at improving the state's green performance. In July 2019, Renewable Energy Project Development Office ('REPDO') of Saudi Arabia's Ministry of Energy, Industry and Mineral Resources ('MEIM') announced a new global record low LCOE (levelised cost of electricity) for the 400MW Dumat Al Jandal onshore wind project which closed at 1.99 US c/kWh. This comes after REPDO successfully awarded the 300MW Sakaka photovoltaic ('PV') project which also broke global records for the lowest LCOE for solar PV at 2.34 US c/kWh during the time of bid. The two projects will contribute to the Kingdom's target of 27.3 GW of renewable energy capacity by 2024 and 58.7 GW by 2030. Following the successful financial close of the Dumat Al Jandal project, REPDO recently launched the tendering process for six new projects with a combined energy capacity of 1.47 GW. A further six projects are on track to be tendered by the end of 2019, bringing in an additional 1.58 GW of renewable energy capacity. All projects tendered by REPDO are 100 per cent IPPs that will be backed by 20 to 25-year power purchase agreements. REPDO also announced details of the bidding process and the timeline for 12 renewable energy projects. In June 2019, REPDO qualified 60 companies, including 28 from Saudi Arabia. Qualified companies will now proceed to the RFP stage as either managing member, technical member, or under a newly-created category of 'local managing member'. This new category will encourage greater local and international partnerships during the forming of bidding consortiums. The projects, which are part of the Kingdom's Round Two of the National Renewable Energy Program ('NREP'), are divided into small 'Category A' projects with the capacity to produce 100 megawatts ('MW') or less, and larger 'Category B' projects with a capacity above 100 MW. The smaller-scale projects are designed to create greater opportunities for local companies to participate in NREP. In January 2019, REPDO invited expressions of interest for the first six solar PV projects to be tendered in Round Two of the NREP, with generation capacity ranging from 20 to 600 MW. This is compared to a total of 42 companies which qualified for Round One NREP projects in 2017. The Ministry expects these projects to attract approximately 5.2 billion Saudi riyals (US$1.4 billion) of private sector investment. All Round Two projects will require a minimum percentage of local content that will be calculated according to the mechanism defined by the Local Content & Government Procurement Authority ('LCGPA'), which aims to increase the value added contribution of products and services to the national economy. As part of Vision 2030, NREP paves the way for the Kingdom to build a reliable and efficient domestic renewable energy sector over the next decade, and these will include power generation projects as well as local manufacturing of related components. Projects within Round Two will carry a minimum requirement of 17 per cent local content as calculated by the mechanisms defined by the LCGPA, which aims to increase the value-added contribution of products and services in the national economy. It is not just big projects that are in play (and we have not touched on mega-projects such as Neom in this article). The King Abdullah Petroleum Studies and Research Centre ('KAPSARC') recently published a study [11] in relation to rooftop solar installations in Mosques. A 124 kilowatt PV system was installed and commissioned on the rooftop of a mosque in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. With net metering, PV reduces the mosque's energy bill by 50 per cent. With appropriate planning, net metering could bring the bill down to zero. Using satellite data the KAPSARC analysis considered rooftops in residential, mosque, shopping mall, and health care buildings within the Riyadh area. The upper limit of rooftop solar PV capacity that can be deployed in the city of Riyadh was found to be 4.34 gigawatts (GW). This capacity represents nearly 22 per cent of the peak load and can satisfy approximately nine per cent of the energy requirement in the greater Riyadh region. The prospects for rooftop solar in the Kingdom are significant. The Public Investment Fund has also recently established the National Energy Services Company ('Tarshid'), a collaborative effort between the Ministry of Energy, Industry and Mineral Resources, the Ministry of Finance and the Saudi Energy Efficiency Center, to act as a catalyst for the development of a more energy efficient Saudi Arabia. Its particular focus will be buildings and street-lighting retrofits and renewable energy. These kinds of benchmarks will also have to wash through to the country's emerging PPP programme. Seeding this kind of local ecosystem will create thousands of sustainable jobs \- again a key target of the country's transformation agenda. Since 2016 huge strides have been in realising the goals of Vision 2030. Fully embedding and mainstreaming environmental initiatives is a crucial part of that platform for renewal. As indicated above in our sketch of the developing regulatory environment the burden will rapidly shift onto proving your business' green credentials \- the era of green-washing is over. For further information, please contact Francis Patalong ( HYPERLINK mailto:f.patalong@tamimi.com f.patalong@tamimi.com HYPERLINK mailto:m.brown@tamimi.com m.brown@tamimi.com ). [1] HYPERLINK https://www.tamimi.com/law-update-articles/saudi-arabias-vision-2030-black-swans-for-saudi-arabias-power-sector/ https://www.tamimi.com/law-update-articles/saudi-arabias-vision-2030-black-swans-for-saudi-arabias-power-sector/ https://financingthefuture.platform350.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/60/2019/09/FF_11Trillion-WEB.pdf https://financingthefuture.platform350.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/60/2019/09/FF_11Trillion-WEB.pdf [3] HYPERLINK https://ane4bf-datap1.s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/wmocms/s3fs-public/ckeditor/files/United_in_Science_ReportFINAL_0.pdf?XqiG0yszsU_sx2vOehOWpCOkm9RdC_gN https://ane4bf-datap1.s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/wmocms/s3fs-public/ckeditor/files/United_in_Science_ReportFINAL_0.pdf?XqiG0yszsU_sx2vOehOWpCOkm9RdC_gN [4] HYPERLINK https://www.fsb-tcfd.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-TCFD-Status-Report-FINAL-053119.pdf https://www.fsb-tcfd.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-TCFD-Status-Report-FINAL-053119.pdf [5] HYPERLINK https://www.spglobal.com/_media/documents/environmental-social-and-governance-evaluation-analytical-approach.pdf https://www.spglobal.com/_media/documents/environmental-social-and-governance-evaluation-analytical-approach.pdf HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2017/dec/11/tsunami-of-data-could-consume-fifth-global-electricity-by-2025 https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2017/dec/11/tsunami-of-data-could-consume-fifth-global-electricity-by-2025 HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/business/2019/oct/08/corporations-told-to-draw-up-climate-rules-or-have-them-imposed https://www.theguardian.com/business/2019/oct/08/corporations-told-to-draw-up-climate-rules-or-have-them-imposed HYPERLINK https://www.reuters.com/article/us-eu-finance-climate/green-bonds-set-for-shake-up-as-eu-agrees-rules-for-sustainable-financial-products-idUSKBN1Y9251?utm_campaign=Carbon%20Brief%20Daily%20Briefing&utm_medium=email&utm_source=Revue%20newsletter https://www.reuters.com/article/us-eu-finance-climate/green-bonds-set-for-shake-up-as-eu-agrees-rules-for-sustainable-financial-products-idUSKBN1Y9251?utm_campaign=Carbon%20Brief%20Daily%20Briefing&utm_medium=email&utm_source=Revue%20newsletter [9] Article by Jonathan Gornall, 7 December 2019: HYPERLINK https://www.asiatimes.com/2019/12/opinion/saudi-arabias-path-toward-solar-energy/ https://www.asiatimes.com/2019/12/opinion/saudi-arabias-path-toward-solar-energy/ [10] HYPERLINK https://www.arabnews.com/node/1586796/corporate-news https://www.arabnews.com/node/1586796/corporate-news [11] KAPSARC: The Potential of Distributed Solar PV Capacity in Riyadh: A GIS-Assisted Study Abdelrahman Muhsen and Amro M Elshurafa, September 2019 HYPERLINK http://imgs.syndigate.info/415/1352/24/158141964171.jpeg http://imgs.syndigate.info/415/1352/24/158141964171.jpeg HYPERLINK http://imgs.syndigate.info/415/1352/32/158141964378.jpeg http://imgs.syndigate.info/415/1352/32/158141964378.jpeg \</doc>
