<doc ID="COP23_UAE1" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="November 1, 2017 Wednesday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
WWF / UN ABU DHABI, 1st November, 2017 (WAM) -- The World Wide Fund for Nature, WWF, has announced that it will participate in meetings in Bonn to highlight key issues that go to the heart of the implementation of the Paris Agreement; keeping global warming below 1.5 degrees C. Close to a year after the landmark treaty's coming into force, member states must make substantive progress on the actual content of the agreement's implementation guidelines in order for it to be fully operational by 2020. They must also launch a process to encourage national governments to increase the ambition of their national targets, NDCs, by 2020. Following the COP decision in Paris to bring non-State actors, like business, cities, investors and subnational governments, into the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change, there will be a strong focus on their role and achievements, and discussions on how to more effectively integrate them into international and national efforts. Manuel Pulgar-Vidal, Leader of WWF's Global Climate and Energy Programme, said, "Recent extreme weather events that we have witnessed globally are a stark reminder of what is at stake. In Bonn, we must spark the momentum necessary to accelerate the climate action happening now, and scale up efforts, in line with keeping warming to 1.5 degrees C." " COP23 Dr. Deepti Mahajan Mittal, Programme Leader, Climate and Energy at Emirates Wildlife Society in association with World Wide Fund For Nature, EWS-WWF, said, " COP 23 is shining a spotlight on closing the global emissions gap which is critical if we are to limit warming to below 1.5 degrees. The current Nationally Determined Contributions will not be adequate to meet the Paris Agreement goals and we hope to see the dialogue at COP inspire more ambition globally." She added, "Here in the UAE, we have a strong foundation for more climate ambition thanks to the adoption earlier in the year by the UAE Cabinet of the National Climate Change Plan 2050 and launch of the UAE Energy Plan 2050." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_UAE2" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="November 14, 2017 Tuesday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
UAE / COP23 DUBAI, 14th November, 2017 (WAM) -- A high-level delegation comprising representatives of the country's public and private sector is attending the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). Delegates from the UAE government, business and academia have joined their counterparts from around the globe at the event that runs from November 6th to 17th, 2017 in Bonn, Germany, to discuss the next steps in the implementation of the Paris Agreement and review the progress of the signatory countries in achieving their climate change goals. Dr Thani bin Ahmed Al Zeyoudi, Minister of Climate Change and Environment, is heading the UAE delegation to COP23 .. Presided by Fiji with the support of the German government, COP23 takes place against a backdrop of extreme weather events that have destroyed the lives of millions of people across Asia, the Americas and the Caribbean. Dr Al Zeyoudi said: "This year witnessed devastating hurricanes, fires, floods, droughts, ice melting and impact on agriculture that could hugely threaten food security. This conference therefore serves as an ideal platform for strengthening cooperation frameworks that will allow countries to tackle the global challenges of climate change." He added: "Considering the current alarming situations, we need to act more swiftly to maintain the momentum created by the historic Paris Agreement if we are to translate its objectives into practical measures. Today, let us together send a positive message from Bonn to the entire world through reaffirming our determination to move forward in shaping the future we aspire to achieve." Speaking on the UAE's ambitious climate action plans, Dr Al Zeyoudi said: "The UAE has made significant progress in combating the climate change impacts through our revolutionary national programs, such as the launch of the National Climate Change Plan 2050 and the National Climate Adaptation Program, which aim to strengthen our national capacities to withstand the climate challenges and transform them into opportunities that ensure long-term economic growth." Dr Al Zeyoudi participated in a high-level panel discussion, held as part of the five-day agenda of events hosted by the Marrakech Partnership for Global Climate Action to demonstrate how cities, regions, businesses and investors work side by side with governments to implement the Paris Agreement. Highlighting the UAE's contributions to achieving the goals of the Paris Agreement and UNFCCC, he noted that the National Climate Change Plan 2050 involves engaging companies and other non-government entities in climate and environment policy-making as well as introducing new solutions and technological innovations that help combat climate change. He emphasized that the country's businesses are leading the change in many climate-related areas. He said that the UAE tackles climate change through effective policies and initiatives that aim to diversify the economy into new, knowledge-based industries. He added that the country continues to dominate the clean energy sector with an ambitious clean energy target of 27 percent by 2021 and 50 percent by 2050. He also stressed that the UAE supports international climate action through renewable energy aid and investments in multiple commercial renewable energy projects across the globe. In closing, he emphasized that the country seeks to reinforce its status as a regional leader and global convener on climate action. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_UAE3" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="January 7, 2018"source="Identity" >
Coinciding with the launch of her new edited book, HABITAT, Dr. Sandra Piesik took some time to answer a few of our questions. Who is your favourite historic architect? And contemporary? Italian architect Giovanni Michelucci, for his capacity to explore beauty in materiality and structure. Contemporary architect: nature, because of its inexhaustible, selfless, un-superficial creativity. I do not think that we should imitate nature, but I think nature and ecosystems are great inspiration; at least [they are] for me. What led you to create your firm 3 ideas Ltd? At the time, there was no information readily available about it. As a European, I wanted to find out: what did the Arab people build before we arrived? Setting up 3 ideas Ltd was the only way to do this, as big architectural practices were not interested in this topic. How should architects address consumption and production? Designers and architects are responsible, but not only them \- we are all responsible for addressing these questions; clients, consumers and developers alike. SDG No 12 [Sustainable Development Goal 12 of the "We are all in the same canoe," said Fiji's Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama, whose country recently held the presidency of COP23 [the 2017 United Nations Climate Change Conference ]. What are common misunderstandings about climate change? It might be that 'it is not related to me' or 'it will not affect me'. I think that the biggest misunderstanding of climate change is in focusing solely on measuring and calculating climate change, or representing it as a diagram on the computer screen. Leaving pragmatic solutions to climate change [and focusing] solely [on] graphic representations, statistics and numbers is the biggest and most damaging thing we could do as a profession. How does vernacular architecture speak to dangerous forms of nationalism? I feel that since the 1970s and the advent of modernisation we lost a concept of national identity. We are living in a confused world. 'Westernisation' brought buildings and cities without identity \- stripped of any characteristics of culture or local environment \- and it is precisely why we need to re-discover ornamentation and cultural characteristics in a new way; to bring back national and cultural identity. What behaviours can consumers adopt to help reduce climate change? I feel that choices need to be made by people themselves, on an individual basis. Buying local produce, supporting local economies and co-ops, and [practising] all forms of 'of 'reduce', 'reuse' and 'recycle' would help. Do we need think about the cycle of production and consumption? I think that central Europe right now offers a brilliant example of circular economy in action, and we have entire countries and cities embracing the circular economy model. It is worth mentioning that the date palm industry circular economy model was present in the MENA region for 8000 years until the 1970s, so there is still scope for re-engaging with models of production and consumption that are indigenous to the Middle East. What locations in world inspire you the most? This interview was edited for length and clarity. ID \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_UAE4" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="December 21, 2017 Thursday"source="Khaleej Times (United Arab Emirates)" >
Obviously, mitigating climate change will require tackling emissions from the meat and dairy industries. The question is how Last year, three of the world's largest meat companies - JBS, Cargill, and Tyson Foods - emitted more greenhouse gases than France, and nearly as much as some big oil companies. And yet, while energy giants like Exxon and Shell have drawn fire for their role in fuelling climate change, the corporate meat and dairy industries have largely avoided scrutiny. If we are to avert environmental disaster, this double standard must change. To bring attention to this issue, the Institute for Agriculture and Trade Policy, GRAIN, and Germany's Heinrich Bll Foundation recently teamed up to study the "supersised climate footprint" of the global livestock trade. What we found was shocking. In 2016, the world's 20 largest meat and dairy companies emitted more greenhouse gases than Germany. If these companies were a country, they would be the world's seventh-largest emitter. Obviously, mitigating climate change will require tackling emissions from the meat and dairy industries. The question is how. Around the world, meat and dairy companies have become politically powerful entities. The recent corruption-related arrests of two JBS executives, the brothers Joesley and Wesley Batista, pulled back the curtain on corruption in the industry. JBS is the largest meat processor in the world, earning nearly $20 billion more in 2016 than its closest rival, Tyson Foods. But JBS achieved its position with assistance from the Brazilian Development Bank, and apparently, by bribing more than 1,800 politicians. It is no wonder, then, that greenhouse-gas emissions are low on the company's list of priorities. In 2016, JBS, Tyson and Cargill emitted 484 million tonnes of climate-changing gases, 46 million tonnes more than BP, the British energy giant. Meat and dairy industry insiders push hard for pro-production policies, often at the expense of environmental and public health. From seeking to block reductions in nitrous oxide and methane emissions, to circumventing obligations to reduce air, water, and soil pollution, they have managed to increase profits while dumping pollution costs on the public. One consequence, among many, is that livestock production now accounts for nearly 15 per cent of global greenhouse-gas emissions. That is a bigger share than the world's entire transportation sector. Moreover, much of the growth in meat and dairy production in the coming decades is expected to come from the industrial model. If this growth conforms to the pace projected by the UN Food and Agriculture Organization, our ability to keep temperatures from rising to apocalyptic levels will be severely undermined. At the United Nations Climate Change Conference ( COP23 To skirt climate responsibility, the meat and dairy industries have long argued that expanding production is necessary for food security. Corporate firms, they insist, can produce meat or milk more efficiently than a pastoralist in the Horn of Africa or a small-scale producer in India. Unfortunately, current climate policies do not refute this narrative, and some even encourage increased production and intensification. Rather than setting targets for the reduction of total industry-related emissions, many current policies create incentives for firms to squeeze more milk from each dairy cow and bring beef cattle to slaughter faster. This necessitates equating animals to machinery that can be tweaked to produce more with less through technological fixes, and ignoring all of this model other negative effects. California's experience is instructive. Pursuing one of the world's first efforts to regulate agricultural methane, the state government has set ambitious targets to reduce emissions in cattle processing. But California is currently addressing the issue by financing programmes that support mega-dairies, rather than small, sustainable operators. Such "solutions" have only worsened the industry's already poor record on worker and animal welfare, and exacerbated adverse environmental and health-related effects. Solutions do exist. For starters, governments could redirect public money from factory farming and large-scale agribusiness to smaller, ecologically focused family farms. Governments could also use procurement policies to help build markets for local products and encourage cleaner, more vibrant farm economies. Many cities around the world are already basing their energy choices on a desire to tackle climate change. Similar criteria could shape municipalities' food policies, too. For example, higher investment in farm-to-hospital and farm-to-school programmes would ensure healthier diets for residents, strengthen local economies, and reduce the climate impact of the meat and dairy industries. Dairy and meat giants have operated with climate impunity for far too long. If we are to halt global temperature spikes and avert an ecological crisis, consumers and governments must do more to create, support, and strengthen environmentally conscious producers. That would be good for our health - and for the health of our planet. -Project Syndicate. Shefali Sharma is Director of Agricultural Commodities and Globalization at the Institute for Agriculture and Trade Policy. Copyright \£9 2017 Khaleej Times. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_UAE5" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="May 18, 2017 Thursday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
EU / ACP / climate deal BRUSELS, 18th May, 2017 (WAM) -- The European Union and 79 African, Caribbean and Pacific (ACP) developing countries, who together make up more than half of the signatories to the Paris Agreement on climate change, today reaffirmed their strong and steadfast commitment to full implementation of the agreement, urging all partners to keep up the momentum created in 2015, according to EUROPA, the official EU website. The EU and the African, Caribbean and Pacific Group of States made the call at a UN climate change conference taking place in Bonn, ahead of the upcoming G7 and G20 leaders' summits and the next annual UN climate negotiations COP23 in November. Commissioner for Climate Action and Energy Miguel Arias Ca?ete said: "Today more than ever, Europe stands by its long-term partners most vulnerable to climate change. We, developed and developing countries together, will defend the Paris Agreement. We are all in, and our joint commitment to this Agreement today is as in Paris: irreversible and non-negotiable." The ACP Group and EU have agreed common positions on the next steps to implement the Paris Agreement and strengthened cooperation to promote low-emission, climate-resilient development. As an example of this increased cooperation, the EU has announced support of EUR 800 million for the Pacific Region up to 2020, with around half earmarked for climate action. The EU will also provide EUR 3 million to support Fiji's COP23 Presidency. The UN climate conference is currently taking place from 8-18 May to prepare the ground for the next Conference of the Parties COP23 , to be held on 6-17 November 2017 in Bonn. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_UAE6" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="September 20, 2017 Wednesday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
Minister of Climate Change & Environment / Sustainable Ocean Economy / 72nd UNGA / New York / Sustainability NEW YORK, 20th September, 2017 (WAM) -- The UAE, in partnership with the European Union and Fiji, hosted a high-level roundtable during the 72nd United Nations General Assembly on enhancing and mobilising investments to promote a sustainable ocean economy that supports climate change mitigation and adaptation efforts. Building on the UN Ocean Conference, held in June 2017, the roundtable discussed ways to enhance preparations for the Our Ocean Conference to be held in Malta in October 2017 and COP23 in Bonn, Germany, in November 2017. The roundtable took place in the presence of Frans Timmermans, First Vice-President of the European Commission, Dr. Thani bin Ahmed Al-Zeyoudi, Minister of Climate Change and Environment, and Inia Seruiratu, Minister for Agriculture, Rural and Maritime Development and National Disaster Management and COP23 High-Level Champion, Fiji. It brought together government and business leaders, financial institutions, international organisations and academics to build a shared view on near-term investment and policy priorities, and, most importantly, to strengthen partnerships to benefit the sustainable ocean economy. In his welcoming remarks, Dr. Thani Al-Zeyoudi underlined the ever-increasing importance of oceans and marine resources, in particular with the adoption of the Sustainable Development Goal 14 on the conservation and sustainable use of the oceans, seas and marine resources. "The marine environment has been a significant component of the UAE's environmental resources and continues to play an integral role in our everyday lives. The discovery of oil strengthened the position of our marine environment as a mainstay of our economic resources. Our marine wealth is equally precious for its rich biodiversity and for enabling the country's significant achievements in the transportation, desalination, tourism and entertainment industries," Dr. Al-Zeyoudi said. The Minister added, "The UAE is home to a wide range of marine species including green turtle, fin whale and dugong. The country is also rich in 'Blue Carbon' coastal and marine ecosystems, such as mangroves, tidal marshes and seagrass, which protect our shorelines, provide nursery grounds and habitats for marine species and support coastal tourism. We also recognise their contribution in mitigating climate change through carbon sequestration and storage." Dr. Al Zeyoudi emphasised that the UAE is taking proactive measures to ensure the sustainability of these valuable natural assets and to meet its national objective for economic diversification. He noted that the UAE's efforts in the field of marine environment conservation are three-fold and include: protection from pollution due to oil and other harmful materials, protection of marine environment ecosystems, and strengthening the country's resilience to the impacts of climate change. He also highlighted a set of relevant policies and national plans in the UAE's marine environment protection portfolio, such as the 'National Plan for the Sustainability of Marine and Coastal Environment', the 'National Strategy for Biodiversity 2015-2021', the 'UAE Green Development Strategy', as well as the 'UAE Energy Strategy 2050' and the 'National Climate Change Plan'. In his concluding remarks, Dr. Thani Al-Zeyoudi reiterated the UAE's commitment to facilitating dialogue and cooperation with the global community on the sustainable management of the marine environment and resources that offer immense social and economic value. Inia Seruiratu highlighted the necessity to engage with different stakeholders to achieve a sustainable economy. He said that "while supporting policy and incentive frameworks are important, the involvement of the private sector, local communities, civil societies and other institutions is crucial to ensure successful implementation." The Fiji high-level champion urged and challenged partners in the room to come up with innovative and transformative approaches, technologies, and financing, to accelerate climate action and build a more resilient ocean sector. He also informed the high-level participants of a planned Oceans Pathway that the Fiji COP23 Presidency would be introduced during COP23 in November. The Oceans Pathway serves to ensure that the nexus between oceans and climate change is integrated into the UNFCC process by 2020. In his remarks, Frans Timmermans underscored the importance of raising awareness of the challenges that oceans face. He emphasised that the responsibility for preserving the world's oceans does not fall on one government or sector, but is rather the collective responsibility that all sectors, governments and communities share. He also reiterated the urgent need for all concerned parties and stakeholders to work together in shaping a global strategy to curb plastic waste entering the oceans. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_UAE7" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="May 8, 2017 Monday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
WWF / Paris Agreement ABU DHABI, 8th May, 2017 (WAM) -- UN climate negotiations resume tomorrow in Bonn, and while negotiators will be getting into the details of implementing the Paris Agreement, outside attention is likely to be on the first major challenge to the global climate deal as the United States considers its future in the agreement. Manuel Pulgar-Vidal, leader of WWF's global Climate and Energy Practice, said, "The Paris Agreement is the world's collective response to tackling climate change. While politics and policies may change, science is giving us a clear and consistent message about climate change. We must stay focused on implementing the agreement to ensure greenhouse gas emissions are urgently reduced to keep the global temperature increase to 1.5 C, and ensure that vulnerable communities are protected from the climate impacts we are already experiencing. "Acting now means that countries can tap the benefits resulting from greater climate action. This includes enhanced health, employment growth and new investment opportunities." Strengthening the collaboration between governments and other actors is critical to accelerate climate action. "Collaboration among national governments, cities, business, regional governments and the public lies at the heart of unlocking these opportunities as rapidly as possible," he said. Continued support for strengthening the Marrakech Partnership can contribute to unlocking new opportunities for action. Countries will have an opportunity around the Facilitative Dialogue in 2018 (2018 FD), to take stock of collective efforts towards the Paris Agreements' long-term objectives. A meaningful outcome of the 2018 FD will be a collective signal from countries that they intend to revise their NDCs with more ambitious targets. "We think a strong decision at COP23 , setting out how the 2018 FD will be organised, is essential," explained Pulgar-Vidal. Finally, progress in the negotiations in Bonn should allow for a comprehensive draft text on the rules for implementing the Paris Agreement at COP23 , to be held in Bonn in November. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_UAE8" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="December 11, 2017 Monday"source="Khaleej Times (United Arab Emirates)" >
The Paris climate agreement was facilitated by a number of political and social forces. Laurence Tubiana In 2015, the so-called "high ambition coalition" of developed and developing countries pushed the Paris climate agreement past the finish line. But when global leaders reconvene in Paris for new talks on climate change at the One Planet Summit today, financial commitments must be the order of the day. Nearly two years have passed since France's then-foreign minister, Laurent Fabius, struck his gavel and declared: "The Paris agreement for the climate is accepted." Next week, President Emmanuel Macron and the French government will host world leaders and non-state actors for the One Planet Summit. The purpose of this gathering is to celebrate climate gains made since 2015, and to boost political and economic support for meeting the targets of the Paris agreement. The Paris climate agreement was facilitated by a number of political and social forces. One of the most influential of these was a group of more than 100 countries known as the "high ambition coalition," which helped finalise the deal in the waning days of the 2015 United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP21). This diverse coalition of leaders - from the richest countries to the most vulnerable Pacific island states - broke a political deadlock. As we reflect on that success, one thing is abundantly clear: the need for ambitious coalitions has returned. Strong global leadership on climate change scored a diplomatic victory two years ago, and today, new economic and political alliances are needed to turn those commitments into action. The diplomatic success of the Paris accord is worthy of praise in its own right; it was a remarkable leap forward in the fight against climate change. But we must not rest on our laurels. With the United States, the world's largest historical emitter of greenhouse gases, dismissive of the accord, the rest of the global community must reaffirm its commitment to reducing carbon dioxide emissions. The best available science estimates that the world has only three years to begin a permanent reduction in greenhouse-gas emissions if there is to be any hope of achieving the Paris accord's goal of keeping warming to "well below 2C" relative to pre-industrial levels. And, whatever urgency science cannot convey is being communicated by the planet itself - through a ferocious display of hurricanes, floods, wildfires, and deadly droughts. Given the immediacy of the challenge, what can and should be done to avert crisis? Solutions start with money, and a main objective of the One Planet Summit is to mobilise public and private financing to fund projects that can reduce climate-changing pollution today. During the summit's "Climate Finance Day," companies, banks, investors, and countries will announce new initiatives. Hollow promises will have no place at this gathering; only real commitments of real money for tangible projects will be discussed. We hope to see hundreds of millions of dollars committed by governments to fund solutions across all fronts of the climate-change battle. Plenty will go to renewable-energy projects, but money will also be committed to clean transportation, agriculture, infrastructure, and urban systems. The One Planet Summit will be an occasion for countries, companies, and private institutions to forge concrete strategies to shift away from fossil fuels. The gathering in Paris will provide an opportunity for other countries to join the Powering Past Coal Alliance, which aims to formalise a deliberate transition from coal, and to help companies achieve net-zero emissions. Ultimately, next week's summit should be a place where governments, businesses, investors, and other key stakeholders collaborate and share ideas, showcase successful projects, and coordinate goals. This event should not stand alone, but rather serve as a springboard for international meetings that will take place over the next few years. Two years after the adoption of a groundbreaking climate agreement, global leaders are set to reconvene in the City of Light. This time, the goal must be to ensure that past agreements amount to more than just words on a page. Laurence Tubiana, a former French ambassador to the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change, is CEO of the European Climate Foundation and a professor at Sciences Po, Paris -Project Syndicate \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_UAE9" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="December 6, 2017 Wednesday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
MOCCAE / GGGI / Climate Change / sustainability DUBAI, 6th December, 2017 (WAM) -- The Ministry of Climate Change and Environment, MOCCAE, in cooperation with the Global Green Growth Institute, GGGI, and the Embassy of the Republic of Korea, held a youth workshop at the Youth Hub in Dubai to discuss topics of climate change adaptation and how young people can get involved. Set against the backdrop of the Youth Climate Mentorship Programme launched during COP23 in Bonn, Germany, the workshop brought together 40 students and young professionals with climate change experts from the UAE and the Republic of Korea, who shared insights on local and international practices on adaptation and interacted with audience members. "The UAE fully supports its youth and seeks their involvement in the national response to the challenges of climate change," said Fahed Mohamed Al Hammadi, MOCCAE's Acting Assistant Under-Secretary, Green Development and Climate Change Sector. "Engaging with young people is a priority for our leadership and we are happy to cooperate with our friends in the international community in this regard. We are building a climate-resilient society to ensure a sustainable economic and environmental future for our nation, and young people must be a part of this process." The seminar comes as part of the Green Growth Youth Programme, which kicked off in 2015 with an introductory workshop and continued in 2016 with several student internships at GGGI's office in Masdar City, Abu Dhabi. "The transition to a green economy cannot happen without engaging young people in green growth and climate change policy," said Dr. Frank Rijsberman, Director-General of GGGI. "GGGI, through its UAE programme, will continue to invest in the coming years in youth training and internships to support this transition," he added. The Korean Embassy also highlighted this event as an example of the robust cooperation between Korea and the UAE in addressing climate change issues. Joint youth workshops are great opportunities that empower the youth to express their opinions regarding current issues and enable them to find solutions for global challenges. These events also allow them to meet with decision makers to discuss the best ways to contribute their creative ideas to advance various sectors towards a better future. In the face of global climate change and resource scarcity, the UAE government has begun the transition to an environmentally, economically and socially sustainable development model by adopting a national green growth plan that emphasizes opportunities for a prosperous, inclusive and climate-resilient future. The National Climate Change Plan was approved by the UAE Cabinet in June 2017, which charts the path of climate change mitigation and adaptation into the future. Youth are an important element in the nation's plans, and encouraging their participation is a priority for the government. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_UAE10" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="November 18, 2017 Saturday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
UAE / Climate Change BONN, 18th November, 2017 (WAM) -- Dr. Thani bin Ahmed Al-Zeyoudi, Minister of Climate Change and Environment, has stated that the United Arab Emirates has made significant progress in combating the climate change impact. He cited in this regard the country's revolutionary national programmes, such as the launch of the National Climate Change Plan 2050 and the National Climate Adaptation Programme, NCAP, which aim to strengthen the state's national capacities to withstand climate challenges and transform them into opportunities that ensure long-term economic growth for current and future generations. This came during UAE's keynote speech at the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC), held from November 6th to 17th, 2017 in Bonn, Germany, to discuss the next steps in the implementation of the Paris Agreement and review the progress of the signatory countries in achieving their climate change goals. Al-Zeyoudi added that in view of the substantial changes to be implemented in the next phase as part of the UAE Centennial Plan 2071, the UAE Energy Strategy 2050 has been announced to boost the country's ambitions to raise the share of clean energy in the national energy mix to 27% by 2021 and 50% by 2050, in addition to laying the foundation stone of the 'Noor Abu Dhabi Plant' featuring cutting-edge photovoltaic technology with a potential to generate 1,177 MW of solar energy. Al-Zeyoudi added that the fourth stage of the Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum Solar Park was launched with a production capacity of 700 MW as part of a plan to produce 5,000 MW of energy by 2030. He indicated that the UAE has also laid the foundation for the first waste-to-energy project and implemented the first carbon capture and storage (CCS) facility in the Middle East and North Africa region. In recognising UAE's most stellar environmental achievements, he highlighted the important role played by Abu Dhabi Future Energy Company, Masdar, which has been leading the country's efforts in the development of renewable energy technologies and solutions since its inception in 2006, and has invested about US$8.5 billion in local and global projects, contributing to the increase of renewable energy capacity by about 2.7 million GW. The minister stressed that this global event is taking place at a time when the global climate has been worsening, and extreme weather events have been occurring at a faster and more severe pace than ever before Al-Zeyoudi reaffirmed UAE's commitment to the objectives of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, the Paris Agreement and all relevant international resolutions, as well as the country's determination to continue its voluntary participation in international efforts to mitigate and adapt to climate change. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_UAE11" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="June 11, 2017 Sunday 6:30 AM EST"source="UAE Government News" >
June 11 -- The organising committee of the fourth World Green Economy Summit 'WGES 2017', which will be held under the patronage of HH Sheikh Mohammed Bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai, organised by Dubai Electricity and Water Authority (DEWA), and the World Green Economy Organisation (WGEO) in collaboration with global partners, has announced that 'WGES 2017' will be held on 24-25 October at Dubai International Convention and Exhibition Centre. The fourth edition of WGES will be held under the theme 'Driving innovation, Leading change'. The summit will adopt innovation as its main theme, since it plays a pivotal role to boost sustainable development solutions which thereby lead the change to a green economy. WGES 2017 is expected to attract more than 3000 participants making it the largest in the MENA region. The summit will be held in conjunction with the 19th edition of Water, Energy, Technology and Energy Exhibition 'WETEX 2017' and the 2nd edition of 'Dubai Solar Show 2017', as part of the Green Week activities in Dubai. "In line with UAE Green Development Strategy launched by HH Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, Vice President and Prime Minister of the UAE and Ruler of Dubai to build green economy in the UAE under the theme "Green Economy For Sustainable Development", and inspired by a quote of His Highness, who said 'Innovation is not an intellectual luxury or propaganda but the secret behind the government's existence', DEWA organises the World Green Economy Summit (WGES 2017), in collaboration with the World Green Economy Organisation (WGEO), which was launched by HH Sheikh Mohammed Bin Rashid Al Maktoum in October 2016 and supported by the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP). WGEO's main role is to reduce the investment risks in the green economy sector, as well as support the global collaboration. WGEO operates through seven platforms - countries, smart & sustainable cities sector, private sector, academia, organisations and civil society, youth sector and financial sector," said HE Saeed Mohammed Al Tayer, Vice Chairman of the Dubai Supreme Council of Energy in Dubai, Managing Director and CEO of DEWA, and Chairman of WGES. "The World Green Economy Organisation has a pivotal role in tackling climate change and finding innovative solutions for sustainable energy, water and environmental challenges. This role integrates with WGES efforts as well as Dubai's instrumental role to enhance and implement the principles of green economy, as part of our wise leadership vision, and to reconfirm the Emirate's leading position as a global hub for finance, business, tourism and innovation," added HE Saeed Mohammed Al Tayer. "We are responsible to maintain and increase the success of the previous three editions of WGES, to reconfirm once more that Dubai is the world's capital of green economy," concluded Al Tayer. Over two days, the Summit will discuss varied new technologies and solutions that will not only provide renewable and alternative resources of energy, but also offer several ways to tap productive and eco-friendly technologies. The Summit will witness participation of top-notch experts in various sectors such as administrations, partnerships, financing, innovation, and global markets. WGES 2017 is a world leading event focusing on green economy globally. The Summit aims to create sustainable future for humanity, and aims to adapt a shift to a greener economy. WGES attracts thousands of participants including decision makers, green economy pioneers, CEOs from public and private sectors, governmental officials and green economy experts. This year, the Summit will focus on supporting partnerships and collaboration between governments and organisations from public and private sectors. The fourth cycle of WGES is timely, particularly as the world is facing the threat of climate change and the increasing need to move to green economy. WGES 2017 shares the same values with United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC), Paris Climate Agreement 2015, COP22 in Marrakech, the upcoming COP23 in Bonn and Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) 2030. Supported by many international organisations such as The International Renewable Energy Agency (IRENA), United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) and United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC), WGES aims to create a sustainable future for the current and future generations. Source: Dubai Electricity and Water Authority Load-Date: \~June 12, 2017 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_UAE12" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="October 29, 2017 Sunday"source="Khaleej Times (United Arab Emirates)" >
He robbed the expat of Dh27,000 cash, mobile phone and bank card. Marie Nammour (alamy.com/ae) A policeman, who wrongfully stopped a motorist and stole his cash and bank card, was sentenced by the Court of First Instance to one year in jail to be followed by deportation. Public prosecution records show the Sudanese cop , 23 , staged the false arrest along with a compatriot friend, 33, to steal the Chinese manager's cash, mobile phone and bank card. The friend, who spoke the victim's language, told him he would be taken into custody and could face a three-month jail term unless he paid the policeman Dh27,000. The friend was found guilty of aiding and abetting the main defendant and was also sentenced to one year in jail and deportation. An Emirati policeman was also charged in the case, but has been acquitted of the charges. The complainant said during interrogation at Bur Dubai police station: "I met the second accused at a nightclub in Jumeirah and was giving him a ride when I was stopped by two police officers on the Sheikh Zayed Road. They asked for my ID and driving licence. After that, I was taken inside the patrol car while the second accomplice drove my car. On the way, they stopped and through their accomplice, I paid the main defendant all the cash I carried, which was Dh3,000." The victim was driven to the International City, where he was waiting for a relative to bring some cash. After the second accused snatched his bank card, the victim managed to escape. The verdict remains subject to appeal. HYPERLINK mailto:mary@khaleejtimes.com mary@khaleejtimes.com Marie Nammour HYPERLINK http://imgs.syndigate.info/28/44/46/150933068329.jpg http://imgs.syndigate.info/28/44/46/150933068329.jpg \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_UAE13" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="November 22, 2017 Wednesday"source="Emirates News Agency (WAM)" >
Climate Change Council / meeting Dr. Al-Zeyoudi said, "The UAE's participation in the 23rd Conference of Parties to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change ( COP 23 ) in Bonn affirmed its commitment to the objectives of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, the Paris Agreement and all relevant international resolutions. It also shows our keenness to continue voluntarily participating in international efforts to mitigate and adapt to climate change." The meeting reviewed the latest developments of relevant technical committees related to the National Climate Change Plan 2050 and the Green Agenda 2030 as well as developments in promoting the transition to green development. The discussion also covered the latest advancements in the field of municipal work, such as the unified guide to municipal work, integrated waste management, occupational safety and health, landscaping and beautification of cities, management of crises, and disasters and emergencies, in order to unify national standards and upgrade municipal work. The topics included the developments of national waste database, dynamic reports, an interactive data platform for each emirate, establishment of a unified federal addressing system, mechanisms to reduce greenhouse gas emissions from vehicles, and lower the carbon footprint. The participants were briefed on the initiatives of the technical committee for education and awareness that aims to educate young people to lead the UAE towards a sustainable future using modern means as well as educate the community about sustainability, green development and environment. The audience was briefed on the national agenda on air quality and treated waste proportion from total waste produced (municipal solid waste) and integrated waste management projects in the UAE. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_UAE14" COP="COP23" country="UAE" date="June 11, 2017"source="Gulf Business" >
The notion of 'progress' can \- and has \- been the subject of intense debate throughout history. Whether framed around the economy, technology, wel- fare, society, or any other topic, different viewpoints, philosophies and agendas have \- and will \- be argued for and against with great ferocity. One of the current era's most ardent- ly fought over issues is the environment. Global warming, intensive farming, mass urbanisation, pollution, climate change resource depletion and numerous other topics have been in the spotlight in recent decades \- with the discussion intensifying in the past few years. Major incidents such as the Exxon Valdez and Deepwater Horizon oil spills, the Chernobyl and Fukushima nuclear power plant accidents, the build-up of the Great Pacific garbage patch, the outcry over GMO farming, the Kuwaiti Oil Fires, chemical warfare, and many more have dominated headlines and debate. And with global commitments by gov- ernments and organisations at events such as the United Nations Climate Change Conference - where the Paris Agreement was negotiated in 2015 to reduce green- house gas emissions - there are few discus- sions that rank so highly in importance, with views so varied. Among the most pertinent issues for the Gulf region is urbanisation \- certainly for the UAE in general and Dubai in partic- ular \- which continues to grow at an accel- erated rate, as it has for the past 30 years. Not only is the erosion of natural habi- tat a major consideration in this regard, but also matters that are associated with population booms \- an increased carbon footprint, large-scale waste production, and countless others. It is against this backdrop that envi- ronment agencies and non-government organisations across the GCC work to strike a balance between environment and development. A difficult tightrope to walk in any part of the world, but perhaps made all the more difficult by the Gulf's rapid post-oil rise. One such NGO negotiating that high- wire is Emirates Wildlife Society, in associa- tion with the World Wildlife Fund. EWS-WWF was created in 2001 to help protect biodiversity in key sites across the UAE, raise awareness of the UAE's eco- logical footprint, and contribute to policy and institutional frameworks that address environmental issues. Among its remits are projects and ini- tiatives concerning marine conservation, including the protection of endangered turtles, 40 species of shark, and the ocean itself with its vital habitats such as coral reefs and sea grass beds. Terrestrial conser- vation focusses on land-based species and ecosystems such as wetlands, mountains and desert scrublands, while the organisa- tion also works to support climate change initiatives in the region \- helping to shrink the UAE's ecological footprint and increase support for renewable energy. A wildlife trade programme in coopera- tion with leading government and private sector stakeholders targets the 'high-profit, low risk' illegal wildlife trade that continues to escalate an alarming rate, and extensive environmental education and outreach ini- tiatives aim to give young people in particu- lar the tools they need to understand and act up key issues. But despite the amount of work that must necessarily take place to establish long-term sustainability, the director gener- al at EWS-WWF, Laila Mostafa Abdullatif, believes that there is no reason the fine balance between environment and develop- ment can't be struck. And rather than rely on good intentions, she and the organisa- tion put their beliefs into practice. "At EWS-WWF, we believe that our economy, society and environment can Interview "Taking an acTive role in environmenTal sTewardship is in facT a golden opporTuniTy for The business communiTy To creaTe innovaTive, smarTer, more cosT-effecTive and susTainable ways To succeed in increasingly compeTiTive markeTs." thrive in unison, and together we can build a prosperous future in harmony with nature," she tells Gulf Business. "We help drive collective action by partnering and connecting policy makers, businesses, government entities, the scien- tific community, academia, other NGOs and the public. In the present and imme- diate future we continue to be particu- larly focused on raising national awareness about how environmental sustainability matters to business." Working heavily to drive action on cli- mate change, biodiversity conversation and wildlife trade, EWS-WWF also strives to educate on the environment and partners with business and government communi- ties to encourage sustainable practices \- counting more than 140 public and private entities across the Gulf as its partners. And while Abdullatif recognises the challenges posed by fast-growing cities such as Dubai, she explains that these dif- ficulties are not exclusive to the UAE and wider Gulf region. "I don't believe the challenges are unique to Dubai. In fact, across the world it's fair to say the value we realise from our natural capital including oceans and coast- lines continues to expand rapidly. "A 2015 WWF report, produced in con- junction with Boston Consulting Group, estimates that the whole range of goods and services that flow from the world's coastal and marine environments can be conserva- tively valued at $2.5 trillion each year, with the overall value of the ocean as an asset at 10 times that. "The ocean and waters of the Gulf play a critical role for the UAE, not only related to fishing and aquaculture, tourism, leisure, and so on, but also across the business spec- trum including production, supply chain and logistics. "If we are to realise the full benefits of our seas and the oceans, both now and in the future, we must take action to ensure the long-term sustainability of this natural capital. Ocean stresses are well document- ed, bio-diversity is declining, temperatures are rising and plastics and other pollutants continue to accumulate in our seas. "My belief is that businesses and con- sumers must recognise quickly that ocean based economies and land activities are interlinked. To achieve a long-term sustain- able economy, the management of natural land and sea assets is vital." This recognition and environmental awareness has been given a brighter spot- light in 2017 thanks to the year being designated the 'Year of Giving' by the UAE's President His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan. Abdullatif says: "The UAE Year of Giving has been a wonderful opportunity to highlight the lesser known avenues avail- able to all of us in 'giving back' to society, the nation and our environment as a whole. With corporations particularly in mind, EWS-WWF already has a number of pro- grammes and initiatives designed to help businesses make an environmental impact. These include the Citizen Science Programme, which allows teams to par- ticipate in a series of water research and learning activities inside the Wadi Wurayah National Park; and the Climate Change Research Learning Programme, which focusses on climate change education. And the list of companies working in partnership with the NGO in different ways is as impressive as it is varied, featur- ing Abu Dhabi Commercial Bank, Dubai Electricity and Water Authority, Waha Capital, Diamond Developers, Linklaters, Geant, Majid Al Futtaim, HSBC and Grant Thornton among others. Geant supermarket, for example, runs a micro donation scheme to reduce plas- tic bags, while Linklaters provides in-kind legal services and Grant Thornton offers in-kind financial audits. "EWS-WWF is fortunate to enjoy the support of so many forward-thinking organisations, including many of our long- term partners whose contributions have enabled our work over the past 16 years," says Abdullatif. "This joint initiative with the Mohammed bin Rashid Global Centre for Endowment Consultancy is following the Global Vision for Endowment, which was launched by His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum to revive the practice of endowment through innovative applications," Abdullatif explains. "The positive participation of the pri- vate sector and social figures has already contributed towards translating the vision of His Highness Sheikh Khalifa, which marks 2017 as the Year of Giving." There appears to be no shortage of goodwill from businesses and organisations to participate in EWS-WWF's work \- be it through financial donations, practical assistance, or any other method. And this is just as well according to Abdullatif, who emphasises that environmental goals can- not be met by NGOs alone. "Achieving long-term environmental sustainability cannot be done in isolation," she says. "As a local conservation entity we can only achieve our goals by collaborating and engaging with the private and public sectors, as well as civil society and grass- roots movements. "To give you an example of this, public- private partnerships have been key to the success of the first phase of the Gulf Green Turtle Conservation project, which brought together eight partners from the UAE and Oman, with funding from businesses and governments alike." But while there is existing support from the private and public sector, there is always room for more cooperation, adds Abullatif. "We are keen to work with more organ- isations in the field of marine conservation, be it through the sponsorship of endan- gered sea turtles as part of the Gulf Green Turtle project, or through a relatively new project investigating the shallow coastal waters of the Northern Gulf Emirates, with a view to understanding recommendations for the establishment of newly demarcated Marine Protected Areas. "There are various ways for corpora- tions and SMEs to join our conservation efforts and we are always delighted to hear from interested parties on any of our exist- ing programmes or with new opportunities for collaborative working." The benefits of these collaborations to groups like EWS-WWF are clear, but there are also several good reasons for businesses to get involved in such projects. As well as superficial image and deeper ethical considerations, energy efficiency, sustainability and employee welfare can be found in greener workplace environments. It's a corporate culture strongly advo- cated by Abullatif, who argues: "Taking an active role in environmental steward- ship is in fact a golden opportunity for the business community to create innovative, smarter, more cost-effective and sustain- able ways to succeed in increasingly com- petitive markets. "The merits of this approach are being demonstrated by many brands such as global leaders Unilever, Ikea, Coca-Cola, IBM, Panasonic Microsoft and HSBC, as well as many UAE brands including Majid Al Futtaim \- a well-recognised con- glomerate working hard to reduce its own [carbon] footprint while supporting civil society. "These and other organisations are already reaping the rewards and showing a positive return on investment from a variety of angles including revenue, stock performance, product-level profitability, brand reputation, accounting for externali- ties, reduced risk exposure, employee and consumer engagement, and more." And while it's the larger corporations that are generating the headlines, entrepre- neurs and small business owners are also part of the environment equation, despite sometimes self-inflicted perceptions that sustainability doesn't affect them. "While there may be a perception among smaller enterprises that sustainabil- ity issues only relate to large corporations, nothing could be further from the truth," argues Abdullatif. "In fact, it is the next generation of young business owners who can embed positive impact as their business evolves. Perhaps owners believe they cannot afford to be sustainable, that measuring environ- mental performance is a costly and unnec- essary burden. However, newly formed companies that integrate sustainability into their core business strategy at the earli- est opportunity are likely to benefit from lower costs, reduced risk, and be nimble in responding to new market opportunities. "Through our Corporate Membership Programme, we offer access to experts whose knowledge and guidance can be use- ful to those who may be just starting their sustainability journey." The desire among companies of all sizes to follow a sustainable path cannot be underestimated. A recent EWS-WWF study showed that 89 per cent of busi- nesses in the UAE wanted more informa- tion on how to reduce their environmental impact, which Abdullatif says suggests a groundswell of awareness. Highlighting one of the reasons companies should follow through with their interest, a 2015 Cone Communications and Ebiquiy Global CSR Study showed that some 88 per cent of global customers were found to be more loyal to companies that support environ- mental and social issues. "To be successful though, sustainability efforts need to be embedded as an organi- sational priority, not only with clear sup- port from leadership, but also reach across to influence a company's supplier base," Abdullatif adds. As engagement by corporations increases and a more concerted push is made for environmental sustainabil- ity, the work of EWS-WWF and other similar organisations becomes much more impactful. Something Abdullatif is quick to acknowledge. "It would be true to say that without the support and contributions from instru- mental forward-thinking institutions, it would not be possible to create a lasting impact. It is thanks to the support of [our partners] that we at EWS-WWF are able work towards a future where businesses and people live in harmony with nature. "We look forward to collaborating with many more private sector champi- ons who recognise that environmental stewardship is the smart choice for today and tomorrow." \</doc>
