<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong1" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 18, 2022 Friday 11:53 AM EST"source="Forkast.News" >
United Nations climate change conference ( COP27 ) in Egypt. See related article: HYPERLINK Ethereum supply would have grown by 350,000 tokens under PoW {\rtlch\af2\afs24\ltrch\fs20\loch\af2\dbch\af2\hich\f2\par Fast facts The platform will mitigate the excess energy that the network produced before the Merge. "The Merge reduced Ethereum's future energy needs by 99.992%. The ECP aims to redress Ethereum's past PoW-based carbon emissions, since the network's launch in 2015," according to ConsenSys' HYPERLINK https://twitter.com/ConsenSys/status/1593242839449620480 announcement . ConsenSys is co-launching the ECP with climate tech firm Allinfra and other companies including Microsoft, Aave, Artblocks, Gitcoin, Filecoin Green, Huobi, the Global Blockchain Business Council, and others. Instead of offsetting emissions through carbon credits, the ECP will fund the development of "climate projects that can significantly mitigate greenhouse gas emissions and achieve decarbonization at scale." HYPERLINK https://forkast.news/ethereum-merge-ugrade-successfully-ether/ The Merge , one of Ethereum's most anticipated upgrades, transitioned the network from a HYPERLINK https://forkast.news/proof-of-work-what-is-it-bitcoin-halving/ proof-of-work to a HYPERLINK https://forkast.news/what-is-proof-of-stake/ proof-of-stake consensus model on Sept. 15.\~ While the Merge significantly slashed the network's electricity consumption, industry participants agree that it will not HYPERLINK overcome Ethereum's "scalability paradox. " Ether rose 1.7% in the last 24 hours, trading at US$1,220 at 7.25 p.m. in Hong Kong, according to HYPERLINK CoinGecko data. See related article: HYPERLINK https://forkast.news/headlines/ethereum-price-undervalued-the-merge-finder/ Ethereum price undervalued since The Merge: report \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong2" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 4, 2022 Friday"source="Hong Kong Free Press" >
Hong Kong has not been aggressive enough in combating the climate crisis in recent years and should not just  lie flat, a local green group said in its latest report, released ahead of a global climate change summit. \~The term, originating in mainland China, suggests doing as little as possible to get by. The Paris Watch Project, which is run by non-government organisation CarbonCare InnoLab, released its annual Hong Kong Climate Action Report which said  little or no progress has been made towards carbon neutrality in Hong Kong. The city was given an overall  C- grade report card, for the second year in a row. CarbonCare InnoLab press conference on November 3, 2022. Photo: CarbonCare InnoLab. The report was published ahead of the United Nations Climate Change Conference , also known as COP27 , which will be held in the Egyptian resort of Sharm El Sheikh from November 6-18. Paris Watch keeps track of Hong Kong\' s efforts to adhere to the international climate change treaty known as the Paris Agreement in terms of cutting carbon emissions and building a sustainable future. The group evaluated the city\' s performance through more than a dozen indicators, such as the pace of cutting greenhouse gas emissions, the transition to renewable energy, the development of low-emission transport, the effectiveness of governance and the use of technology. Lamma Power Station. File photo: Tom Grundy/HKFP. The predicted rebound was not unique to Hong Kong, the group said, as other parts of the world experienced a similar resumption of activities after the pandemic. But the Hong Kong authorities should have set more aggressive targets to achieve carbon neutrality. In 2021, Hong Kong HYPERLINK https://hongkongfp.com/2021/10/06/hong-kong-policy-address-hk240-billion-pledge-to-combat-climate-crisis/ pledged to cut total carbon emissions by 26 to 36 per cent from the 2005 level by 2030 and to become carbon-neutral by 2050. The Paris Watch Project said Hong Kong lagged behind some of its East Asian counterparts. The report compared Hong Kong with five other cities: Singapore, Seoul, Tokyo and Shenzhen and Guangzhou in the mainland. Seoul had pledged to reduce emissions by 40 per cent by 2030, while Tokyo promised 50 per cent. \' D-\' governance The  judging panel of the report card, which was comprised of academics and experts in climate change studies, concluded that Hong Kong did worst in establishing an effective governance, with the grade being  D-, the lowest among 14 other indicators. Chief Executive John Lee. Photo: Almond Li/HKFP. ,  said Ringo Mak, the group\' s adviser and one of the judges of the report card. Mak said Hong Kong was promised a Climate Change and Carbon Neutrality Office and an Advisory Committee under https://hongkongfp.com/2021/10/06/hong-kong-policy-address-hk240-billion-pledge-to-combat-climate-crisis/ the Hong Kong Climate Action Plan 2050 introduced by former chief executive Carrie Lam . But those proposals had not yet come to fruition and no officials had been appointed to head those offices. Urgent actions needed The organisation acknowledged that Hong Kong was taking action but said current actual or planned measures were not ambitious enough in a world where the impact of climate change was becoming more apparent \- such as record high temperatures in Hong Kong and flash floods in other countries.  If Hong Kong is simply complacent with its current climate change response, it may not reach its carbon neutrality target, the group said. Photo: GovHK. The government was urged to align its 2030 and 2035 targets with the recommendations made by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change. By 2030, Hong Kong needs to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by 45 per cent compared to 2005, the group said.  Climate injustice had become more prevalent as the climate crisis worsened, said CarbonCare InnoLab founder Chong Chan-yau. The concept refers to people who contribute the least to climate change but bear the brunt of its consequences. Hong Kong, as a developed metropolis, should do more to address the injustice and alleviate the crisis, Chong said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong3" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 22, 2022 Tuesday 3:00 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
For 30 years, developing nations have fought to establish an international fund to pay for the  loss and damage they suffer as a result of climate change. As the COP27 climate summit in Egypt wrapped up over the weekend, they finally succeeded. While it\' s a historic moment, the agreement of loss and damage financing left many details yet to be sorted out. What\' s more, many HYPERLINK critics have lamented the overall outcome of COP27 , saying it falls well short of a sufficient response to the climate crisis. As Alok Sharma, president of COP26 in Glasgow, noted:  Friends, I said in Glasgow that the pulse of 1.5 degrees was weak. Unfortunately it remains on life support. But annual conferences aren\' t the only way to pursue meaningful action on climate change. Mobilization from activists, market forces and other sources of momentum mean hope isn\' t lost. Loss and damage fund HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2022/nov/19/five-crucial-issues-in-fight-to-save-planet-and-what-cop27-did-about-them There were hopes COP27 would lead to new commitments on emissions reduction, renewed commitments for the transfer of resources to the developing world, strong signals for a transition away from fossil fuels, and the establishment of a loss and damage fund. Also read: The \' loss and damage\' climate agenda will sink us all By any estimation, the big breakthrough of COP27 was the agreement to HYPERLINK establish a fund for loss and damage. This would involve wealthy nations compensating developing states for the effects of climate change, especially droughts, floods, cyclones and other disasters. Most analysts have been quick to point out there\' s still a lot yet to clarify in terms of donors, recipients or rules of accessing this fund. It\' s not clear where funds will actually come from, or whether countries such as HYPERLINK https://www.smh.com.au/environment/climate-change/developed-or-developing-china-question-divides-cop27-as-bowen-meets-counterpart-20221118-p5bzav.html China will contribute, for example. These and other details are yet to be agreed. We should also acknowledge the potential gaps between promises and money on the table, given HYPERLINK https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-021-02846-3 the failure of developed states to deliver on US$100 billion per year of climate finance for developing states by 2020. This was committed to in Copenghagen in 2009. But it was a HYPERLINK https://news.mongabay.com/2022/11/cop27-climate-loss-damage-talks-now-on-agenda-but-u-s-resistance-feared/ significant fight to get the issue of loss and damage HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/its-the-big-issue-of-cop27-climate-summit-poor-nations-face-a-1trillion-loss-and-damage-bill-but-rich-nations-wont-pay-up-194043 on the agenda in Egypt at all. So the agreement to establish this fund is clearly a monumental outcome for developing countries most vulnerable to the effects of climate change \- and least responsible for it. It was also a win for the Egyptian hosts, who were HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/almost-200-nations-are-set-to-tackle-climate-change-at-cop27-in-egypt-is-this-just-a-talkfest-or-does-the-meeting-actually-matter-191586 keen to flag their sensitivity to issues confronting the developing world. The fund comes 30 years after the measure was HYPERLINK https://edition.cnn.com/2022/11/03/opinions/cop27-climate-loss-and-damage-vanuatu-sutter/index.html first suggested by Vanuatu back in 1991. Not-so-good news The loss and damage fund will almost certainly be remembered as the marquee outcome of COP27 , but other developments were less promising. Among these were various fights to retain commitments made in Paris in 2015 and Glasgow last year. In Paris, nations agreed to limit global warming to well below 2 degrees Celsius, and preferably to 1.5 degrees this century, compared with pre-industrial levels. So far, the planet has warmed HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/this-is-the-most-sobering-report-card-yet-on-climate-change-and-earths-future-heres-what-you-need-to-know-165395 by 1.09 degrees , and emissions are HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/global-carbon-emissions-at-record-levels-with-no-signs-of-shrinking-new-data-shows-humanity-has-a-monumental-task-ahead-193108 at record levels . Temperature trajectories make it increasingly challenging for the world to limit temperature rises to 1.5 degrees Celsius. And the fact that keeping this commitment in Egypt was a hard-won fight casts some doubt on the global commitment to mitigation. China in particular HYPERLINK https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/16/climate/cop27-global-warming-1-5-celsius.html had questioned whether the 1.5-degree target was worth retaining, and this became a key contest in the talks. New Zealand Climate Change Minister James Shaw HYPERLINK https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/quote-box-reaction-to-un-climate-meet-deal-on-disaster-fund/2022/11/19/5ec52c1e-6880-11ed-b08c-3ce222607059_story.html said a group of countries were undermining decisions made in previous conferences. He added that this  really came to the fore at this COP, and I\' m afraid there was just a massive battle which ultimately neither side won. Perhaps even HYPERLINK https://www.ft.com/content/b3a6ea05-1357-4564-a448-27b16a376a4a more worrying was the absence of a renewed commitment to phase out fossil fuels, which had been flagged in Glasgow. HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2022/nov/20/cop27-agrees-to-historic-loss-and-damage-fund-to-compensate-developing-countries-for-climate-impacts Oil-producing countries Instead, the final text noted only the need for a  phase down of unabated coal power , which https://www.theadvocate.com.au/story/7988167/critics-lament-cop27-deal-lack-of-ambition/ many viewed as inadequate for the urgency of the challenge. Likewise, hoped-for rules to stop HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/toxic-cover-up-6-lessons-australia-can-draw-from-the-uns-scathing-report-on-greenwashing-194054 greenwashing and new restrictions on carbon markets weren\' t forthcoming. Both this outcome and the failure to develop new commitments to phase out fossil fuels HYPERLINK https://www.scimex.org/newsfeed/cop27-agreement-what-has-it-achieved arguably reflect the power of fossil-fuel interests and lobbyists. COP26 president Alok Sharma captured the frustration of countries in the high-ambition coalition, HYPERLINK https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/quote-box-reaction-to-un-climate-meet-deal-on-disaster-fund/2022/11/19/5ec52c1e-6880-11ed-b08c-3ce222607059_story.html saying :  We joined with many parties to propose a number of measures that would have contributed to [raising ambition].  Emissions peaking before 2025 as the science tells us is necessary. Not in this text. Clear follow-through on the phase-down of coal. Not in this text. Clear commitments to phase out all fossil fuels. Not in this text. And the energy text weakened in the final minutes. And as United Nations Secretary General Antonio Guterres HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/environment/live/2022/nov/19/cop27-fears-15c-target-danger-negotiations-overrun-live lamented :  Our planet is still in the emergency room. Beyond COP27 In the end, exhausted delegates signed off on an inadequate agreement, but largely avoided the backsliding that looked possible over fraught days of negotiations. The establishment of a fund for loss and damage is clearly an important outcome of COP27 , even with details yet to be fleshed out. But otherwise, the negotiations can\' t be seen as an unambiguously positive outcome for action on the climate crisis \- especially with very little progress on mitigating emissions. And while the world dithers, the window of opportunity to respond effectively to the climate crisis continues to close. It\' s important to note, however, that while COPs are clearly significant in the international response to the climate crisis, they\' re not the only game in town. Public mobilisation and activism, market forces, aid and development programs, and legislation at local, state and national levels are all important sites of climate politics \- and potentially, significant change. There are myriad examples. Take the international phenomenon of HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/how-young-climate-activists-are-making-their-voices-heard-at-cop27-over-egypts-protest-suppression-193210 school climate strikes HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/cannon-brookes-shakes-up-agl-what-now-for-australias-biggest-carbon-emitter-194625 takeover of AGL Energy, Australia\' s biggest carbon\~emitter. They point to the possibility of action on climate change outside formal international climate negotiations. So if you\' re despairing at the limited progress at COP27 , remember this: Nations and communities determined to wean themselves off fossil fuels will do more to blunt the power of the sector than most international agreements could realistically hope to achieve. HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com The Conversation under a Creative Commons license. Read the HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/cop27-one-big-breakthrough-but-ultimately-an-inadequate-response-to-the-climate-crisis-194056 original article . \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong4" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 4, 2022 Friday 8:48 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
World leaders and climate experts are gathering for pivotal United Nations climate-change talks next week in Egypt. Known as COP27 , HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/almost-200-nations-are-set-to-tackle-climate-change-at-cop27-in-egypt-is-this-just-a-talkfest-or-does-the-meeting-actually-matter-191586 the conference will aim The world must rapidly decarbonize to avoid the most dangerous climate change harms. World leaders know this. But that knowledge must urgently turn into concrete commitments and plans. If humanity continues on its current path, we\' re going to leave a hotter, deadlier world for the children of today and all future generations. Earth desperately needs COP27 to succeed. I\' m a climate scientist and I believe world leaders should have these three things top-of-mind heading into the conference. Planet is undeniably in crisis So far, Earth has warmed just over 1 degree Celsius relative to pre-industrial levels, meaning we\' ve already damaged the climate system. Our greenhouse gas emissions have already caused sea level to rise, sea ice to shrink and the ocean to become more acidic. Extreme events in recent years \- particularly heatwaves \- have the fingerprints of climate change all over them. HYPERLINK The record-smashing heat HYPERLINK a deadly 40 degrees Celsius The ocean, too, has suffered HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/how-much-do-marine-heatwaves-cost-the-economic-losses-amount-to-billions-and-billions-of-dollars-170008 a succession of marine heatwaves Frighteningly, we risk tipping the climate into a dangerous new regime bringing even worse consequences. HYPERLINK https://www.science.org/doi/abs/10.1126/science.abn7950 Research from September finds we\' re on the brink of passing five major climate  tipping points, such as the collapse of Greenland\' s ice-sheet. Passing these points will lock the planet into continuing damage to the climate, even if all greenhouse gas emissions cease. Human health is also on the line. HYPERLINK https://www.thelancet.com/countdown-health-climate Recent research revealed that the climate crisis is undermining public health through, for instance, greater spread of infectious diseases, air pollution and food shortages. Among its disturbing findings, heat-related deaths in babies under a year old, and adults over 65, increased by 68% in 2017-2021 compared with 2000-2004. Future generations cannot afford our dithering on action to reduce emissions. Emissions reduction is too slow Some countries, particularly in Europe, are succeeding in reducing greenhouse gas emissions through transitioning to renewable energy. But globally it\' s not happening fast enough. A HYPERLINK https://unfccc.int/news/climate-plans-remain-insufficient-more-ambitious-action-needed-now UN report last week found that if nations deliver on their climate action goals for 2030, Earth will still heat by about 2.5 degrees Celsius this century \- overshooting the Paris Agreement goal to keep global warming well below 2 degrees. Such warming would be HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/if-all-2030-climate-targets-are-met-the-planet-will-heat-by-2-7-this-century-thats-not-ok-170458 disastrous , especially in poorer parts of the world that have contributed little to global emissions. For decades, the world has talked about reducing carbon-dioxide emissions. But annual global emissions have risen by https://www.icos-cp.eu/science-and-impact/global-carbon-budget/2021?fbclid=IwAR0SwhQBUh-ij47mZpILLN7xnIscFPaki7DuC-TlNbFXvuEMcUxg1G_xabg more than 50% in my lifetime, and since the first COP back in 1992. The UN HYPERLINK https://wedocs.unep.org/bitstream/handle/20.500.11822/40875/EGR2022_KR.pdf?sequence=3 warns there\' s still  no credible pathway to limiting warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius. Until we reach close to net-zero emissions, the amount of CO in our atmosphere will rise and the planet will warm. At our current rate, we are warming the planet by about 0.2 degree Celsius every decade. With so many challenges facing the world, including the Russian invasion of Ukraine and the cost-of-living crisis, it may be tempting to view climate change as a problem that can wait. This would be a terrible idea. Only concerted efforts from all nations will avoid destroying our most sensitive ecosystems, such as coral reefs. We should be doing everything we can to stop this by transitioning away from fossil fuels. Any new fossil-fuel development is just making the problem worse and will cost humanity and the environment far more in future. And yet HYPERLINK https://iea.blob.core.windows.net/assets/c282400e-00b0-4edf-9a8e-6f2ca6536ec8/WorldEnergyOutlook2022.pdf the International Energy Agency has just projected that the net income for oil and gas producers will double in 2022  to an unprecedented US$4 trillion, a $2 trillion windfall. We can\' t, as climate activist Greta Thunberg put it, just have more  HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/sep/28/blah-greta-thunberg-leaders-climate-crisis-co2-emissions blah, blah, blah  from world leaders at COP27 \- we need concrete action to reduce greenhouse gas emissions. What now? COP27 must lead to a rapid transition away from fossil fuels, including no new fossil-fuel developments, and more support for countries dealing with the biggest climate-change impacts. We must be on a credible path to reach global net-zero emissions within the next few decades. The lack of progress at past global climate talks means I\' m not optimistic that COP27 will achieve what\' s needed. But I hope world leaders will prove me wrong and not let their nations down. This article is republished from HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com The Conversation under a Creative Commons license. Read the HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/3-things-a-climate-scientist-wants-world-leaders-to-know-ahead-of-cop27-193534 original article . \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong5" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 26, 2022 Saturday"source="Hong Kong Free Press" >
The recently ended COP27 climate change conference in Sharm el-Sheikh, Egypt, resulted in a HYPERLINK mixed bag of tepid pledges to address climate change. The conference made no progress on upping global ambition to cut greenhouse gas (GHG) pollution. The nominal objective of limiting global warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius above historical levels is no closer to realisation. On the plus side, developed countries finally recognised longstanding demands from poor countries to create a new  loss and damage fund to compensate them for their suffering from worsening storms, floods, wildfires and other manifestations of climate change. An almighty battle will ensue over the coming year to decide who will pony up the money for this fund. Climate advocates campaign for a  loss and damage fund at COP27 in Sharm el-Sheikh, Egypt, on November 19, 2022. Photo: UN. HYPERLINK Not for the first time COP27 Chinese diplomats worked hard to block measures that might obligate Beijing to do more to reduce its GHG emissions or provide loss-and-damage assistance to poor countries. This unwillingness to face up to China\' s role in fuelling the climate crisis apparently originates at the top. Chinese leader Xi Jinping failed to join 100 other leaders at COP27 . Although he was in good company; his  HYPERLINK best friend  \- Vladimir Putin \- also failed to show up. It\' s not that world leaders\' attendance at COPs greatly affects negotiations \- it rarely does \- but it at least shows that they are concerned about the issue in some way. Perhaps Xi\' s attendance, combined with a domestic propaganda blitz, could have galvanised more support among the Chinese people for aggressive action on climate change. Xi did not send his premier Li Keqiang to Sharm el-Sheikh, or even his foreign minister. By sending relatively low-level officials \- the Chinese delegation was led by a vice-minister of ecology and environment \- Beijing laid bare its pusillanimous commitment to tackling climate change. US President Joe Biden speaks at COP at Sharm el-Sheikh, Egypt, on November 11, 2022. Photo: UN. Even elderly US President Joe Biden made the effort to attend COP27 . Perhaps that\' s because he could share some positive news about HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2022/aug/05/us-climate-bill-slash-emissions-analysis-biden US action on climate change \- too little action, to be sure, but action nonetheless. Biden could at least say that American GHG emissions are on the decline. Not so in the case of China. It produces HYPERLINK https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-57018837 more GHG pollution than all Western countries and Japan put together. Both its total emissions and its percentage of global emissions are rising, despite repeated HYPERLINK https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-60984663 warnings from scientists Xi HYPERLINK https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3113775/xi-jinpings-pledge-cut-chinas-carbon-emissions-raises declared in 2020 that China\' s carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions would peak by 2030. Given his total grip on power, one might therefore assume that China is moving full speed ahead to cut its burning of fossil fuels. Alas, that\' s not what is happening. Because Xi did not specify the scale and pace of China\' s emissions before 2030, there are powerful economic and political incentives across the country to increase the burning of fossil fuels, HYPERLINK https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/03/business/energy-environment/china-coal-natural-gas.html especially coal , in the meantime. Burning more coal means keeping miners employed. It means extracting more profit from state-owned coal mines and coal-burning power plants and factories. It means squeezing more economic growth from China\' s coal reserves. File photo: Pixabay. The problem with this approach is that China\' s continued investments in coal and other fossil fuels means that any reductions in the country\' s CO2 emissions after 2030 will start from a level that is too high to prevent extreme climate change. Those emissions will exacerbate the problem for centuries to come because CO2 remains in the atmosphere for up to HYPERLINK https://climate.nasa.gov/news/2915/the-atmosphere-getting-a-handle-on-carbon-dioxide/ 1,000 years . This is a recipe for climate disaster, including in China. Behaving so irresponsibly is also a disaster for China\' s HYPERLINK https://hongkongfp.com/2022/03/02/russia-ukraine-war-gives-a-glimpse-of-chinas-new-world-order-and-of-beijings-faltering-reputation/ faltering global reputation HYPERLINK declined dramatically Xi\' s no-show at COP27 can only worsen this problem, especially among those who are most severely affected by China\' s climate-changing emissions. They will eventually tire of China\' s HYPERLINK #block-6378f20d8f0874ab9710d3fb refusal to accept any divergence from its anachronistic designation as a  developing country \- right HYPERLINK https://unfccc.int/process/parties-non-party-stakeholders/parties-convention-and-observer-states alongside Bangladesh and Benin \- that it had when climate negotiations began more than three decades ago. That designation allows China to avoid formal responsibility for climate action, even as it ignores the economic accomplishments that the Chinese Communist Party crows about domestically and internationally in other contexts. An Apple store in Shanghai, China. File Photo: Wikicommons. The average person in China is  HYPERLINK 34 times richer  than when the first climate agreement was reached in 1992. How many Chinese billionaires, luxury shopping malls, skyscrapers, high-speed trains, warships and satellites will China need before it finally acknowledges that it ought to have more responsibility than Chad and Chile? It\' s not that China deserves disproportionate blame for climate change. Fingers can justifiably be pointed toward the West. But at least most Western countries are starting the essential process of bringing their GHG pollution down and belatedly accepting responsibility to aid poor countries in their climate fights. If there is any hope of preventing climate catastrophe, global GHG emissions must decline very quickly. However, in 2021 China\' s GHG emissions HYPERLINK increased at the fastest rate HYPERLINK https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/03/business/energy-environment/china-coal-natural-gas.html more than the rest of the world put together \- and it is locking coal into its future energy mix by building more coal-fired plants to produce electricity, steel and cement. Yangzhou coal plant in China. File photo: Wikicommons. HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2022/apr/26/too-many-new-coal-fired-plants-planned-for-15c-climate-goal-report-concludes coal-fired power has been commissioned in China since the Covid-19 pandemic began than in the whole of the rest of world. As of January this year, China had more than HYPERLINK https://www.statista.com/statistics/859266/number-of-coal-power-plants-by-country/ 1,100 coal power plants HYPERLINK government backing . HYPERLINK https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3199652/china-faces-uphill-battle-coal-transition-ditching-fossil-fuel-crucial-stave-climate-change-impact China\' s coal emissions HYPERLINK pledge to shift away from coal COP27 to HYPERLINK https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3156029/cop26-summit-chinas-climate-commitments-spotlight-after-coal block a pledge to phase out coal use globally. That\' s very HYPERLINK https://www.fairplanet.org/story/cop27-chinas-climate-obligations-come-under-scrutiny/ difficult to justify For example, even when measured by purchasing power parity, China\' s gross domestic product is HYPERLINK https://www.statista.com/statistics/270439/chinas-share-of-global-gross-domestic-product-gdp/ less than 20 percent HYPERLINK https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-57018837 climbing toward 30 percent To argue, as Beijing likes to do, that much of its emissions can be attributed to exports is factually HYPERLINK #consumption-based-accounting-how-do-emissions-compare-when-we-adjust-for-trade misleading and fails to acknowledge that the profits accruing from those exports are the source of the wealth generation that the CCP is so proud to proclaim. You can\' t blame others for the environmental externalities of making yourself wealthy. Photo: Pikrepo. China\' s failure to take responsibility for its GHG emissions also cannot be justified by demography. Less than 20 percent of the world\' s population lives in China \- again, far short of its share of global GHG pollution. Furthermore, China\' s per capita GHG emissions are only slightly below those of Germany and Japan, both major exporters, and exceed those of France and the United Kingdom. By 2030 China\' s HYPERLINK https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/interactive/2022/climate-change-pledge-progress-cop27/ per capita emissions China\' s lacklustre attitude toward its emissions is not even justified by Beijing\' s assertion that China is entitled to burn fossil fuels today because the West did so in the past. This assertion fails to acknowledge that the West did not know until quite recently that such behaviour would lead to climate disaster. In contrast, China has known almost from the start of its opening up and drive to promote economic growth at all costs that its use of fossil fuels would have this effect. China\' s cumulative HYPERLINK https://graphics.reuters.com/CLIMATE-UN/EMISSIONS/jnvwexaryvw/ historical emissions For more than 15 years, HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2007/jun/19/china.usnews China\' s annual CO2 emissions HYPERLINK #country three times those of the United States. A sign held by a climate advocate at COP27 reads  Stop fossil autocrats, at Sharm el-Sheikh, Egypt, on November 12, 2022. Photo: UN. Adding insult to injury, Beijing has made HYPERLINK climate cooperation COP27 , China\' s climate envoy, Xie Zhenhua, HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/nov/09/cop7-china-us-climate-talks-taiwan declared that US House Speaker Nancy HYPERLINK https://hongkongfp.com/2022/08/28/national-insecurity-china-endangers-the-world-when-the-climate-crisis-falls-hostage-to-a-manufactured-one/ Pelosi\' s visit to Taiwan Beijing\' s fit of pique extended even to email. According to American climate envoy, John Kerry, before COP27 Xie HYPERLINK https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environmnet/2022/11/14/g20-china-us-climate-xi-biden/ refused to answer Kerry\' s emails . The recent meeting between Biden and Xi at the G20 summit in Bali opened a pathway for bilateral climate https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2022/nov/19/china-and-us-renew-commitment-to-tackling-climate-crisis-but-differences-remain discussions to resume COP27 , it appears that those HYPERLINK https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3200305/cop-27-china-and-us-held-constructive-climate-talks-more-follow-beijings-envoy-says talks are back on track As it has done at most previous COPs, China demonstrated at COP27 that it prioritises almost everything \- economic growth,  national security, diplomatic submission by other countries \- above concerted action to mitigate the climate crisis. Revealing Beijing\' s true colours, at COP27 HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2022/nov/19/cop27-divisions-and-splits-threaten-deal-to-tackle-climate-crisis Chinese negotiators HYPERLINK peak global emissions A woman holds a sign saying  Payment overdue at COP27 at Sharm el-Sheikh, Egypt, on November 18, 2022. Photo: UN. Chinese officials want their country to be known as a leader in green energy and  HYPERLINK https://hongkongfp.com/2022/07/23/chinas-ecological-civilisation-a-large-scale-form-of-greenwashing/ ecological civilisation HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2022/nov/20/deal-on-loss-and-damage-fund-at-cop27-marks-climbdown-by-rich-countries As Paul Bledsoe at the Progressive Policy Institute in Washington, DC, observed,  Global emissions can\' t fall until China\' s emissions fall. This is the key to climate protection. Bledsoe isn\' t alone in thinking that COP27  was something of a failure because it completely let the world\' s biggest emitter, China, off the hook. Just before the opening of COP27 , Xie HYPERLINK https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3198699/cop27-chinas-top-climate-envoy-calls-rich-countries-support-poor-nations-most-risk-environmental called on  all sectors of the international community to practice green and low-carbon production and lifestyles. The disconnect between Xie\' s call and his country\' s continuing addiction to coal is glaring to those not living behind Beijing\' s Great Wall of reality distortion. At COP27 Yet, China HYPERLINK declared that, as a  developing country, it has no obligation whatsoever to respond to that demand, despite the undeniable fact that a great proportion of future loss and damage, and millions of lives lost, will arise due to China\' s gargantuan \- and still rising \- GHG pollution. Will China agree anytime soon that its obvious wealth and great-power status create an obligation for it to cut its GHG pollution without delay and compensate those affected? Don\' t count on it. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong6" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 8, 2022 Tuesday 4:10 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
COP27 , which kicked off in Bali this week, continues the dialogue that commenced with the adoption of the Paris Agreement by 196 parties in the French capital on December 12, 2015. This agreement entered force on November 4, 2016. The goal is to limit global warming to well below\~2 degrees Celsius and ideally to\~1.5 degrees compared with pre-industrial levels.\~ Implementing the Paris Agreement requires economic and social transformation that involves altering production and consumption with a focus on minimizing and even removing negative environmental impacts. For governments, this is about facilitating a rapid shift away from energy systems that produce greenhouse gas emissions and to environmentally friendly forms of transportation. The Paris Agreement is about actions intended to mitigate and adapt everyday living to reduce negative environmental impacts, and it tends to ignore the impacts that war has on climate change.\~ Resource dependency Russia\' s war with Ukraine highlighted Europe\' s over-dependency on Russian gas and oil. It also alerted all nations to the dangers of being too dependent on any one country for essential supplies. One perverse impact of Russia\' s invasion of Ukraine is that it will undermine the long-term global market for Russian petrochemicals and will hasten the transition to renewable energy. Russia needs to diversify its economy rapidly away from its over-dependence on revenues from oil and natural gas. This diversification process is impossible as long as sanctions are imposed on Russia. The Kremlin\' s only solution is to withdraw from Ukraine and to negotiate some settlement that would facilitate Russia\' s economic diversification. This is not going to happen under President Vladimir Putin, and Russia is thus on the highway toward a rapidly shrinking and declining economy.\~ War discussed at COP27 There is another side to Russia\' s war with Ukraine.\~This\~ HYPERLINK http://tracking.vuelio.co.uk/tracking/click?d=G6IJtH8LUgsUrq4sRjaipEZInb0Au_ASv_jo7b9-xLTCwYeRB2Y4sVho8Psi9dxkq86P1RBTGVRPKxnNSTMoUqO1vLOL8LOT6pmz97DERyar4bVA1TIx9pfPkRGZI5v4hC_8GLmeu1kcgUB0IvsUnMhpHBbfiCKXFxvh2dQwTGA51zlLzzb3SH522kjqumgd5QrOifnpN8Ur2R_DP9VG3v81 Tuesday , there is scheduled a COP27 side event to discuss\~ Impacts of Russia\' s War against Ukraine on European Climate Policies and Ways Forward. But the problem with side events in that they are side events. For this discussion, the focus is on European policies in response to Russia\' s full-scale invasion of Ukraine. This is a too modest and European-focused discussion.\~ Russia\' s unprovoked attack on Ukraine has major direct, indirect, and induced impacts on global warming. Every missile or shot fired by the two sides results in the release of unnecessary greenhouse gas emissions. All war is unnecessary, and all war has major local and global negative environmental impacts.\~ Direct impacts include the mass destruction of cities resulting in the unnecessary release of carbon embedded in physical infrastructure. They also include anything that immediately impacts everyday living that enhances emissions, for example the unnecessary release of carbon due to forced migration. Indirect impacts include emissions related to reconstruction, but also the production of weapons as well as habitat destruction or contamination. The delivery of humanitarian aid has a large carbon footprint. All the investment and resources that Moscow is expending on war with Ukraine could be applied to reducing Russia\' s greenhouse gas emissions and in enhancing the quality of life of all its citizens. This investment could also have been spent on facilitating Russia\' s economic diversification. Russia could have the best quality of life of all countries and a diversified economy, but instead the decision was to waste resources in producing weapons and engaging in unnecessary war.\~ War is about waste and destruction, and this includes unnecessary greenhouse gas emissions. COP27 could agree to label all wars as unnecessary and as environmental crimes, climate crimes or as climate violations. The problem here is in defining  unnecessary. To Vladimir Putin, his Ukrainian war is necessary. Nevertheless, he has a major conflict of interests here, and is unable to make an informed or objective judgment of his actions.\~ When Russia\' s war with Ukraine concludes, there needs to be an assessment of crimes against humanity, war crimes and climate crimes. An analysis needs to be made of the direct, indirect, and induced impacts of the war on climate change. Russia must be held to account, and this includes financing actions intended to reduce the negative environmental impacts of the war. There must be a rigorous, robust, and transparent assessment with this process designed to act as a deterrent.\~ \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong7" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 20, 2022 Sunday"source="Hong Kong Free Press" >
When Super Typhoon Mangkhut barrelled into Hong Kong on September 17, 2018, its ferocious winds and record-breaking storm surge uprooted some 1,500 trees, caused countless window panes to shatter, left hundreds injured and devastated coastal communities. It also awoke many residents to the reality of the climate crisis.\~ The aftermath of Super Typhoon Mangkhut. File photo: Supplied. Environmental advocates point to the extreme weather event \- the direct economic loss from which was HYPERLINK https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2225603220300564 estimated to have cost the city HK$4.6 billion \- as a turning point in attitudes.  People are more aware of the climate crisis these past few years. Especially after the 2018 super typhoon, Tom Ng, a campaigner with Greenpeace, told HKFP.\~ That is the first step; that people are aware and acknowledge that the issue is affecting them, Hg said.\~ However,  it is still not enough. At the Egyptian Red Sea resort of Sharm el-Sheikh \- which for the past two weeks has played host to world leaders, international media, business and banking executives, as well as key climate stakeholders \- a group of young Hongkongers has been working to try and make sure more is done to further the city\' s climate agenda.\~ CarbonCare InnoLab youth delegate Connie Lam at COP27 in Egypt. Photo: Supplied. Attending the 27th session of the Conference of Parties ( COP27 ) of the UN Framework Convention of Climate Change (UNFCCC) were Judy Cheung, 30, Chin Chin Lam, 26, and Ryan Yip, 22. They formed part of a youth delegation with Hong Kong-based NGO CarbonCare InnoLab (CCIL), in the absence of any officials representing the city.  Frankly speaking, we are quite disappointed with the fact that the Hong Kong government does not treasure the opportunity to participate in COP CarbonCare InnoLab\' s Kwok Hui Chung The last time the Hong Kong government sent someone to the annual climate summit was in 2017, when then-environment secretary Wong Kam-sing joined the Chinese delegation at COP23 in Bonn, Germany.\~ According to a HYPERLINK https://www.info.gov.hk/gia/general/201711/16/P2017111600513.htm statement , while hosting a Hong Kong session at the China Pavilion, Wong said the climate crisis was  a cross-sector, cross-domain subject which has far-reaching socio-economic and cultural impacts across the globe. As  a member of the global village, Hong Kong must  contribute proactively to combating climate change, Wong added.\~ Ever since, however, this member of the global village has been absent, whilst the city\' s new leader John Lee had https://hongkongfp.com/2022/10/22/hong-kong-policy-address-1000-days-on-still-no-roadmap-out-of-pandemic-rules-which-impoverished-thousands/ little to offer in terms of environmental commitments in his inaugural Policy Address. Former environment secretary Wong Kam-sing (second left) joins a panel discussion at a Hong Kong session in the China Pavilion at COP23 in Bonn, Germany, on November 15, 2017. Photo: GovHK.  Frankly speaking, we are quite disappointed with the fact that the Hong Kong government does not treasure the opportunity to participate in COP, Kwok Hui Chung, CCIL\' s senior programme officer, told HKFP by phone from Sharm el-Sheikh. Hong Kong is not a party to the UNFCCC, but it has set its own target of achieving carbon neutrality by 2050.  We believe that, as a city, Hong Kong has a responsibility to reduce carbon emissions and keep 1.5 degrees alive, Kwok said.\~ He was referring to the Paris Agreement, an international treaty negotiated at COP21 that outlined a commitment to keep the mean global temperature rise below 2 degrees Celsius, and preferably limit the increase to 1.5 degrees, thus reducing the effects of the climate crisis. China is among the 194 UNFCCC members that are signatories to the accord.\~ Ryan Yip at the establishment of the Climate Education Coalition at the Climate Education Pavilion at COP27 . Photo: Supplied.  As decided by the Central People\' s Government, the Paris Agreement applies to the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (SAR) as well, a spokesperson from the Environment and Ecology Bureau told HKFP.  Hong Kong is committed to the target of striving to achieve carbon neutrality before 2050 and reduce the total carbon emissions from the 2005 level by half before 2035, they said.  We have been closely monitoring discussions at the COP conferences to assess the implications of the discussion outcomes on our climate actions. A question about the lack of official presence at this year\' s event went unanswered, with the EEB spokesperson saying that Hong Kong had been present at COP21, when the Paris Agreement was adopted,  and the subsequent COPs. The first ever Children and Youth Pavilion at COP27 in Sharm el-Sheikh. Photo: Supplied. Last month, a HYPERLINK https://www.unep.org/resources/emissions-gap-report-2022 report from the United Nations Environment Programme found that the world was falling well short of the goal set out in the Paris Agreement. Under current measures, temperatures could rise as much as 2.8 degrees by the end of the century. Hong Kong warning signs For Hong Kong, this would manifest in a number of ways. Pointing to an assessment conducted by the Hong Kong Observatory, Eva Yeung \- senior manager of community resilience at the Hong Kong Red Cross (HKRC) \- said the city  will experience climate change in terms of rising temperatures and sea levels.\~  We are a coastal city, there are a lot of coastal communities that may be severely impacted by future sea level rise but also storms or typhoons Chin Chin Lam, COP27 youth delegate  The sea level has recorded an average rise of about 3 centimetres per decade in Hong Kong under the impact of global warming, Yeung said. This has the greatest impact on low-lying and coastal regions, with the impact accelerated by typhoon-generated storm surges, Yeung added. Climate scientists agree that typhoons will become more frequent as the world heats up. Residential complexes such as Heng Fa Chuen in Chai Wan are particularly vulnerable. The estate, home to more than 18,000 people, saw flooding in 2017 after being HYPERLINK caught off guard by Typhoon Hato HYPERLINK https://hongkongfp.com/2018/09/17/heng-fa-chuen-seaside-housing-estate-cleans-typhoon-mangkhut-brings-floods-destruction/ battered by Manghut Benches, trees, and bricks uprooted at Heng Fa Chuen by Super Typhoon Mangkhut. File Photo: Holmes Chan/HKFP.  We are a coastal city, there are a lot of coastal communities that may be severely impacted by future sea level rise but also storms or typhoons, said Chin Chin Lam, one of the CCIL youth delegates. COP27  Seoul is such a developed city, similar to Hong Kong I think that serves as a bit of a wakeup call to Hongkongers, Lam said.  As well as Typhoon Mangkhut and actually the HYPERLINK https://hongkongfp.com/2022/11/02/hong-kong-hoists-t8-storm-signal-as-severe-tropical-storm-nalgae-nears/ November typhoon \- what was that ? When did we ever have typhoons in November? I think these things are slowly creeping up on Hongkongers [to show] that climate change is real, it\' s happening to us as well. Chin Chin Lam at COP27 in Shark el-Sheikh. Photo: Supplied. A heatwave in July also highlighted HYPERLINK https://hongkongfp.com/2022/07/25/3-deaths-over-weekend-as-hong-kong-sees-hottest-july-on-record-experts-warn-of-link-to-climate-crisis/ how global heating affects Hong Kong Outdoor workers \- typically those in low-income roles such as street cleaners, labourers and delivery drivers \- experience the worst of this. Those living in substandard housing are also unduly impacted.  If you live in a [subdivided housing] unit, the temperature inside will feel on average 5 degrees Celsius higher than [the temperature] that is reported outside from the Hong Kong Observatory, Lam said. Ng from Greenpeace expanded on this, saying that residents of subdivided units often had no way of keeping cool.  A lot of [them] cannot afford to have a fan or air conditioning in their homes, because fans cost too much space and AC costs too much money, Ng said. Hong Kong during a heat wave in July 2022. File photo: Lea Mok/HKFP. The impact of 2.8 degree heating is not limited to Hong Kong,  it would affect food supply across the world, Ng said. For a city that imports more than 90 per cent of everything it eats and drinks, that is not good news. When Covid-19 disrupted fresh produce deliveries from mainland China and HYPERLINK https://hongkongfp.com/2022/02/08/covid-19-hong-kong-veg-prices-soar-as-cross-border-truckers-quarantined-chinese-state-media-says-dynamic-zero-strategy-scientific-choice/ sparked panic buying and inflated prices in February, it was the poorest households that were left with little to eat. This, HKRC\' s Yeung, said was indicative of how the climate crisis will impact Hongkongers:  People with limited resources will suffer more. \' We shouldn\' t give up\' To reduce the impact of climate change, both globally and in Hong Kong, requires the involvement of the government, of businesses and of individuals, Ng said. COP27 take a selfie with Alok Sharma, the president of COP26. Photo: Supplied. Greenpeace recently looked into government departments\' environmental reports to see what carbon reduction measures were in place and whether targets had been set to help Hong Kong achieve net-zero by 2050. What the organisation found, Ng said, was  not good.  A lot of them do not have their own carbon neutrality targets, and their measures are just not really matching the goal of carbon neutrality, he added, pointing to a lack of direction from the Environmental Protection Department (EPD). Guidelines on environmental performance reporting exist, but they were written in 1999 and have not been updated since.  That creates some problems, Ng said.  Twenty-three years ago, climate change was not as huge of an issue as it is now. In response to an enquiry about the guidelines, the EPD said:  We are going to review and update the guideline to include those latest requirements and targets. The plenary hall at COP27 . Photo: Supplied. Whether a lack of departmental reporting and targets will affect Hong Kong\' s goal of net-zero by 2050 is uncertain.  It\' s a possibility, Ng said.  I cannot tell if we are going to achieve it, I cannot tell if the government is doing enough or not. We need everyone to work really hard on this issue, to make it possible to reach carbon neutrality by 2050. There are those already dedicated to the cause; CCIL youth delegates Cheung, Lam and Yip among them. Cheung and Yip co-founded Climate Sense, an advocacy group that aims to involve local educators, policy makers and curriculum developers to promote climate education in Hong Kong.  We try to engage the government, Cheung told HKFP, adding that they have submitted reports to the Education Bureau and the EPD.  It is not just a social campaign to engage the public, but also to engage the government and let them hear the voice of the Hong Kong public and also the youth, she said. Judy Cheung at COP27 . Photo: Supplied.  When governments make their decisions, they are not only driven by the global agenda or economic circumstances, but they are also driven by the voices and responses from local people, Cheung added.  So if people don\' t care about climate change, or if they think they can\' t make any changes and they become less responsive to the issue, then governments may become less responsive as well, because no one is pushing them to do more on this agenda.  Climate change is not just an environmental issue anymore, [it is] more like a social issue that requires all stakeholders \- especially youth advocates \- to unite, to get involved and to take robust action. Ryan Yip, Youth delegation  Us, as individuals, shouldn\' t give up. Lam agreed.  Individual actions make a lot of difference, it\' s like a ripple effect. She turned vegetarian several years ago, and used her experience to illustrate how to change attitudes.  You do something, and your friends ask you why you are doing it, and you explain that it\' s for climate change. And then maybe your individual actions would inspire others to do the same, Lam said. When Lam returned to Hong Kong four years ago after studying overseas, she said there were very few places she could go out to eat. But now, there are significantly more choices \- even McDonald\' s offers a vegetarian breakfast option.  Compared to four years ago, people don\' t think I\' m weird that I\' m a vegetarian anymore. So I think you do see these changes, and these come from individual actions. It also comes down to consumer choices.  Companies go where the money goes, so choose where you spend, Lam said. For Yip, climate education is key.  Education can develop a sense of ownership and responsibility among citizens and residents, and they won\' t feel as helpless, he said.  Climate change is not just an environmental issue anymore, [it is] more like a social issue that requires all stakeholders \- especially youth advocates \- to unite, to get involved and to take robust action. Ryan Yip at COP27 Cheung, Lam and Yip sounded simultaneously inspired and overwhelmed by their experience at COP27 . Designed to be an  implementation-based event, where the policy focus of previous summits was finally translated into action, they spoke of hours-long negotiations over how certain things in agreements were phrased. And while the topic of loss and damage \- the destructive impacts of the climate crisis that cannot be avoided \- was added to the official COP agenda for the first time, whether the Sharm el-Sheikh event would achieve much remained to be seen. Negotiations, which were scheduled to end on Friday, overran.  Everyone is trying really hard to achieve something, but there are 198 parties now, so there is a lot to talk about, a lot to go through, and sometimes these administrative processes or details take a long time to discuss, Lam said.  I don\' t know if we can keep 1.5 degrees alive, because we are on track to 2.8, but I am still hopeful I also wish that things could be implemented quicker, she added. However, Lam said the question of hope might be different were it posed to someone from Pakistan, where 33 million people were displaced by devastating floods in September.  I think their position, their answer would not be the same, they would not have hope. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong8" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="EQS TodayIR"source=" " >
EQS-News: Laser Photonics Corporation As COP27 Talks Continue, This Blasting Company Is Helping Create A Sustainable New Future 14.11.2022 / 15:21 CET/CESTThe issuer is solely responsible for the content of this announcement.World leaders are gathering for the 27th session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP27 ) in Egypt to discuss the future of the planet. As governments discuss policies, companies are bringing positive change to the marketplace by finding environmentally sustainable innovations to improve major industries. One potential innovator is Laser Photonics Corp. (NASDAQ: LASE), a company helping change the sand and abrasive blasting market through its industrial laser technologies. Laser Photonics Corp. are integrators of low and high-power industrial fiber lasers along with its R & D department are seeking to lead the growing industrial market. Its lasers ? which were at North America?s largest metal forming and finishing trade show ? have uses ranging from engraving and 3D printing to cleaning and conditioning. Through its innovation and commitment to safety, it hopes to create an industry that is more green for the environment and more protective of workers? health.The company recently an order for the U.S. Navy that is part of a series of order completions in both the public and private sectors that are geared toward reducing waste and helping give the industry an environmentally positive future. The company delivered its CleanTech Handheld LPC-1000CTH lasers to the U.S. Navy Kings Bay Trident Refit Facility as the Navy tackles rust and corrosion of its ships and equipment.21st-Century Solutions To Age-Old ProblemsLaser Photonics? industrial laser products aim to provide a modern alternative to the less efficient, more pollutive, and more risky sand and abrasive blasting industry. Labor Unions, as well as the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA), are waging war on unsafe industry practices as they close in around abrasive blasting methods. The EPA?s on blasting put parameters around its use based on air quality, noise pollution, and waste production. OSHA has also the ?significant risk? to workers? health associated with exposure to crystalline silica ? a common hazard in abrasive blasting procedures ? and has imposed strict rules regulating this kind of exposure.Meanwhile, Laser Photonics lasers, which frequently get the job done in half the time, produce no hazardous waste, and employ the of safe design and use regulations could effectively make cleaning and conditioning a fast and hassle-free procedure. This is why numerous Fortune 1000 companies are choosing Laser Photonics, which has a strong blue-chip customer base of key players across industries. These range from Dell Technologies Inc. (NYSE: DELL) and DuPont de Nemours Inc. (NYSE: DD) to Elkhart Plastics Inc., Evergreen Solar, Sony Group Corp. (NYSE: SONY), and Seagate Technology Holdings PLC (NASDAQ: STX). Laser Photonics has also seen diverse interest from government agencies, the U.S. Army, Navy, National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), and Veterans Administration. ?We are continually working to penetrate new verticals within the U.S. government, including the DoD (Department of Defense), to demonstrate both the efficiency and financial benefits of using our technology to drive sales to new customers within the organizations,? Laser Photonics CEO Wayne Tupuola said.Other companies in the industrial laser market include Coherent Corp. (NASDAQ: COHR), Lumentum Holdings Inc. (NASDAQ: LITE), Novanta Inc. (NASDAQ: NOVT), and Adapt Laser.Interested in learning more about Laser Photonics? Visit its .Laser Photonics is a vertically-integrated manufacturer and R&D Center of Excellence for industrial laser technologies and systems. LPC seeks to disrupt the $46 billion, centuries old, sand and abrasives blasting markets, focusing on surface cleaning, rust removal, corrosion control, de-painting and other laser-based industrial applications. LPC's new generation of leading-edge laser blasting technologies and equipment also addresses the numerous health, safety, environmental, and regulatory issues associated with the old methods. As a result, LPC has quickly gained a reputation as an industry leader for industrial laser systems with a brand that stands for quality, technology and product innovation. Currently, world-renowned and Fortune 1000 manufacturers in the aerospace, automotive, defense, energy, industrial, maritime, space exploration and shipbuilding industries are using LPC's "unique-to-industry" systems. This post contains sponsored advertising content. This content is for informational purposes only and is not intended to be investing advice.Contact DetailsBrian Siegel, IRC\e, M.B.A. Senior Managing Director Hayden IRCompany WebsiteNews Source: News Direct 14.11.2022 CET/CEST Dissemination of a Corporate News, transmitted by EQS News - a service of EQS Group AG.The issuer is solely responsible for the content of this announcement.The EQS Distribution Services include Regulatory Announcements, Financial/Corporate News and Press Releases.Archive at HYPERLINK http://www.eqs-news.com www.eqs-news.com {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell Language: English {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell Company: Laser Photonics Corporation {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell United States {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell ISIN: US51807Q1004 {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell EQS News ID: 1487249 {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell End of News EQS News Service {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell 1487249\~\~14.11.2022\~CET/CEST \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong9" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 17, 2022 Thursday 3:13 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
HYPERLINK https://unfccc.int/cop27 COP27 \~is under way in Sharm El Sheikh, Egypt. Although the Ukraine war and other issues have shifted some people\' s immediate focus away from the battle against global warming, it remains a central concern of our epoch.\~ HYPERLINK https://public.wmo.int/en/our-mandate/climate/wmo-statement-state-of-global-climate Reports indicate \~that not only are we failing to meet our climate goals, we are also falling short of the targets by a large margin. Worse, the potent\~ HYPERLINK https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/2022/06/27/methane-emissions-rising-report/ methane greenhouse gas emissions Even though methane lasts for a shorter time in the atmosphere,\~ HYPERLINK viewed over a period of 100 years HYPERLINK https://www.aljazeera.com/opinions/2022/5/11/climate-change-is-devastating-the-global-south#:~:text=While%20such%20impacts%20are%20global,can%20no%20longer%20support%20them. much higher \~in the equatorial and tropical regions, where most of the world\' s poor live. In this column, I will address two issues. One is the shift from coal to natural gas as a transitional fuel, and the other is the challenge of storing electricity, without which we cannot shift successfully to renewable energy. The problem of methane The advanced countries of North America and Europe bet big on natural gas, which is primarily methane, as the transition fuel from coal. In Glasgow during COP26, advanced countries even made coal the key issue,\~ HYPERLINK https://asiatimes.com/2021/12/poorer-nations-not-falling-for-greenwashed-imperialism/ shifting the focus \~from their greenhouse emissions to that of China and India as big coal users. The assumption in using natural gas as a transitional fuel is that its greenhouse impact is only half that of coal. Methane emissions also last for a shorter time \- about 12 years \- in the atmosphere before converting to carbon dioxide and water. The flip side is that it is a far more potent greenhouse gas. Its effects are 30 times as great over a 100-year period than an equivalent amount of carbon dioxide. So even a much smaller amount of methane has a much more significant global warming impact than carbon dioxide. The bad news on the methane front is that methane leakage from the natural-gas infrastructure is much higher, possibly as much as\~ HYPERLINK six times \~as much \- according to a March\~ HYPERLINK https://earth.stanford.edu/news/methane-leaks-are-far-worse-estimates-least-new-mexico-theres-hope#gs.x9znt3 Stanford University study HYPERLINK https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2022-methane-leaks-natural-gas-energy-emissions-data/?leadSource=uverify%20wall the actual leakage \~of methane from the\~ HYPERLINK https://www.kayrros.com/methane-watch/ natural-gas infrastructure with satellites \~and aircraft using infrared cameras. The technology of measuring methane leaks from natural-gas infrastructure is easy and cheap. After all, we are able to detect methane in exoplanets far away from the solar system. Surely saving this planet from heat death is a much higher priority. The other data are the measurement of atmospheric methane conducted by the\~ HYPERLINK https://public.wmo.int/en/our-mandate/climate/wmo-statement-state-of-global-climate World Meteorological Organization The US Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) estimates that\~ HYPERLINK https://www.nytimes.com/2022/03/24/climate/methane-leaks-new-mexico.html 1.4% \~of all natural gas produced in the US leaks into the atmosphere. But the March\~ HYPERLINK https://earth.stanford.edu/news/methane-leaks-are-far-worse-estimates-least-new-mexico-theres-hope#gs.x9znt3 Stanford University Even if methane leaks are only 2.5% of natural-gas production, they will offset all the benefits of switching from coal to natural gas.  Clean natural gas may be three to four times as bad as even dirty coal. The EPA does not conduct any physical measurements. All it uses to estimate methane emissions is a formula that involves a number of subjective factors, along with the number of wells, length of pipelines, etc. The impact of methane leaks can be seen in another set of figures. The WMO HYPERLINK https://public.wmo.int/en/media/press-release/more-bad-news-planet-greenhouse-gas-levels-hit-new-highs reported the biggest jump The tragedy of methane leaks is that while they are easy to spot and not very expensive to fix, many companies have no incentive to take even these baby steps if it impacts their\~ current \~bottom line. The\~ larger good \- even\~ bigger profits , but\~ \- does not interest them. They aren\' t likely to change unless they are forced to by regulatory or direct state action. The cynicism of the rich countries on global warming can be seen in their conduct during the Ukraine war. The\~European Union has HYPERLINK restarted some of its coal plants Further, the EU has cynically argued that developing oil and gas infrastructure in Africa is all right as long as it is\~ HYPERLINK solely for supply to Europe The problem of energy storage The key to a transition to renewable energy \- the only long-term solution to global warming \- is to find a way of storing energy. Renewables, unlike fossil fuels, cannot be used at will, as the wind, sun, and even water provide a continuous flow of energy. While water can be stored in large reservoirs, wind and sun cannot be, unless they are converted to chemical energy in batteries. Or unless they are converted to hydrogen and then stored in either tanks or in geological formations, underground or in salt caverns. There has been a lot of hype about batteries and electric cars. Missing here is that batteries with current technology have a much lower energy density than oil or coal. The\~energy from oil or natural gas is HYPERLINK https://www.batterypowertips.com/comparing-ev-battery-and-fuel-cell-energy-density-faq/ 20-40 times that of the most efficient battery \~available currently. For an electric vehicle, that is not such a major issue. It simply determines how often the vehicle\' s batteries need to be charged and how long charging will take. It means developing a charging infrastructure with a quick turnaround time. The much bigger problem is how to store energy at the grid level. Grid-level storage means supplying electricity from stored energy. Grid-level batteries are being suggested to meet this task. What the proponents of grid-level batteries neglect to inform us is that they may supply power for short-term fluctuations \- night and day, windy and non-windy days \- but they cannot meet the demand from long-term or seasonal fluctuations. This brings us to the question of the energy density of storage: How much energy does a kilogram of lithium battery hold as compared with a kilogram of oil, natural gas, or coal? The answer with current technology\~ HYPERLINK https://www.batterypowertips.com/comparing-ev-battery-and-fuel-cell-energy-density-faq/ is 20-40 times less HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/lithium-is-finite-but-clean-technology-relies-on-such-non-renewable-resources-109630 exhaust all our lithium I will not address the prohibitive energy cost \- electric or fossil fuel \- of private versus public or mass transportation, and why we should switch to the latter. I will instead focus on addressing the larger question of how to\~ HYPERLINK https://physicsworld.com/a/why-we-need-to-tackle-renewable-energys-storage-problem/ store renewable energy Is it possible that a new technology will solve this problem? (Remember the dream of nuclear energy that will be not only clean but also so cheap that it will\~ HYPERLINK http://www.thisdayinquotes.com/2009/09/too-cheap-to-meter-nuclear-quote-debate.html not need to be metered If not, we have to look at currently available solutions. They exist, but using them means seeking alternatives to batteries for addressing grid-level problems of intermittent renewable energy. It means repurposing\~ existing \~hydro projects to work as grid-level storage and\~ HYPERLINK https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/salt-cavern developing hydrogen storage No extra dams or reservoirs, as the opponents of hydroelectricity projects fear. And of course, it means more public transportation instead of private transportation. All of these existing solutions mean making changes on a societal level that corporate interests oppose \- after all, doing so would require public investments for social benefits and not for private profits. Capital privileges short-term private profits over long-term social benefits. Remember how oil companies had the earliest research to show the impact of global warming due to carbon dioxide emissions? They not only hid these results for decades but also launched a campaign denying that global warming is linked to greenhouse gases. And they funded climate-change deniers. The contradiction at the heart of global warming is private greed over social needs. And who funds such a transition, the poor or the rich? This is also what COP27 is all about, not simply about how to stop global warming. This article was produced in partnership by \~ HYPERLINK https://www.newsclick.in/ Newsclick \~ \~ https://globetrotter.media/ Globetrotter , which provided it to Asia Times. Prabir Purkayastha is the founding editor of Newsclick.in, a digital media platform. He is an activist for science and the free software movement. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong10" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 22, 2022 Tuesday 3:46 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
Throughout COP27 British newspaper The Guardian, which can always be relied upon to bash the Arab Gulf monarchies on the slightest pretext, dedicated a long article to what it considered to be the shocking revelation that the United Arab Emirates, which will be hosting COP28 next November, had taken the perfectly normal step of sending a large delegation to the conference in Sharm El Sheikh, Egypt. Meanwhile, Saudi Arabia\' s grand strategy for carbon capture, far more ambitious than anything else currently on offer in this vital field, endorsed by the United Nations as an essential weapon in the world\' s necessarily multifaceted armory in the battle against global warming, has been dismissed by Greenpeace and its media enablers as a  false solution and  a waste of time and money. But the real waste of time and money at COP27 was  well, COP27 . Not because the entire conference was undermined by the supposedly sinister Gulf lobby, but because it was hijacked and fatally compromised by the superficially righteous  loss-and-damage brigade. This might sound like a great idea, a virtuous exercise in  climate justice. But in reality it is an insane distraction from the all-important job in hand \- saving the planet. Thanks to the focus on  loss and damage, no progress at all was made at COP27 toward the world\' s already shaky climate-change goals. Worse, the stage has now been set for years of continuing inaction over the only thing that truly matters. The actual mechanics of the  guilt tax \- which countries will pay which, and how much \- have yet to be thrashed out. This means that, for the foreseeable future, instead of getting on with the business of saving the planet, the entire COP process is in danger of being shunted into a cul-de-sac of bickering and horse-trading over the loss-and-damage issue. The irony is that while the squabbling over compensation goes on, the impact of uncontrolled climate change on the nations demanding compensation will grow only worse. It\' s difficult to see what consolation a pocketful of gold will be for a nation already under water. The despair among the  guilty nations who felt obliged to sign up to this self-defeating agenda at Sharm El Sheikh is palpable.  We went with  the agreement  because we want to stand with the most vulnerable, said Germany\' s climate secretary Jennifer Morgan, who was, as\~ HYPERLINK https://www.reuters.com/article/climate-un-idCAKBN2SA01F Reuters reported ,  visibly upset that the far more important goal of stronger climate-change ambition had been compromised for the sake of the deal. Even the\~ HYPERLINK https://www.wwf.org.uk/press-release/wwf-closing-statement-cop27 World Wildlife Fund COP27 . The UN, constitutionally obliged to stand up for the underdog, has been backed into a corner by the special pleading of the  victim states. Secretary General Antonio Guterres looked\~ HYPERLINK https://twitter.com/antonioguterres/status/1594181881771212802?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Etweet tired and defeated \~as he welcomed the loss-and-damage agreement as  an important step towards justice, while adding that  we need to drastically reduce emissions now \- and this is an issue this COP did not address. We now face a catastrophic scenario in which, as the impacts of global warming become ever worse \- more of the stuff like the floods we have seen in countries\~ HYPERLINK such as Pakistan \~and Nigeria \- instead of working to attack the cause, the world will be squabbling about which countries should be paid how much in compensation. Inevitably, this will go on, unresolved and sucking up bandwidth, for years. In the face of the impending and increasingly likely disaster predicted by numerous and increasingly alarming\~ HYPERLINK https://www.ipcc.ch/report/sixth-assessment-report-working-group-3/ reports from \~the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, this amounts to a criminal waste of precious time and money, both of which would be better spent on solving the central, existential problem. The UAE, which signed up to host COP28 in good faith, is doubtless braced for the slings and arrows that will come its way, and is to be applauded for nevertheless sticking its head above the parapet. But now it also finds itself in the invidious position of being expected to pick up the ball that was dropped in Egypt while simultaneously trying to progress the loss-and-damage agenda. It simply can\' t be done. Addressing climate change demands a singleminded, united global effort, and loss and damage is a divisive, politically motivated distraction. At the very least, this issue must be cut out from the truly urgent business of the Conference of the Parties to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, and handed over to a completely different body, with no overlapping engagement. Between now and next year the UN and the Parties to the Convention need to get a grip. If they don\' t, COP28 in the UAE will be swamped by this self-defeating nonsense, and all of us \- including the aggrieved nations of the Global South \- will pay the price. This article was provided by \~ HYPERLINK Syndication Bureau , which holds copyright. Jonathan Gornall is a British journalist, formerly with The Times, who has lived and worked in the Middle East and is now based in the UK.\~Follow him on Twitter @JonathanGornall . \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong11" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="EQS TodayIR"source=" " >
EQS-News: Worksport The New Cold War ? How One Company Is Preparing For Potential Supply Chain Issues Resulting From US-China Tensions 07.10.2022 / 14:00 CET/CESTThe issuer is solely responsible for the content of this announcement.From Moscow to Beijing, the geopolitical situation today is stark. Chinese leader Xi Jinping recently with Russian President Vladimir Putin in Xi?s first meeting outside China since the pandemic began ? a move suggesting a strengthening relationship between the two world powers.The Ukrainian-Russian war, and the new Cold War between the West and Russia, have thrown the West into consternation. An energy crisis looms over Europe, meanwhile, tensions continue to develop in the relationship between the United States and China. Rifts are in the aftermath of House Speaker Nancy Pelosi?s visit to Taiwan, and fears are mounting that Taiwan could become the next Ukraine. One consequence of the conflict over Taiwan has been the Chinese withdrawal from climate target agreements. Despite the collaboration promised between the U.S. and China at the 2021 United Nations Climate Change Conference (known as COP26), Pelosi?s early August visit to Taiwan led to China threatening to not cooperate on climate policies ? despite producing 27% of global greenhouse gases. Relationships have also become strained as a result of accusations of human rights violations and genocide being leveled against China for its treatment of the Uyghur minority in its Xinjiang region.Is it Time To Move US Production Out Of China?If the continued souring of the American-Chinese relationship is not enough to make foreign manufacturers nervous, there are also signs that the Chinese economy is starting to wobble. The is dropping out of the Chinese housing market, presaging a collapse that could cause tremors reminiscent of the 2008 U.S. housing crisis. Real estate currently accounts for one-third of economic activity in China ? the share of real estate in the U.S. ? and a crisis there would cause shock waves across the entire Chinese economy.What all this means for future geopolitical relations between China and America remains to be seen, but it will most likely raise concerns for companies whose production is located in China ? with the COVID-19 pandemic having highlighted the global supply chain issues that could result from disruptions to operations there. Companies ranging from Apple Inc. (NASDAQ: APPL) and adidas AG (OTCQX: ADDDF) to Tesla Inc. (NASDAQ: TSLA) and Target Corp. (NYSE: TGT) have large manufacturing facilities in China. With the future currently cloudy, how will investors maintain confidence if this economic and political uncertainty continues?Many companies are starting to talk about moving back to American soil, with the construction of new factories in the U.S. by 116% in the past year.Leading The Pack In The Return To US ShoresOne company in the energy and automotive space that is preparing in advance and is Worksport Ltd. (NASDAQ: WKSP). Providing solutions in renewable energy, Worksport and its subsidiaries take their patented designs through production in an effort to innovate in the energy and automotive industries. Worksport?s subsidiaries include Terravis Energy Inc. (Latin for Earth and force), which produces the Non-Parasitic Electric Vehicle (NPEVTM) charging platform that it hopes will spark interest in the electric vehicle industry. Worksport?s SOLIS (Spanish for sun) tonneau covers for trucks function as on-the-go solar chargers for its COR battery systems. To prepare for the challenges that could soon be posed for manufacturers in China, the company will soon begin manufacturing its products in America. It purchased a new, 222,000-square-foot facility in Buffalo, New York, recently and plans to have the factory up and running at full capacity by Christmas. No matter what happens in the east, Worksport is working to ensure that it is positioned for continued growth and operations can continue as usual in any circumstance.?With all the manufacturing issues plaguing multiple industries today, from supply chain issues to the risk of IP [intellectual property] being compromised, on-shoring production to a facility we own is the next logical step in Worksport?s growth strategy,? Worksport CEO Steven Rossi said. Excited by the prospect of new jobs and innovative technology, New York?s Empire State Development Acting Commissioner, President and CEO-designate Hope Knight said, ?As Worksport?s first U.S. production facility, this project will solidify the company?s investment within New York State, help foster innovation and green technology and provide the potential for even more jobs in the future.?To learn more about Worksport, visit its . Worksport Ltd. was founded in 2011 with a passion for making products better, simpler, and more beautiful, bringing innovation to an innovation-less market. Starting as a producer of tonneau covers for pickup trucks in the United States and Canada, Worksport has since evolved to position itself as an innovator in its space. Over the past 5 years, Worksport has been working on its hybrid energy system named TerraVis, a portable solar power generation system capable of forming personal microgrids for pickup trucks. Developing the technology that makes up the TerraVis system is the first step in the Company?s strategy to increase its market share through innovation in the auto forest and clean tech sectors.This post contains sponsored advertising content. This content is for informational purposes only and not intended to be investing advice.Contact DetailsWorksport+1 888-554-8789News Source: News Direct 07.10.2022 CET/CEST Dissemination of a Corporate News, transmitted by EQS - a service of EQS Group AG.The issuer is solely responsible for the content of this announcement.The EQS Distribution Services include Regulatory Announcements, Financial/Corporate News and Press Releases.Archive at HYPERLINK http://www.eqs-news.com www.eqs-news.com {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell Language: English {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell Company: Worksport {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell United States {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell ISIN: US98139Q2093 {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell EQS News ID: 1459411 {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell End of News EQS News Service {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell 1459411\~\~07.10.2022\~CET/CEST \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong12" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 5, 2022 Saturday 3:30 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
It is 28 years since the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change entered force, with the simple but fantastically complex ambition of  preventing dangerous human interference with the climate system. Since then, 198 countries have ratified the convention, and on Sunday their representatives will gather at Sharm El Sheikh, Egypt, for the 27th Conference of the Parties, or COP27 . With some 30,000 delegates flying in from all over the world, this will be among the largest climate-change conferences ever staged. But is there any point? Last month, the UN Environment Program (UNEP) published its 13th\~ HYPERLINK http://unep.org/resources/emissions-gap-report-2022 Emissions Gap Report Whether it will be heard or not will become apparent over the coming two weeks in Sharm El Sheikh.  Every year, wrote UNEP executive director Inger Andersen\~in her foreword to the report,  the negative impacts of climate change become\~more intense.  Every year, they bring more misery and pain to hundreds of millions of people across the globe. Every year, they become more a problem of the here and now, as well as a warning of tougher consequences to come. The world is, she added,  in a climate emergency, and yet  still nations procrastinate. At the end of October, a series of fresh reports confirmed that, despite all the hot air generated by COP after COP, the global climate crisis continues to get worse. Among the more sobering was the annual\~ HYPERLINK https://public.wmo.int/en/media/press-release/more-bad-news-planet-greenhouse-gas-levels-hit-new-highs greenhouse gas bulletin There is, of course, the great puzzle of our time \- how to maintain energy supplies while transitioning to renewables. But it is clear from depressing facts such as these that there is no serious concerted effort under way to solve it. After the\~ HYPERLINK https://unfccc.int/process-and-meetings/the-paris-agreement/the-paris-agreement Paris Agreement \~in 2015, in which nations agreed on the goal of limiting global warming to well below 2 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels, nations submitted Nationally Determined Contributions, detailed commitments on how they planned to do their bit to help the world hit that goal. Those NDCs were updated after COP26 in Glasgow and, after totting up the various pledges, UNEP has concluded that, quite frankly, they needn\' t have bothered. The problem is this. In setting out its plans, almost every country has failed to pull its weight, presumably in the hope of maintaining economic advantage while other nations step forward to bear a greater share of the necessary reductions in global emissions. The result, says UNEP, is that there has been only very limited progress in reducing the  immense  gap between the emissions reductions promised and the emissions reductions needed to achieve the temperature goal of the Paris Agreement by 2030. The bottom line is this: To stand even the slightest chance of limiting global warming to the ideal 1.5 degrees Celsius increase identified at Paris, annual global greenhouse gas emissions must now be reduced by an astonishing 45% in just eight years. Think about everything you do that contributes to greenhouse gas emissions \- driving, flying, lighting, heating or cooling your home, watching television, operating the washing machine, and so on \- and imagine doing 45% less of all those things by 2030. Now imagine the country in which you live doing the same, reducing all\~transport, agriculture, energy production by the same amount. This is a near-impossible target. And even if the world\' s wealthy developed nations did start to invest more urgently and realistically in alternative energy, any emissions reductions they might achieve are going to be offset by emerging economies that are burning increasing amounts of fossil fuels as they strive to attain the same advantages that the West has enjoyed since the dawn of the industrial revolution. Instead of the 45% reduction in emissions now necessary by 2030, even if every nation delivered fully on its existing\~NDC pledges, the total reduction in carbon emissions achievable by 2030 is a pathetic, all-life-on-earth-threatening 3.6%. Clearly, commitment is lacking. At COP26, all 193 national parties to the Paris Agreement agreed to revise and strengthen their climate plans. The fact that only 24 have done so is, in the masterfully understated\~ HYPERLINK https://unfccc.int/news/climate-plans-remain-insufficient-more-ambitious-action-needed-now view of Simon Stiell Speaking last week, Stiell added:  We are still nowhere near the scale and pace of emission reductions required to put us on track toward a 1.5 degrees Celsius world. It is hard to avoid the conclusion that pretty much every COP since 1994 has been little more than a festival of pledges, an opportunity for politicians to promise big on the world stage and deliver small back home. COP27 on November 18, Egypt must be given the benefit of the doubt. This week, in an interview with\~ HYPERLINK New Scientist magazine COP27 would be different, that it would be a  reality check, putting pressure on countries to deliver on existing promises before making new ones. This article was provided by \~ HYPERLINK Syndication Bureau , which holds copyright. Jonathan Gornall is a British journalist, formerly with The Times, who has lived and worked in the Middle East and is now based in the UK.\~Follow him on Twitter\~@JonathanGornall . \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong13" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="EQS TodayIR"source=" " >
DGAP-News: Pond Technologies Holdings Inc. Slashing Methane Emissions 30% By 2030 Could Be Key To Achieving Net Zero Targets ? Here?s What AgTech Companies Are Doing To Help 10.08.2022 / 14:35 The issuer is solely responsible for the content of this announcement., creating atmospheric concentrations that are 2\'bd times denser than preindustrial levels.About 25% of that methane comes from the agricultural sector alone ? mostly from gassy cows whose .With an estimated worldwide and each cow belching approximately of methane each year, those burps add up. President Biden has even supported a bill that would tackle this issue, , due to its impact on the environment. That?s why companies like () are exploring cost-effective, scalable ways to cut agricultural methane emissions and help nations around the world meet their Global Methane Pledge.Nations Need To Cut Methane Emissions If They Hope To Hit Net Zero GoalsAs part of the Global Methane Pledge launched at the 2021 United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP26) last year, 111 countries collectively responsible for 45% of methane emissions committed to reduce those emissions to 30% below 2020 levels by 2030.Methane is one of the most potent greenhouse gasses in Earth?s atmosphere ? it has over the warming power of carbon dioxide and accounts for as much as of the global temperature increase scientists expect to see in the next 20 years.Because of this enhanced warming effect, cutting 170 Mts, 30% of 2020 levels, in methane emissions would be the equivalent of scrubbing of carbon dioxide emissions from the atmosphere per year.If the global temperature increase surpasses 1.5 C above its pre industrial average, scientists warn of the following could occur:Extreme heat events ? like the recent record-breaking heat wave that swept Europe this summer, sparking wildfires in four countries and contributing to over ? that used to happen once a decade or less would happen more than four times per decade.The risk of severe flooding will more than double for 73% of the world?s population. The total forest area at risk of forest fires would nearly double in the United States alone and fires could become about 37% more frequent. An average of more than 114 million people each month will be exposed to extreme drought conditions that could ruin food crops and make already-scarce drinking water even harder to come by. Curbing Agricultural Emissions Might Hinge On Discovering An Anti-Methane Diet For LivestockMethane in agriculture is produced primarily by livestock ? especially cows ? as their digestive process as a byproduct that is released when they burp. That means tackling methane levels for farmers means devising a way to make cows burp less.The approach that?s made the most progress is changing cows? diet. Royal DSM (OTCQX: KDSKF), for example, has already shown some success with this approach using a feed additive called Bovaer that?s been shown to reduce methane from burping by .Algae May Hold Another Key To Slashing Methane EmissionsIn April, Pond Technologies with Cross River Infrastructure Partners LLC and Livalta/AB Agri, a subsidiary of Associated British Foods plc (LSE: ABF) to identify algae strains that could reduce methane emissions when added to livestock feed. The research partnership could be a promising one as of red macroalgae (seaweed) found that it could cut methane emissions by up to 80% when added to cattle feed. However, scaling the production of seaweed would require turning large swaths of shorelines into seaweed farms, which could end up having its own environmental impacts on ocean and coastal ecosystems.That?s why Pond is partnering with these companies to explore microalgae strains that could offer the same methane-busting benefits as seaweed. Pond has already deployed what it reports is an innovative, scalable that allows producers to grow microalgae in tanks where the conditions are optimized for algae growth.The tanks also help cut CO2 emissions themselves. Because algae use CO2 to grow, the proprietary Pond tanks can take the raw stack gas from power plants, factories and other high-emission facilities and convert it into clean, breathable air.The goal, then, is to identify microalgae strains that can be grown in these CO2-scrubbing platforms so that the companies can harvest them and turn them into feed additives. That way, each batch is pulling double duty: scrubbing emissions as it grows in the tank and curbing emissions again after it?s fed to livestock.Featured photo by Jan Koetsier on About Pond TechnologiesLocated in Markham, Ontario, Pond has developed a proprietary system that can profitably transform CO2 into valuable products. Its Pond Carbon business focuses on absorbing greenhouse gas emissions, transforming these into food, feed, and nutraceutical ingredients. Pond recently added a Biotech division focused on the growth of unique strains of microalgae to be used as a reproductive medium for the expression of human antibodies and proteins.For more information, please visit This post contains sponsored advertising content. This content is for informational purposes only and is not intended to be investing advice.Contact DetailsPond Technologies, Inc.Grant SmithBenzingaBenzinga Brand StudioCompany WebsiteNews Source: News Direct 10.08.2022 Dissemination of a Corporate News, transmitted by DGAP - a service of EQS Group AG.The issuer is solely responsible for the content of this announcement.The DGAP Distribution Services include Regulatory Announcements, Financial/Corporate News and Press Releases.Archive at HYPERLINK http://www.dgap.de www.dgap.de {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell Language: English {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell Company: Pond Technologies Holdings Inc. {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell United States {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell ISIN: CA73238C1041 {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell EQS News ID: 1417723 {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell End of News DGAP News Service {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell 1417723\~\~10.08.2022\~ \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong14" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 30, 2022 Wednesday 3:06 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
The recent COP27 On the other hand, however, critics say that the conference failed to agree on the mechanisms for reaching net zero emissions. The final agreement signed by members does not pledge to curb the use of fossil fuels, as suggested by India and the European Union. However, a deep dive into the 12-month action plan agreed at COP27 shows that it does contain some new ideas which many observers have overlooked.\~ The document includes plans to ramp up hydrogen production for cleaner energy, as well as a package of actions to increase the supply of low-carbon material for public infrastructure projects. In total, the sectors included in the plan account for more than 50% of global greenhouse gas emissions. As well as hydrogen production, sectors such as agriculture, road transport, and power all feature. The HYPERLINK https://www.smartenergydecisions.com/research/2022/11/21/the-breakthrough-agenda-report-2022 Breakthrough Agenda HYPERLINK 7-9% of all fossil fuel-based carbon-dioxide emissions. Results will be presented at COP28 in Dubai next November, where delegates hope to see a significant boost to the credibility and transparency of the green steel sector. Standardizing steel A program of private and public procurement of green industrial goods is also intended to incentivize investment in green steel to bring down manufacturing costs in the long term. Dedicated Climate Investment Funds will be set up to help drive the transition in polluting industries like steel. Still, the scale of the challenge ahead is enormous. The International Energy Agency alongside energy research consultancy Wood Mackenzie estimate that a total investment of about US$1.4 trillion will be needed to decarbonize the iron and steel sector by 2050. Existing methods As it stands, state and market mechanisms to mobilize capital toward innovation and development in green metallurgy have failed to move the needle. The majority of investment in such projects come either from venture capital firms or from existing industry players investigating greener ways to manufacture the gray metal. The gradual replacement of blast furnaces with electric-arc furnaces (EAFs) is already under way in some companies. EAF-based mills produce 28% of the world\' s steel, but they account for only 8% of the CO 2 generated by the steel industry. EAFs produce less than 1.5 tons of greenhouse gas equivalent emissions per ton of steel, compared with 2.3 tons in blast furnaces. China, which produces HYPERLINK https://www.e3g.org/news/china-s-crucial-role-in-decarbonising-the-global-steel-sector/ more than 60% of all global emissions from steel production, is now transitioning toward EAFs. Climate-change think-tank E3G HYPERLINK https://www.e3g.org/news/china-s-crucial-role-in-decarbonising-the-global-steel-sector/ says this could help cut Chinese emissions from steel by almost 40% by 2050 relative to 2020 levels. But whereas blast furnaces use iron ore, EAFs need a different raw material: direct reduced iron (DRI), usually in the form of hot briquetted iron (HBI), to facilitate transportation. HBI comprises 90% iron, and has a metallization degree of more than 93% and a density exceeding 5.0 grams per cubic centimeter, which makes it well suited for the production of steel in electric-arc furnaces and converters. Russian mining and metals company Metalloinvest, with an installed capacity of about 4.5 million metric tons of HBI per annum, controls about half of the global market of HBI supplies, according to Midrex 2021 data. The company focuses on green metallurgy and has plans to commission new HBI plants. Zero-carbon steel It is also theoretically possible to produce zero-carbon steel. Sweden\' s SSAB made history in July 2021 when it delivered the world\' s first zero-carbon steel \- made with green hydrogen \- to the Volvo Group. The world\' s first carbon-free steel was made using a technology designed by SSAB along with energy company Vattenfall and iron-ore miner LKAB. SSAB claims that the technology, called HYBRIT, could reduce Sweden\' s total carbon emissions by at least 10%. However, SSAB does not plan to roll out its fossil-fuel-free steel on an industrial scale until 2026, underlining the difficulty of scaling up innovative new carbon-cutting technologies. Luxembourg-based ArcelorMittal, the world\' s largest steel producer, plans to build the world\' s first zero-carbon steel facility in Spain. The plant will run on green hydrogen and renewable energy. However, renewable-energy news site Recharge HYPERLINK https://www.rechargenews.com/energy-transition/world-s-first-large-scale-zero-carbon-steel-plant-will-require-500m-of-public-money/2-1-1042649 reports that the company has asked for \ 500 million (US$517.6 million) of public money to realize the project, highlighting the cost of such installations. Nonetheless, policymakers hope that in the future, markets will reach a tipping point, where industrial-scale low-carbon steel is manufactured on a large enough scale that it becomes the more desirable and commercially viable choice. Regulation, including carbon pricing mechanisms and standardized emissions disclosures, should help to foster quicker uptake. In the short term, however, it falls to manufacturers and investors to redirect resources toward this vital effort. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong15" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 25, 2022 Friday 3:12 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
After a two-year slowdown, tourism is once again booming in the Middle East. As countries lift their Covid-19 restrictions and demand for return tickets, the World Travel and Tourism Council (WTTC) projects that the sector\' s contribution to regional GDP will grow\~ HYPERLINK https://wttc.org/news-article/middle-east-travel-tourism-sector-expected-to-create-3-6-million-new-jobs-within-the-next-decade more than 36% \~in 2022, to more than US$256 billion. While this is undoubtedly great news for countries where tourism accounts for a large share of revenue, there\' s an existential threat to this tourism rebound: climate change. The countries most dependent on tourism are also the very locations most affected by the changing weather. In Jordan, where tourism is one of the top earners of foreign currency and the\~second-largest private-sector employer, accounting for 7.3% of pre-pandemic jobs, drought is exacerbating water scarcity\~in one of the world\' s most water-scarce countries.\~ Searing heat and a historic lack of rain are threatening tourist destinations across Jordan. The Dead Sea, for instance, is shrinking by more than a meter annually, with its shoreline receding and sinkholes growing.\~It\' s not even hyperbole to say that the Dead Sea, which is facing a reduced flow from its tributary, is rapidly dying.\~\~ Climate change is also contributing to decreased water levels in the Jordan River, where Jesus was baptized. Today, upstream water diversions have turned the river into a muddy trickle, much to the chagrin of Christian pilgrims.\~ It works the other way, too. In November 2018, rare torrential rains flooded Petra, Jordan\' s prized tourist attraction and a UNESCO World Heritage Site,\~ HYPERLINK forcing the evacuation While there were no reported deaths in Petra, 13 people \- including two young girls and a rescue diver \- died in other parts of the country. Two weeks earlier, flooding near the Dead Sea\~ HYPERLINK https://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-45983337 killed 21 people , mostly children, when their bus was swept away. In Egypt, meanwhile,\~rising temperatures have damaged some of the famed monuments in Luxor and changed the color of archeological stones. Tourism is the backbone of Egypt\' s economy and is the largest travel and tourism sector in Africa, according to the WTTC. Fortunately, Egypt\' s coral reefs, which are popular with divers,\~have so far been\~ HYPERLINK https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/cop27-host-egypt-red-sea-coral-reefs-resilient-under-stress-2022-10-27/ spared the wrath of climate change The United Nations Office for Disaster Risk Reduction (UNDRR) forecasts a 40% increase\~in the number of weather-related disasters globally over the next decade.\~At last month\' s  A World for Travel forum in Nimes, France, Paola Albrito, the\~ HYPERLINK https://www.undrr.org/news/paola-albrito-appointed-new-director-undrr new director of UNDRR Not only will these disasters upend the lives of millions, they will also wreak havoc on the tourist infrastructure where they strike. Current efforts to mitigate the impact of climate change on the region\' s tourism sector are mixed. On one level, countries have committed to change, with\~ HYPERLINK several plans and strategies Jordan, for example, has a five-year\~ HYPERLINK Green Growth National Action Plan The country has made climate-related gains in other areas, too. It has pioneered a 10-year energy strategy for long-term low-carbon economic growth, and in May, Jordan became the first developing country to build\~ HYPERLINK https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/feature/2022/05/24/countries-on-the-cusp-of-carbon-marketsI digital tools to track emissions Meanwhile, at the recent UN climate talks in Egypt ( COP27 ), regional leaders discussed the need for the industry itself to\~ HYPERLINK https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-11-14/how-tourism-can-hit-net-zero-by-2050-an-unrealistic-but-not-impossible-solution reduce its carbon footprint HYPERLINK https://www.unwto.org/news/unwto-at-cop27-uniting-tourism-around-tangible-climate-action-plans The tourism sector requires a reset But in other ways, climate-change adaptation and mitigation remain an afterthought in the Middle East. Again, Jordan\' s experience is illustrative. Implementation hinges on donor support,\~ HYPERLINK https://jordantimes.com/news/local/climate-change-hit-impoverished-jordanians-hardest-streamlining-funding-process-vital which is scarce . Jordan\' s current\~ HYPERLINK https://www.mota.gov.jo/ebv4.0/root_storage/en/eb_list_page/national_tourism_strategy_en_(release_1.0)_20.12.2021.pdf national tourism strategy https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/10/3/copper-mine-threatens-jordans-largest-nature-reserve allow copper mining For now, climate change hasn\' t put off tourists to the region. The FIFA World Cup, which started in Qatar this week, is expected to attract\~ HYPERLINK https://fastcompanyme.com/impact/fifa-world-cup-2022-will-score-big-for-qatar-but-is-it-ready-for-a-million-fans/ more than a million visitors HYPERLINK 11% annually by 2030 Even world leaders\~ HYPERLINK https://www.arabnews.com/node/2202721/middle-east flocked to Egypt\' s tourist attractions \~after wrapping up COP27 climate talks in Sharm El Sheikh. But before countries get too comfortable in the post-Covid tourism rebound, governments must make the connection between climate change and economic survival. The Middle East has already seen what a pandemic can do to the tourism industry. We can\' t afford to be burned again. This article was provided by\~ HYPERLINK http://www.syndicationbureau.com/ Syndication Bureau \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong16" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="EQS TodayIR"source=" " >
EQS-News: Chariot Ltd Chariot discusses latest green hydrogen project in Morocco from COP27 07.11.2022 / 15:54 CET/CESTThe issuer is solely responsible for the content of this announcement.Contact DetailsProactiveProactive UK Ltd+44 20 7989 0813News Source: News Direct 07.11.2022 CET/CEST Dissemination of a Corporate News, transmitted by EQS News - a service of EQS Group AG.The issuer is solely responsible for the content of this announcement.The EQS Distribution Services include Regulatory Announcements, Financial/Corporate News and Press Releases.Archive at HYPERLINK http://www.eqs-news.com www.eqs-news.com {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell Language: English {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell Company: Chariot Ltd {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell United States {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell ISIN: GG00B2R9PM06 {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell EQS News ID: 1481039 {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell End of News EQS News Service {\rtlch\alang1025\afs24\ltrch\fs24\lang1033\langnp1033\langfe1033\langfenp1033\cell 1481039\~\~07.11.2022\~CET/CEST \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong17" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 2, 2022 Wednesday 4:10 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
Hong Kong is HYPERLINK https://www.hkma.gov.hk/eng/news-and-media/press-releases/2022/11/20221101-4/ hosting this week a much-anticipated investment summit that brings together heads of the world\' s top banks and other big names in finance. These  Wall Street titans from more than 100 major global monetary institutions were called on to tackle HYPERLINK https://www.hkma.gov.hk/eng/news-and-media/insight/2022/09/20220929/ three sets of challenges and opportunities in economy, technology and sustainability. So many influential industry leaders \- \~collectively able to mobilize trillions of dollars \- gathered in one forum. So much potential for meaningful action.\~ While it was encouraging to see the financial sector\' s role in addressing the climate crisis acknowledged by the Hong Kong Monetary Authority as a HYPERLINK key focus area , it is likely that the event itself has been limited to discussion and networking. If so, such a  business-as-usual approach represents a wasted opportunity. We need to look no further than recent headlines to see why: from floods in Pakistan a few months ago to Tropical Storm Nalgae raging toward Hong Kong itself this week, no corner of the world is immune to the growing intensity of the climate crisis and the mounting challenges posed by HYPERLINK https://livingplanet.panda.org/ biodiversity loss . With each disaster HYPERLINK https://www.gfdrr.org/en/breaking-link-between-extreme-weather-and-extreme-poverty costing the world economy billions every year , the risks of inaction for all life on this living planet are greater than any challenge we\' ve ever faced. It https://www.un.org/en/un75/climate-crisis-race-we-can-win threatens to sink entire cities, displace and starve billions, fuel further geopolitical tensions, push millions into poverty, and multiply a whole host of other global challenges.\~ The Asia-Pacific region is already HYPERLINK https://www.unescap.org/kp/2022/asia-and-pacific-sdg-progress-report-2022#:~:text=unescap%40un.org-,Asia%20and%20the%20Pacific%20SDG%20Progress%20Report,Widening%20disparities%20amid%20COVID%2D19&text=This%20report%20analyses%20progress%20towards,vulnerabilities%20among%20different%20population%20groups. 35 years behind the commitment to achieve all 17 Sustainable Development Goals, faces a minimum of HYPERLINK https://www.campaignfornature.org/environmental-groups-call-on-rich-nations-to-provide-at-least-60-b-annually-to-address-biodiversity-loss US$60 billion in deficits HYPERLINK https://climatechampions.unfccc.int/how-to-address-asia-pacifics-biodiversity-crisis-and-encourage-nature-positive-growth/#:~:text=Asia%20Pacific%20is%20rich%20in,will%20have%20an%20unimaginable%20impact. as much as 63% ($19 trillion) of the region\' s global GDP is at risk \- a much higher share than the global average \- \~from nature-related losses in the region.\~ None of this is good for business (or anyone). This is what needs to happen, and it doesn\' t involve reinventing the wheel. We can navigate beyond  https://www.hkma.gov.hk/eng/news-and-media/insight/2022/09/20220929/ the uncertainties brought by rising interest rates and the risk of stagnation  and accelerate economic growth by channeling investments back to nature. As https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/feature/2022/09/07/world-bank-group-exceeds-new-climate-finance-target-31-7-billion-in-funding-for-climate-action several leaders in the financial sector have shown, investing in nature is not mutually exclusive to financial growth and development. According to HYPERLINK https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/companies-markets/nature-based-solutions-could-yield-us43-trillion-in-economic-value-by-2030 some studies , nature-based opportunities could deliver $4.3 trillion of annual economic value and generate 232 million jobs in Asia and the Pacific by 2030.\~ To take advantage of these opportunities, we need to include and invest in the livelihoods of our primary partners in any nature-based financial opportunity: indigenous peoples and local communities (IPLCs), particularly women and youth, who have centuries of experience in understanding how to benefit sustainably from nature. With 32% of global land and associated inland waters HYPERLINK https://wwflac.awsassets.panda.org/downloads/report_the_state_of_the_indigenous_peoples_and_local_communities_lands_and_territories_1.pdf owned or governed by IPLCs We cannot go on having low-stakes discussions to  inspire change. What we need now are concrete actions that channel resources back into ecosystem regeneration, nature-based solutions, sustainable development and alternative livelihoods. We already know that money talks. Swiftly following this week\' s financial summit in Hong Kong is the high-profile https://unfccc.int/cop27 UN Climate Change Conference ( HYPERLINK https://unfccc.int/cop27 COP27 ) in Egypt, starting on Sunday, and then the HYPERLINK https://www.unep.org/events/conference/un-biodiversity-conference-cop-15 UN Biodiversity Conference (COP15) It is imperative that global leaders take advantage of these opportunities and step up, to transform economies and value natural resources. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong18" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="December 5, 2022 Monday 8:41 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
Warming seas and fast-eroding coastlines, destructive storm surges, and polluted water sources are the tip of the iceberg for smaller Pacific Islands facing extreme weather and climate change. For the 2.5 million people in the small island Pacific states, the onslaught of the climate crisis is a visible and daily reality.\~ The numbers being attached to growing economic losses, including damage to infrastructure, and food, energy, and water loss, are getting into figures that move from millions to billions. Add to this the costs of loss of life, schooling, epidemic spread, and displacement.\~ All of which are pushing island ecosystems beyond the limits of adaptation. For low-lying Pacific atoll nations, the impacts are existential. It is estimated that tidal waters will flood half of the land area of Funafuti, Tuvalu\' s capital, by 2050. By 2100, 95% of its lands will be flooded by routine high tides, pollute all drinking water, and destroy basic food security and energy supply. We have heard all the Pacific Island leaders repeatedly state their case \- while their countries are experiencing some of the worst impacts of a warming planet, these nations are responsible for a negligible fraction of greenhouse gas emissions.\~ They are not sitting passively, awaiting the worst. Through grit and resilience \- built on decades of struggles \- many Pacific nations have developed blueprints to combat the climate crisis, and measure the loss and damages caused by climate change.\~ This has required options for accelerated energy transitions, applications of new technologies, and innovation. Vanuatu is HYPERLINK expanding energy access https://twitter.com/Tuvalu_MJCFA/status/1597035909655896064 creating a digital version of the country . Youth are stepping up. It is inspiring to see groups such as the Pacific Islands Students Fighting Climate Change making their voices heard, and to see youth-led campaigns have legal advice issued on climate change by the United Nations\' International Court of Justice. Last month at COP27 in Egypt, we saw the power of this collective advocacy, with the establishment of a Loss and Damage Fund. While the details must still be worked out, its establishment is a milestone in 30 years of climate talks. Such a resource could provide much-needed financial assistance to developing countries in the faster recovery and rebuilding after climate-related disasters. Costs and benefits No country can afford to sit out the fight against climate change, especially the large emitter nations and multinational corporations. Much more must be done by the rest of the world to ensure indusrtial-era global warming stays below 1.5 degrees Celsius. All countries and carbon-heavy industries must accelerate away from fossil fuels, scale investments in renewable energy, and share the technologies needed to rapidly advance adaptation. At the heart of this debate and action lies the issue of climate justice. We must all be able to recognize the disproportionate impacts of climate change on those least responsible for causing it. And we must actively ensure no countries or peoples are left behind in pursuit of a more sustainable, and more just, net-zero future. At the UN Development Program (UNDP), we are working with 16 countries in the Pacific to support them to enhance their climate ambitions. These are expressed in their revised Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) to reducing greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. The lens of climate justice, which puts those most vulnerable at the center of the choices and decisions being made, is critical to this effort.\~ The UNDP\' s policy paper on  HYPERLINK https://www.undp.org/publications/environmental-justice-securing-our-right-clean-healthy-and-sustainable-environment Environmental Justice Such NDC ambitions can and must be realized by national and international stakeholders joining together \- with the shared political commitment and resources to make it happen. The costs of climate action are high; however, the costs of inaction are much, much higher. Developing countries will have to pursue all avenues of financing and developed countries and investors must make good on their financial commitments, including through old and new financing instruments that significantly reduce the cost of lending. While Pacific Island nations continue to push for meaningful climate action and climate justice, those responsible for the lion\' s share of GHG emissions, must accept their responsibility and respond positively. Our future \- in this Age of Humans \- depends on it.\~ \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong19" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 21, 2022 Monday 5:08 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
The story of renewable energy across the Middle East and North Africa (MENA) is usually told from one viewpoint: the sun that beats down relentlessly on the region\' s deserts. Solar is indeed a tremendous source of power and increasingly made to move electrons. But wind also blows across the Middle East\' s plains, hills and seas \- and mega-projects are harnessing it. The MENA region actually began using modern wind power on a commercial scale a decade before solar, with projects in Morocco, Egypt and Israel and at Tafila in Jordan, where turbines languidly turn near the ancient castle of Kerak. But solar really took off from 2010 as costs fell. The cheapest electricity in the world is generated from solar in the United Arab Emirates and Saudi Arabia. World-scale projects such as the largest single-site solar farm at al-Dhafra in Abu Dhabi, weighing in at 2 gigawatts, and two of the biggest multi-project locations, the Mohammed bin Rashid solar park in Dubai (5GW) and Benban in Egypt (1.8GW), grab the headlines. Smaller-scale solar panels can also be placed on homes and factories. Last year, the region generated 20.5 terawatt-hours of solar electricity, as against 15.6TWh of wind, nearly all from Egypt and Morocco. By comparison, Morocco, one of the region\' s smaller electricity users, consumed 41TWh from all sources. While not as consistent as northwestern Europe, there are excellent wind resources in the MENA region. Southern Morocco, the areas around the Gulfs of Suez and Aqaba in Egypt, Jordan and northwestern Saudi Arabia, southern Egypt, and the southeast coast of Oman are all very windy. Parts of Libya, southern Tunisia, the Algerian Sahara, inland Iran and Kuwait also have strong winds. In contrast to much of Europe, the region has wide-open spaces where wind farms are not blocked by community opposition. Egypt, host of the\~ HYPERLINK https://cop27.eg/#/ COP27 climate change \~meeting, is capitalizing most of all. With 1.59GW currently installed, 0.75GW under construction and 1.6GW planned, it signed a swath of projects in recent weeks. These include memoranda of understanding with\~ HYPERLINK https://see.news/egypt-norway-sign-mou-to-implement-5-gw-wind-energy-project Norwegian developer Scatec HYPERLINK https://www.thenationalnews.com/climate/cop27/2022/11/08/uae-and-egypt-to-build-one-of-worlds-largest-wind-farms/ with the UAE \~clean-energy vehicle Masdar for 10GW, and with\~ HYPERLINK https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/saudi-acwa-power-signs-mou-10-gw-wind-project-egypt-2022-11-01/ Saudi power developer These would be the second-largest wind farms in the world: Only the 20GW Gansu in China is bigger. Acwa is already building a 1.1GW wind farm at Gebel El Zeit on the Gulf of Suez, which will be the region\' s biggest when it starts up in late 2026. Egypt\' s projected total of 24GW would be the seventh-largest national capacity in the world on current figures. In addition, Egypt, Saudi Arabia, Oman, Morocco and Mauritania will require huge wind farms to drive their planned green hydrogen projects, which use renewable electricity to electrolyze water. Pluses and minuses Wind power under MENA conditions is likely to be more expensive than solar, even if Saudi Arabia did secure a very competitive tariff of 2.13 US cents per kilowatt-hour for its first wind farm at Dumat al-Jandal (the lowest solar contract in the region was at 1.03 cents per kilowatt-hour). Wind power also takes longer to build, and output is not as predictable beyond a few days. But wind has several advantages. Most obviously, it blows at night \- often more strongly than during the day. This makes it complementary to solar power. It is particularly useful on hot early autumn evenings, when people need air-conditioning even after sunset. MENA solar power achieves a capacity factor \- a source\' s average output as a proportion of its peak output \- of around 20% over the course of a year, allowing for night-time and seasons. Egyptian wind power manages 53%. Solar and wind in the best locations can have a combined capacity factor above 70%. This high capacity factor is particularly important for the economics of green hydrogen, which depend on maximizing the electrolyzer\' s running hours while using the cheapest possible electricity. This explains why Egypt, Morocco, Oman and Saudi Arabia have taken the regional lead in renewable hydrogen, as have other windy coastal desert countries worldwide such as Australia, Chile and Namibia. And the higher capacity factors mean that a gigawatt of wind displaces more gas or oil consumption than solar does. Ambitious deployment of wind could see Egypt\' s requirement for gas to make electricity dropping in the 2030s, as the country\' s own production declines and net-zero carbon targets draw closer. A few vital questions remain. First, where will Egypt in particular put the turbines for its enormous planned projects? The windy corridors around Sinai are relatively constrained and flanked by mountains. Areas further south on the Red Sea coast, or well inland with more difficult logistics, will have to be considered. The latest agreements do not publicly specify a location or a timeline. Second, will the region venture offshore, as northwestern Europe has done so successfully? This brings stronger and more consistent winds, and a much larger area to develop, albeit at higher costs. Third, do current wind announcements overlap with green hydrogen projects? If not, the requirement for wind will be much bigger \- and the competition for good sites and equipment more intense. Fourth, can the less blustery MENA countries, particularly the UAE, Qatar and Bahrain, make economic use of turbines optimized for slower wind speeds? And fifth, will the other windy and power-short countries that have so far made little progress, such as Iraq, Kuwait, Libya and Tunisia, start adopting the technology? If these questions can be answered positively, the turning turbine as much as the shimmering solar panel will symbolize MENA\' s energy transition. This article was provided by \~ HYPERLINK http://www.syndicationbureau.com/ Syndication Bureau , which holds copyright. Follow this writer on Twitter @robinenergy . \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong20" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 10, 2022 Thursday 4:45 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
As we all strive to recover from the twin impacts of Covid-19 pandemic and the Russian invasion of Ukraine, charting a new growth path that is more resilient to shocks, more inclusive and less resource-intensive has become a top priority. The need for a green transition is high on the global policy agenda and an essential element in the ongoing negotiations at the UN Climate Change Conference in Egypt ( COP27 ) from November 6-18.\~ Among the various measures put forward to achieve this ambition, enhancing energy efficiency is well recognized as a viable way to deliver quick wins on multiple fronts, from reaching bold climate commitments to ensuring national energy security. Energy efficiency can contribute to the nationally determined commitments (NDCs) under the 2015 Paris Agreement for reducing domestic greenhouse gas emissions and reducing air pollution for the benefit of everybody\' s health. It results in using less energy to reach the same outcome by optimizing performance and cutting down on energy waste. This is achieved by adopting better practices, and investing in technology, designs and materials, contributing directly to easing pressure on the environment, and reducing production costs, allowing more space for improved sustainability, competitiveness, and economic growth.\~ Energy efficiency is also a key foundation for green growth and sustainable development. For households, energy saved lowers energy bills, making savings available for other spending priorities. For businesses, this means reduced costs, increased competitiveness, and better image, which would serve as competitive edge to attract more investment. Energy efficiency, in this sense, contributes to greening value chains, opening opportunities to gain further access to global markets. Cambodia\' s response Energy efficiency is an important element of Cambodia\' s NDCs and its energy security, which in the light of the impacts of the Ukraine war has become ever more important. Although not a direct victim of the energy crisis, Cambodia has recognized the need to be energy secure for decreasing its vulnerability to external shocks. The debt crises in some of Cambodia\' s neighboring countries, for instance, could exacerbate vulnerability by disrupting supply chains and affecting energy import prices. Cambodia is cognizant of the need to be less dependent on energy imports and less affected by volatile fossil-fuel prices, for which investment in renewable energy and energy efficiency would mitigate the effects.\~ So how can we accelerate energy efficiency?\~ Initiatives such as the HYPERLINK https://cinea.ec.europa.eu/programmes/life/clean-energy-transition_en LIFE (L\' Instrument Financier pour l\' Environnement) Clean Energy Transition Program of the European Union seek to support development of best practice in energy efficiency addressing behavioral, market, and regulatory barriers to energy efficiency. In Cambodia, among other priorities, the government seeks to promote energy efficiency in buildings. In a pilot scheme funded by the Cambodia Climate Change Alliance, the first Cambodia Energy Efficiency Competition recognized last month 22 buildings belonging to 14 companies for achieving energy savings of 9% on average, with the top performer reaching 36% of savings. This was achieved without any investment in new equipment, appliances, or retrofits. The competition relied purely on the commitment and engagement of building users, including offices, commercial spaces, public buildings and warehouses. This contest also demonstrated a high level of enthusiasm among Cambodian youth, with six participating public universities. It is to be hoped that such initiatives will be replicated and scaled up to reach a critical mass of public and private entities and promote energy-sensitive behavior as standard practice.\~ To accelerate change, investments will be needed. Mechanisms are being put in place by governments and the private sector. In Cambodia for instance, the United Nations Development Program (UNDP) partnered with EuroCham, the official chamber of the European business community in the kingdom, to support a more favorable regulatory framework for energy services companies (ESCOs), providing expertise and financing solutions for clients to implement energy efficiency measures without large upfront capital investments. In the garment, footwear and travel-goods industry, the European Union works in partnership with relevant ministries, the Garment Manufacturers Association of Cambodia (GMAC) and brands to support the adoption of energy efficient technologies and practices. For the private sector to invest, clear policy signals are essential. For example, Cambodia\' s recently approved Power Development Plan considers energy efficiency in its scenarios, and likewise the National Energy Efficiency Policy to be issued by the end of this year. Other key measures under consideration include energy efficiency standards for buildings and key electrical appliances, energy audits, and ESCO market development. These policies, regulations, and standards will provide a clear framework and targets for acceleration of energy efficiency in Cambodia.\~ Prioritizing the adoption of these measures will put Cambodia on track to achieve sustainable economic growth that is equitable with socio-economic gains. As long-term development partners, we welcome Cambodia\' s commitments and progress to date in this direction and stand ready to support the government of Cambodia and the private sector in this important endeavor. The Cambodia Climate Change Alliance is a partnership funded by the European Union and Sweden and implemented by the UNDP, the National Council for Sustainable Development and the Ministry of Environment. It provides support for the country\' s national climate action agenda, including strategies, legislation, mobilization of public and private climate finance and funding for innovative adaptation and mitigation initiatives. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong21" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 11, 2022 Friday 7:14 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
The US midterms have drawn global attention because of their potential to affect the remainder of President Joe Biden\' s term in office and his relationships with the rest of the world. Because of the type of Republicans who have been elected and their smaller-than-expected numbers, the Democratic president\' s foreign policy is likely to be less affected by the midterm results HYPERLINK https://foreignpolicy.com/2022/11/05/us-midterm-elections-foreign-policy-republicans-congress/ than many had expected The results did bring some small but significant gains for the Republican party, but it was not the shellacking for Biden HYPERLINK suffered by former president Barack Obama in 2010 or the HYPERLINK https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-elections-bush-idUSN0747831720061108 thumping received by George W Bush Unlike domestic policies, Biden\' s foreign policy has largely been a continuation of that of his predecessor, Donald Trump, leading Democrats and Republicans to fall into line. But the main difference between Biden and Trump on foreign policy has been the response to the Ukraine war. Top of the agenda for many foreign policy observers will be whether the US\' s commitment to providing support to Ukraine will continue. Since the Russian invasion began in February, Congress has already authorized over $40 billion of military support and https://www.devex.com/news/funding-tracker-who-s-sending-aid-to-ukraine-102887 humanitarian aid to be sent to Ukraine. While members of the congressional hard right, such as Marjorie Taylor Greene, had promised that  https://thehill.com/homenews/house/3719467-marjorie-taylor-greene-under-republicans-not-another-penny-will-go-to-ukraine/ not another penny will go to Ukraine HYPERLINK https://i0.wp.com/asiatimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/000_VD9NM.jpg?resize=780%2C520&ssl=1 Link to Image Opposition to Biden\' s Ukraine policy has mostly come from Trump\' s ultra-right. HYPERLINK According to reports Kevin McCarthy, the Republican likely to HYPERLINK https://www.cbsnews.com/news/kevin-mccarthy-house-speaker-campaign/ replace Nancy Pelosi HYPERLINK https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-10-18/mccarthy-warns-gop-may-cut-back-ukraine-aid-if-party-wins-house might limit the funding available for aid . The extent of this will be dependent on the influence of the more radical figures within the congressional Republican caucus. Another signal is that senior members of the Senate HYPERLINK https://www.foxnews.com/politics/senators-tout-broad-support-ukraine-kyiv-visit-gop-divided-sending-aid recently said that there was strong bipartisan support for Ukraine. Republican senator Rob Portman and Democratic senator Chris Coons traveled to Ukraine to reassure Zelensky. With some Trump loyalists not doing well and moderate Republicans like South Carolina\' s Nancy Mace winning seats, the hardliners may have to back down. Republicans might use their control of the House to exert influence on Biden to change direction on immigration issues. Throughout the campaign, HYPERLINK Republicans have raised immigration They could force Biden to reduce immigration numbers from Central and South America by threatening to withhold funds for Ukraine. In the wake of the midterm results, interestingly Biden has already HYPERLINK https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-11410967/Joe-Biden-pledges-cooperation-phones-Kevin-McCarthy-huddles-Marjorie-Taylor-Greene.html reached across the divide A Republican-controlled House is likely to back Biden\' s China policy. The Biden White House chose to continue the tough China tariffs adopted by the Trump administration, while not emulating some of Trump\' s wild accusations. While in office, Trump HYPERLINK https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-47140128 argued that China was responsible for the loss of US jobs, especially in the manufacturing industry. He also HYPERLINK https://edition.cnn.com/2020/10/02/asia/trump-china-coronavirus-intl-hnk/index.html repeatedly accused China Since taking office in 2021, Biden has retained the tariffs placed on Chinese imports. At a press conference earlier in the year, HYPERLINK https://edition.cnn.com/2022/01/26/politics/china-tariffs-biden-policy/index.html Biden said this was because China had not fulfilled its commitment to the Phase One deal agreed between Beijing and Trump in 2020. As HYPERLINK https://www.cato.org/blog/us-china-phase-one-deal-phase-two-or-time-phase-it-out part of the deal , which brought respite to a trade war between the US and China, the US had agreed to review the tariffs if China substantially increased its imports of US goods. This continued hardline policy and HYPERLINK https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-62951347 Biden\' s pledge to defend HYPERLINK https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/biden-offer-temporary-safe-haven-hong-kong-residents-us-2021-08-05/ administration\' s criticism HYPERLINK https://foreignpolicy.com/2022/10/31/us-midterm-elections-republicans-china-biden-trade-geopolitics-strategy/ Some commentators have suggested HYPERLINK https://i0.wp.com/asiatimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Joe-Biden-Xi-Jinping-China-US.jpg?resize=780%2C429&ssl=1 Link to Image Biden could find it difficult to get congressional ratification for any international agreement that the United States makes at COP27 . Environmental policy \- domestic or foreign \- is one area where Democrats and Republicans differ considerably. Biden reversed Trump\' s withdrawal from HYPERLINK https://unfccc.int/process-and-meetings/the-paris-agreement/the-paris-agreement the Paris climate agreement Biden will find it hard to sign up Republican allies on this issue, despite the claims of former secretary of state John Kerry, Biden\' s climate envoy, that climate negotiations are  HYPERLINK https://www.cnet.com/news/politics/midterms-cant-undo-bidens-climate-action-promises-john-kerry-at-cop27/ not an ideological exercise While Congress has passed a great deal of climate-based legislation, some experts believe that a Republican-controlled Congress would halt any further progress in tackling climate change. Republicans have labeled Biden\' s environmental policy a  HYPERLINK https://www.realclearenergy.org/articles/2021/05/19/president_biden_must_end_the_radical_green_agenda_777860.html radical green agenda https://www.politico.com/news/2022/11/01/house-gop-2023-energy-bill-00063739 within their own party Overall, the weaker showing of the Trump Republicans in these midterms is likely to mean less opposition to Biden\' s foreign policy agenda. Dafydd Townley is Teaching Fellow in International Security, University of Portsmouth This article is republished from The Conversation under a Creative Commons license. Read the original article. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong22" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 5, 2022 Saturday 3:30 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
Representatives of more than 190 countries (including 100 heads of state) are descending on Sharm El Sheikh this weekend for the UN\' s COP27 climate conference. But progress since last year\' s breakthrough agreements at COP26 in Glasgow has been painfully slow.\~ The United Nations Environment Program\' s recent HYPERLINK https://www.unep.org/resources/emissions-gap-report-2022 Emissions Gap Report As global economies look to accelerate their rollout of electric vehicles and low-carbon infrastructure, senior figures from both industry and governments have voiced concerns that resource shortfalls could hinder the green transition. One metal that will be crucial in this respect is copper. Its high conductivity makes it the optimal choice for the wiring, foil, and cables inside electrical systems. No feasible substitutes currently exist, so the production of copper will need to increase drastically to supply this transition from a carbon-intensive energy system to a mineral-intensive one. Demand drivers Eighty percent of copper\' s uses are linked to its property as a conductor, so it follows that the push to electrify our lifestyle will also lead to a surge in the demand for copper.\~ Indeed, a HYPERLINK https://www.spglobal.com/commodityinsights/en/market-insights/latest-news/energy-transition/071422-world-copper-deficit-could-hit-record-demand-seen-doubling-by-2035-s-p-global study by S&P Global finds that by 2050,  transition-related applications are expected to boost overall copper demand to about 50 million metric tons from the current 25 million. Global sales of electric vehicles (EVs) have already grown HYPERLINK https://www.woodmac.com/horizons/red-metal-green-demand-coppers-critical-role-in-achieving-net-zero/ threefold in the last three years. By 2025, they are HYPERLINK https://www.statista.com/statistics/960920/global-electric-vehicle-market-share-by-segment/#:~:text=Electrified%20and%20battery%20electric%20vehicles%20%2D%20global%20sales%202020%2D2025&text=Cars%20with%20an%20electrified%20engine,percent%20of%20worldwide%20car%20sales. expected to account for roughly a quarter of the global car market. This type of vehicle can use more than three times as much copper as a car with an internal-combustion engine. Renewable energy installations are even more copper-intensive. An offshore wind farm uses around HYPERLINK https://www.spglobal.com/commodityinsights/en/market-insights/latest-news/energy-transition/071422-world-copper-deficit-could-hit-record-demand-seen-doubling-by-2035-s-p-global five times the amount of copper per megawatt needed for hydrocarbon-fueled power plants. Solar facilities, meanwhile, require more than twice as much copper as conventional power plants. The significance of this fact will not be lost on the European Union legislators who have decided to bring forward the target of doubling European solar capacity from 2030 to 2025. The race to secure copper is on. All of these factors are likely to lead to a historic copper deficit as consumption spikes. If supply continues at the pace of current recycling and exploration projects, this demand simply cannot not be met. As things stand, the market output of copper is around 25 million metric tons a year. Consultancy Wood Mackenzie recently published a HYPERLINK report forecasting that 9.7 million tons of extra annual supply will be needed over the next decade from projects that have not yet been approved (this amount is equal to almost a third of current refined-copper consumption).  The outcome of our end-use modeling reveals that the likelihood of delivering the copper required to meet future demand shifts from challenging in our base case to improbable in our AET-1.5 (accelerated energy transition) scenario, the Wood Mackenzie report finds.  In AET-1.5, low-carbon copper demand over the next 20 years would be equivalent to 60% of the current market size. Yet supply is hindered by a complex cocktail of regulatory, supply-chain, and organizational hurdles.\~ Maximo Pacheco, chairman of Codelco, which is the world\' s largest producer of copper, HYPERLINK told the Financial Times that it would be up to four years before the Chilean company could reach last year\' s output levels. Beset by lower recovery rates, falling ore levels, and dwindling margins, Codelco \- which claims to account for 10% of global copper output \- is fighting to ramp up its production. A downturn in the global economy has also proved problematic for global commodities, which are seeing prices fall even as the long-term prognosis for demand grows. One result of this is that copper stocks at metals exchanges are falling to historic lows. Kostas Bintas, co-head of metals and mining at Trafigura, which is one of the world\' s largest copper traders, HYPERLINK https://www.ft.com/content/80fdd315-2db4-46fa-a76e-6d3d4eff83e5 told the FT that the market currently runs on inventories equivalent to just 4.9 days of global consumption, with the margin expected to drop as low as 2.7 days by the end of the year. The Russia question Russia has unwittingly provided a big impetus for the switch to renewable energy sources. Ever since Russian troops crossed the Ukrainian border in February, anxieties about energy security in Europe have been translated into a movement toward renewable energy sources. Russia\' s contribution to the solution of copper shortages adds another intriguing dimension. The world\' s largest country is already responsible for HYPERLINK around 4% of copper production. But with vast resources yet to be exploited, it has the potential to be a significant force in easing the copper supply dearth. Already, Russian projects to extract more copper are in the pipeline. Udokan, which is Russia\' s largest proven copper deposit and HYPERLINK likely one of the three biggest in the world, has not been developed since it was discovered in Soviet times.\~ However, Alisher Usmanov\' s holdings company USM (also an owner of iron-ore producer Metalloinvest) has https://www.chita.ru/text/gorod/2022/09/07/71634224/ announced that exports from the site in Russia\' s Far East will begin in 2023. Production volume is HYPERLINK https://www.mining.com/russias-largest-new-copper-deposit-to-be-developed-under-un-global-compact-guidelines/ likely to be in the region of 135,000 metric tons of copper per year once the facility is completed.\~ Given that China consumes around 400,000 metric tons of Russian copper per year, a significant amount of the demand for any new Russian copper projects is likely to come from Russia\' s neighbor to the south. HYPERLINK US$23 billion per year in order to hit the zero-carbon targets set by the Paris Agreement). Now, more than ever, international cooperation and coherent policies on the red metal are desperately needed. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong23" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 8, 2022 Tuesday"source="Hong Kong Free Press" >
If you have ever been lucky enough to walk through a pristine tropical forest in Asia you would have immediately been struck by something \- the noise. During the day the air is thick with the buzzing of insects, the singing of birds, the chattering monkeys and myriad other animals. As night falls the soundscape changes to the strange chirps, grunts and squeaks of tree frogs and geckos, interrupted by the occasional cry of an owl. A forest in Hong Kong\' s Lung Fu Shan country park. Photo: Mercedes Hutton/HKFP. For anyone who has experienced these things, they may notice something strange about the forest in Hong Kong \- it is almost completely silent.\~ The story of why Hong Kong\' s forests fell silent is one of industry, colonialism, war, death and rebirth. In the absence of humans the territory would be completely covered in a dense forest teeming with wildlife. While Hong Kong is rightfully proud that over 50 per cent of its land area is wooded and green, people are often surprised to discover that this verdant and beautiful landscape is a relatively modern feature. Almost all the forest that we see today in Hong Kong did not exist even as recently as 1950.\~ Hong Kong\' s forest started to be removed on an industrial scale to create space for agriculture and to fuel the ceramics industry, which was a central part of the local economy until the 1700s. Following this the British began extracting timber for use in construction and as fuel. They only slowed their harvest once a number of landslides made them realise that the forests were necessary for HYPERLINK https://hongkongfp.com/2016/08/07/hkfp-history-brief-visual-history-1972-deadly-kotewall-road-landslide/ stabilising the steep hillsides The aftermath of a landslide in Mid-Levels in 1972. Photo: Wikicommons. The final nail in the coffin was the arrival of the Japanese during the second world war. They systematically cleared almost every inch of remaining forest from every hill and valley across the entire territory. Just a few remnant patches survived high in the mountains, and in the form of fung shui woods, traditionally located behind villages. These sylvan survivors can still be visited today, and offer us a rare glimpse of what the original forest in Hong Kong might have looked like.\~ Gazing around now, most people would be shocked to find out that the miles of lush forest surrounding them is only about 70 years old. In many areas the trees have made a remarkable comeback, sprouting from the seeds left dormant in the soil and taking advantage of the abundant rain and sunshine to recolonise the once barren hills. In other areas, such as Kadoorie Farm, concerted effort has been put into actively replanting trees. Walking in places like Tai Po Kau or Tai Mo Shan you could be forgiven for thinking that you were exploring an ancient, wild woodland. That is until you notice the abandoned rice terracing beneath your feet, or other subtle signs of recent human habitation amongst the trees. Walking trails at Kadoorie Farm & Botanical Garden Photo: Tom Grundy/HKFP While the woodlands were able to bounce back to an extent from seedbanks and planting initiatives, many animals that were driven out by the destruction of their habitat had no surviving populations from which to grow. The nearest area of forest with a relatively intact ecosystem lies in mainland China, in Dinghu Shan on the other side of Guangdong. The 200 miles of urban sprawl between here and there have created an impermeable barrier to the natural migration of wildlife. As such, the trees in Hong Kong grew back, but there were fewer animals to fill the emerging forests. This raises the question; should we actively relocate animals from forests in mainland China to rewild the woodlands of Hong Kong? There is precedent for similar interventions in Hong Kong. During the building of the airport a number of small islands were destroyed, which comprised the last remaining habitat of Romer\' s tree frog. A local scientist collected as many individuals as possible and established a breeding population at the University of Melbourne, Australia. Later, the species was successfully reintroduced to Hong Kong Island and the New Territories, having become locally extinct in the wild. In mainland China there have also been successful reintroductions of species, such as Pere David\' s deer, which became extinct in 1900 and was reintroduced from captive populations in Europe. More recently crested ibis, which were thought to be extinct in the wild in China in the 1980s, have been released from captive breeding programs in Shaanxi.\~ Romer\' s tree frog, an indigenous species that was successfully reintroduced after disappearing from Hong Kong. Photo: Wikkicommons. There are two major reasons why reintroducing species and rewilding should be explored. Firstly, expanding a species\' range and increasing its wild population boosts its conservation potential and gives it a greater chance of survival in the future. Secondly, species contribute to the functioning of ecosystems in complex ways that benefit both humans and wildlife alike. In Hong Kong for example, many species that are responsible for the dispersal of seeds have gone locally extinct, but they live happily just 200 miles away in the forests of mainland China. We are not talking here about re-introducing things like tigers, but more diminutive creatures such as Edwards\' long-tailed giant rat, and the greater necklaced laughing thrush. These species eat fruits, berries and seeds, then as they move around the landscape they excrete them and allow new trees to grow in new locations. In doing so they provide a free, efficient, and natural tree planting service, which the government otherwise spends money, time and resources on. There is currently a limited interest from the government to reintroduce species such as these, because they are not considered threatened in mainland China. However, the government overlooks the wider ecological benefit these animals would bring to Hong Kong. The greater necklaced laughingthrush. Photo: Wikicommons. In the age of climate change, trees provide us with a crucial ecosystem service \- absorbing tonnes of carbon from the atmosphere and locking them up it securely in their trunks, branches and roots. Mature forests offer unrivalled benefits to carbon sequestration, but without the natural wildlife that once existed here helping these forests to spread around Hong Kong, they may be held back from recovering from the destruction of the previous century. Supporting the natural regeneration of forests offers us one of the simplest and cheapest tools in our kit to combat the climate catastrophe. This is therefore seen as a global priority, with the United Nations declaring this the HYPERLINK https://www.decadeonrestoration.org/#:~:text=The%20UN%20Decade%20on%20Ecosystem%20Restoration%20aims%20to%20prevent%2C%20halt,if%20everyone%20plays%20a%20part. Decade of Ecosystem Regeneration The Hong Kong government has a commitment to improve its local biodiversity, and also to help combat the climate emergency as outlined in its HYPERLINK Biodiversity Strategy Action Plan As the COP27 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP27_Hong.Kong24" COP="COP27" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 12, 2022 Saturday 3:33 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
BANGKOK  President Biden greets Cambodia\' s war-toughened Prime Minister Hun Sen at a November 12-13 ASEAN summit in Phnom Penh amid US Magnitsky Act sanctions and feuding about China\' s presence at Cambodian ports along the Gulf of Thailand.  Hun Sen would like President Biden to be mute, deaf, and blind on democracy, human rights, and freedom in Cambodia, Arizona State University professor Sophal Ear, a Cambodia-born author on the Southeast Asian country, said in an interview.  Hun Sen wants the US to accept Cambodia the way he runs the country, namely to accept Cambodia\' s choice of partners in China, and to accept that what is going on politically in Cambodia is just Cambodia\' s internal affairs and none of the US\' s business, Sophal Ear said. Hun Sen often projects a pugnacious image when dealing with the US, but mellows his tone when praising China, which has showered the impoverished nation with investments and projects in recent years.  Biden is likely to arrive with at least two priorities in mind \- cautioning Hun Sen not to become too dependent on China and easing up on his political opposition, Craig Etcheson, an author on Cambodia, said in an interview.  The US will be watching China\' s involvement in Cambodia closely, and should continue with its current policy of a judicious mix of inducements and pressures, Etcheson suggested. White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre announced on October 28:  In Cambodia, he [Biden] will reaffirm the United States\' enduring commitment to Southeast Asia and ASEAN centrality, building on the success of the historic US-ASEAN Special Summit in Washington, DC. The Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) includes Brunei, Cambodia, Indonesia, Laos, Malaysia, Myanmar, Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam. Cambodia is this year\' s rotating ASEAN chairman. Cambodia and China deny those allegations. Hun Sen however leans heavily on China\' s financial assistance to boost his nationalist and capitalist themes and policies. In October 2021, the US Embassy in Phnom Penh\' s Spokesman Chad Roedemeier said:  The government of Cambodia has not been fully transparent about the intent, nature, and scope of this project or the role of the PRC [People\' s Republic of China] military, which raises concerns about intended use of the [Ream] naval facility. HYPERLINK https://i0.wp.com/asiatimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Cambodia-Ream-Naval-Base.jpg?resize=780%2C469&ssl=1 Link to Image The US Embassy is  aware of consistent, credible reporting that significant construction by the People\' s Republic of China continues at Ream Naval Base, Roedemeier told the US government\' s Voice of America (VOA). Cambodian government spokesperson Phay Siphan told VOA,  We confirm that the base is not built to serve the interest of China. It\' s a world port that any country can visit officially. It\' s not for China to use exclusively, said Phay Siphan.  The CPP (Mr. Hun Sen\' s ruling Cambodian People\' s Party) does seem to be annoyed that the US disregards their protestations of innocence in regards to Ream, Etcheson said. In November 2021, the Treasury\' s Office of Foreign Assets Control announced sanctions, under the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act, against Cambodia\' s navy commander and a defense ministry official  for their roles in corruption in Cambodia. They allegedly  conspired to profit from activities regarding the construction and updating of Ream Naval Base facilities by overcharging the costs, the US Treasury said.  Of the 28 active sanctions on Cambodia listed by the Office of Foreign Assets Control within the US Department of the Treasury, 26 fall under a law called the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act, the Washington-based Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) said in June.  This law allows the United States to place targeted sanctions on individuals and entities responsible for committing human rights violations or acts of corruption anywhere around the world.  The Global Magnitsky Act was never meant to alter the strategic behavior of states. Washington\' s use of GMA as a back door to punish Phnom Penh for its strategic balancing toward Beijing has been ineffective, and undermines the legitimacy of the tool, the CSIS report\' s joint authors Gregory B Poling, Charles Dunst and Simon Tran Hudes said. In 2020, the Treasury Department sanctioned a Chinese company for allegedly illegally seizing land along the Gulf of Thailand in Koh Kong province from farmers and fishermen, and evicting them, to build a US$3.8 billion luxury gambling and lifestyle project. The Dara Sakor Seashore Resort includes an international airport and a port for cruise ships, and  could be used to host [Chinese] military assets, then-State Secretary Mike Pompeo said. China\' s embassy in Phnom Penh said:  The US sanction, citing domestic law, is a blatant hegemonic act.  The US suppression on the legitimate investment of a Chinese enterprise in Cambodia will not only harm the lawful rights and interests of the enterprise, but also trample on the sovereignty of Cambodia, China\' s embassy said. HYPERLINK https://i0.wp.com/asiatimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Xi-Hun-Sen-e1533007779253.jpg?resize=780%2C564&ssl=1 Link to Image  This one does not have anything to do with the government, because it\' s a private company, government spokesperson Phay Siphan told VOA.  Dara Sakor is civilian \- there is no base at all. It could be converted, yes, but you could convert anything. The Chinese company also denied the allegations. China became Cambodia\' s biggest military source in 2018. Some analysts perceive Cambodia as a proxy for US-China rivalry.  Cambodia is on course to be the next Asian Tiger, and that is good news for America, Cambodia\' s Ambassador to the United States, Chum Sounry, said last year.  Ford Motors recently announced that it is building a $21 million assembly plant in the Pursat province of Cambodia.  And the recent virtual business summit showcased the ease of doing business in Cambodia experienced by US companies in a range of industries  from energy to manufacturing, and financial services to health care, the ambassador said. Hun Sen meanwhile has been asking Biden to stop demanding Cambodia repay money Washington loaned a US-backed regime in the 1970s to buy bombs to drop on Cambodia during the regional US-Vietnam War.  I consider the US debt Cambodia owed during the rule of [prime minister] Lon Nol to be a \' dirty\' debt that forced Cambodia to buy American bombs and drop them on the heads of Cambodians, causing many deaths and injuries, Hun Sen said in a 2021 speech. US aircraft killed more than 150,000 civilians by dropping 2,756,941 tons of ordnance on Cambodia beginning in 1965 and peaking in 1970-73, according to a  Bombs Over Cambodia report published by Yale University\' s Genocide Studies Program. The US was trying to destroy cross-border communist Viet Cong guerrillas\' havens. But the intense bombing helped popularize Pol Pot\' s jungle-based Khmer Rouge insurgency against Lon Nol, a US-backed general who had seized power in a 1970 coup, the Yale report said. During the 1970s, Hun Sen was a Khmer Rouge regiment commander. In 1975, Pol Pot toppled Mr. Lon Nol and obliterated his government. Lon Nol died in California in 1985. The US reportedly had loaned Lon Nol\' s anti-communist regime nearly $280 million which, with accrued interest, today totals more than $500 million.  That [Lon Nol] government has not existed in nearly 50 years, the CSIS report said.  Three separate Cambodian regimes \- the Khmer Rouge, the People\' s Republic of Kampuchea, and the modern-day Kingdom of Cambodia \- have ruled Phnom Penh since. HYPERLINK https://i0.wp.com/asiatimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/US-Cambodia-Nixon-April-30-1970.jpg?resize=780%2C499&ssl=1 Link to Image  It is unreasonable to expect the existing Cambodian government to pay back this debt that it did not incur, the CSIS report said. In 1975, victorious Khmer Rouge enforced an ultra-Maoist, horrific  killing fields regime which left up to two million Cambodians dead from extrajudicial executions, torture, starvation, and policies that intentionally destroyed the country\' s medical, agricultural, financial and other systems. In 1977, Hun Sen defected when internal Khmer Rouge purges worsened. Safe in neighboring Vietnam, he was groomed in Hanoi and installed as Cambodia\' s foreign minister after invading Vietnamese troops chased Pol Pot back into the jungle in 1979. In 1985, during Vietnam\' s 10-year occupation, Hanoi ensured Mr. Hun Sen became Cambodia\' s prime minister. Future twists may come if Hun Sen\' s son and heir apparent, Hun Manet, becomes Cambodia\' s next leader. Hun Manet trained at the US Military Academy at West Point, New York. Biden\' s total trip begins in Egypt on November 11 at a conference on Climate Change ( COP27 ) in Sharm el-Sheikh. After Cambodia, Mr. Biden goes to Bali, Indonesia, November 13-16 for a G20 Leaders\' summit where he will meet with his Chinese counterpart Xi Jinping. Richard S Ehrlich is a Bangkok-based American foreign correspondent reporting from Asia since 1978. Excerpts from his two new nonfiction books,  Rituals. Killers. Wars. & Sex.  Tibet, India, Nepal, Laos, Vietnam, Afghanistan, Sri Lanka & New York and  Apocalyptic Tribes, Smugglers & Freaks are available here. \</doc>
