<doc ID="COP23_Canada1" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 21, 2017 Tuesday"source="Canadian Government News" >
Ottawa: The Government of Canada has issued the following news release: Catherine McKenna, Minister of Environment and Climate Change, led a strong and productive delegation at this year\' s United Nations Climate Change Conference ( COP23 ) in Bonn, Germany. This global gathering advanced the work of the Paris Agreement so that climate action can be guaranteed for generations to come. COP23 brought together people from all parts of society to highlight both the challenges and solutions related to climate change, including opportunities to invest in clean growth, and the transition to a clean energy economy. Canada\' s diverse delegation to COP 23 included: Indigenous leaders; representatives from the provinces, territories and municipalities; youth; business leaders; civil society, opposition members; and Government of Canada negotiators and experts. Canada played a leadership role in helping advance the guidelines for the Paris Agreement. Canada is pleased that countries came together to launch the Local Communities and Indigenous Peoples\' Platform; providing a space to share knowledge and amplify their voice. In addition, the adoption of a gender action plan that will help build capacity and support gender representation in future international climate change negotiations and decision-making was a significant achievement for Canadian negotiators. An important highlight from COP 23 was the launch of the new  Powering Past Coal Alliance by Minister McKenna and her UK counterpart, Claire Perry. This initiative generated broad interest and support from over 20 countries, cities and states and Minister McKenna is looking forward to continuing this momentum given the numerous health and climate benefits of reducing coal-fired electricity. Canada also announced the formation of a North American Climate Leadership Dialogue with Mexico and the US Climate Alliance, a bipartisan coalition of 15 U.S. governors committed to reducing greenhouse gas emissions consistent with the goals of the Paris Agreement. Minister McKenna praised Fiji for its role in presiding over COP23 . She reiterated Canada\' s commitment to protect our oceans and advance global climate action by building the resilience of coastal communities, including Small Island Developing States (SIDS). Quotes  I was honoured to lead an inclusive delegation from Canada to COP 23 which demonstrated Canada\' s steadfast commitment to implement the Paris Agreement and take global climate action. Canada is pleased to have worked with the UK in launching the \' Powering Past Coal Alliance. The world has moved on; coal fired electricity isn\' t coming back. We are also pleased to have moved ahead in helping give a greater voice to Indigenous People in our international engagement and advancing a gender action plan. \- Catherine McKenna, Minister of Environment and Climate Change In case of any query regarding this article or other content needs please contact: HYPERLINK mailto:editorial@plusmediasolutions.com editorial@plusmediasolutions.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada2" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 13, 2017 Monday"source="CTV Television, Inc. CTV NATIONAL NEWS 23:00:00 ET" >
LISA LAFLAMME: It's one of the sideline sessions at the climate change summit in Germany. The scientific truth is humans emit 100 times more carbon, and the biggest single source is coal. CTV's senior political correspondent Glen McGregor on the fight for facts. GLEN MCGREGOR (Reporter): As governments from around the world meet to discuss the fight against climate change, they receive discouraging news on cutting carbon. GLEN PETERS (Center for International Climate Change Research): We're expecting the emissions to pop up, maybe around about two percent to a record high, and this is sort of demonstrating that we can't be complacent and emissions will stay flat. MCGREGOR: Efforts by developed countries, including Canada, had halted the rising greenhouse gasses over the past two years, but emissions from the developing world continue to climb, choking major cities like New Delhi. Canada comes to the COP23 summit pitching a plan in co-operation with the UK to end the use of coal by 2030, at odds with the Trump administration, which promises to restore the coal industry and held a panel to push clean coal technologies. It was interrupted by protestors who mockingly sung the Trump campaign anthem, God Bless the USA, while Canada's environment minister tweeted about the need to phase out coal all together, saying we must work together and transition to cleaner forms of energy. ELIZABETH MAY (Green Party Leader): Those who argue about phasing out coal generally are arguing about, you know, how fast can we do it, not should we do it. And the US is alone in that. MCGREGOR: The data on rising emissions come as 15,000 scientists signed on to a petition warning climate change is now a threat to the future of humanity. DALE MARSHALL (Environmental Defence): It's good to have that many scientists behind that letter. Hopefully it compels governments to do more, and individuals to do more, but frankly, none of this is new. MCGREGOR: Many delegates at the COP23 are concerned that the targets set by the Paris agreement just two years ago aren't enough to halt the planet's rising temperatures. They want countries like Canada to be more aggressive in phasing out fossil fuels. Lisa. LAFLAMME: All right, Glen McGregor from Ottawa tonight. Thanks, Glen. From one summit to another now, and an awkward moment that's getting a lot of play. Donald Trump learns the secret hand shake of international relations. Plus, a 5th woman comes forward against conservative fire brand Roy Moore. (COMMERCIAL BREAK) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada3" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 28, 2017 Tuesday"source="Ontario Farmer" >
A well-known Canadian program designed to manage agricultural nutrients stepepd out on the global stage at the United Nations Climate Change Conference ( COP23 ) held in Germany Nov. 6-17. Fertilizer Canada was at COP23 to highlight its sustainable agriculture solutions, including 4R Nutrient Stewardship and the Nitrous Oxide Emission Reduction Protocol (NERP). The organization represents Canadian manufacturers, and wholesale and retail distributors of nitrogen, phosphate, potash and sulphur fertilizers. "Canada has a great story to tell about the research being done and how to reduce greenhouse gas emissions from fertilizer use," said Fertilizer Canada vice-president Clyde Graham in an interview from Germany, where he gave a presentation at COP23 to a broad panel of representatives including food and fertilizer companies. The 4R program is based on applying the right source at the right rate and right time to the right place to ensure responsible fertilizer use as part of sustainable food production. The science-based fertilizer management system is currently in use in Alberta, Manitoba, Ontario, New Brunswick and Prince Edward Island, according to Fertilizer Canada. NERP was developed by the Canadian fertilizer industry to reduce unwanted nitrogen losses to the air by up to 25 per cent through the principles of 4R Nutrient Stewardship and is aligned with the United Nation's Sustainable Development Goals. "I think we're doing a great job to get science trans-lated into information farmers can use in the field to increase yields and reduce greenhouse gases," he added. "We're increasingly more precise by using the 4Rs. For example, there are several million acres in western Canada operating under these 4R principles and that's a great story." With a global population of over nine billion expected by 2050, Fertilizer Canada says that 77 per cent of future crop production growth is estimated to come from increased yields (compared to nine per cent from new farmland brought into production and 14 per cent from increased cropping intensity) -and fertilizer will play a key role in achieving that target. Graham admits progress is slow at international forums like COP, but he believes Canada is making progress in sharing its successes and how they could be applied in other countries around the globe. The Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) has already recognized the 4Rs and stated that information on this system should be compiled, synthesized, and disseminated to farming communities everywhere. "We are talking to the right people at the FAO and funding agencies like World Bank; the work we have done in Canada can be used in other countries, especially on small farms, and I'd like to see the world understand and adopt this," he said. Following a recent agreement with the Canadian Cooperative Association, Fertilizer Canada has committed to increasing food security using climate smart methods for smallholder farmers in developing countries. "It's not finalized yet but we're hoping in next few weeks to get some positive signals in getting the funding we need to reach smallholder farmers with the same messaging we've used here in Canada," he said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada4" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 9, 2017 Thursday"source="Canadian Government News" >
Victoria: The Government of British Columbia has issued the following news release: Minister of Environment and Climate Change Strategy George Heyman will be working with global leaders on ways to cut carbon pollution while growing a sustainable economy at the United Nations Climate Change Conference COP23 in Bonn, Germany.  Tackling climate change is key to building a strong, sustainable economy that benefits everyone, said Heyman.  Climate change is a global problem that demands global solutions. It\' s important that we work together with people from all over the world to develop strategies to cut carbon pollution, while making life better for people. Heyman will speak at numerous engagements while he attends the conference from Nov. 12\- 16, 2017. Topics he will be discussing include Indigenous involvement with climate change, the challenge of ocean acidification, transportation and B.C.\' s role in the Pacific Coast Collaborative. The conference provides a rare chance to connect with world leaders to share what is being done to reduce climate change at home and to learn what other nations are doing to combat one of the greatest challenges facing our planet. Quick facts: B.C. recently appointed a Climate Solutions and Clean Growth Advisory Council to help provide a road map to building a strong sustainable economy that benefits everyone, while meeting B.C.'s obligation to address climate change. B.C. is planning on legislating an interim target for 2030 of a 40% overall reduction in carbon emissions. The Province is increasing the carbon tax by $5 per tonne per year, beginning April 1, 2018. This increase will be paired with new climate-action rebate cheques to low- and middle-income families, which will see most B.C. families receiving more back from the rebate than they pay in new carbon taxes. The Province will also work with emissions intensive industries to maintain their competitiveness, while reducing emissions. In case of any query regarding this article or other content needs please contact: HYPERLINK mailto:editorial@plusmediasolutions.com editorial@plusmediasolutions.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada5" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday 8:15 AM PST"source="Market News Publishing" >
EARTH ALIVE CLEAN TECHNOLOGIES INC ("EAC-Z") - Invited To Present Its Achievement At The Start Up Energy - Transition (set) Event Of The Un Climate Change Conference - ( cop23 ) In Bonn, Germany Earth Alive Clean Technologies Inc. ("Earth Alive" or the "Company"), a leading Canadian Clean-Tech company, developer and manufacturer of state-of-the-art microbial technology-based products for sustainable agriculture and mining, is pleased to announce that it was formally invited to join the Canadian delegation at the UN Climate Change Conference hosted by the secretariat of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). In addition, Earth Alive was invited by the Government of Canada to participate and present its achievements in the Start Up Energy Transition (SET) event held yesterday. Earth Alive joined the Canadian delegation in Bonn, Germany and presented its business activities, in the context of sustainable solutions, at the Start Up Energy Transition (SET) event. This opportunity came from the recent partnership between SET and the Government of Canada, which aims at strengthening the existing SET network in North America in order to boost innovation in the field of sustainable energy solutions and cleaner technologies. The Honourable Stephane Dion, Canadian Ambassador to Germany, was part of the SET 2018 launch to present the newly-formed partnership, and evaluate the start-ups which were presented. Mr. Frederic Perron-Welch, Director of Sustainable Development at Earth Alive, commented, "Earth Alive distinguishes itself by offering innovative and sustainable solutions for the agriculture and mining industries; two major contributors to the global carbon footprint and land degradation. It is an honour to be able to represent the Company at COP23 , and the opportunity to present our achievements to international experts, heads of industry, political figures, and other interested parties reinforces our commitment to providing environmentally sound technologies to countries around the world." The twenty-third session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP 23 ) was divided into two zones for the two weeks of November 6-17, 2017 and accreditation to the "Bonn Zone" enables Earth Alive's representatives to access various climate action events, exhibits and pavilions, including high-level political events and media activities organized by the UNFCCC and Government of Germany. About the UN Climate Change Conference COP23 is organized by Bonn-based UN Climate Change, presided over by the Government of Fiji and organizationally and logistically supported by the Government of Germany, the region of North-Rhine-Westphalia and the City of Bonn. The Conference, coming just two years after the landmark adoption of the Paris Climate Change Agreement, will also further fuel momentum among cities, states, regions, territories, business and civil society in support of national climate action plans, the internationally-agreed temperature goal and the wider objectives of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development." For additional information, please visit HYPERLINK https://cop23.unfccc.int https:// .unfccc.int / About Earth Alive Clean Technologies Earth Alive aims to be a key player in world markets of environmentally sustainable industrial solutions. The Company works with the latest innovations in microbial technology to formulate and patent innovative products that can tackle the most difficult industrial challenges, once only reserved to environmentally harmful chemicals and additives. The Company is focused on environmental sustainability in the agriculture industry and dust control for the mining industry. For additional company information, please visit: HYPERLINK http://www.earthalivect.com www.earthalivect.com The CSE has neither approved nor disapproved the contents of this press release. The CSE does not accept responsibility for the adequacy or accuracy of this release. Forward-Looking Information Except for statements of historical fact, this news release contains certain forward-looking statements within the meaning of applicable securities law. Forward-looking statements are frequently characterized by words such as "plan", "expect", "project", "intend", "believe", "anticipate", "estimate" and other similar words, or statements that certain events or conditions "may" occur. Although Earth Alive believes that the expectations reflected in the forward-looking statements are reasonable, there can be no assurance that such expectations will prove to be correct. Such forward-looking statements are subject to risks and uncertainties that may cause actual results, performance or developments to differ materially from those contained in the statements. Except as required under applicable securities legislation, the Company undertakes no obligation to publicly update or revise forward-looking information, whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise. For media information and interview requests: Earth Alive Clean Technologies Inc. Mr. Michael Warren Cell.: +1 (438) 333-1680 HYPERLINK mailto:mwarren@earthalivect.com mwarren@earthalivect.com HYPERLINK http://www.earthalivect.com www.earthalivect.com ______________________________________ _______________________________________________ ____________________________________________________________ (c)2017 Market News Publishing Inc. All rights reserved. Toronto:(416)366-8881 Vancouver:(604)689-1101 Fax:(604)689-1106 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada6" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday 3:39 AM EST"source="Marketwired" >
MONTREAL, QUEBEC--(Marketwired - Nov. 15, 2017) - Earth Alive Clean Technologies Inc. (CSE:EAC)(CSE:EAC.CN)(CNSX:EAC) ("Earth Alive" or the "Company"), a leading Canadian Clean-Tech company, developer and manufacturer of state-of-the-art microbial technology-based products for sustainable agriculture and mining, is pleased to announce that it was formally invited to join the Canadian delegation at the UN Climate Change Conference hosted by the secretariat of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). In addition, Earth Alive was invited by the Government of Canada to participate and present its achievements in the Start Up Energy Transition (SET) event held yesterday. Earth Alive joined the Canadian delegation in Bonn, Germany and presented its business activities, in the context of sustainable solutions, at the Start Up Energy Transition (SET) event. This opportunity came from the recent partnership between SET and the Government of Canada, which aims at strengthening the existing SET network in North America in order to boost innovation in the field of sustainable energy solutions and cleaner technologies. The Honourable Stephane Dion, Canadian Ambassador to Germany, was part of the SET 2018 launch to present the newly-formed partnership, and evaluate the start-ups which were presented. Mr. Frederic Perron-Welch, Director of Sustainable Development at Earth Alive, commented, "Earth Alive distinguishes itself by offering innovative and sustainable solutions for the agriculture and mining industries; two major contributors to the global carbon footprint and land degradation. It is an honour to be able to represent the Company at COP23 , and the opportunity to present our achievements to international experts, heads of industry, political figures, and other interested parties reinforces our commitment to providing environmentally sound technologies to countries around the world." The twenty-third session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP 23 ) was divided into two zones for the two weeks of November 6-17, 2017 and accreditation to the "Bonn Zone" enables Earth Alive's representatives to access various climate action events, exhibits and pavilions, including high-level political events and media activities organized by the UNFCCC and Government of Germany. About the UN Climate Change Conference COP23 is organized by Bonn-based UN Climate Change, presided over by the Government of Fiji and organizationally and logistically supported by the Government of Germany, the region of North-Rhine-Westphalia and the City of Bonn. The Conference, coming just two years after the landmark adoption of the Paris Climate Change Agreement, will also further fuel momentum among cities, states, regions, territories, business and civil society in support of national climate action plans, the internationally-agreed temperature goal and the wider objectives of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development." For additional information, please visit HYPERLINK https://cop23.unfccc.int https:// .unfccc.int / About Earth Alive Clean Technologies Earth Alive aims to be a key player in world markets of environmentally sustainable industrial solutions. The Company works with the latest innovations in microbial technology to formulate and patent innovative products that can tackle the most difficult industrial challenges, once only reserved to environmentally harmful chemicals and additives. The Company is focused on environmental sustainability in the agriculture industry and dust control for the mining industry. For additional company information, please visit: HYPERLINK http://www.earthalivect.com www.earthalivect.com The CSE has neither approved nor disapproved the contents of this press release. The CSE does not accept responsibility for the adequacy or accuracy of this release. Forward-Looking Information Except for statements of historical fact, this news release contains certain forward-looking statements within the meaning of applicable securities law. Forward-looking statements are frequently characterized by words such as "plan", "expect", "project", "intend", "believe", "anticipate", "estimate" and other similar words, or statements that certain events or conditions "may" occur. Although Earth Alive believes that the expectations reflected in the forward-looking statements are reasonable, there can be no assurance that such expectations will prove to be correct. Such forward-looking statements are subject to risks and uncertainties that may cause actual results, performance or developments to differ materially from those contained in the statements. Except as required under applicable securities legislation, the Company undertakes no obligation to publicly update or revise forward-looking information, whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise. CONTACT: Earth Alive Clean Technologies Inc. Mr. Michael Warren Cell.: +1 (438) 333-1680 HYPERLINK mailto:mwarren@earthalivect.com mwarren@earthalivect.com HYPERLINK http://www.earthalivect.com www.earthalivect.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada7" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="June 13, 2017 Tuesday 09:21 PM EST"source="Canadian Press" >
SACRAMENTO, Calif. - California Gov. Jerry Brown was named Tuesday as a special envoy to states at the next United Nations Climate Change Conference , further elevating his international profile as a leader on the issue as President Donald Trump backs away from a key international agreement. The announcement of Brown's role at the November conference in Bonn, Germany, by Fiji Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama comes on the heels of the governor's meetings with Chinese President Xi Jinping and German Environment Minister Barbara Hendricks to discuss climate change. "I will lean on Gov. Brown to continue to bring the great leadership he has demonstrated time and time again, and to mobilize a strong contingent of like-minded leaders from around the world, to show the world that we mean business," Bainimarama said during a news conference at the historic governor's mansion in Sacramento. The four-term governor has made reducing greenhouse gas emissions and boosting green technology a key tenet of his administration. He's launched non-binding climate change pacts, including the newly formed U.S. Climate Alliance of states committed to upholding the carbon reductions goals in the Paris climate agreement, from which Trump plans to withdraw. Bainimarama on Tuesday joined Fiji in the Under2 Coalition, a pact among cities, states and countries that Brown helped launch in 2015 aimed at keeping the rise of global temperatures below 2 degrees Celsius. Bainimarama hailed U.S. states' commitment to upholding the Paris agreements. He noted Trump's choice to withdraw could bring fireworks to the U.N. conference, known as " COP 23 ." "I think the withdrawal of the White House is going to make COP 23 very exciting," he said. Brown won't be the only governor potentially playing an outsize role at the conference. Fellow West Coast Govs. Kate Brown of Oregon and Jay Inslee of Washington, who also travelled to Sacramento on Tuesday, both plan to attend with other governors in the state's Climate Alliance. "We're going to play a very important role," Jerry Brown said. The state agreement is a non-binding commitment to uphold the Paris goals, which include reducing the country's emissions by 26 to 28 per cent from 2005 levels. Many of the 13 states involved already have their own targets in place, and the goal of the coalition is to collaborate and share ideas on using green technology and other means to meet the goal. "When the president decided to run up the white flag of surrender to the challenge of climate change, we jumped right into the barricades," Inslee said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada8" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday"source="Canadian Government News" >
Ottawa: The Government of Canada has issued the following news release: The 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change Event: Minister McKenna will participate in a panel discussion about Indigenous leadership on climate action in Canada. Time: 1:00 p.m. (CET) / 7:00 a.m. (EST) Location: Bonn Zone, room 10 Note for media: Open coverage Event: Minister McKenna will participate in a Facebook Live armchair discussion with Catherine Stewart, Canada\' s Chief Negotiator Time: 4:30 p.m. (CET) / 10:30 a.m. (EST) Note for Media: Media are welcome to follow the conversation at the Environment and Natural Resources in Canada Facebook page Event: Minister McKenna will moderate a discussion at the Delphi/GLOBE Canada Carbon Pricing Leadership Coalition business event. Time: 5:00 p.m. (CET) / 11:00 a.m. (EST) Note for media: Open coverage Event: Minister McKenna will attend a joint ministers\' reception hosted by the Fiji Presidency and Germany\' s Ministry of the Environment Time: 8:45 p.m. (CET) / 2:45 p.m. (EST) In case of any query regarding this article or other content needs please contact: HYPERLINK mailto:editorial@plusmediasolutions.com editorial@plusmediasolutions.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada9" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 7, 2017 Tuesday"source="Postmedia Breaking News" >
Prime Minister Justin Trudeau fancies himself a leader on climate change. Is he? This week, the COP23 United Nations climate change negotiations have begun in Bonn, Germany. The talks, which are to continue until Nov. 17, are only starting; many challenges are on the agenda, particularly issues relating to the loss and damage and adaptation that some countries must now undergo as a result of climate change. As a climate researcher and young Canadian who has attended such conferences since 2012, I am familiar with these negotiations, and the political willpower they require. And, I am waiting for Trudeau to finally demonstrate this political will. It is clear from the initial outset of these talks in Bonn that leadership from national governments is fundamental. The United Nations process requires ambitious political leadership as these negotiations look to reach a pivotal moment in 2018, where new efforts to reduce greenhouse-gas emissions need to be introduced. Countries - especially those with industrialized fossil fuel-based economies, such as Canada - must play a constructive role in creating political space for more ambitious commitments for greenhouse-gas emissions reductions. A transition to renewable energy rooted in environmental justice is at the forefront of this leadership. In this vein, Trudeau is quick to assert that Canada is leading on climate change. The rhetoric is widespread and easy to find; all too often, however, Trudeau substitutes empty words for action. Trudeau's grand statements about Canada's climate leadership do not constitute leadership in and of themselves. As it stands, there is very little concrete improvement in Canada's commitments in the United Nations under Trudeau in comparison to those of Stephen Harper. Canada's contribution to the Paris Agreement - the first universal treaty on climate change - has remained unchanged from what Harper had proposed. Back home, Justin Trudeau has reaffirmed the urgency of climate change, all the while losing no time in approving such bitumen pipeline projects as Kinder Morgan, in British Columbia, and the Pacific Northwest liquified natural gas project. The gap between Trudeau's actions and his feel-good rhetoric is staggering and alarming. Moreover, as the United States President Donald Trump attempts to challenge the overwhelming scientific evidence for climate change, Trudeau has been silent. I am shocked, as someone studying climate change science, that our prime minister has not swiftly asserted his support of climate science and recommitted himself to standing up where the United States is reneging. We have been seeing this leadership from elected officials outside of the United States federal government, such as with state governors and municipal mayors. Where is Trudeau among the voices calling for increased action on climate change? As a matter of fact, rather than maintain his acceptance of then-President Barack Obama's decision to not pursue the Keystone XL pipeline, Trudeau has welcomed Trump's revival of the project. Climate leaders do not build oil pipelines. They do not dismiss the concerns of Indigenous communities affected by fossil fuel extraction. They do not ignore the concerns of their youth, who are demanding a livable future. In order to claim climate leadership at the United Nations, Justin Trudeau must reject new fossil fuel projects, especially the Kinder Morgan pipeline. He must reaffirm Canada's commitment to climate change, making explicit the stark contrast to our United States neighbours. A Canada that leads on climate change is a Canada that increases its commitments to climate action in response to United States withdrawal. Of course, the negotiations at the United Nations have only just begun - there is still time for Canada to demonstrate leadership, and I am waiting. Yet, until Justin Trudeau rejects new fossil fuel infrastructure, recognizes First Nations rights, and stands up to Donald Trump, Canada cannot claim to be leading. Leehi Yona( HYPERLINK https://twitter.com/leehiyona https://twitter.com/leehiyona COP23 United Nations climate talks and a Master of Environmental Science candidate at Yale University. !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2017 Postmedia Network Inc. All rights reserved. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada10" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 6, 2017 Monday 11:57 AM EST"source="Canadian Press" >
This article was originally published on The Conversation, an independent and nonprofit source of news, analysis and commentary from academic experts. Disclosure information is available on the original site. Author: Deborah de Lange, Assistant Professor, Global Management Studies, Ryerson University With the United States planning to withdraw from the Paris Agreement, European nations such as France and the Netherlands are likely to fill the leadership vacuum at the United Nations ' climate change conference kicking off in Bonn, Germany, this week. Unless Canada steps up to the plate now, the upcoming meeting, also known as the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parities ( COP23 ), could become one more missed opportunity for Canada. Canada has - since the nation's abdication from the Kyoto Accord in 2011 - been a relative laggard on climate change policy. According to the 2017 Climate Change Performance Index, released by the Climate Action Network Europe, Canada still ranks among the worst of the 58 countries assessed. The most recent evidence of the government's insincere promises and weak climate policies can be seen in its green light to the Kinder Morgan pipeline in British Columbia. Although Canada ratified the Paris Agreement under Trudeau, the government has yet to deliver meaningful policy that can change behaviour in favour of the climate. A national carbon tax of $50 per tonne of carbon emitted will be implemented over five years by adding $10 per tonne each year until it reaches $50 per tonne in 2022. However, oil and gas firms have been shadow pricing carbon for years. For example, a Harvard case study examining British Columbia's leadership on the carbon tax from 2008 to 2009 finds that even a tax of $100 per tonne will not change fossil fuel companies' decisions. There are many other models of carbon taxation that Canada could follow. For example, Sweden leads on carbon tax policy and finds that it is good for its economy. Sweden's carbon tax amounts to the equivalent of $200 per tonne. A more effective Canadian policy would be to start at $100 per tonne of carbon emitted and add $20 per tonne per year for five years, bringing the rate up to where Sweden is today. But this would be playing catch-up, not providing leadership. Direct policies are even better. Canada could phase out fossil fuels and phase in clean, safe renewable energy. These transitions are possible: we phased out inefficient incandescent light bulbs. Wanted: Climate innovation In past climate discussions, Canada has positioned itself as it would during trade negotiations. Its approach has been to get the best deal while minimizing change or acceding to corporate interests. But climate change is not a trade agreement - climate change is the most urgent issue of our time and requires global cooperation. Canada must do more than offer symbolic support to existing solutions to mitigate climate change. The nation has a chance to lead, but it must do so by example, not only in words. Other nations and regions, including Europe, China and India have made concrete headway since ratifying the Paris Agreement. Several countries are phasing out the sale of gasoline and diesel cars, and cities like Paris plan to ban them from their streets. France and the United Kingdom have said that they will ban the sale of gasoline and diesel vehicles by 2040. Germany is in discussions with its auto industry to find solutions. Norway and the Netherlands say they'll hit that target sooner, in 2025 and 2030 respectively. Norway is a petro state, just like Canada. Yet even Norway is booting vehicles with combustion engines from its roads. For Norway, electric vehicles represent a strategic industry that will boost its economy. A race to the top To lead, Canada has to distance itself from its recent past behaviours and engage in a race to the top. Dropping out of the Kyoto Accord was shocking. Our national carbon emissions are tops on a per capita basis and are high on other relative measures. At climate discussions, we have had a reputation for dragging forward movement backwards. Although the press liked to talk about the "bromance" between U.S. President Barack Obama and Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, these leaders took fundamentally different policy positions. Obama was progressive, while Trudeau is regressive. Obama stopped the Keystone XL pipeline in the name of "national interest," whereas Justin Trudeau has supported pipelines even in the face of mounting opposition. Canada could shake off its tar-sands reputation by stepping forward and doing the unexpected. On a sector-by-sector basis, we should implement carbon reduction policies by specific dates. Most carbon emissions come from the energy and transportation sectors; focusing on these can be tremendously effective at reducing carbon emissions. We could, for example, ban the use of combustion engines in vehicles by 2025, stop all newly proposed pipeline projects and plan a phase out of tar sands operations by 2030. Canada should also phase out coal-fired and gas power plants in favour of renewable energy by 2025. Other sectors such as buildings, agriculture and industry also emit greenhouse gases, and must be addressed. Definitive policies in a stable environment are critical for building Canada's future clean sustainable industries. By standing out on climate change, Canada would win international respect and regain the trust that it has recently lost. Global connections If Canada leads on the Paris Agreement, the country demonstrates that it is a viable trade partner in Europe's eyes. EU nations have a defined circular economy strategy that avoids damaging the Earth by resource and energy use. These nations want environmental, social and institutional or governance principles tied to trade agreements. In turn, we would become a trusted partner on the international stage. International trade could also reduce our economic reliance on the United States, a nation that is increasingly isolating itself, and connect Canada - and the provinces - to markets that would allow us to be part of the global circular economy. Sustainable development opportunities with the European Union, China and India could open markets for Canadian provinces whose economies now rely on fossil fuels, allowing for their economic diversification. These provinces need support to make the shift. Eight years ago, Canada set a target to reduce its greenhouse gas emissions by 17 per cent by 2020 compared to 2005 levels. That target now looks unattainable, but it could still meet the 2030 target of reducing emissions by 30 per cent relative to 2005 levels. The Pan-Canadian Framework on Clean Growth and Climate Change is a step in the right direction, but we need more. As long as Canada's climate policies continue to feed fossil fuel use, the country will not lead at COP23 - a missed opportunity at a crucial time. ___ This article was originally published on The Conversation. Disclosure information is available on the original site. Read the original article: HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/canada-has-the-opportunity-to-be-a-climate-leader-in-bonn-86384 https://theconversation.com/canada-has-the-opportunity-to-be-a-climate-leader-in-bonn-86384 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada11" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 17, 2017 Friday"source="National Post's Financial Post & FP Investing (Canada)" >
Canada and the U.K. will lead a coalition of 20 countries planning to phase out the use of coal-fired power by 2030, though a handful of the countries in the group burn no coal. Environment and Climate Change Minister Catherine McKenna and U.K. Minister of State for Climate Change and Industry Claire Perry announced the formation Thursday of a group of countries that had agreed to phase out coal over the next dozen years. The group will also try to expand its membership to 50 by next fall's United Nations Climate Change Conference in Poland. "I'm thrilled to see so much global momentum for the transition to clean energy and the move away from coal power - and this is only the beginning," McKenna said in a release. Similarly, Perry said the U.K. is committed to phasing out "unabated coal-fire power generation no later than 2025 and we hope to inspire others to follow suit." Canadian and U.K.-based groups supporting the phase-out of coal expressed hope that countries like South Korea, Japan and Germany, which burn more coal than any in the group of 20, would join. All told, coal consumption from the group of 20 comprises just over two per cent of total coal consumed around the world, according to data from BP Plc. and World Bank. None of the world's largest coalburning countries - led by China, India, the U.S., Japan and Russia - are members of the coalition announced Thursday. Canada burns the most coal of any country on the list of 20 and had already announced plans to transition its electric system away from the fossil fuel by 2030, largely thanks to efforts by provinces such as Ontario and Alberta. The U.K. is the second largest coal consumer in the coalition, followed by the Netherlands, Mexico, France and Austria. A handful of countries in the group - including Angola, Costa Rica, El Salvador and Fiji - neither produce nor consume any coal. !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2017 Postmedia Network Inc. All rights reserved. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada12" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="July 22, 2017 Saturday"source="Prince George Citizen (British Columbia)" >
While Al Gore has plenty of praise for Justin Trudeau's efforts to combat climate change, he says there's still room for improvement on the prime minister's environmental agenda. Trudeau makes a brief cameo in Gore's new climate-change documentary An Inconvenient Sequel: Truth to Power. The former U.S. vice-president is seen having a quick chat with Trudeau during the 2015 United Nations climate-change conference in Paris. Trudeau was among the world leaders, including former U.S. president Barack Obama, who helped formally ratify the global treaty to reduce emissions, adapt to climate change and pay for mitigation measures. U.S. President Donald Trump recently announced plans to withdraw from the agreement. "I'll tell you, for me, Justin Trudeau has been a real breath of fresh air, and Canadians should know that he and his team made a huge difference in the Paris negotiations in helping the world come together," Gore said in an interview Friday. "He's really provided outstanding leadership. "I don't agree with everything he's doing, but I admire his leadership and the vision and the speeches and what he's been doing and saying, and what he's been doing has really made a huge difference." When asked about his specific areas of disagreement, he pointed to the "continued heavy use of fossil fuels," such as Trudeau's support of the Trans Mountain pipeline expansion. He didn't single out Canada, noting that the U.S. is also heavily reliant on fossil fuels. "I completely understand that this is a time of transition and so moving forward to get the policy right, to get the price on carbon to work with the provinces, to work in the global community to get the right agreement worldwide, that's really a crucial step that we have to take right now," he said. Jeff Skoll, the Canadian-born producer of An Inconvenient Sequel, said that they had a recent screening of the film in Washington, D.C., a few nights ago for individuals from the U.S. House of Representatives, the Senate and "other Washington insiders." He said the Trudeau introduction to Gore elicited an overwhelming positive response. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada13" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 17, 2017 Friday"source="National Post (f/k/a The Financial Post) (Canada)" >
COP23 wrapped up in Bonn this week, the annual jamboree for the international climate class. It's an article of faith among them that man-made climate change is an apocalyptic threat. And it is a faith, much like Justin Trudeau recently praised the Governor General's "faith in science." There are true believers in lab coats too. "COP" stands for Conference of the Parties to the 1992 United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change. The framework is now 25 years old, and the apocalypse is apparently closer than ever. So officials the world over convene every year to ratchet up the urgency. Bonn is the 23rd time they have done so. A few years back, Canada's delegation to COP21 numbered in the hundreds. Every so often the COPs conclude a big agreement on emission targets, as they did in Kyoto 1997 or in Paris 2015. Countries like Canada and the United States then ignore the targets. At COP23 , the Trump administration was regularly denounced for saying that they would not meet their targets. Canada won't, but doesn't declare as much, which is how polite people do it. However, it is not at all clear what the relationship is between the COPs and what is actually happening on the climate file. On the eve of Bonn, the UN environment program chief said that "the U.S. will live up to its Paris commitment, not because of the White House, but because of the private sector. All the big American companies are dedicated to go in the green direction." That seems like very good news. Isn't it better if emissions targets are met because it is efficient and profitable to do so? That's what it means when "companies go in green direction." Better to meet the targets through entrepreneurial freedom than to miss them through government coercion. Emissions are a function of energy sources and economic growth. At COP23 , it was reported that from 2014 to 2016 global emissions did not rise. In 2017 they did. Who knows why? It is devilishly difficult to predict the future of energy markets even a few years out, let alone a generation or two hence. The International Energy Agency released its World Energy Outlook this week; it's not part of the COP23 proceedings, but it is likely more relevant to the future of emissions than any agreements that the COPs conclude. The energy outlook identifies two major trends, one that's been known for a long time, the other a surprise of the last 15 years. Global energy demand will climb as population grows and China and India grow into middle-class economies; that much is well known. The other trend creating extraordinary change in global energy is the emergence of the United States as the world's largest oil and gas producer, something wholly unexpected before the emergence of shale gas. That was not something known back when the COPs gathered at Kyoto. That has firstly commercial consequences. Canada's future as an energy superpower is threatened by a former customer. Not only do Americans need less Canadian energy, but their exports - not ours - are going to be meeting the rising Asian demand. All of which is more evidence that the global energy market has changed dramatically, completely independent of policies favouring renewable sources. But as the cost of the latter drops, it is entirely predictable that the global energy scene will look vastly different in another 15 years. We just don't know what it will look like. We do know that the COP38 conference will be held; few things are more certain than the momentum toward another UN conference. It is also quite certain that emissions levels will be affected by technological advances far more than government regulation. It is quite possible that emissions will fall - including American emissions - because of shifts to different sources of energy, primarily from coal to natural gas, but also to renewables. Indeed, it is very possible that Canadian emissions will fall because of a shrinking energy sector. Falling emissions due to declining economic activity is the East German option; shuttering moribund communist factories was good for reducing emissions. The World Energy Outlook forecasts oil production and the oil price in 2040. The COP process has targets that far out. But the real news is that the energy world has been changing dramatically and will continue to do so, regardless of what is agreed to in Kyoto or Paris or Bonn. The last 200 years have seen a global shift in energy sources from wood to coal to oil to gas, accompanied by the rise of hydro and nuclear. That shift will only accelerate in the years ahead. If the apocalypse is averted it will not be because of UN agreements. !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2017 Postmedia Network Inc. All rights reserved. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada14" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="October 16, 2017"source="SNL Canada Energy Week" >
Canada and the United Kingdom have agreed to spearhead a push for the elimination of emissions from coal-fired electricity generation at an upcoming climate-change summit. Canada's minister of environment and climate change, Catherine McKenna, met with her U.K. counterpart, Claire Perry, Oct. 11 to discuss ways to mitigate coal-plant emissions. The two discussed cooperation in advancing carbon capture, utilization and storage, according to a Canadian government statement. The meeting comes ahead of the 23rd session of the Conference of Parties, or COP23 , summit planned for November in Bonn, Germany. Canada's government has legislated the end to coal-plant emissions by 2030, while the U.K. plans to phase out traditional coal-fired generation by 2025. Canada has already granted exemptions to its plan to isolated provinces without access to natural gas sources that would back up renewables. While other countries participating in COP23 have agreed to cut emissions, host country Germany and China are both expanding their coal-fired generating fleets. "Canada and the United Kingdom will champion a global alliance on the transition from unabated coal-fired electricity at next month's United Nations climate change meetings in Bonn, Germany," the ministers said in a joint statement. "Phasing unabated coal power out of the energy mix and replacing it with cleaner technologies will significantly reduce our greenhouse gas emissions, improve the health of our communities, and benefit generations to come. We are doing our part, but we recognize the need to accelerate the international transition from burning coal to using cleaner power sources." Canada already has two industrial-scale carbon capture and sequestration, or CCS, projects in operation, Royal Dutch Shell plc's Quest CCS project and SaskPower's Boundary Dam project. Those facilities were both built with provincial government aid prior to the election of McKenna's government. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada15" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday"source="The Toronto Star" >
Environment Minister Catherine McKenna says Canada is going full-steam ahead with its push for a global alliance to eliminate coal-fired electricity, and that she isn't concerned the United States - with its pro-coal president - is trumpeting an opposite approach. McKenna, who is in Bonn, Germany, for the 23rd annual United Nations climate change conference this week, told reporters by phone on Tuesday that Canada will work with countries and sub-national players such as businesses and American states that "understand that we need to power past coal." She played down the suggestion that Canada's position would create friction with the U.S. as the countries get set to resume strained negotiations to change the North American Free Trade Agreement. "The U.S. administration has taken a different position from the rest of the world when it comes to action on climate change under the Paris Agreement," McKenna said, referring to U.S. President Donald Trump's announcement in June that the U.S. will drop out of the global pact to curb greenhouse gas emissions and stop global warming beyond two degrees this century. "We're just moving forward, and we've always said that we will work with whoever wants to take emissions action on climate change and that anyone is welcome to join our powering-past-coal alliance," McKenna said. But those approaches contrast sharply with the direction of the United States. Aside from Trump's past statements that climate change is a "hoax," his administration has also promised to boost the flagging U.S. coal industry. On Monday, the American delegation to the Bonn talks held an event with executives from the energy industry, who argued that fossil fuels and nuclear energy should be part of a climate change solution rather than phased out. The event was disrupted by chanting protesters, the New York Times reported, and prompted a quip from former New York mayor and anti-coal campaigner Michael Bloomberg, who said: "Promoting coal at a climate summit is like promoting tobacco at a cancer summit." The U.S. is the third-largest coal consumer in the world, after India and China, which is responsible for roughly half of global demand for coal, according to the energy statistics tracker, Enerdata. Canada, meanwhile, has committed to phasing out coal-fired electricity by 2030, as it pushes to meet its Paris Agreement target to reduce greenhouse gas emissions to 30 per cent below the 2005 level that year. Nova Scotia, however, struck a deal with Ottawa in November 2016 that allows it to keep burning coal for electricity beyond the phase-out deadline, while committing to further emissions reductions in other sectors. Canadian mines also produced 61 million tons of coal in 2016, when the country exported 30 million tons, according to Natural Resources Canada. McKenna said the "vast majority" of Canada's coal exports are used for steel production rather than electricity and defended Canada's "leadership" in the effort to reduce greenhouse gas emissions. "No countries here are talking about a return to coal; everyone's talking about the opportunity to move to cleaner sources of energy and the need to do that as fast as possible," she said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada16" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="December 5, 2017 Tuesday 06:39 PM EST"source="Canadian Press" >
OTTAWA - Environment Minister Catherine McKenna says getting China into Canada's international alliance to wean the world off coal power would be a huge win, but the world's most populous country can't make that kind of commitment right now. McKenna is in Beijing this week as part of Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's China trade mission. She tells The Canadian Press she trusts that China is committed to climate change, has installed a significant amount of renewable energy, is cutting back on building new coal plants and is on track to meet its commitment to see its emissions peak before 2030. But while she has discussed coal with Chinese officials, getting them into the alliance is not on the table. "I just don't think they're in a position to sign on yet," she said. Twenty nations signed onto the Canada-United Kingdom Powering Past Coal Alliance at the United Nations climate change conference in Germany last month. None of them are among the world's biggest consumers of coal power, such as China, the United States, India, Germany and Japan. The goal is to grow the group to 50 within a year, but the 20 in the alliance right now are already among the world's least dependent on coal, including five which don't use coal at all. China is the world's No. 1 producer and consumer of coal, consuming more of it than the rest of the world combined. In 2014, about 70 per cent of its power supply and 71 per cent of its emissions came from burning coal. There are nearly 4,000 coal-fired plants in operation across the country. Burning coal to make electricity is the single biggest source of carbon dioxide emissions from human activity, representing almost half the total production of carbon dioxide emissions in the world. A typical 500-megawatt coal plant produces the same amount of emissions in a year as 600,000 cars. About nine per cent of Canada's emissions - and 10 per cent of the country's electricity - came from burning coal in 2015, the last year for which emissions data is available. Canada intends to phase out coal by 2030, although agreements with Saskatchewan and Nova Scotia to make that happen are still in the works. The Paris climate change accord aims to keep risks associated with climate change from skyrocketing by limiting global warming to less than two degrees Celsius by the end of the century. The scientific analysis that informed the Paris agreement says developed nations have to be off coal by 2030, with the rest of the world to follow by 2050, if there is to be any chance of meeting that target. McKenna acknowledged having China at the Powering Past Coal Alliance table would be hugely beneficial to bringing the rest of the world into the coal-phase out plan. "Maybe at some point they will be ready, but ultimately every country has to figure it out," she said. Canada and China released a joint statement Monday on climate change reaffirming both countries are committed to the Paris agreement. The statement talks about "reducing reliance on traditional fossil energy and transitioning to clean energy," but never mentions coal. Catherine Abreu, executive director of Climate Action Network Canada, said while China should get credit for agreeing to cancel more than 100 planned coal plants at home, Chinese companies are still one of the biggest players in building coal plants internationally. Germany's Urgewald environmental group tracks coal plants and says there are 1,600 new plants being planned in 62 countries. Chinese power companies are behind 700 of the plants, and about 140 of those are not in China. "That is something that China can absolutely make a move on and that Canada should be having a conversation about." - Follow @mrabson on Twitter \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada17" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 20, 2017"source="SNL Canada Energy Week" >
The governments of Canada and the U.K. formally launched their effort to move the world off of coal-fired generation in Bonn, Germany, on Nov. 16, through what they called the Powering Past Coal Alliance. In the hours after the announcement, as many as 26 nations and governments also signed on to the list representing U.S. states, Canadian provinces and European countries. The move contrasts with statements supporting fossil fuels made by U.S. officials attending the United Nations Climate Change Conference , where world leaders are working to write the rulebook for the 2015 Paris Agreement on climate change. Axios reported Nov. 16 that George David Banks, a special assistant to President Donald Trump for international energy and environment, told reporters in Bonn that the White House is considering forming a clean coal alliance. Secretary of Energy Rick Perry in October also alluded to a possible partnership with African nations to expand electricity access across the continent, including fossil fuel generation, adding that he also supported forming a global clean coal alliance. The declaration issued Nov. 16 from the Powering Past Coal Alliance leaves open possibilities for new coal technologies that can prevent carbon emissions from coal. But the group described the phase-out of "traditional" coal generation as "one of the most important steps governments can take to tackle climate change and meet our commitment to keep global temperature increase well below 2 degrees [Celsius], and to pursue efforts to limit it to 1.5 degrees [Celsius]." Keeping the warming of the planet to within that range is the goal of the Paris Agreement, to which all nations except the U.S. have committed. Trump announced in June that the U.S. would withdraw from the agreement, but under its terms, no nation can withdraw until 2020. Coal must be phased out in the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development and European nations by 2030 to meet the Paris accord's goals, while the rest of the world must phase it out by 2050, the declaration states. Under the terms of the new alliance, the committed governments must phase out traditional coal power plants and place a moratorium on any new coal-fired power plants that do not have carbon capture and sequestration technology. The alliance aims to grow to 50 members by the next edition of the U.N. Conference of the Parties. U.S. states that have joined the alliance include Washington and Oregon. Canada has already pledged to phase out coal by 2030. According to S&P Global Market Intelligence data, Canada has a combined coal capacity of 9,864 MW as of Nov. 16. Hours after the announcement of the alliance, U.S. lead delegate Judith Garber took a more conciliatory tone in her address to the climate conference. Garber is the acting assistant secretary of the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs for the U.S. Department of State. Garber said Trump was clear about his intentions with the Paris Agreement and the U.S. may re-engage in the deal at a later date under terms that are more favorable. Trump has also been clear about remaining a global leader in clean energy and innovation and cutting greenhouse gases, Garber said. She noted a previous commitment made by the president to fellow G20 leaders to do so and said the U.S. wants to support "the cleanest and most efficient power generation, regardless of source." "The U.S. will continue supporting a balanced approach to climate mitigation, economic development, and energy security, that takes into consideration the realities of the global energy mix," Garber said. "The U.S. intends to remain engaged with our many partners and allies around the world on these issues, here at the U.N. Framework Convention, and everywhere else." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada18" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 17, 2017 Friday"source="Stratford Beacon-Herald" >
At the COP23 meeting this week in Bonn, scientists warned that abrupt environmental changes are threatening the security of humankind. Although this is not something that can be fixed, we still can try to make it less difficult to face these challenges by slowing population growth. Though paradoxical, many countries have completed, or are about to complete, the demographic transition due to efforts in child survival and basic education. The exceptions are the poorest countries, whose populations will continue to grow fast as long as their children are neglected. Therefore to stabilize the world population, the poorest countries must receive more aid for the health and education of their children. Sadly, Canadian foreign aid as a percentage of gross national product has fallen from 0.47 per cent in 1985 to only 0.25 per cent in 2017. And worse, a smaller proportion of foreign aid is dedicated to education. Yes, smaller, despite inspiring declarations and an honorary citizenship for Malala. Next February, the rich countries will announce their contributions to the Global Partnership for Education (GPE). Prime Minister Trudeau must double the Canadian contribution to the GPE because education is prevention and this is an emergency. Pamela Walden-Landry Montreal !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2017 Sun Media Corporation. All rights reserved. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada19" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="December 1, 2017 Friday"source="Toronto Sun" >
"Abandoning coal will betray the poor" presents a false choice between coal power and household biomass (Germain Belzile, Nov. 25). The poor need not exchange deaths due to choking indoor air pollution from poor-quality biomass cookstoves for deaths from outdoor air pollution due to coal power - currently numbering more than 800,000 per year worldwide. Phasing out kerosene and household coal and introducing next-generation cook stoves and solar photovoltaics helps families breathe easier indoors. Phasing out coal - recommended by the recent Lancet Countdown on Climate Change, the Canadian Public Health Association and the Canadian Medical Association - reduces greenhouse gases and deaths from outdoor air pollution, which is why I was happy to speak in support of the Powering Past Coal announcement at COP23 . Climate change is the biggest health threat of the 21st century and disproportionately impacts women living in poverty. Treating climate change with coal phase-out is a critical prescription for a healthy planet now - and in the future. DR. COURTNEY HOWARD PRESIDENT CANADIAN ASSOCIATION OF PHYSICIANS FOR THE ENVIRONMENT (Studies calculating deaths due to fossil fuels while failing to calculate lives saved due to fossil fuels - for example through the provision of reliable electricity - are suspect from the start) !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2017 Sun Media Corporation. All rights reserved. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada20" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 24, 2017 Friday"source="Prairie Post West" >
Education: the worldwide neglected solution Editor: At the recent (Conference of the Parties, United Nations Climate Conference) COP23 meeting last week (Nov. 6-17) in Bonn, scientists warned that abrupt environmental changes are threatening the security of humankind.\'ca Although this is not something that can be fixed, we still can try to make it less difficult to face these challenges by slowing population growth. Though paradoxical, many countries have completed or are about to complete the demographic transition, due to efforts in child survival and basic education. The exceptions are the poorest countries whose populations will continue to grow fast as long as their children are neglected. Therefore to stabilize the world population, the poorest countries must receive more aid for the health and education of their children. Sadly, Canadian foreign aid as a percentage of Gross National Product has fallen from 0.47% in 1985 to only 0.25% in 2017. Worse, a smaller proportion of foreign aid is dedicated to education. Yes, smaller, despite inspiring declarations and an honorary citizenship for Malala. Next February, the rich countries will announce their contributions to the Global Partnership for Education. Prime minister Trudeau must double the Canadian contribution to the GPE because education is prevention and this is an emergency. Pamela Walden-Landry, Montreal \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada21" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 14, 2017 Tuesday"source="Stratford Beacon-Herald" >
Re: Sexist taunts obscure reality of climate change (Nov. 11). Right now, hundreds of people from all over the globe are working on humanity's behalf at COP23 (Conference of the Parties) in Bonn, Germany. They are fleshing out the rule book nations will follow to keep global warming below 2C. Unfortunately, the Bonn climate talks are overshadowed by the harsh fact that greenhouse gases in our atmosphere continue to increase. We face a stark choice: up our game much faster than originally anticipated at the Paris climate talks or pay dire consequences. Scientists tell us this problem is ours to face for the larger part of this century. No more smoke and mirrors with self-serving sexist taunts. Climate change is real: let's get past the hurtful and the petty and support simple and effective carbon fee and dividend. Carole Lavall\'e9e \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada22" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 8, 2017 Wednesday 6:27 AM GMT"source="CBC News" >
Environment Minister Catherine McKenna said "clearly a mistake was made" Tuesday after a tweet from her official departmental account praised Syria for joining the Paris climate agreement. "Canada Salutes Nicaragua and Syria for joining on to the Paris Agreement! Global #ClimateAction. # COP23 Nicaragua and Syria were the final two countries to sign on to the climate accord, leaving the U.S. as the only United Nations-member state not supporting the agreement. The tweet attracted dozens of complaints from other Twitter users, many of them pointing to the widely suspected use of chemical weapons by the regime of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad. 'Your public praise is misplaced' McKenna's critics included Conservative deputy leader Lisa Raitt. "Hey @ec_minister - this ... is actually what your gov't should be saying about Syria," a tweet from Raitt's account said, linking to a U.S. State Department tweet about chemical-weapons use in Syria. Jason Kenney, leader of Alberta's United Conservative Party, also weighed in, calling the 195-nation pact "empty virtue signalling." The celebratory Nicaragua and Syria tweet was sent from @ec_minister. Its description says it is run by Environment and Climate Change Canada, Parks Canada and the Canadian Environmental Assessment Agency. McKenna tweeted her response to the controversy from her personal account, @cathmckenna. "Clearly a mistake was made from my Dept twitter. We've been clear that the murderous Assad regime must end attacks against its people." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada23" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 13, 2017 Monday"source="Northern Daily News (Kirkland Lake)" >
Climate change talks in Germany are headed for a collision course on coal this week - and Canada is right in the middle of it. Environment Minister Catherine McKenna arrived Sunday in Bonn, Germany, to attend the second week of COP23 , the annual United Nations climate change talks that two years ago led to the Paris climate change accord. This year, the parties to Paris are hammering out rules for how that accord will be implemented, how carbon will be counted and how countries will be held accountable for their emissions cuts. McKenna and her British counterpart, Claire Perry, minister of state for climate change and industry, want the conversation to focus on getting rid of coal as a power source, which is responsible for more than 40 per cent of global carbon dioxide emissions. McKenna and Perry are hosting a joint event Nov. 16 to launch a joint campaign calling for other countries to declare a plan not to build any more unabated coal-fired plants and eliminate existing ones. Unabated plants are those that have no carbon capture or storage technology to keep emissions from ending up in the atmosphere. "We want every country to look at how they can reduce their use of coal and phase it out and we want to be supporting developing countries to do so," McKenna told The Canadian Press in an interview last week. A year ago, Canada committed to eliminating coal as a source of power by 2030. Britain has committed to getting rid of it by 2025. Since Canada and the U.K. first announced their coal phase-out campaign last month, Italy and Netherlands added themselves to the list of countries aiming to get rid of coal. France had already set a 2025 coal-phase out target. But their anti-coal initiative is in direct contrast with the United States, which is kicking off the week with an event promoting all the ways fossil fuels like coal can be part of the narrative of combating climate change. "I anticipate it will be a big story this week," said Catherine Abreu, executive director of Climate Action Network Canada, who has been in Bonn since the talks began Nov. 6. Last month, Scott Pruitt, the head of the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, declared the "war on coal is over" as he tore up the U.S. Clean Power Plan, a legacy of President Barack Obama that required states to cut emissions based on energy consumption and offered incentives to foster renewable power and energy efficiency. The U.S. successfully managed to convince the G20 to include a statement about the U.S. helping other countries "access and use fossil fuels more cleanly and efficiently" in its final statement in July. On Monday, U.S. officials and fossil fuel industry representatives will make presentations about it. McKenna however said the world has already decided with its money that coal is a relic of the past. "The market has moved on coal so the good news is you now have clean energy like wind and solar that's cheaper and there's far more investments in wind and solar than there is in coal," she said. Despite her bravado, the Global Coal Plant Tracker shows plans are afoot for another 1,600 new coal plants, which once operational would expand coal power by 42 per cent around the world. China's energy companies are behind 700 of them, despite China's pledge earlier this year to scale back its coal plans at home. India's state-run National Thermal Power Corp. intends to invest more than $10 billion to build new coal plants over the next five years. If Canada and the U.K. can get China and India involved to some extent, it would be a real victory, Abreu said. She doesn't expect them to agree to phase coal out entirely, but agreeing to help would be a big step. The Greens want Germany to meet its emissions reduction targets, which would require it to abandon coal. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada24" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 9, 2017 Thursday 11:03 AM EST"source="Canadian Press" >
BERLIN - Environmental campaigners on Thursday slammed a proposal to reform the European Union's emissions trading system, saying it undermines international efforts to curb climate change. The European Commission said the preliminary agreement between the EU Parliament and member states will strengthen the bloc's emissions trading system after 2020 and would put the bloc on track to achieving "a significant part of its commitment" under the Paris Agreement. Some 195 countries are currently taking part in talks in Germany aimed at implementing the 2015 climate accord. Environmental group WWF said that while the deal will reduce the oversupply of emissions allowances that had weighed on the market, heavily polluting sectors will continue to get emissions certificates worth billions of euros for free until 2030. "You couldn't make it up," said Sam Van den Plas, a climate specialist at WWF's European policy office. "While EU negotiators at COP23 in Bonn are making progress on the Paris Agreement, EU decision-makers back in Brussels are busy undermining it." "Today's shameful agreement ... means Europe's largest emitters will be paid to pollute, rather than having to pay," he added. The Climate Action Network Europe, an alliance of environmental groups, said the EU deal would throw a lifeline to the continued use of coal, one of the most polluting forms of fossil fuel. "Instead of making polluters pay, the EU decided to do the exact opposite," said Wendel Trio, the group's director of CAN Europe. "It allowed its flagship climate tool to continue subsidizing coal plants." Several European countries, especially Germany and Poland, still rely heavily on coal to produce electricity. On Thursday, former New York City mayor Michael Bloomberg announced he is donating $50 million to encourage countries outside the United States to move away from coal. Bloomberg has already spent $64 million to campaign against the use of coal in America. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada25" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 6, 2017 Monday"source="Postmedia Breaking News" >
BONN, Germany - The Latest on global climate change talks in Bonn, Germany (all times local): 11:45 p.m. Fiji's prime minister has told climate negotiators that "the need for urgency is obvious" as diplomats opened talks on implementing the Paris agreement to fight climate change. Prime Minister Voreqe 'Frank' Bainimarama, who is chairing the two-week meeting in the German city of Bonn, offered greetings "from one of the most climate-vulnerable regions on earth" as he addressed the conference Monday. Bainimarama said nations should "meet our commitments in full, not back away from them." He didn't refer directly to President Donald Trump's announcement that the U.S. will pull out of the Paris climate accord unless his administration can secure a better deal. But Bainimarama says "the only way for every nation to put itself first is to lock arms with all other nations and move forward together." -- 9:25 a.m. Diplomats and activists have gathered in Germany for two-week talks on implementing the Paris agreement to fight climate change. Environmental groups staged protests in the western city of Bonn and at a nearby coal mine ahead of the meeting to highlight Germany's continued use of heavily polluting fossil fuels. The 23rd conference of the parties, or COP23 , will be opened Monday by Fiji's Prime Minister Voreqe 'Frank' Bainimarama. The Pacific island nation is already suffering the impacts of global warming. Negotiators will focus on thrashing out some of the technical details of the 2015 Paris accord, which aims to limit global warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius. While President Donald Trump has expressed skepticism, a recent U.S. government report concluded there's strong evidence that man-made climate change is taking place. !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2017 Postmedia Network Inc. All rights reserved. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada26" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 8, 2017 Wednesday 1:43 PM GMT"source="CBC News" >
Federal Environment Minister Catherine McKenna says a tweet from her official departmental account praising Syria for joining the Paris climate agreement was "completely unacceptable" and she takes responsibility. "Canada Salutes Nicaragua and Syria for joining on to the Paris Agreement! Global #ClimateAction. # COP23 Nicaragua and Syria were the final two countries to sign on to the climate accord, leaving the U.S. as the only United Nations-member state not supporting the agreement. The tweet attracted dozens of complaints from Twitter users, many of them pointing to the widely suspected use of chemical weapons by the regime of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad. The celebratory Nicaragua and Syria tweet was sent from @ec_minister. Its description says it is run by Environment and Climate Change Canada, Parks Canada and the Canadian Environmental Assessment Agency. McKenna has a separate personal account. "The tweet was completely unacceptable. It was from my departmental Twitter account. We took action right away as soon as we saw it. Look, I'm a human rights lawyer I know more than anyone that the murderous Assad regime and the actions that they're committing, the atrocities against their own people, are completely unacceptable," she said. "I'm the minister, I take responsibility. "I can assure everyone I will not be meeting with Syria at the Bonn climate talks that I'm going to next week." 'Your public praise is misplaced' McKenna's critics included Conservative deputy leader Lisa Raitt. "Hey @ec_minister - this ... is actually what your gov't should be saying about Syria," a tweet from Raitt's account said, linking to a U.S. State Department tweet about chemical weapons use in Syria. Jason Kenney, leader of Alberta's United Conservative Party, also weighed in, calling the 195-nation pact "empty virtue signalling." On Wednesday, Conservative Leader Andrew Scheer called the Syria tweet "unfortunate." "I can understand how that kind of thing can happen. It's unfortunate. I don't think it reflects well on the department. Certainly not something I think Canadians want to see, government officials congratulating countries led by dictators." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada27" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 22, 2017 Wednesday"source="Northern Daily News (Kirkland Lake)" >
Before the Ottawa Santa Claus parade got underway on Saturday, Liberal cabinet minister and downtown Ottawa's local MP Catherine McKenna posted to social media: "It's starting to snow just in time for the parade! As the Minister responsible for weather, I'm either a hero or a zero... depends how you feel about winter." The strange post caught observers off guard. "Pretty sure Canada does not have a Minister of Weather," Conservative Senator Linda Frum remarked. McKenna's actual title is minister of environment and climate change - a new, activist label. From 1979 until 2015 it was simply minister of environment. Prime Minister Justin Trudeau changed the post's name when he got into office to signal his passion for the green agenda. While it's clear McKenna was joking about being a hero for sprinkling Ottawa's Bank Street with snow, it's unclear whether she understood how odd it was to be rolling weather into her ministerial domain. "Even her jokes run counter to the proper functioning of her office," Postmedia columnist Lorrie Goldstein wrote. "She should be explaining that weather is not climate and climate is not weather." Regardless of what McKenna was getting at, there's been a tone to her repeated virtue-signalling on this file that lacks humility. This was echoed in her recent choice of Halloween costume: donning a green "climate crusader" super hero outfit. While Trudeau, McKenna and other government officials are jet-setting about the global cocktail circuit discussing, among other items, ways to phase out coal - as was the focus of McKenna's recent COP23 visit - back home there is a real human cost to this agenda. Shortly after entering office, the Liberals announced the doubling to $2.5 billion of the amount of taxpayer money being sent abroad into the United Nations climate coffers. This money comes from the pockets of the hardworking people McKenna and Trudeau serve, but that's rarely acknowledged. Meanwhile, people in Ontario are pushed into energy poverty by the province's green agenda - which McKenna and Trudeau seem keen to replicate nationally. All this to pursue federal targets that everyone knows we won't meet. It's one thing to approach climate change as an earnest public policy discussion. But the Liberals current angle, with its in-yourface theatrics, needs more humility. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada28" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="February 28, 2018 Wednesday"source="Postmedia Breaking News" >
On climate change - it's much easier to make targets than to follow through. That's been Edmonton's experience, says Coun. Ben Henderson, who joined Edmonton Talk Back at noon Wednesday to discuss the way forward. Ten years ago, council set an ambitious set of targets for 2018 and pledged to be carbon neutral by 2050. Then the city's population boomed. It built more recreation centres and fire stations, bought a much larger parks and roads fleet. At the same time, council balked at the planned large purchase of green energy and slowed down the LED streetlight conversion( HYPERLINK http://edmontonjournal.com/news/local-news/let-there-be-light-edmonton-continues-to-switch-street-lamps-to-leds http://edmontonjournal.com/news/local-news/let-there-be-light-edmonton-continues-to-switch-street-lamps-to-leds ). They've made some progress but not as much as hoped. In 2015, emission were nearly double the 2018 target. They've been edging down since. But with the world arriving this weekend for the United Nation's Cities and Climate Change Science Conference( HYPERLINK https://www.edmonton.ca/attractions_events/schedule_festivals_events/cities-and-climate-change-science-conference.aspx https://www.edmonton.ca/attractions_events/schedule_festivals_events/cities-and-climate-change-science-conference.aspx Henderson was part of those early discussions. He was also at the United Nations Climate Change Conference in Paris in 2015 and this term, he's rededicated himself to action( HYPERLINK http://edmontonjournal.com/news/local-news/a-snapshot-of-the-new-edmonton-councils-priorities http://edmontonjournal.com/news/local-news/a-snapshot-of-the-new-edmonton-councils-priorities ), pledging to make Edmonton's energy transition strategy a priority. Henderson says Edmonton has big decisions coming up on renovating city buildings for green energy, and on buying green energy through the grid. If it partners with the province to secure green energy for city operation, they might have a big enough buy to significantly bring down prices and change the markets for renewable energy in Alberta. But this time, council needs to understand its targets and hit them, he said. "We kept on setting objectives, then being a little dishonest about what it takes to get there." HYPERLINK mailto:estolte@postmedia.com estolte@postmedia.com HYPERLINK mailto:estolte@postmedia.com estolte@postmedia.com twitter.com/estolte( HYPERLINK http://www.twitter.com/estolte http://www.twitter.com/estolte Edmonton's greenhouse gas emission targets for city operations, excluding transit. Coming up Coun. Jon Dziadyk joins Edmonton Talk Back next Thursday at noon to discuss his council initiative on literacy. Coun. Tim Cartmell is up March 15 to discuss how to identify and fix the missing links in Edmonton's networks for biking and walking. Edmonton Talk Back started with year with an invitation to each council member to take questions on one subject they intend to focus on this term. You can alsolisten to them as a podcast here( HYPERLINK https://soundcloud.com/edmontontalkback https://soundcloud.com/edmontontalkback ). Let us know what you think of the format. Addiction is a form of mental illness. No one who accepts that could turn a blind eye to what's happening today among the homeless in Edmonton's core communities, argues Coun. Scott McKeen. McKeen joined Edmonton Talk Back to share his own story and counter the myths he said are keeping society from effectively dealing with the current crisis. People driven to homelessness from addiction need housing and support - not judgment, he said, arguing for a program to give people access to medically clean drugs in a controlled environment if that's what they need to stabilize and improve. "People physically addicted to drugs should been seen in the same light as someone suffering from cancer or diabetes," he said. Sarah Hamilton - Urban design Expect debate on the importance of welcoming urban design this term as one new city councillor promises to make that her mission. Ward 5 Coun. Sarah Hamilton is launching an initiative on design this year to city council, hoping to build a powerful lobby to ensure all the good design guidelines city council endorses actually change what Edmonton residents see on the streets. "This isn't about big projects. It's about what small changes we can make that enable good design," she said, recruiting architects, engineers, designers and residents to help understand what's standing in the way today, and how to change it. Andrew Knack - West LRT The West LRT is in the final stages of design with council set to make key decisions separating key intersections from traffic. So we asked Andrew Knack - the Ward 1 councillor who's been knee-deep in LRT planning since his community league days - to be the second guest for our new urban affairs interactive video series. Knack explains why he's not sure Edmonton should spend $200 million to $300 million on elevating the track at 109 Street and 104 Avenue. He wants the city to investigate new high-tech traffic signals across the city instead. Viewers also asked questions about vehicle access along 87 Avenue and 156 Street, about the alternative strategy for one-way traffic flow pitched by Stony Plain Road businesses, and about bus rapid transit. Aaron Paquette - Food security At City Hall, many councillors lead specific initiatives, bringing city officials and members of the community together to solve a certain issue. Aaron Paquette, councillor for Ward 4, wants his initiative to be on food security. That means being ready for the implications of climate change, such as weather patterns affecting food production or distribution. It's also about building community around food and ensuring everyone has sufficient access. Check out the story Paquette shares about his mom's role in all this at minute 3:40 in the video. Her need for food security changed the Duggan community. !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2018 Postmedia Network Inc. All rights reserved. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada29" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday"source="Postmedia Breaking News" >
Of all the empty gestures in the pathetic history of global climate policy-making, few match the air-headedness of Canada's intent - to be officially announced Thursday at the United Nations COP23 climate conference in Bonn - to lead a global campaign to rid the world of carbon-emitting coal. By any measure, Canada is a nobody in the coal business, ranking near the bottom of all global measures of the industry, worth less than one per cent of global production and consumption. Canada is a non-player, a zero, an insignificant speck on the great world coal market. But that isn't stopping Environment Minister Catherine McKenna, donning her Climate Crusader Halloween outfit, from swooshing into COP23 to take on the world. "Canada is committed to phasing out coal," she said. Not just in Canada. "We've created an alliance with the U.K., we're going to get other countries around the world to help support moving forward on a coal phase-out. Coal is not only the most polluting fossil fuel but it's also terrible for health." At last report, McKenna had recruited Italy and the Netherlands to join her anti-coal crusade. Italy, the Netherlands and the United Kingdom are just like us: tiny players in coal, but big players in the greatest climate industry of all, political posturing. It's been 25 years since the 1992 Rio Earth Summit established the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change. Over the quarter-century through 22 Conventions of the Parties and assorted protocols and agreements, from Kyoto to Copenhagen to Cancun to Paris, the great international climate-control machine has produced millions of words and kept tens of thousands of bureaucrats and NGOs, corporate-sustainability executives and politicians busy agreeing to continue to agree to do something about what they all agree is an urgent global crisis. The hallmark of the annual Conventions of the Parties (COP) events is political grandstanding surrounded by spectacle that leads nowhere. It leads nowhere for good reason. The calls to put an end to the use of fossil fuels such as coal keep running up against the reality that continued use of fossil fuels is essential to increasing economic growth and prosperity for all the world's people. Wind and solar can never provide the energy needed to power and feed the world. They cannot replace coal or oil or gas. There are no real alternatives to fossil fuels. But the UN machine, 25 years after its creation, keeps spinning out empty plans, proposals, protocols and schemes. And now Canada has offered the UN one of its own empty-headed schemes: saving the world from coal. Here's a rough ranking of the world's coal-consuming nations (as listed by endcoal.org) and ranked by megawatts of generating capacity and percentage share of global capacity: China: 922,062 MW (47%) U.S.: 281,127 MW (14.3%) India: 218,091 MW (11%) Germany: 50,826 MW (2.6%) Russia: 48,790 MW (2.5%) South Africa: 40,513 MW (2%) South Korea: 34,706 MW (1.8%) Indonesia: 28,269 MW (1.4%) Australia: 25,122 MW (1.3%) Ukraine: 23,259 MW (1.2%) Most of these countries, along with others around the world, have new coal plants under construction that, combined, will add new global capacity of 263,961 megawatts in coming years. Still more coal plants are in the planning stage. Canada, meanwhile, has zero coal plants under construction and an existing few plants with a capacity of 9,809 megawatts, equivalent to 0.45 per cent of world capacity. By announcing Ottawa's anti-coal crusade, McKenna effectively declared climate war on other nations. No, not the United States, although media reports instantly positioned her move as a brush off to Trump. As Canada the Climate Crusader flew into Bonn to fight coal, the United States - which some say is shaping up to be the world's energy superpower - staged an event promoting clean coal as the way of the future. By going after coal, Ottawa and McKenna have staked out a tricky geopolitical position. While McKenna postured in Bonn against the U.S. and coal, Prime Minister Justin Trudeau was in Manila, attempting to charm the Asians. On Monday he met with leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), a group of 10 countries with big plans to continue to boost economic development. And they plan to do it with coal. ASEAN member include Indonesia, Vietnam, Thailand and the Philippines, all of which have big coal projects in the works. Did Trudeau lean in on the Philippines' leader and whisper, "Listen, forget those coal plants or I'll send my environment minister after you?" Vietnam is also a major coal producer eager to supply the region with the coal it needs. At a meeting in September, ASEAN energy ministers reviewed forecasts that clean coal would allow the region to increase coal's share of power generation in the region from 32 per cent to 50 per cent by 2040. In a statement, the energy ministers said they "discussed the outlook through 2040 on the rising coal use in the region and reaffirmed the need for increased promotion of clean coal technologies (CCT). They acknowledged the continuing role of coal in addressing the energy security, economic competitiveness, and environmental sustainability in the region." Coal power is abundant and affordable, and experts say clean coal can help supply the world's developing nations with the new energy it needs to grow and prosper. This is one case where the world meeting in Bonn does not need more Canada and its crusading politicians. !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2017 Postmedia Network Inc. All rights reserved. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada30" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="December 21, 2017 Thursday"source="Daily Herald-Tribune (Grande Prairie)" >
In 2017, Prime Minister Justin Trudeau continued to portray man-made climate change as an imminent, existential threat to humanity, while doing little to lower Canada's industrial greenhouse gas emissions linked to global warming. The disconnect between the Liberals£pocalyptic rhetoric on climate change, most often in the pronouncements of Environment Minister Catherine McKenna, and their lack of meaningful action, actually began before they won power in 2015. In opposition, Trudeau mocked former prime minister Stephen Harper's emission reduction targets as international embarrassments. Once in office, McKenna described them as the floor of what the Liberals would achieve. Today, the United Nations - the organization Trudeau made these commitments to - says Canada will miss these targets "by a wide margin". Unless it buys billions of dollars worth of carbon offsets annually on global carbon markets. The problem, which the UN acknowledges, is that these markets are riddled with fraud. Thus offsets do not reliably reduce emissions. The UN likes Trudeau because, unlike Harper, he makes a show of supporting its climate change agenda. It was being kind in saying Trudeau's unlikely to achieve his targets. It's impossible to achieve them. To reach his 2020 target, Trudeau would have to reduce Canada's emissions by 111 megatonnes annually within three years, the equivalent of shutting down our entire electricity sector (79 Mt annually) and 44% of our agricultural sector (73 Mt annually). To achieve his 2030 target, Trudeau would have to reduce Canada's emissions by 219 megatonnes annually within 13 years, the equivalent of shutting down our entire transportation sector (173 Mt annually), plus our entire waste disposal sector (48 Mt annually). Between 2014 and 2015, the last year for which statistics are available, Canada reduced emissions by five megatonnes. To achieve Trudeau's promised reductions would require the immediate imposition of a Canadian carbon price of hundreds of dollars per tonne of emissions. McKenna just announced the delay, until the end of 2018, of the implementation of Trudeau's national mandatory minimum carbon price for the provinces and territories, starting at $10 per tonne in 2018, rising to $50 per tonne in 2022. McKenna regularly makes announcements to create the impression of action in the absence of action. At a UN conference on climate change in Bonn, Germany in November, McKenna proclaimed Canada would be a leading player in international efforts to "power past coal". Coal is largely irrelevant to Canadian emissions since we get only 10% of our electricity from it. This is extremely low by international standards, primarily because Ontario's Liberal government unilaterally shut down the last of its coalfired power plants in 2014, with no help from Ottawa, when the Harper government was in power. Less than a month after her "power past coal" announcement, McKenna merely shrugged while in Beijing, acknowledging China, the world's largest consumer of coal which gets 70% of its electricity from it, refused to join the "power past coal" initiative. "I just don't think they're in a position to sign on yet," she said. Carbon pricing in Canada is being implemented independently by provinces like Ontario and Alberta, but because there's no requirement that it be revenue neutral, these are just cynical, ineffective cash grabs from the public. The Trudeau government, no doubt, will continue to talk big about lowering emissions in 2018, without lowering them. mailto:lgoldstein@postmedia.com lgoldstein@postmedia.com @sunlorrie !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2017 Sun Media Corporation. All rights reserved. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada31" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="December 7, 2017 Thursday"source="Quesnel Cariboo Observer" >
Editor, The struggle to keep humanity below 2.0C at COP 23 , in Bonn Germany, expresses a deficiency of social feeling and social co-operation. The world committed half of what is needed to stay below 2.0C. Dire warnings of 15,000 scientists around the world are being made real. Runaway global warming is to be our fate. Humanity can still strive for human decency by evolving an ideal global human community. Seventeen United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (UNSDG) achieved by 2030 is humanity's last chance for social ideals globally. Possible is a world of equality, justice, and peace. This is doable. All human progress, without knowing how to live in peace, justice, and equality with each other, is worthless. Some 15,000 scientist's 2017 "Letter to Humanity" enlightens us clearly. We are destroying the planet's ecosystem we all depend on for decent human survival. Their gift to each of us includes 13 suggested steps to avert global climate disaster. Ayn Rand's The Virtue of Selfishness turned vice into virtue and virtue into vice; ultra-right's credo. When we speak of virtue, we mean each person contributing their share for the whole. When we speak of vice, we mean selfish obstruction of social cooperation. Rand is a social failure because she denigrated social feeling and social co-operation necessary for social survival. Elevating selfishness leads to social destruction. Be "One for All and All for One" opposed to "Every Man for Himself." From COP 1 to COP 23 , we witnessed failure to keep global temperature from passing 1.5C. We witnessed failure to stay below humanity's red line. COP 24 in Poland, 2018, will be where anti-social obstruction for social co-operation persists. For human decency, it is crucial that we each know confidently, the 17 UNSDG's achievable by 2030 with social feeling and social co-operation unobstructed. Herb Nakada Williams Lake \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada32" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="July 25, 2017 Tuesday"source="Northumberland News" >
COBOURG - With the environment on the minds of many Canadians in light of recent wildfires and flooding, Cobourg residents may be surprised to learn two of its own hold senior roles working on Canada's climate change initiatives. Cobourg District Collegiate Institute West graduates Matt Jones and Catherine Stewart both work on climate change in top positions in the federal government. Jones is assistant deputy minister at Environment and Climate Change Canada, responsible for implementing Canada's domestic action plan on climate change - The Pan-Canadian Framework. Stewart, the daughter of Christine Stewart, MP for Northumberland from 1988-2000 and former minister of the environment, has just recently taken on the role of Canada's chief negotiator for climate change. Although they both grew up in Cobourg and graduated from Cobourg District Collegiate Institute West (Stewart in the late 1980s and Jones in the early 1990s), they never knew each other until they met in Ottawa around the time of the United Nations Climate Change Conference in Paris in late 2015, said Stewart. Most recently, they met at the United Nations Climate meeting held in Bonn, Germany. After earning a master's degree in public policy and administration from Carleton University, Stewart worked in the Privy Council Office, Foreign Affairs and the Department of National Defense before coming to work at the Environment and Climate Change Canada. When she joined Environment and Climate Change Canada in 2014, she recalled walking in the minister's office and seeing a portrait of her mother, Christine, hanging with all the other former ministers. She recalled thinking how it was a cool point in her career. Aside from family connection, Stewart feels the environment is an important issue. "I think this is the issue of today - I think we need to take action on climate change," said Stewart in a telephone interview from Ottawa. There has been a real momentum gathering since the Paris Climate Agreement. It is not just governments but youth, businesses and others are more aware of climate change. "It is really exciting to be part of that momentum." Stewart said she admired her mother and followed her career but is happy working as a public servant and has no plans to run for office. As Canada's chief negotiator for climate change, Stewart travels around the world for climate change meetings. The countries who signed the Paris Climate Agreement meet regularly to ensure goals are met to reduce carbon emissions. In her role she also supports the minister of environment and climate change in foreign meetings. She recently travelled to Bologna, Italy, for the G7 meeting. With three teenage boys at home, life is busy. Her husband, who she met growing up in Northumberland, also has a busy job and it can be tough on the family. There are challenges balancing the job and family, she said. "The park on Fourth Street was like a swamp," Jones said in a telephone interview from Ottawa. Jones studied economics and also earned a master's degree in public policy and administration at Carleton University. He started in a junior position as a public servant and worked his way up in what is now Environment and Climate Change Canada. After the climate change conference in Paris, Jones spent about a year as part of a team working on Canada's Pan-Canadian Framework or the domestic action plan on climate change. Canada has set a target to reduce its greenhouse gas emissions by 30 per cent below 2005 levels by 2030. "My team did the work to set that target," said Jones. In his new position as an assistant deputy minister at Environment and Climate Change Canada, he is working on implementing the plan. The Pan-Canadian Framework includes how to adapt to the climate change. "We know these extreme (weather) events are coming - how do we adapt," said Jones. Climate change is impacting the intensity and frequency of events such as floods, wildfires, drought, extreme heat, high winds and winter road failures, according to the Pan-Canadian Framework. Part of adaptation includes working on infrastructure to reduce disaster risks and protect communities from climate-related hazards such as flooding and wildfires. Traditionally-built infrastructure such as roads, dykes, seawalls and bridges must be adapted to address changes in climate. Natural infrastructure such as constructed/managed wetlands and urban forests can built to deliver additional benefits, such as carbon storage and health benefits. Federal, provincial, and territorial governments will also work together through the National Disaster Mitigation Program to develop and modernize flood maps and to assess and address flood risks. What is the Pan-Canadian Framework? The Pan-Canadian Framework on Clean Growth and Climate Change is Canada's plan - developed with the provinces and territories and in consultation with Indigenous peoples - to meet emissions reduction target and grow the economy. The Pan-Canadian Framework has four main pillars: pricing carbon pollution; complementary measures to further reduce emissions across the economy; measures to adapt to the impacts of climate change and build resilience; and actions to accelerate innovation, support clean technology and create jobs. In implementing the Pan-Canadian Framework on Clean Growth and Climate Change, federal, provincial and territorial governments will review progress annually to assess the effectiveness of the collective actions and ensure continual improvement. Visit HYPERLINK https://www.canada.ca/en/services/environment/weather/climatechange/pan-canadian-framework.html https://www.canada.ca/en/services/environment/weather/climatechange/pan-canadian-framework.html for more information. Climate change fast facts: In Canada's Arctic, the average temperature has increased at a rate of nearly three times the global average. Over the period 1948 to 2013, the average annual temperature in Canada has warmed by 1.6 C. Canada has generally become wetter in recent decades with increasing annual average precipitation. Global average sea level rose about 21 centimetres between 1880 and 2012 at an average rate of 1.6 millimetres/year Glaciers in British Columbia and Alberta have lost, respectively, about 11 per cent and 25 per cent of their surface area over the period 1985-2005, while glaciers in Yukon have lost about 22 per cent since the 1950s Source: Environment and Climate Change Canada Load-Date: \~July 29, 2017 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada33" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 10, 2017 Friday"source="Cornwall Standard Freeholder" >
It was, declared Environment and Climate Change Minister Catherine McKenna with the equivalent of a Twitter shrug, "a mistake." The mistake being that Canada, through her ministry, had tweeted its congratulations to Syria for signing the Paris climate accord in a Twitter account that features a smiling McKenna as its avatar. This on the same day a United Nations investigation concluded Syrian President Bashar al-Assad's government used sarin gas against his own people in Khan Shaykhun on April, 4, 2017, killing 100. That was part of the ongoing, sixyear Syrian civil war, in which 470,000 have died and 13.5 million of the country's 22 million people are in need of humanitarian assistance, including six million Syrians displaced internally and five million made refugees - 33,266 accepted by Canada in 2016 alone. But, good job, tweeted our government through its "Minister C. McKenna @ec_minister" Twitter site, declaring: "Canada salutes Nicaragua and Syria for joining on to the Paris Agreement!Global#Climate Action.# COP23 ," illustrated by the flags of both countries. Within minutes, Deputy Conservative Leader Lisa Raitt tweeted back: "Hey @ec_minister - this is actually what your gov't should be saying about Syria. Your public praise is misplaced," citing a speech by American UN ambassador Nikki Haley to the Security Council on that same day about the use of chemical weapons in Syria by its government and ISIS. Alberta United Conservative Party Leader Jason Kenney tweeted: "Trudeau Govt in one tweet. Butcher Assad: never mind that unpleasantness about gassing kids. You've joined us in empty virtue signalling!" As many others, aghast at Canada's praise for the murderous Syrian regime, took McKenna to task, her ministry deleted its pro-Syrian tweet and McKenna tweeted in response to Raitt, on her own, "Catherine McKenna @cathmckenna" account (which also features a photo of her smiling as its avatar): "Clearly a mistake was made from my Dept Twitter. We've been clear that the murderous Assad regime must end attacks against its people." Unfortunately, the impact of McKenna's correction was diminished somewhat by the fact the pinned tweet on her personal account (one chosen by the user to be the first tweet everyone who comes to the site sees) was a picture of McKenna posing as a "Climate Crusader" in a green mask, beside Justin Trudeau as Clark Kent/Superman, with the message, "We all need to be superheros (sic) in the fight against climate change. #HappyHalloween Canada! #ClimateCrusader." This is aside from the fact McKenna's account is a never-ending litany of photos of happy people and happy minister McKenna, reminding one of the satirical DPRK_News parody Twitter site, which features pictures of happy North Koreans and happy North Korean dictator Kim Jong-un. The other big feature on McKenna's personal Twitter account is neverending happy stories about renewable energy and government programs to address climate change, so much so that you would never know the government she represents claims the world faces an imminent, existential threat from global warming in which hundreds of millions of people will soon die. Nor that Canada won't meet its 2020 or 2030 UN greenhouse gas reduction targets unless it buys billions of dollars worth of useless carbon offsets on fraud-ridden global carbon markets. But hey, we can all be "superheros" (sic) in the fight against climate change. HYPERLINK mailto:lgoldstein@postmedia.com lgoldstein@postmedia.com Load-Date: \~November 10, 2017 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada34" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="June 26, 2017 Monday"source="MetroNews.ca" >
An Inconvenient Truth about climate change was more of a call to action for one of Vancouver's leading clean tech companies. "A friend of mine attended the UN conference on climate change and shared that data with me before the documentary had come out," Cheam recalled. "I was in university at the time and when I heard it, I felt very compelled personally to do something to address the problem of climate change. And so Neurio started and has always been a very purpose-driven company." Collaborating with engineering students as part of a school project, Cheam conceptualized a business dedicated to helping people achieve zero-carbon homes and prototyped an energy monitor that would tell users how much electricity any device plugged into a wall socket was consuming. Twelve years later, Neurio employs 25 people - from hardware and software engineers to data scientists - and sells energy monitors and analytics software to residential solar panel installers. The Vancouver-based company's technology can now be found in more than 120,000 solar-powered homes, mostly in the United States. The plan is to hit one million homes. "We evolved from a product you would install in a socket to monitor a single appliance to being able to monitor a whole home's energy consumption," Cheam, president and CEO of the company, said. "The product, the customer and the market have all evolved over time, but the main purpose of getting zero-carbon homes has been the consistent trend through all the different pivots that we've had." Cheam said the current focus of the company is on providing hardware and software to installers that proves switching to alternative energy isn't just good for the environment. "If we're actually going to achieve the greater goal of zero-carbon homes, we really have to be supportive of the alternative energy industry, like residential solar storage," she said. "In order to compete, you actually have to be better than traditional power or you're not going to win. So it has to be better priced but it also has to be better in experience. "Everybody would love to be more energy efficient and reduce their environmental footprint. But the hard part is what you have to give up to do so." Cheam said Neurio's energy monitors and solar expansion kits help co-ordinate the various components that make up a solar power system - the panels, batteries and pumps - to work as one, while its apps and data software allow homeowners to squeeze the most out of the power they generate and store. "In a world without Neurio, if you were to go solar, all you would know is how much [electricity] you generate. There would be no data to tell you how much you saved because the system doesn't actually know how you consume power in your home," Cheam said. "If you have that data, you can do the math. If you generate X amount and use Y amount, this is how much savings. In the context of the home, you know when you should be charging or discharging your batteries so we can maximize the amount of savings and achieve the amount of power that you want to draw to run your air conditioner or television and everything else. "When you have solar storage and when you have energy data, we've created a paradigm shift where going green, switching to alternative energy, doesn't mean you have to give up your lifestyle." Having those tools in hand also turns each homeowner into an energy use expert, bringing Cheam one step closer to fulfilling her original desire to tackle climate change. "The energy industry is the No.1 contributor of carbon," said Cheam. "If you can make that relatable on a very personal level and educate people in their homes, they will continue to be educated when they walk out of their home." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada35" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 26, 2017 Sunday"source="Ottawa Sun" >
This year's edition of the Great Greenhouse Gas Show, COP23 , has just been held in Bonn, Germany. During the event, Canada's Environment Minister, Catherine McKenna, along with her British counterpart, worked on building a coalition of countries that will push for eliminating coal-fired power. There's just one small problem: Even if coal-fired power plants only account for 11% of Canada's electricity capacity, and that percentage is decreasing, 41% of the world's production of electricity is fueled by coal. For poorer countries, coal is often the best choice in extending the availability of electricity to households. According to the International Energy Agency (IEA), about 1.1 billion people, among the poorest on the planet, have no access to electricity in their homes in 2017, and 2.8 billion use wood, kerosene, dung, or coal fires for their daily cooking and heating needs. Interior air pollution, because of these household fires, is responsible for 2.8 million premature deaths per year in the developing world. Collecting wood is furthermore a time-consuming activity (mainly falling on the shoulders of women) and this time could be put to better use. In 2030, the IEA predicts that 675 million humans will still have no access to electricity, and 2.3 billion will still be wasting their time trying to collect enough fuel, which will pollute the air they breathe at home. Yet, much progress is being made: From 2000 to 2012, 60 million more people per year got access to electricity. Since 2012, this progress has accelerated to 100 million per year. But we still have a long way to go, and this road to success is paved, and will continue to be paved for a good long while, with coal, an inexpensive and technologically easy to use energy source. In fact, the countries that have recently made the biggest breakthroughs in electricity accessibility (Indonesia, China, and India) have also built substantial numbers of coal-fired power plants. But shouldn't we be focusing on reducing GHG emissions? According to the IEA, even if producing electricity with coal produces significant GHG emissions, it also leads to a reduction of the burning of biomass and coal by households. The net effect of the use of coal to power electricity plants is therefore null or negligible, simply because if developing countries can't use coal to produce electricity, their citizens will turn to even more polluting ways of cooking and heating their homes. Leading by example instead of moralizing the poor Canada's campaign against coal power plants is ill advised. If it works, it will have very little effect on global GHG emissions. Success would, however, contribute to keeping more people living in miserable conditions. In fact, this war on coal is a war on the planet's poorest people. The poorest of the poor. In countries in which access to electricity is not a problem, such as Canada and the United Kingdom, reducing the use of coal is probably a good idea, as long as there are economic alternatives. So why don't we lead by example, instead of trying to impose a useless burden on the developing world. !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2017 Sun Media Corporation. All rights reserved. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada36" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 11, 2017 Saturday"source="Postmedia Breaking News" >
A Vision Vancouver councillor plans to introduce a motion seeking to address a perception of "undisclosed conflicts" for councillors who work for public relations firms, while a rival NPA councillor says the motion is a "thinly veiled reference" to him and a waste of time. Next week's council agenda includes a motion entitled "Transparency in Financial Disclosure by Members of Council( http://council.vancouver.ca/20171114/documents/motionb1.pdf http://council.vancouver.ca/20171114/documents/motionb1.pdf )" set to be moved by Vision Coun. Andrea Reimer. The motion would ask city staff to "provide a mechanism for members of the public to have access to information on potential conflicts of interest for members of council" working for communications or government relations firms. Reimer, in Germany Friday for the COP23 climate forum, said by email: "The motion seeks disclosure from members of council on all their financial interests in the case where the nature of their employment - lobbyists, consultants - obscures those financial interests ... Just as the public would have the right to know if he worked for a corporation directly, the public has a right to know if a councillor is being paid to lobby on behalf of a corporation." Reimer said one possible outcome of the motion could be the City Clerk asking councillors for a list of clients served through their work with a communications or lobbying firm. Reimer's motion says: "Recently a Councillor stated they would donate 100 per cent of their publicly funded salary to charity indicating they receive substantial personal financial benefit from private interests but the exact interests are unclear due to the nature of their external employment." Reimer did not answer in her email whether this was a reference to council's newest addition, NPA Coun. Hector Bremner, but he believed it was. Bremner, elected in last month's byelection to replace departing Vision Coun. Geoff Meggs, is the vice-president of public affairs for communications firm Pace Group, and has registered in the past with B.C.'s lobbyist registry. During the byelection campaign, Bremner told The Vancouver Courier( HYPERLINK http://www.vancourier.com/news/vision-is-done-says-new-npa-councillor-1.23064973 http://www.vancourier.com/news/vision-is-done-says-new-npa-councillor-1.23064973 ) he "would commit to donate( \~ HYPERLINK http://www.vancourier.com/news/new-vancouver-city-councillor-makes-debut-1.23080203 http://www.vancourier.com/news/new-vancouver-city-councillor-makes-debut-1.23080203 ) his $82,000 councillor salary this year to 'whatever worthy cause.'" On Friday, Postmedia asked Bremner about his plans for his salary, and he said he still planned to donate some amount of it, but had not yet finalized a plan. Bremner said Reimer's motion has more to do with "casting aspersions" and scoring political points than improving transparency. "I'm not quite sure what it accomplishes over and above what the existing law does," Bremner said, adding he plans to abide by the well-established conflict and disclosure laws governing council. Bremner said it's unfortunate this motion could "move the conversation away from issues that matter," such as the city's escalating homelessness and ongoing opioid crisis. "I fully support any measure to add confidence and transparency," Bremner said, adding he supports municipal campaign finance reform as well, although he had questions and criticisms about details of the B.C. NDP's plan on that front. "But it's pretty clear this is about politics and it's not about any serious concern," he said. "I don't know if this is really an effective use of anybody's time." Reimer's motion is on the agenda for Tuesday's council meeting. HYPERLINK mailto:dfumano@postmedia.com dfumano@postmedia.com HYPERLINK mailto:dfumano@postmedia.com dfumano@postmedia.com twitter.com/fumano( HYPERLINK http://twitter.com/fumano http://twitter.com/fumano Load-Date: \~November 10, 2017 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada37" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 22, 2017 Wednesday"source="The Taber Times" >
Story courtesy of energynow.ca Climate change talks in Germany were headed for a collision course on coal last week - and Canada is in the middle of it. Environment Minister Catherine McKenna arrived in Bonn, Germany, to attend the second week of COP23 This year, the parties to Paris are hammering out rules for how that accord will be implemented, how carbon will be counted and how countries will be held accountable for their emissions cuts. McKenna and her British counterpart, Claire Perry, minister of state for climate change and industry, want the conversation to focus on getting rid of coal as a power source, which is responsible for more than 40 per cent of global carbon dioxide emissions. McKenna and Perry hosted a joint event Nov. 16 to launch a campaign calling for other countries to declare a plan not to build any more unabated coal-fired plants and eliminate existing ones. Unabated plants are those that have no carbon capture or storage technology to keep emissions from ending up in the atmosphere. "We want every country to look at how they can reduce their use of coal and phase it out and we want to be supporting developing countries to do so," McKenna told The Canadian Press in an interview. McKenna did not, however, commit any additional money to the program. About 10 per cent of electricity in Canada comes from coal, and 40 per cent of the electricity around the world is generated by coal-fired power plants. A year ago, Canada committed to eliminating coal as a source of power by 2030. Britain has committed to getting rid of it by 2025. Since Canada and the U.K. first announced their coal phase-out campaign last month, Italy and Netherlands added themselves to the list of countries aiming to get rid of coal. France had already set a 2025 coal-phase out target. But their anti-coal initiative is in direct contrast with the United States, which kicked off the week with an event promoting all the ways fossil fuels like coal can be part of the narrative of combating climate change. "I anticipate it will be a big story this week," said Catherine Abreu, executive director of Climate Action Network Canada, who has been in Bonn since the talks began Nov. 6. Last month, Scott Pruitt, the head of the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, declared the "war on coal is over" as he tore up the U.S. Clean Power Plan, a legacy of President Barack Obama that required states to cut emissions based on energy consumption and offered incentives to foster renewable power and energy efficiency. The U.S. successfully managed to convince the G20 to include a statement about the U.S. helping other countries "access and use fossil fuels more cleanly and efficiently" in its final statement in July. McKenna however said the world has already decided with its money that coal is a relic of the past. "The market has moved on coal so the good news is you now have clean energy like wind and solar that's cheaper and there's far more investments in wind and solar than there is in coal," she said. Despite her bravado, the Global Coal Plant Tracker shows plans are afoot for another 1,600 new coal plants, which once operational would expand coal power by 42 per cent around the world. China's energy companies are behind 700 of them, despite China's pledge earlier this year to scale back its coal plans at home. India's staterun National Thermal Power Corp. intends to invest more than $10 billion to build new coal plants over the next five years. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada38" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="September 19, 2017 Tuesday"source="Canadian Government News" >
Ottawa: Royal Canadian Mounted Police has issued the following news release: Canada, China, and the European Union convened the Ministerial Meeting on Climate Action to advance discussions on the full implementation of the Paris Agreement and to demonstrate continued political commitment to global action. Representatives from 34 governments of major economies and other key players on climate change met in Montreal, Canada. Ambassador Nazhat Shameem Khan of Fiji facilitated the meeting with representatives from Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Chile, China, Ecuador, Egypt, Estonia, Ethiopia, EU, Fiji, France, Germany, India, Indonesia, Italy, Japan, Maldives, Mali, Marshall Islands, Mexico, Morocco, Norway, Poland, Republic of Korea, Russian Federation, Rwanda, Saudi Arabia, South Africa, Spain, Turkey, United Kingdom, and the United States. Recognizing that the environment and the economy go hand-in-hand and that ambitious climate action will protect the environment, spur clean growth and sustainable development, create jobs, and improve human health, many emphasized that global efforts are at a critical juncture and indicated a strong commitment to the full implementation of the Paris Agreement. Further, many expressed that the Paris Agreement is irreversible and all stated that it will not be renegotiated. The United States re-confirmed that it will withdraw from the Paris Agreement but is open to re-engaging on terms more favourable to it. Recognizing the importance of providing clarity and certainty to all actors, including investors, many participants acknowledged their political commitment to complete the Paris Work Programme in 2018. Many expressed the importance of the Paris Agreement and its modalities, procedures, and guidelines to continue to build trust and help solidify confidence in the global commitment to climate action. It was highlighted that technical negotiations at COP23 should build on the spirit of Paris, and be constructive and balanced to advance consensus on modalities, procedures and guidelines that will help all Parties in the implementation of their Paris Agreement obligations. There was support for the efforts of the Moroccan and Fijian COP Presidencies in determining the modalities for the 2018 Facilitative Dialogue, based on consultations with Parties. It was reiterated that the Dialogue should help Parties take stock of progress made and further drive ambition, including in collaboration with non-state actors. The importance of pre-2020 action and the need to build on current efforts were acknowledged. Many also pointed to the importance of financial, technology and capacity building support and recognized the progress being made. Furthermore, many highlighted their support for the Marrakesh Partnership on Global Climate Action and that sub-national governments, Indigenous and local communities, and non-party actors are essential in achieving these objectives and that multilateral processes should continue to be more inclusive and recognize the importance of gender equality. To share lessons and best practices, many participants highlighted their countries\' approaches and experiences in reducing emissions and adapting to climate change, and broadly emphasized their steadfast determination to implementing these efforts and their Nationally Determined Contributions. It was underscored that taking action now is critical in order to accelerate the global transition to a low-carbon and resilient economy. A number of participants welcomed the momentum and movements of the market in that regard and underscored the importance of carbon pricing. In light of the commitment to moving forward together and demonstrating progress, a strong message was sent to negotiators to carry forward the positive and open spirit of the Ministerial on Climate Action to advance their work on implementing the Paris Agreement through the completion of the Paris Work Programme and the 2018 Facilitative Dialogue. Canada, China and the European Union were thanked for taking this initiative and for their offer to co-convene a second meeting in 2018 in Europe. In case of any query regarding this article or other content needs please contact: HYPERLINK mailto:editorial@plusmediasolutions.com editorial@plusmediasolutions.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada39" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 4, 2017 Saturday 11:07 AM EST"source="Canadian Press" >
BERLIN - Climate change is back on the agenda with a global climate conference kicking off Monday in the German city of Bonn. Who's coming, what are the key debates about and how green will this meeting be? Five things to know about the U.N. conference known as COP23 , which runs from Nov. 6-17. ____ WHO IS COMING TO BONN? Up to 25,000 people are expected to attend the talks, which will be presided over by Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama of Fiji - the first time that a small island nation will be at the helm of a major international climate conference. Participants will include diplomats from 195 nations, as well as scientists, lobbyists and environmentalists. The United States, which has announced its intention to pull out of the landmark Paris climate accord, will be represented by Undersecretary of State for Political Affairs Thomas Shannon. Key countries to watch during the talks are the emerging economic powers China and India. Other nations - Estonia, Peru, Ecuador, Iran, Mali, Ethiopia and the Maldives - will also be in the spotlight for leading major international groupings. French President Emmanuel Macron, German Chancellor Angela Merkel and other leaders are expected to fly to Bonn toward the end of the summit to give the talks a final push and signal their commitment to fighting climate change. ___ WHAT ARE THE BIG CLIMATE CHANGE TOPICS NOW? The 2015 Paris accord set a target of limiting global warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius (2.7 degrees Fahrenheit) - or 2 degrees at the most - by the end of the century. This includes coming up with international standards for how to measure carbon emissions, to make sure that one nation's efforts can be compare to another's. A second debate centres around how countries take stock of what's been achieved and set new, more ambitious goals for curbing carbon emissions after 2020. The third big issue concerns money. Experts agree that shifting economies away from fossil fuels and preparing countries for some of the inevitable consequences of climate change will require vast financial resources - including some from the U.S. administration of President Donald Trump, which is doubtful about man-made climate change. ___ WHY BONN? Organizing a massive global conference in Fiji would have strained the Pacific nation's resources and posed a travel nightmare for thousands of delegates. Germany offered to host the talks in Bonn, the country's former capital, because it has ample conference space and is already home to the U.N. climate change agency. Still, they are going to miss the sunshine of Fiji. The weather in Bonn is generally dreary at best in November. ___ HOW GREEN WILL THE CONFERENCE BE? Germany says the two-week talks will as environmentally friendly as possible. The country is setting aside part of the 117 million euro ($136.3 million) budget for a fleet of bicycles and electric buses to ferry people between venues. Each participant will receive a bottle to fill with tap water - a move organizers say will save half a million plastic cups. Germany's environment ministry is also investing in renewable energy projects to compensate for the greenhouse gas emissions caused by people from all over the world flying into Bonn for the talks. ___ AND WHAT ABOUT GERMANY'S COAL USAGE? Germany likes to portray itself as a leader in the fight against global warming and Merkel's reputation as the "climate chancellor" is partly built on the pivotal role she played during past negotiations. But environmentalists note that Germany still gets about 40 per cent of its electricity from coal-fired plants - one of the most carbon intensive sources of energy. And German highways are also virtually unique in having no general speed limit, despite the fact that auto emissions rise dramatically at higher speeds. If prosperous Germany fails to meet its own emissions targets, as current predictions suggest, critics say that would send a bad signal to the rest of the world. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada40" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 17, 2017 Friday"source="St. Catherine's Standard" >
At a car factory in this city named after Toyota, the usual robots with their swinging arms are missing. Instead, workers intently fit parts into place by hand with craftsmanship-like care. The big moment on the assembly line comes when two bulbous yellow tanks of hydrogen are rolled over and delicately fitted into each car's underside. While much of the world is going gung-ho for electric vehicles to help get rid of auto emissions and end reliance on fossil fuels, Japan's top automaker Toyota Motor Corp. is banking on hydrogen. Toyota sells about 10 million vehicles a year around the world. It has sold only about 4,000 Mirai fuel-cell vehicles since late 2014, roughly half of them outside Japan. The Mirai, which means "future," is not cheap at $57,500, but Toyota loses money on each one. Still, the company's goal is to sell 30,000 fuel-cell vehicles a year by about 2020. Hydrogen fuel cells don't suffer the EVs'main drawback of limited range. The Tesla Model S can go about 480 km on a single charge, although that varies depending on driving conditions, and that's quite a distance for an EV. Other models run out of juice quicker, at about half that, because the longer the range, generally the heavier the batteries. And electric vehicles usually take hours to charge. The Mirai can run for 502 km per fuelling, under U.S. EPA conditions, and fuels as quickly as a regular car. Toyota's chairman, Takeshi Uchiyamada, believes hydrogen is an ideal, stable fuel for a future lowcarbon society. "In this light, hydrogen holds tremendous potential," Uchiyamada, known as "the father of the Prius," the world's top-selling hybrid car, said during a tour of the factory. "Hydrogen doesn't exist in the natural world on its own, but you can create hydrogen from various materials," he said. The Prius turned out to be a good bet for Toyota. The Mirai could be the same. But not everyone shares Uchiyamada's enthusiasm for hydrogen. A fuel cell mixes hydrogen with the oxygen in the air to generate electricity that can power a motor. Producing the highly flammable gas and getting it into the vehicles requires energy. Ultimately, the idea is to convert energy from renewables like wind and solar power into hydrogen, or even make hydrogen from sewage waste. Unlike a gas-powered internal combustion engine, the only byproducts from a fuel cell are electricity, heat and water. There are no emissions of pollutants that can cause global warming. So fuel cells could be used to power cars, trains, buses, trucks and forklifts, and to provide electricity and heat for homes. Detroit-based General Motors Co., Mercedes-Benz of Germany, Japan's Honda Motor Co. and Hyundai of South Korea have also developed fuel-cell vehicles that are on the roads in extremely limited numbers. The global stock of electric vehicles will soon surpass 2 million, according to the International Energy Agency. It's projected to climb to between 9 million-20 million by 2020. Fuel cell vehicles are scarcely a presence. The Hydrogen Council, made up of 28 companies that are promoting hydrogen fuel, said in a report this week that it expects hydrogen to power about 10 to 15 million cars and 500,000 trucks by 2030. It also forecasts it will be widely used for industries, heating and power and power storage. The group met this week in Bonn, on the sidelines of the COP23 UN meeting on the environment. Toyota and other manufacturers pursuing hydrogen fuel cells face some significant hurdles. Japan has an ample 28,000 EV charging stations but only 92 hydrogen fuelling stations, and they are costly to build. Hydrogen is viewed as potentially hazardous: The 1937 Hindenberg disaster, when 36 people died when the hydrogen-fueled airship caught fire and crashed, ended an earlier era of hydrogen-powered passenger travel. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada41" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 10, 2017 Friday"source="CTV NEWS CHANNEL Television, Inc. POWER PLAY WITH DON MARTIN 17:00:00 ET" >
OMAR SACHEDINA: Good evening, everyone, and welcome to "Power Play" for Friday, November 10th. A day when talks on the Trans-Pacific Partnership began with problems ended with progress and now questions about what's next. We'll get to that top story in just a moment. Also ahead, the prime minister and Aung San Suu Kyi have a face-to-face meeting. What did Justin Trudeau say to the honourary Canadian citizenship who many have accused of turning a blind eye to a catastrophic humanitarian crisis that's displaced hundreds of thousands of Rohingya Muslims from Myanmar? We'll also have a chat with the environment minister, Catherine McKenna, as she heads to Germany for the annual UN conference on climate change . And new details on how Ottawa will tax marijuana users. But first, let's get to some breaking news right now. CTV News has learned the ethics commissioner is examining Finance Minister Bill Morneau and his involvement in Bill C-27. NDP ethics critic Nathan Cullen first raised that issue with the commissioner, Mary Dawson, last month. He joins me now from Terrace, British Columbia, via Facetime. So, Nathan, when did you get this letter and notification from the ethics commissioner? NATHAN CULLEN (NDP Ethics Critic): I'm just looking at the letter here. It would have been about an hour ago. So Ms. Dawson wrote to us, and she's using a section that I think it's somewhat important, 45.1 of the code. I'll read it to you. It says, if the commissioner has reason to believe that a public office holder has contravened the act, the commissioner may examine this on his or her initiative, which I think is what's happened here is that we wrote the commissioner, as you know, some time ago. She has decided on her own initiative that there's enough evidence with Mr. Morneau and a potential conflict of interest that she's opening up an investigation into the finance minister. SACHEDINA: The finance minister's office is saying this is an examination and not an investigation. Is this just a game of semantics? What do you think about that? CULLEN: Yeah. This is, section 45.1 is, this is how it's done. I'm not sure that it would be smart for the Liberals to try to split hairs and use legalistic terms because it's, just admit to what's happened. There's been a problem from the very beginning. This finance minister told us that he put his shares in Morneau Shepell, I mean it bears retelling, Omar, that why are we here? He told us that these were in a blind trust. They weren't. They used an ethical loophole to get around that. He introduced a pension bill which his company and he used to advocate for because they made money from it. Now he's in the public sector. He's an elected member of parliament, and he introduced the bill. We had concerns with that, and now we have Ms. Dawson, our ethics commissioner, doing an investigation into the potential conflict of interest. I think just admitting to what is obvious to everybody would be a good start for the finance minister, rather than trying to play semantics. SACHEDINA: So is it even possible for him to continue the functions of his job right now? What do you think should happen to him? CULLEN: It's a really interesting question. Certainly let's start with the piece of legislation that Mr. Morneau introduced around targeted benefits. Stand aside for a moment that many people think it's a very bad piece of legislation, but the cloud surrounding that bill, clearly we asked the Liberals to withdraw it. They chose not to. We've asked also the Liberals to close these ethical loopholes that have been exploited that allowed Mr. Morneau to do this kind of activity, keep the shares in control. They chose not to do that. So if they could start to move in that direction, that would help restore some faith. But in terms of Mr. Morneau personally, and his job as finance minister for the country, I mean our finance minister is under investigation from the ethics commissioner under a possible conflict of ethics breach. He also has... SACHEDINA: So what do you think should happen? Should he step down? What are you calling for? CULLEN: Yeah, I'm not, I'm personally, I think it's an incredibly serious thing to ask a minister of the crown to step down, we take this very seriously. But if he doesn't come forward, if he doesn't come forward with what's in the other numbered accounts that he still has, he hasn't told us what else he owns, and Mr. Trudeau promised all Canadians when he got elected, all of his ministers would disclose their personal holdings, that's still not happening. So he's in a world of trouble, Omar. I'm not sure what he does. And I'm sure Mr. Morneau and Mr. Trudeau will be talking this weekend. SACHEDINA: Okay, I appreciate you coming on. I've got to leave it there, Nathan. Thanks so much. CULLEN: You bet. SACHEDINA: Just want to bring up a statement from the finance minister's office. They're saying since the first day in office the minister of finance has worked with the conflict of interest and ethics commissioner and followed her recommendations and advice, including having a screen in place that was determined to be the best measure of compliance by the commissioner. In this spirit, the minister will answer any questions the commissioner has on this matter. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada42" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="January 17, 2018 Wednesday 3:11 AM PST"source="Market News Publishing" >
MONDELEZ INTERNATIONAL INC ("MDLZ-Q") - Establishes New Partnership to Protect Forests in Ghana Mondelez International announced it has signed a Memorandum of Understanding with the Forestry Commission of Ghana, Ghana Cocoa Board and United Nations Development Programme (UNDP), reinforcing its commitment to reduce emissions in its cocoa supply chain across Ghana. Through Cocoa Life, Mondelez International's signature sustainable cocoa sourcing program, the company will take a leading role in implementing projects to deliver the Ghana Cocoa Forest REDD+ Program (GCFRP) which aims at tackling deforestation and forest degradation. "Deforestation makes up the largest part of our carbon footprint, which is why it's so important for us to address this issue head on. Through this collaboration, we can be even more efficient in safeguarding the environment and helping cocoa farmers become resilient against climate change," said Hubert Weber, Executive Vice President and President Europe at Mondelez International. "This partnership builds on Cocoa Life's ongoing forest protection efforts. It's an exciting new chapter in our work in Ghana and fits with the commitment we made by signing the Cocoa &Forests Initiative Framework for Action at COP23 ." Mondelez International is contributing $5 million over five years to the GCFRP, which aims to significantly reduce the high rate of deforestation and forest degradation, as well as their associated greenhouse carbon emissions, from cocoa farming within Ghana's High Forest Zone. Together with these partners, Mondelez International will execute an action plan in key Hotspot Intervention Areas, focusing on:  Mapping all land uses, including cocoa farms  Implementing climate smart cocoa practices to increase yields and sustainability  Improving access to finance to foster good practices by farmers and communities  Legislative and policy reform to support program execution  Coordination and measurement, reporting and verification "The Ghana government is promoting public-private partnerships, which are critical for sustainable economic growth in all sectors, including the forestry sector. It is, therefore, encouraging that Mondelez International's Cocoa Life program is partnering with government to implement an integrated landscape approach to sustainable cocoa production and forest management," said John Peter Amewu, Minister for Lands and Natural Resources in Ghana and signatory of the Cocoa &Forests Initiative. "Cocoa Life is a valuable asset to the realization of the Joint Framework for Action under the Cocoa &Forests Initiative, as it brings on board advanced environmental protection strategies at farmer, community and national levels." Since 2013, Cocoa Life has worked with the Ghana Cocoa Board and UNDP to promote environmentally sustainable production practices while conserving ecosystems and natural resources in cocoa landscapes across Ghana. Mondelez International is also a founding member of the Cocoa &Forests Initiative, in which 12 leading cocoa and chocolate companies are partnering to reduce deforestation in the cocoa supply chain. About Cocoa Life Cocoa Life aims to create empowered and thriving cocoa farming communities, reaching more than 200,000 farmers across six countries and benefiting more than a million people by 2022. Mondelez International's ultimate goal is to sustainably source all the company's cocoa supply, mainly via Cocoa Life. By working in partnership with farmers, NGOs, suppliers and government institutions, Cocoa Life is part of Mondelez International's Impact for Growth - a commitment to driving business growth with positive change in the world. Follow our progress on HYPERLINK http://www.cocoalife.org/progress www.cocoalife.org/progress About Mondelez International Mondelez International, Inc. (NASDAQ:MDLZ) is building the best snacking company in the world, with 2016 net revenues of approximately $26 billion. Creating more moments of joy in approximately 165 countries, Mondelez International is a world leader in biscuits, chocolate, gum, candy and powdered beverages, featuring global Power Brands such as Oreo and belVita biscuits; Cadbury Dairy Milk and Milka chocolate; and Trident gum. Mondelez International is a proud member of the Standard and Poor's 500, NASDAQ 100 and Dow Jones Sustainability Index. Visit HYPERLINK http://www.mondelezinternational.com www.mondelezinternational.com HYPERLINK http://www.twitter.com/MDLZ www.twitter.com/MDLZ HYPERLINK mailto:news@mdlz.com news@mdlz.com ______________________________ _______________________________________________ ____________________________________________________________ (c)2018 Market News Publishing Inc. All rights reserved. Toronto:(416)366-8881 Vancouver:(604)689-1101 Fax:(604)689-1106 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada43" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="December 21, 2017 Thursday"source="The Times & Transcript (New Brunswick)" >
The euphoria in Paris in 2015, when 196 countries agreed to address climate change, was palpable. It should have been bottled. Since then, despite the United Nation's annual COPs (Conferences of the Parties) on climate change, very little progress has been made. After COP23 in Bonn, Germany, last month, disappointment, particularly among civil society groups, was the prevailing sentiment. We could question the sincerity of governments that are negotiating the actions their countries will take. For example, the Canadian government's top priority for Bonn (stated clearly on its website) was creating opportunities for Canadian businesses. Germany, which in many ways is an environmental paragon, still gets 40 per cent of its energy from coal and German drivers haven't slowed down to reduce emissions. These observations are not intended to ignore Canadian efforts to address the problem through carbon pricing and other measures, or Germany's numerous initiatives to spur the development of alternative energy. Nevertheless, the promise of Paris remains unfulfilled. There's more than enough hypocrisy to go around. But what's becoming increasingly clear is that governments can't be expected to address the elephant in the room: consumption. And that contributes mightily to global warming. This is understandable because consumption drives the economy. (Remember, in the wake of the 9/11 attacks, George Bush advised Americans to go to the mall.) Without a healthy economy driving employment and generating the tax revenue that governments depend on, economies would collapse. Governments are also reluctant to institute unpopular measures to curb consumption lest they be punished in the next election. Against this backdrop, it appears the planet is doomed. Or is it? Are we hapless passengers on a destructive path or participants in our own governance? Many climate skeptics have pointed out that automobiles are a major source of air pollution, yet this issue is largely ignored. These critics have a valid point despite their views on global warming. Our lavish lifestyles certainly contribute to a warming climate because of the things we buy and the energy used to make them. Thus we have been enthusiastic participants in an obscene level of consumption. In the last few months, we've had Halloween with its increasingly elaborate decorations and costumes, followed by Black Friday, which is becoming a global spending spree. Tucked in between was Singles' Day in China, that country's answer to Black Friday, on Nov. 11. On that day alone, e-commerce conglomerate Alibaba sold products worth US$25.3 billion! This was a 39 per cent increase over last year. At the risk of sounding like a Scrooge/Grinch mashup, I must confess that the orgy of Christmas spending gives me nightmares. There's no question that the Christmas season is suffused with wonderful and heartwarming acts of generosity, but these go hand in hand with excess. There will be a veritable arms race in neighbourhoods with elaborate displays of giant Santas and other seasonal figures on lawns, and the blaze of Christmas lights. Then there's the tsunami of gifts showered on young and old. Nothing is further from the minds of shoppers than the effect of their purchases on the planet. The amount of garbage created by the plastic packaging alone is enormous. A recent documentary deals with this ubiquitous material. A Plastic Ocean describes the heartbreaking toll that plastic is taking on the oceans and aquatic life. Not only is it killing fish, those that don't die are becoming dangerous for humans to eat because of their toxicity from the plastic they've swallowed. As inhabitants of this beleaguered planet, we can't stand idly by, feeling smug because we're recycling and composting. What we need to do and do urgently is refrain from gluttonous consumption and adopt mindful consumption instead. I don't mean going into a meditative trance in a store. But it might help to take a few moments to ponder the impact of each purchase on the environment. Some refer to this as pre-cycling. There are a few pinpricks of light in the gloom: many individuals are concerned about the sustainability of our resources and are making changes to their lifestyles. Unfortunately, we need a critical mass of citizens to do likewise if there's to be any appreciable effect on consumption patterns. Getting so many countries to agree, even in principle and perhaps grudgingly, to address climate change is an achievement to be celebrated. Although the motives of some governments might be suspect, it's up to the citizens of developed countries to kick it up a notch and become more thoughtful consumers. The health of the planet is in our hands. Doreen Barrie is an adjunct assistant professor in the Political Science Department at the University of\~Calgary. Distributed by Troy Media !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2017 Times &; Transcript (Moncton) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada44" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="December 20, 2017 Wednesday"source="The Chronicle Journal" >
By Doreen Barrie The euphoria in Paris in 2015, when 196 countries agreed to address climate change, was palpable. It should have been bottled. Since then, despite the United Nation's annual COPs (Conferences of the Parties) on climate change, very little progress has been made. After COP23 in Bonn, Germany, last month, disappointment, particularly among civil society groups, was the prevailing sentiment. We could question the sincerity of governments that are negotiating the actions their countries will take. For example, the Canadian government's top priority for Bonn (stated clearly on its website) was creating opportunities for Canadian businesses. Germany, which in many ways is an environmental paragon, still gets 40 per cent of its energy from coal and German drivers haven't slowed down to reduce emissions. These observations are not intended to ignore Canadian efforts to address the problem through carbon pricing and other measures, or Germany's numerous initiatives to spur the development of alternative energy. Nevertheless, the promise of Paris remains unfulfilled. There's more than enough hypocrisy to go around. But what's becoming increasingly clear is that governments can't be expected to address the elephant in the room: consumption. And that contributes mightily to global warming. This is understandable because consumption drives the economy. (Remember, in the wake of the 9/11 attacks, George Bush advised Americans to go to the mall.) Without a healthy economy driving employment and generating the tax revenue that governments depend on, economies would collapse. Governments are also reluctant to institute unpopular measures to curb consumption lest they be punished in the next election. Against this backdrop, it appears the planet is doomed. Or is it? Are we hapless passengers on a destructive path or participants in our own governance? Many climate skeptics have pointed out that automobiles are a major source of air pollution, yet this issue is largely ignored. These critics have a valid point despite their views on global warming. Our lavish lifestyles certainly contribute to a warming climate because of the things we buy and the energy used to make them. Thus we have been enthusiastic participants in an obscene level of consumption. In the last few months, we've had Halloween with its increasingly elaborate decorations and costumes, followed by Black Friday, which is becoming a global spending spree. Tucked in between was Singles' Day in China, that country's answer to Black Friday, on Nov. 11. On that day alone, e-commerce conglomerate Alibaba sold products worth US$25.3 billion! This was a 39 per cent increase over last year. At the risk of sounding like a Scrooge/Grinch mashup, I must confess that the orgy of Christmas spending gives me nightmares. There's no question that the Christmas season is suffused with wonderful and heartwarming acts of generosity, but these go hand in hand with excess. There will be a veritable arms race in neighbourhoods with elaborate displays of giant Santas and other seasonal figures on lawns, and the blaze of Christmas lights. Then there's the tsunami of gifts showered on young and old. Nothing is further from the minds of shoppers than the effect of their purchases on the planet. The amount of garbage created by the plastic packaging alone is enormous. A recent documentary deals with this ubiquitous material.\'caA Plastic Ocean describes the heartbreaking toll that plastic is taking on the oceans and aquatic life. Not only is it killing fish, those that don't die are becoming dangerous for human to eat because of their toxicity from the plastic they've swallowed. As inhabitants of this beleaguered planet, we can't stand idly by, feeling smug because we're recycling and composting. What we need to do and do urgently is refrain from gluttonous consumption and adopt mindful consumption instead. I don't mean going into a meditative trance in a store. But it might help to take a few moments to ponder the impact of each purchase on the environment. Some refer to this as pre-cycling. There are a few pinpricks of light in the gloom: many individuals are concerned about the sustainability of our resources and are making changes to their lifestyles. Unfortunately, we need a critical mass of citizens to do likewise if there's to be any appreciable effect on consumption patterns. Getting so many countries to agree, even in principle and perhaps grudgingly, to address climate change is an achievement to be celebrated. Although the motives of some governments might be suspect, it's up to the citizens of developed countries to kick it up a notch and become more thoughtful consumers. The health of the planet is in our hands. Doreen Barrie is an adjunct assistant professor in the Political Science Department at the University of Calgary. \£9 2017 Distributed by Troy Media \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada45" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 13, 2017 Monday"source="The Chronicle Journal" >
HL: Coal the burning issue at talks By Mia Rabson THE CANADIAN PRESS OTTAWA - Climate change talks in Germany are headed for a collision course on coal this week - and Canada is right in the middle of it. Environment Minister Catherine McKenna is arriving today in Bonn, Germany, to attend the second week of COP23 , the annual United Nations climate change talks that two years ago led to the Paris climate change accord. This year, the parties to Paris are hammering out rules for how that accord will be implemented, how carbon will be counted and how countries will be held accountable for their emissions cuts. McKenna and her British counterpart, Claire Perry, minister of state for climate change and industry, want the conversation to focus on getting rid of coal as a power source, which is responsible for more than 40 per cent of global carbon dioxide emissions. McKenna and Perry are hosting a joint event Nov. 16 to launch a joint campaign calling for other countries to declare a plan not to build any more unabated coal-fired plants and eliminate existing ones. Unabated plants are those that have no carbon capture or storage technology to keep emissions from ending up in the atmosphere. "We want every country to look at how they can reduce their use of coal and phase it out and we want to be supporting developing countries to do so," McKenna told The Canadian Press in an interview last week. A year ago, Canada committed to eliminating coal as a source of power by 2030. Britain has committed to getting rid of it by 2025. Since Canada and the U.K. first announced their coal phase-out campaign last month, Italy and Netherlands added themselves to the list of countries aiming to get rid of coal. France had already set a 2025 coal-phase out target. But their anti-coal initiative is in direct contrast with the United States, which is kicking off the week with an event promoting all the ways fossil fuels like coal can be part of the narrative of combating climate change. "I anticipate it will be a big story this week," said Catherine Abreu, executive director of Climate Action Network Canada, who has been in Bonn since the talks began Nov. 6. Last month, Scott Pruitt, the head of the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, declared the "war on coal is over" as he tore up the U.S. Clean Power Plan, a legacy of President Barack Obama that required states to cut emissions based on energy consumption and offered incentives to foster renewable power and energy efficiency. The U.S. successfully managed to convince the G20 to include a statement about the U.S. helping other countries "access and use fossil fuels more cleanly and efficiently" in its final statement in July. On Monday, U.S. officials and fossil fuel industry representatives will make presentations about it. McKenna however said the world has already decided with its money that coal is a relic of the past. "The market has moved on coal so the good news is you now have clean energy like wind and solar that's cheaper and there's far more investments in wind and solar than there is in coal," she said. Despite her bravado, the Global Coal Plant Tracker shows plans are afoot for another 1,600 new coal plants, which once operational would expand coal power by 42 per cent around the world. China's energy companies are behind 700 of them, despite China's pledge earlier this year to scale back its coal plans at home. India's state-run National Thermal Power Corp. intends to invest more than $10 billion to build new coal plants over the next five years. If Canada and the U.K. can get China and India involved to some extent, it would be a real victory, Abreu said. She doesn't expect them to agree to phase coal out entirely, but agreeing to help would be a big step. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada46" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 10, 2017 Friday"source="Postmedia Breaking News" >
"I wouldn't join any club that would have me as a member," ace wisecracker Groucho Marx famously said. As with any durable putdown, contained within its smart-ass punch is a worthy insight, the wisdom of the tamer proverb: "You can tell a person's character by the company he keeps." The line should be haunting the pretentious Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences (Sciences?) this year, as, starting with Harvey Weinstein, various luminaries of its exalted membership have been revealed one by one to be either sexual marauders or keepers of the silence around sexual marauders. Who wants to join the club that's exalted Harvey Weinstein? The academy is a prize example of the Groucho rule. Now, the Liberals will never challenge Groucho for quips and putdowns, but lately, they've been making a bid in the slapstick and farce department. They boldly announced a month or so ago that they were going after "tax cheats" and scurrilous "evaders," like store clerks who get in-house discounts and family farmers who shamelessly make use of tax "loopholes." You know, the very rich at Home Hardware and the back forty. It wasn't long before both the PM and his finance minister were tangled up in their own net, with questions about numbered companies and family trusts, falling back on the increasingly ineffectual ethics commissioner Mary Dawson as an excuse for sailing so close to their own ethical guidelines. Then came the Paradise Papers and tales of Liberal-friendly billionaires with offshore accounts-all legal of course, but rather tawdry coming from so righteous a government. As comedy it rivalled the closet scene in the classic A Night at the Opera. Halloween gave them a temporary lift. Trudeau and his environment minister Catherine McKenna delightfully went with the spirit of the day-he by showing up dressed as Clark Kent/Superman, and her by showing up in a green Lone Ranger mask and climate activist T-shirt. Underneath, the unctuous caption: "We all need to be superheroes in the fight against climate change." If a riposte is needed to put that sullen "climate Barbie" slur finally to rest, that photo is it. This is a serious ministry. The tweet has been deleted. But even superheroes have their off days, and it was not long before the masked climate activist supplied an example. From McKenna's Twitter feed came this curious? odd? startling? inexplicable? effusion: "Canada salutes Nicaragua and Syria for joining on to the Paris Agreement!" Note the exclamation mark, high signal of enthusiasm and approval. It took but minutes for this tweet to generate a near universal outcry of puzzlement and wonder. Outside of North Korea, which has also signed on to the Paris Accord, Syria has the most despicable and murderous government in the world. What in Heaven's name was the Minister of Environment and Climate Change up to, offering effusive congratulations to Bashar al-Assad? And what in Heaven's name can Bashar al-Assad offer to the oft-invoked "climate community" that has our tranquil nation saluting him? Has he promised to cut back fighter jet traffic in the bombing of his own citizens? Does displacing some two to three million Syrian citizens count in some sadistic way in cutting back on Syria's carbon emissions? Has he pledged to cut back on the gas attack emissions? McKenna, to be fair, was not alone here. Out of the great march of the penguins, the UN Convention on Climate Change COP 23 in Bonn, Germany (25,000 in attendance), came near-equal raves, all eagerly noting that, with Syria signing on, only Donald Trump was out of the accord. It says something about the monomania of the avid climate change crusaders that they will reach for any grimy stick with which to beat Trump, even if the stick in question is the hideous and murderous dictator of Syria. The repeated headline the world over was this: Syria Plans to Sign the Paris Climate Deal. That Makes the U.S. the Only UN Country Opposing It. If that's what it takes to bash Trump, well then Welcome Bashar. Has the COP 23 Naturally, McKenna backtracked on the tweet, blaming it first on staff, then taking responsibility for it. But it's not clear she drew the real message of her error, or understands why pariahs such as North Korea and Syria see advantage in joining the club of planet-savers-even as they savage the citizens of the part of the planet they actually control. Let's try to point to the moral here. There is nothing so convenient (and empty) for signalling political virtue than what is ludicrously called "making a commitment to halt climate change." If such a move appeals to Bashar al Assad and Kim Jong Un, what value is it, and what truth can be in it? !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2017 Postmedia Network Inc. All rights reserved. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada47" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 13, 2017 Monday 4:36 PM GMT"source="CBC News" >
The fissures in the Canada-U.S. relationship will be more apparent than ever this week during the United Nations climate change talks in Germany as Canada pushes to phase out coal as a power source. Canada's position runs counter to the Trump administration, which has declared the "war on coal is over" and promised to breathe life into the industry. "Canada is committed to phasing out coal. We've created an alliance with the U.K., we're going to get other countries around the world to help support moving forward on a coal phase-out. Coal is not only the most polluting fossil fuel but it's also terrible for health," said Environment Minister Catherine McKenna ahead of her trip. "If the U.S. is going to step back, we've said we're going to step up, and that's exactly what we'll be doing." McKenna is in Bonn to attend COP23 , the annual United Nations climate change talks, which saw the birth of the Paris climate change accord two years ago. Since then, the U.S. has not only ushered in a new administration, but has signalled its plans to withdraw from the Paris agreement. This year, players are meeting to dole out the rules for how that accord will be put into action, how carbon will be measured and how to keep countries accountable for their promised emission cuts. Canada, U.K., launching joint campaign in Bonn The pair are launching a joint campaign this week that will call on other countries to promise not to build any more unabated coal-fired plants and eliminate existing ones. Unabated plants don't have carbon capture or storage technology to keep emissions from ending up in the atmosphere. McKenna told The Canadian Press they want to help support developing countries to reduce their reliance on coal, but didn't commit any additional money to the program. About 40 per cent of the world's power is generated from burning coal. In Canada, a tenth of electricity comes from coal plants. A year ago, Canada committed to eliminating coal as a source of power by 2030. Britain has committed to getting rid of it by 2025. Since Canada and the U.K. first announced their coal phase-out campaign last month, Italy and the Netherlands have added themselves to the list of countries aiming to get rid of coal. France had already set a 2025 coal-phase out target. Green Party Leader Elizabeth May, who is also overseas for the meetings, heaped praise on McKenna's move to isolate the U.S. "The initiative, I have to say, is brilliant politics, that Catherine McKenna and the U.K. are together, with other countries joining us," she said. "It certainly puts Canada in a very good light globally." But Canada and the U.K.'s anti-coal initiative is in direct contrast with the Trump administration. On Monday, officials hosted an event promoting the virtues of clean coal and nuclear power as options to cut emissions, given that the world's reliance on fossil fuels isn't going to evaporate overnight. The event struggled as protesters dominated the attendees in the room and then shut it down for more than 10 minutes with a flash mob song. 'Versions' of the U.S. in Germany Last month, Scott Pruitt, head of the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, declared the "war on coal is over" as he tore up the U.S. Clean Power Plan, a legacy of President Barack Obama that required states to cut emissions based on energy consumption and offered incentives to foster renewable power and energy efficiency. On Monday, Canada, Mexico and an alliance of 15 U.S. governors signed on to an agreement around clean transportation, like zero-emission vehicles, carbon pricing and reducing use coal-fired electricity. "Let's be clear, there are many different versions of the United States that are here," McKenna told CBC News from Bonn. The environment minister drew parallels between how some governors are forging ahead under Trump and how provinces acted under former prime minister Stephen Harper. "Many provinces put a price on pollution, they moved forward on clean power, they took a whole variety of other measures, and you're seeing the same thing happening in the United States," McKenna said. "You've seen provinces like Ontario take action and they've gone from 30 smog days or more to nothing, so that's really important." If Canada and the U.K. can get China and India involved to some extent, it would be a real victory, said Catherine Abreu, executive director of Climate Action Network Canada, who has been in Bonn since the talks began Nov. 6. In recent years, China overtook the U.S. as the world leader in renewable power development. But it has also struggled to integrate its sprawling wind and solar facilities into an electricity grid still dominated by coal-fuelled power plants. Abreu doesn't expect either country to agree to phase coal out entirely, but said agreeing to help would be a big step. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada48" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 16, 2017 Thursday"source="therecord.com" >
TOYOTA, Japan - At a car factory in this city named after Toyota, the usual robots with their swinging arms are missing. Instead, workers intently fit parts into place by hand with craftsmanship-like care. The big moment on the assembly line comes when two bulbous yellow tanks of hydrogen are rolled over and delicately fitted into each car's underside. While much of the world is going gung-ho for electric vehicles to help get rid of auto emissions and end reliance on fossil fuels, Japan's top automaker Toyota Motor Corp. is banking on hydrogen. Toyota sells about 10 million vehicles a year around the world. It has sold only about 4,000 Mirai fuel cell vehicles since late 2014, roughly half of them outside Japan. The Mirai, which means "future," is not cheap at $57,500, but Toyota loses money on each one. Still, the company's goal is to sell 30,000 fuel-cell vehicles a year by about 2020. Hydrogen fuel cells don't suffer the EVs' main drawback of limited range. The Tesla Model S can go about 480 kilometres on a single charge, although that varies depending on driving conditions, and that's quite a distance for an EV. Other models run out of juice quicker, at about half that, because the longer the range, generally the heavier the batteries. And electric vehicles usually take hours to charge. The Mirai can run for 502 kilometres per fuelling, under U.S. EPA conditions, and fuels as quickly as a regular car. Toyota's chair, Takeshi Uchiyamada, believes hydrogen is an ideal, stable fuel for a future low-carbon society. "In this light, hydrogen holds tremendous potential," Uchiyamada, known as "the father of the Prius," the world's top-selling hybrid car, said during a tour of the factory. "Hydrogen doesn't exist in the natural world on its own, but you can create hydrogen from various materials," he said. The Prius turned out to be a good bet for Toyota. The Mirai could be the same. But not everyone shares Uchiyamada's enthusiasm for hydrogen. A fuel cell mixes hydrogen with the oxygen in the air to generate electricity that can power a motor. Producing the highly flammable gas and getting it into the vehicles requires energy. Ultimately, the idea is to convert energy from renewables like wind and solar power into hydrogen, or even make hydrogen from sewage waste. Unlike a gas-powered internal combustion engine, the only byproducts from a fuel cell are electricity, heat and water. There are no emissions of pollutants that can cause global warming. Yet the energy unleashed is powerful: Hydrogen is the fuel that sends NASA rockets into space. So fuel cells could be used to power cars, trains, buses, trucks and forklifts, and to provide electricity and heat for homes. Detroit-based General Motors Co., Mercedes-Benz of Germany, Japan's Honda Motor Co. and Hyundai of South Korea have also developed fuel cell vehicles that are on the roads in extremely limited numbers. The global stock of electric vehicles will soon surpass two million, according to the International Energy Agency. It's projected to climb to between 9 million and 20 million by 2020. Fuel cell vehicles are scarcely a presence. The Hydrogen Council, made up of 28 companies that are promoting hydrogen fuel, said in a report this week that it expects hydrogen to power about 10 million to 15 million cars and 500,000 trucks by 2030. It also forecasts it will be widely used for industries, heating and power and power storage. The group met this week in Bonn, on the sidelines of the COP23 UN meeting on the environment. Toyota and other manufacturers pursuing hydrogen fuel cells face some significant hurdles. Japan has an ample 28,000 EV charging stations but only 92 hydrogen fuelling stations, and they are costly to build. Hydrogen is viewed as potentially hazardous: the 1937 Hindenburg disaster, when 36 people died when the hydrogen-fueled airship caught fire and crashed, ended an earlier era of hydrogen-powered passenger travel. A fill-up with hydrogen takes about as long as at a gas pump, while EV charging takes about 30 minutes using special equipment for quick charging. Regular charging can take hours. "I'm not claiming that hydrogen will replace any form of energy, but it will find its place in the world energy mix," Benoit Potier, chief executive of French industrial gas company Air Liquide, and a chair of the Hydrogen Council, said. Air Liquide has been working on producing, storing and distributing hydrogen fuel for more than four decades. Potier says he expects costs for making the gas will fall as its use becomes more widespread. Not all Japanese automakers are sold on the idea. Manabu Satou, general manager of technology at Toyota's rival Nissan Motor Co., finds it an "utter mystery" why anyone would be so set on fuel cells when China, the world's biggest car market, is going for conventional EVs. Ryuichi Kino, who has written about electric vehicles and energy, views fuel cell vehicles as an excessively expensive, futuristic technology. "If it focuses too much on fuel cells, Japan is going to end up super-ultra-Galapagos," he said, alluding to the secluded Pacific islands that are home to unique species that don't exist elsewhere. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada49" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="October 27, 2017 Friday"source="CTV NEWS CHANNEL Television, Inc. POWER PLAY WITH DON MARTIN 17:00:00 ET" >
OMAR SACHEDINA: Joining me now is federal environment minister, Catherine McKenna. Minister, you heard there, I believe, what Minister Squires had to say. I'm just curious to get your reaction, because she's basically saying Manitoba is doing its part. CATHERINE MCKENNA (Environment Minister): Yeah. MCKENNA: Look, I think today is a big day for Manitoba. They put a price on pollution, and that's really important. We know that polluting isn't free, and now we have nine out of ten Canadian provinces that have committed to putting a price on pollution. That's 97 percent of our population. So looking forward to seeing the details of Manitoba's plan. But I also want to be clear. We've set out the price schedule that we need to see, and it reaches $50 per ton by 2022, which is beyond the $25 that Manitoba is proposing. And we just believe that across the country, we need to have a price, the same price across the country, and that's what we're expecting, but certainly happy to hear about Manitoba's plan today. SACHEDINA: Okay. But it just sounded like she said that they weren't going to budge, that it would be set at $25 per ton, and no chance of going higher. So what will, what will the feds do to get to it the $50 they want? MCKENNA: Well, I mean, look, we're going to be reviewing every year so that our plan requires a price of $10 per ton by, starting in 2018. So each year we'll be reviewing it. Manitoba is good for the first two years. And after that, we're going to really, you know, need to see how they're going to meet the price that we've set. SACHEDINA: But you've been clear about the $50. Will you say, Manitoba you need to absolutely get to $50? Will you impose that? MCKENNA: We've been clear that we need to see a price in pollution that goes up every year to $50. And this is just an indication, the environment and the economy go together. Today, I was with the minister of environment (inaudible) in British Columbia. British Columbia has managed to increase their price, reduce their emissions, and grow their economy, and that's what the, you know, provinces need to be doing. We need to be moving to a cleaner future and we can do that while we increase the price, you know, put a pollution, make investments in clean technology, make investments in, in infrastructure. And this is the environment and the economy going together. SACHEDINA: But what's wrong with letting a province take its own initiative? Because each province, I mean, you heard the Manitoba minister there say that Manitoba has a unique situation, with letting provinces come up with their own situation. She says she's not fixated on the numbers. So why, why is it important for you to get to that target? MCKENNA: I mean, we're fixated on reducing emissions and growing a clean economy. And that's why we've said that, you know, we've said what our plan requires. It's also an issue of fairness across the country. We want to see a price that makes sense. Businesses, business wants certainty. And, look, we're going to sit down with Manitoba, understand their plan. I think there are good elements of their plan, and certainly the most important thing is a recognition across the country, recognition by Canadians that polluting isn't free, that we need to be protecting the environment. We need to be growing a clean economy. Today, I was very excited that we took a big step with British Columbia that we're moving forward on creating a new national park in South Okanagan, working with the First Nations. And this is a real opportunity to brand Canada as, you know, one of the cleanest countries in the world, to attract good investment, and also ensure more sustainable future for our kids, which they deserve. SACHEDINA: Well, the environment certainly a sticking point between Canada and the US. I want to touch a little bit on something else. A new US ambassador to Canada said she believes both sides of the climate change debate, which had a lot of people scratching their heads. What's your response to that one? MCKENNA: There's only one side to climate science and that is climate change is real. It's manmade. And it's having an impact all over the world, including in Canada and the United States, and that we need to be taking it seriously, and taking action based on the science, and that's what Canadians certainly expect. I'm very proud to live in a country where, look, just today, as we see Manitoba is putting a price on pollution, and we're moving forward to protect our environment, and also to grow clean economy and attract investment. That's where the world's going. I'm off to COP23 to the meeting on climate change in a few weeks, and I'm going to be meeting with countries around the world who are committed to climate action, as well as state governors, like Jerry Brown from California, meeting businesses from the United States, we're all moving forward to tackle climate change because we only have one planet. SACHEDINA: Okay, Minister McKenna, thanks so much. Enjoy beautiful British Columbia, my home province. MCKENNA: All right. SACHEDINA: Appreciate that. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada50" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="October 31, 2017 Tuesday"source="Postmedia Breaking News" >
GENEVA - The U.N.'s environment program said Tuesday countries and industries need to do more to meet targets to trim emissions of greenhouse gases that experts say are contributing to global warming. In its latest "Emissions Gap" report issued ahead of an important climate conference in Germany next week, the program takes aim at coal-fired electricity plants being built in developing economies and says investment in renewable energies will pay for itself - and even make money - over the long term. Tuesday's report comes as U.N. officials are making a renewed push to maintain momentum generated by the Paris climate accord of 2015. It aims to cap global temperature increases to 2 degrees Celsius (Fahrenheit) by the year 2100 compared to average world temperatures at the start of the industrial era. "The Paris agreement boosted climate action, but momentum is clearly faltering," said Edgar Gutierrez-Espeleta, Costa Rica's environment minister who heads the 2017 UN Environment Assembly. "We face a stark choice: up our ambition, or suffer the consequences." A new round of U.N. climate talks known as COP 23 starts in Bonn, Germany, on Monday, when countries will take stock of their achievements and prepare more ambitious national goals. In a summary of the report, UNEP says that current trends suggest that even if current national commitments are met, a temperature increase of 3-degrees Celsius by the end of the century is "very likely - meaning that governments need to deliver much stronger pledges when they are revised in 2020." "Should the United States follow through with its stated intention to leave the Paris agreement in 2020, the picture could become even bleaker," the statement said, alluding to the Trump administration plans to withdraw the U.S. from the global climate pact. On the upside, the agency highlights "rapidly expanding mitigation action" and says carbon-dioxide emissions have remained stable since 2014, thanks partly to renewable-energy use in China and India. It cautioned that other greenhouse gases like methane continue to rise, however. UNEP trumpets the positive effects of investment in solar and wind energy and efficient appliances and cars, and efforts to preserve forests. !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2017 Postmedia Network Inc. All rights reserved. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada51" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="Print Version"source="Plastics News " >
Officials at Plastic Bank are forging major business partnerships, getting props from the United Nations and preparing for a Vatican visit as their programs to stem the tide of ocean-bound plastic spread beyond the shores of Haiti and the Philippines. The Vancouver-based for-profit social enterprise pays poor people to pick up plastic from waterways, canals, beaches and other access points to oceans. They redeem the items at collection centers for money, goods and services like cooking fuel and phone charging. Then partners on the ground sort, wash and reduce the plastic to flake for easy shipping to manufacturers, including Germany-based Henkel AG & Co. The maker of home, laundry and personal care products like Loctite adhesive and Persil detergent announced it is forming a strategic partnership with Plastic Bank to become a leader in sustainability. Henkel describes the partnership as "turning environmental challenges into life chances" in an Oct. 24 news release about its new role to support recycling infrastructure in impoverished areas. Details will be released at a Nov. 15 news conference in D\'fcsseldorf, Germany. In a phone interview, David Katz, founder of Plastic Bank, lauded Henkel for becoming the first major consumer goods company to be a strategic partner. He said the manufacturer will pay a premium for "social plastic" to use in packaging while it not only meets sustainability goals but improves thousands of lives. The plastic collectors often put their redemption income toward school tuition, which brings educational and career opportunities. Katz says Plastic Bank addresses the root cause of ocean plastic while easing global poverty. In another new effort, Henkel and Shell Oil are participating in plastic off-set programs like those used to reduce carbon footprint, Katz said. For its part, Shell has committed to fund the collection of 1 million kilograms (2.2 million pounds) of ocean-bound plastic and then to use the flake. By the end of the year, Katz expects to announce similar new partnerships with billion-dollar companies, including one that aims to be the first plastics-neutral company in the world. This company will determine how much plastic is used per employee and then make a contribution that equates to the cost of extracting that volume of material from the environment. More than 8 million tons of plastic is dumped into the oceans every year, according to Plastic Bank. Some of it comes from developing countries with poor or no waste management systems in place. To show business partners like Shell the ocean-bound plastic in Haiti, Katz took a company representative a mile above the capital of Port-au-Prince to a hillside community where garbage collection is a challenge. Rains carry plastic bottles, bags and other garbage to creeks and streams that flow down to the ocean. The town is a point of origin, making the collection center there an important point of diversion. "We're engaging the entire world to be a part of the prohibition of plastics from flowing into the ocean. That's what we're doing," Katz said. "The world needs to not focus on cleaning the ocean, which is ridiculous. The last thing the world needs to do is clean the ocean. The very last thing. We get to that right after we turn off the tap of plastics flowing into the ocean." Brazil, Indonesia next At the COP23 Climate Summit, which runs Nov. 6-17 in Bonn, Germany, Plastic Bank will receive a Lighthouse Momentum for Change award from the United Nations. The award recognizes practical and scalable efforts to address climate change and set sustainable development goals. With dozens of collection centers each in Haiti and the Philippines boosting the incomes and living standards of an estimated 10,000 people, Plastic Bank plans to set up operations in Brazil and Indonesia next. Even though there's a premium on social plastic, which goes to pay the collectors, Katz said the material is in a category by itself with a valuable branding and marketing story compared to virgin plastic and even recycled plastic. "That's what we provide our customers," Katz said. "They can exhibit that they are helping clean the world and eliminate poverty." He likens Plastic Bank to a convenience store where the world's poor turn plastic waste into a currency for things they need. The collected items then become feedstock for flake, which Katz said even if used for only 10 percent of a product's content, offers environmental, social and financial benefits. "We price outside the resin market but it does make an impact," Katz said. "We turn the model upside down and take that price incentive - the additional fee for extracting the material - and we create it as a reward for the poor. Now it becomes a livable wage. That's what we do." Vatican interested Katz has been invited to the Vatican on Nov. 19, which Pope Francis designated as the first World Day for the Poor. The pope is calling on people of all faiths to serve those living in poverty through deeds, not words. He cites a "bitter and endless list" of reasons behind poverty, including oppression, violence, moral degeneration and greed. Katz is supposed to meet the pope and offer some ideas about how the Catholic Church and its 1.2 billion members could work with Plastic Bank to benefit parishes and communities. Katz said the partnership could help collection efforts in Brazil, where few municipal recycling programs exist and 64 percent of the 130 million people are Catholic. "Part of our program is creating ecosystems globally that increase recycle rates, especially where there are none," Katz said. He envisions a program where Catholics bring their recyclables to church weekly and Plastic Bank offers some kind of match. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada52" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday 03:00 PM EST"source="Canadian Press" >
EDITORS: Following is a list of news events for Thursday, Nov. 16 as of 3 p.m: x-denotes wire, y-denotes picture, z-denotes graphics coverage. Copy from other events based on merit and availability. All times local unless otherwise noted. Queries about these events and stories in The Canadian Press report should be directed to the departments listed below (all phone numbers 416 area code): National News 507-2150; Sports Desk 507-2154; Ontario Desk 507-2159; Photo Desk 507-2169; IT Desk (Technical Trouble) 507-2099 or 1-800-268-8149. WORLD BONN - Environment Minister Catherine McKenna holds a media availability to answer questions following the COP23 meetings. (7 a.m. at Dial 1-866-206-0153 or 613-954-9003, passcode 3194025(pound key)) LONDON - Fertilizer, chemicals and farm inputs retailer Agrium Inc. presents at the CIBC U.K. Agriculture Conference. (8:30 ET). Webcast at HYPERLINK www.agrium.com . ATLANTIC HALIFAX - The Halifax Women's History Society officially unveils a bronze monument, The Volunteers/Les Benevoles, to pay tribute to women volunteers during the Second World War. (11 a.m. at Halifax Waterfront, just north of the Halifax Farmers' Market) HALIFAX - Communities, Culture and Heritage Minister Leo Glavine launches the cookbook, Nova Scotia Cookery: Then and Now, featuring recipes from the past 150 years that were updated by some of Nova Scotia's most prominent chefs. (6:45 p.m. at Nova Scotia Archives, 6016 University Ave.) HALIFAX - Dalhousie University and St. Mary's University jointly host a preview of the 2017 Halifax International Security Forum - The Future of Global Leadership. (7 p.m. at McInnes Room, Dalhousie Student Union Building, 6136 University Avenue) OTTAWA OTTAWA - Trial continues for Basil Borutski, charged with first-degree murder in the deaths of three women in the Ottawa Valley in 2015. Through Dec. 1. (10 a.m. at Ottawa Courthouse, room 36) OTTAWA - Statistics Canada releases Canada's international transactions in securities for September and the monthly survey of manufacturing for September. (8:30 a.m. at HYPERLINK http://www.statcan.gc.ca www.statcan.gc.ca ) OTTAWA - Media are invited to participate in one-on-one telephone interviews with Brig.-Gen. Daniel MacIsaac, Commander, Joint Task Force-Iraq for an update on the defeat of Daesh (8 a.m.-10 a.m.). (Contact DND media relations 613-996-2353) ONTARIO TORONTO - First-degree murder trial for Dellen Millard and Mark Smich, accused of killing Laura Babcock. Through Dec. 23. (10 a.m. at 361 University Ave., room 2-7) TORONTO - Ontario Transportation Minister Steven Del Duca, joined by MPP Arthur Potts and OPP Sgt. Kerry Schmidt, makes an announcement. (9:30 a.m. at Canadian Tire, 1025 Lake Shore Blvd. E.) TORONTO - The Ontario Electricity Stakeholders Alliance, a diverse group of 19 major energy consumers, producers and distributors from across Ontario, makes an announcement on the future of energy planning in Ontario. (10 a.m. at Queen' Park Media Studio) TORONTO - Roxgold Inc. discusses third-quarter results. Dial 1-888-231-8191 or 647-427-7450. Go to HYPERLINK http://www.roxgold.com www.roxgold.com for the webcast. (11 a.m.) TORONTO - Hydro One president and CEO Mayo Schmidt speaks to the Empire Club of Canada. (12:45 p.m. at Royal York Hotel, Imperial Room) TORONTO - Senator Rosa Galvez continues her lecture tour on the Lac Megantic oil spill and its environmental aftermath. (6 p.m. at Mastro's Restaurant, 890 Wilson Ave.) WHITBY, Ont. - Senator Rosa Galvez continues her lecture tour to talk about the Lac Megantic oil spill and its environmental aftermath. (12 p.m.) PRAIRIES CALGARY - Seven Generations Energy Investor Day, 8:30 a.m.-12:30 p.m. (Metropolitan Centre) EDMONTON - Alberta Association of Municipal Districts and Counties fall convention. Through Nov. 17. (Shaw Conference Centre, 9797 Jasper Ave.) EDMONTON - Itinerary for Heritage Minister Melanie Joly: 9 a.m., takes part in a fireside chat about Creative Canada (Varscona Theatre, 10329-83 Ave. NW.); 11 a.m., announces funding for anti-discrimination and intercultural understanding projects (Edmonton Intercultural Centre, 9538-107 Ave. NW. (McCauley School). RED DEER, Alta. - Trial continues for Jason Klaus and Joshua Frank, charged with first-degree murder and arson in the deaths of Klaus's parents and his sister. Police believe Gordon and Sandra Klaus, along with their daughter Monica Klaus, died in a house fire in Castor, Alta., in December 2013. Through Nov. 17. (10 a.m. at Court of Queen's Bench) WINNIPEG - Trial for Guido Amsel, charged with five counts of attempted murder and explosives-related charges after three explosive packages were mailed in July 2015. Through Nov. 30. WINNIPEG - MP Terry Duguid, on behalf of the Indigenous Services Minister Jane Philpott, visits Southeast Collegiate to announce the construction of an expansion to the campus. Media availability will follow. (3 p.m. at 1301 Lee Boulevard) NORTH BATTLEFORD, Sask. - Leadership candidates for the Saskatchewan Party participate in a debate. (7 p.m. at Dekker Centre) REGINA - The lawyer for former Saskatchewan Roughrider Justin Cox to appear in court on behalf of his client. Cox is charged with assault. (9:30 a.m. at Courthouse, Room 7B) REGINA - Public Safety Minister Ralph Goodale and Sask. Government Relations Minister Larry Doke co-host a national roundtable on flood risk. Insurance Bureau of Canada president and CEO Don Forgeron will deliver remarks. BRITISH COLUMBIA RICHMOND, B.C. - Doris Paul - Xele'milh and Carol Todd will be the recipients of the Second Annual Be More Than a Bystander Awards. (10:30 a.m. at EVA BC Annual Training Forum, Sheraton Vancouver Airport Hotel, 7551 Westminster Highway) VANCOUVER - Conservative Party Leader Andrew Scheer addresses a Greater Vancouver Board of Trade breakfast meeting. (7:45 a.m. at Pan Pacific Hotel, Oceanview Suite 5, 999 Canada Place) VANCOUVER - Homeless protesters rally outside as Premier John Horgan and Housing Minister Selena Robinson appear at an Urban Development Institute luncheon. (12 p.m. at Fairmont Hotel at Canada Place, 900 Canada Place) VICTORIA - Members of the media are invited to sample military rations, try on full combat gear, practice on a fully electronic shooting range and attempt the Forces' physical fitness test. (10 a.m. at Bay Street Armoury, 713 Bay Street) WHISTLER, B.C. - Whistler Blackcomb offers a tour and media availability ahead of its Nov. 17 opening date. (1 p.m. at base of Whistler Village Gondola) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada53" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="December 5, 2017 Tuesday"source="Waterloo Region Record" >
Policy-makers meeting in Bonn, Germany, for the COP 23 climate conference have an excellent opportunity to accelerate the transition to sustainable transport via electric vehicles. With prices for electric vehicles falling rapidly and advances in battery technology extending their range to more than 300 kilometres, the biggest remaining impediment to the adoption of battery-powered cars is the dearth of charging stations. For consumers to switch to electric cars, they need to know that, no matter how far they venture from home, they will be as certain to encounter a charging station as they now are to find a filling station. This is precisely where policy-makers are now in a position to enable a quantum leap in e-mobility. To date, progress has been slow. Across the European Union, there are only an estimated 120,000 non-residential charging stations, according to the European Alternative Fuels Observatory. In the United States, where more than a half-million all-electric or plug-in hybrid cars have been sold, there are roughly 16,000 non-residential charging sites. In China, where last year alone more than 350,000 electric vehicles were sold, the government is aiming to raise its total to 800,000 charging sites by the end of 2017. As a technology leader, ABB is engaged in the effort to develop high-power charging technologies for electric vehicles, extend the power-grid connections that support these charging systems, and move toward renewable power generation. In this effort, we are one of several companies working with transport officials around the world to set up fast-charging networks for electric cars, buses and other types of transportation. To speed up the transition, policy-makers have a variety of measures at their disposal ranging from tax breaks for investments in charging systems; establishing international standards for charging protocols; funding additional research for high-power charging technologies; or even mandating installation of charging stations at some existing filling stations, such as those located on public highways. Technological advances have given us a historic opportunity to run the world without consuming the earth. The key is for all of us work together to combine electric vehicles with renewable power generation, connecting them with a smart grid. As the environmental and public health concerns of our long-standing reliance on fossil fuels have grown, it is clear just how much we stand to gain by embracing new and improved ways to travel. The faster we can make this happen, and rid our cities of air pollution and our atmosphere of greenhouse gas emissions, the better. Dr. Ulrich Spiesshofer is President and Chief Executive Officer of ABB Ltd, a pioneering technology leader, serving customers in utilities, industry and transport and infrastructure globally. With revenues of $34 billion in 2016, the ABB Group of companies operates in more than 100 countries and employs about 136,000 people. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada54" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 17, 2017 Friday 9:45 AM GMT"source="CBC News" >
If you think all Inuit are insulted by the Edmonton Eskimos name, think again. Since the latest push by the mayor of Winnipeg to get the CFL team to change the name to something "more inclusive," many Inuit have spoken out on social media, and reached out to CBC North, to voice their support for the moniker. Kenneth Ruben, in Paulatuk, N.W.T., posted a message to politicians on Facebook, saying "We as 'the real Eskimos,' want the name to remain!!" His post has since been shared nearly 600 times. "I just really thought it was kind of a ridiculous platform for the politicians to jump on, seeing that we have far more pressing issues in both the Northwest Territories and Nunavut, and any of our native Eskimo communities," he told CBC. "Nunavut has a housing crisis, so does the Northwest Territories. Our cost of food has just gone absolutely crazy. The suicide rates in both Nunavut and the Northwest Territories are among the highest in Canada." "I really think that these politicians should put their efforts elsewhere and concentrate on things that affect our people more than a name, a moniker on a sports franchise that has nothing to do with insulting our people," Ruben said. Source of pride Dominic Angutimarik called CBC's talkback line from Igloolik, Nunavut, to say he also supports the name. "I wouldn't want them to change their name simply because it's just a title and, in fact, I feel honoured as an Inuk person to see the name Eskimos as they probably had thought that Inuit were capable people with integrity," he said in Inuktitut. Jenna Palituq, from Clyde River, Nunavut, said Eskimo is a generational word that's fine by her. "They're known all over the world as Edmonton Eskimos and they are representing and making a name for the Eskimos," Palituq said. Erin Pameolik, from Coral Harbour, Nunavut, said she'd be disappointed if the football team changed its name. "I would be, because I'm known as an Eskimo and they're good representation for us Inuit." Natan Obed, president of Inuit Tapiriit Kanatami, which represents more than 60,000 Inuit, has spoken out against the name. He recently said it's his hope that the team "will respect the wishes of Inuit and replace its moniker with a team name that is not widely considered an ethnic slur." Obed is in Germany at the COP 23 UN climate change conference and wasn't available to comment for this story. For Ruben, the name has always been a source of pride, and is the reason he followed the team. "Growing up as a kid, I first caught on to a football game and Edmonton Eskimos were playing and I really thought it was our own team. I felt a sense of pride," Ruben said. Ruben thinks politicians should be focussing their energy, and money, on more important issues Inuit face. "For me it's just political grandstanding. It has nothing to do with our social issues now. You have never heard of a person who lost a house, or can't get a house because of the Edmonton Eskimos name." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada55" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 14, 2017 Tuesday"source="Daily Oil Bulletin" >
Canadas environment and climate change minister who is attending a United Nations climate conference in Bonn, Germany says there is huge momentum in terms of moving forward on the Paris agreement under which countries have agreed to limit their greenhouse gas emissions. What we are doing is building on the actions we have been showing at home, everything from phasing out coal, putting a price on carbon pollution, making investments in public transportation and clean innovation, Catherine McKenna said today in a conference call from COP 23 . It is important to recognize that the government of Alberta took very strong action which actually enabled us to get an ambitious climate plan in Canada, she said. They put a hard cap on emissions from the oilsands, they put a price on carbon and they also are phasing out coal so we need to make sure we are supporting those actions, that we are working together and that as part of the Paris agreement you increase your ambition. According to McKenna, global players in Bonn are seeing the leadership role that Canada is taking on climate change. I think it is very important that we talk about how Canada has been able to work with business, work with labour, work with environmentalists, work with provinces to get our climate plan and there are other things that we can be doing which is why we have started this initiative [an alliance with the United Kingdom to phase out coal globally.] The Global Alliance to Power Past Coal, which is to be officially launched on Thursday will bring together cities, states, provinces, countries, businesses that are also committed to a phase-out of coal which globally still accounts for 40 per cent of electricity production, she said. McKenna said that when it comes to coal its important to emphasize that the price of renewable sources of energy has dropped dramatically in the past few years. We need to be looking at how we can support increases in green power at home but also how we can do it abroad, she said. We want to be supporting countries that want to make the decision to turn to clean power as opposed to opening another coal power plant. And while the United States under President Donald Trump has renewed its commitment to coal, Canada is working with 15 U.S. state governors whose states account for 40 per cent of the economy, McKenna noted. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada56" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 6, 2017 Monday"source="Postmedia Breaking News" >
BONN, Germany - Diplomats and activists have gathered in Germany for two-week talks on implementing the Paris agreement to fight climate change. Environmental groups staged protests in the western city of Bonn and at a nearby coal mine ahead of the meeting to highlight Germany's continued use of heavily polluting fossil fuels. The 23rd conference of the parties, or COP23 , will be opened Monday by Fiji's Prime Minister Voreqe 'Frank' Bainimarama. The Pacific island nation is already suffering the impacts of global warming. Negotiators will focus on thrashing out some of the technical details of the 2015 Paris accord, which aims to limit global warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius. While President Donald Trump has expressed skepticism, a recent U.S. government report concluded there's strong evidence that man-made climate change is taking place. !@COPYRIGHT=\£9 2017 Postmedia Network Inc. All rights reserved. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada57" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 4, 2017 Saturday 11:19 AM EST"source="Canadian Press" >
BONN, Germany - Thousands of demonstrators have marched through Bonn to protest the use of fossil fuels ahead of a global climate conference being held in the western German city next week. Participants in Saturday's event carried banners with slogans that included "Revolution Not Pollution," ''Frack Off Our Land" and "Trump: Climate Genocide." Protest organizers say some 25,000 people took part in the demonstration. Police had no official estimates, but said the size of the crowd was "clearly more" than the 10,000 expected. Many protesters criticized the German government's reliance on coal-fired power plants for much of the country's energy even as it pursues ambitious targets for renewable sources. Protester Holger Heinrich said: "Germany finally has to contribute, and not only talk." The 2017 United Nations Climate Conference known as COP23 begins on Monday. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada58" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="November 10, 2017 Friday"source="CTV NEWS CHANNEL Television, Inc. POWER PLAY WITH DON MARTIN 17:00:00 ET" >
OMAR SACHEDINA: And for her analysis on Canada's climate plan, I'm joined by Debbie De Lange, global management studies professor at Ryerson University. Professor, great to have you on. You heard there what the minister had to say. She says that Canada has taken concrete steps. You have said that Canada is not aggressive enough. Why? DEBORAH DE LANGE (Ryerson University): Well, so far, we're still seeing oil pipelines being considered and approved, and so while it's true, I think the minister has made some really good points about some future strategies, overall the government hasn't actually acted fast enough, and, for example, we need a strategy for 100 percent clean energy in this country, and we need to talk about divesting of fossil fuels and moving away from that industry. So I think that if we understand the requirements at COP-23 , we need to stop burning fossil fuels and also selling fossil fuels. SACHEDINA: But doesn't the government need to strike a balance with its climate plan? I mean if you're encouraging, for example, somebody to try to get active, you're not going to get them to run a marathon right away. You want them to hop on a treadmill for 10 minutes, 15 minutes at a time, work their way up to not shock the system. Is it a prudent approach that way? DE LANGE: I agree with you, but the thing is we've known about this problem since at least the 1980s, and it's time to ramp up the action. So we can't move slowly at this stage. We have to accelerate. And there has to be obviously a plan for a phase-out of fossil fuels and a phase-in of clean energy, but, for example, the US, a country that's being criticized a lot, there's a report from Stanford that shows a plan to phase in 100 percent renewable energy across all 50 states. And we don't have a plan like that. There hasn't been the research done to see how every province and territory in this country can phase in 100 percent renewable energy. So we need that report done, for example. Where is it? SACHEDINA: Let's talk about the price on carbon, $50 a tonne by 2022, a plan that Manitoba has taken issue with to an extent. But you're saying even that's not sufficient, and there is the Harvard study that you pointed to in a recent article. Tell us about that. DE LANGE: Well, oil and gas companies have been shadow pricing carbon for years now, and they know what level at which a price makes a difference to their decision-making, and this study shows that even at a hundred dollars a tonne it really doesn't change decision-making of companies. And we can see in other more advanced countries, advanced in terms of having implemented a carbon tax, like Sweden, for example, they have much higher levels of carbon taxes, and they will brag that their economies are doing very, very well, very, very strong economies. And they'll attribute that to having a carbon tax. So in fact, for example, we should start at $100 a tonne and add $20 a tonne per year for five years just to catch up with where Sweden is today. So I think we have an opportunity to lead on climate change, and lead on solutions to it, and at $50 a tonne in five years, because we're doing $10 a year, so it's over five years, we're not leading. We're still lagging. SACHEDINA: All right. We'll leave it there. Debbie De Lange from Ryerson University. Thank you so much. DE LANGE: Thank you. SACHEDINA: And what do you think? Do you think Canada is doing enough on climate change? Are we moving too slow, or are we moving too fast? We'd love to know what you think, so reach out to us through social media, on Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram. You can of course email us, our address is HYPERLINK mailto:powerplay@ctvnews.ca powerplay@ctvnews.ca (COMMERCIAL BREAK) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Canada59" COP="COP23" country="Canada" date="October 31, 2017 Tuesday 12:02 AM EST"source="Canadian Press" >
GENEVA - The head of the U.N. environment program said Tuesday the United States is likely to live up to the Paris climate deal despite President Donald Trump's planned pullout, because "all the big American companies" are working toward greener operations. The comments from UNEP executive director Erik Solheim came as the U.N. agency presented its latest "Emissions Gap" report , which gives a scientific assessment about how national efforts are affecting the greenhouse gas emission trend. The report's release ahead of a crucial climate meeting next week in Bonn, Germany, aims to inject new momentum to the Paris accord and even strengthen it in 2020. Trump, however, has vowed to pull out the U.S. because he insists it's unfair to the United States. U.N. officials are increasingly citing the role of companies in the fight against climate change. "There is one question that I get more often than any other question wherever I go on the planet and it is a very simple one. It is: 'What about Donald Trump?'" Solheim told a panel in Geneva by videoconference from Nairobi. "In all likelihood, the United States of America will live up to its Paris commitment, not because of the White House, but because of the private sector," he said. "All the big American companies are dedicated to go in the green direction." But UNEP said countries and industries still need to do more to meet targets to cut greenhouse gas emissions that experts say contribute to global warming. The report criticizes coal-fired electricity plants being built in emerging economies, and insists that investment in renewable energies will pay for itself - and even make money - over the long term. "The Paris agreement boosted climate action, but momentum is clearly faltering," said Edgar Gutierrez-Espeleta, Costa Rica's environment minister who heads the 2017 U.N. Environment Assembly. "We face a stark choice: Up our ambition, or suffer the consequences." The Paris accord aims to cap global temperature increases to 2 degrees Celsius (Fahrenheit) by the year 2100 compared to average world temperatures at the start of the industrial era - and even hopes to limit the increase to 1.5 degrees C. UNEP says trends suggest that even if current national commitments are met, a temperature increase of 3 degrees Celsius by the end of the century is "very likely - meaning that governments need to deliver much stronger pledges when they are revised in 2020." "Should the United States follow through with its stated intention to leave the Paris agreement in 2020, the picture could become even bleaker," UNEP said. Lead author John Christensen of U.N. Environment noted some U.S. states like California were "acting independently of what the White House decides." He said Trump's bid to peel back constraints on the coal industry won't mark a major shift because "it simply doesn't pay off." He also said the U.S. targets in the Paris accord, as agreed by the Obama administration, were "not that ambitious in the first place." But Christensen told the Geneva panel that the Trump administration's impact on efforts could affect "negotiation dynamics" with other countries and embolden "what I call 'noise-makers:' they are the ones that are opposed to the basic idea" of fighting climate change. Bob Ward, an expert on climate change policy at the London School of Economics, agreed that the coal industry is "unlikely to be revived in the United States because it is being displaced by cleaner and cheaper sources of energy." "Many countries now recognize that the transition to a low-carbon economy will generate sustainable growth and development, with lower poverty and higher living standards," he said. "High-carbon economies look increasingly uncompetitive." A new round of U.N. climate talks known as COP 23 starts in Bonn, Germany, on Monday, when countries will take stock of their achievements and prepare more ambitious national goals. On the positive, UNEP highlighted "rapidly expanding mitigation action" and says carbon-dioxide emissions have remained stable since 2014, thanks partly to renewable energy use in China and India. It cautioned that other greenhouse gases like methane continue to rise, however. UNEP has trumpeted solar and wind energy, efficient appliances and cars, and efforts to preserve forests. Solheim cited tests this week on the world's first solar-powered railroad in Australia and the launch of a hydrogen-run subway system in northern China. "We are at the watershed moment: We have stopped the rise in CO2 (carbon dioxide) emissions - there is every reason to believe we can bring them down," Solheim said. "The train is on the right track, but our duty is to speed it up." \</doc>
