<doc ID="COP23_China1" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 7, 2017 Tuesday"source="China Daily" >
The 23rd Conference of Parties ( COP 23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) kicked off here on Monday with a call to adhere to the path of Paris Climate Change Agreement. General view shows the opening session of the COP23 United Nations Climate Change Conference BONN - The 23rd Conference of Parties ( COP 23 The COP 23 At the opening ceremony of the COP 23 , UN climate change executive secretary, Patricia Espinosa, said: "Together with the Sustainable Development Agenda, we have a clear path forward to truly address climate change and sustainable development." Espinosa outlined the work governments will be looking to address in Bonn. The goal, above all, is to take the next essential steps to ensure that the Paris Agreement's operating system is completed in time and that ways, as well as means to implement it, are strengthened. The newly-elected COP 23 president, Frank Bainimarama, prime minister of Fiji, said "All over the world, vast numbers of people are suffering, bewildered by the forces against them. Our job as leaders is to respond to the suffering with all means available to us." China's special representative on climate change, Xie Zhenhua, said at a press conference prior to the COP 23 that China hoped participants could reach a draft guideline reflecting the needs of all parties and all the key elements in the Paris agreement. At a press conference of the Chinese delegation held in Bonn on Monday, Lu Xinming, a negotiator from the National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC), said the Bonn meeting comes at a "crucial and watershed phase" both for defining implementation guidelines of the Paris Agreement and also for battling the climate change across the globe. Lu said that China had made ample preparations for the meeting and had submitted five proposals to the meeting on implementing the Paris Agreement, which has demonstrated China's "proactive attitude in participating into and guiding the global climate negotiations." Pledging that China will play a proactive and constructive role during the COP 23 , Lu told reporters that the country will also host some 30 side events during COP 23 to present China's climate policies, and achievements in coping with climate change. German authorities expected 25,000 guests, including representatives of governments and non-governmental organizations, and 1,500 journalists, to attend the Bonn conference which will last until Nov 17. According to the COP 23 press release, negotiators will also address issues including checking on the progress of the delivery of 100 billion dollars of support for developing countries by 2020 and the bringing into force of the Doha Amendment of the first international emission reduction treaty, the Kyoto Protocol. HYPERLINK http://imgs.syndigate.info/498/1493/93/151002399831.jpg http://imgs.syndigate.info/498/1493/93/151002399831.jpg eca86bd9e0d11b6b538806.jpg \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China2" COP="COP23" country="China" date="May 9, 2017 Tuesday"source="China Daily" >
The United Nations Climate Change Conference kicked off Monday in the western German city of Bonn. FRANKFURT - The United Nations Climate Change Conference kicked off Monday in the western German city of Bonn. Around 3,000 delegates gathered here for talking over further implementation of the Paris Agreement on climate change, as well as for preparation for the next session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 ) to the UN Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) which is to be held November in Bonn. The ten-day conference consists of three main sessions, according to the schedule released by UN, namely the session of the Subsidiary Body for Implementation(SBI), the session of Subsidiary Body for Scientific and Technological Advice(SBSTA), as well as the third part of the first session of the Ad Hoc Working Group on the Paris Agreement (APA). Though it isn't an official topic, global concerns over the uncertainty that the new US government would probably exit Paris Agreement are casting shadow over the conference. US President Donald Trump said last month on his 100th day in office that he would make a "big decision" on Paris within the next two weeks. The Paris Agreement was agreed by the 195 member economies that attended the 21st session of the Conference of the Parties (COP21) to UNFCCC 2015 in Paris. "That 195 countries have agreed on binding targets is huge achievement, which shall not be endangered," Jochen Flasbarth, state secretary of the German Environment Ministry, told the opening plenary. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China3" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 8, 2017 Wednesday"source="China Daily" >
Syrian representatives at the 23rd United Nations Climate Change Conference of Parties ( COP 23 ) in Bonn have announced that their country will belatedly join the Paris Climate Accord, German media dpa and Spiegel reported on Tuesday. Photo taken on June 23, 2017 shows a Tibetan antelope in Nagqu, Southwest China's Tibet autonomous region. [Photo/Xinhua] BERLIN - Syrian representatives at the 23rd United Nations Climate Change Conference of Parties ( COP 23 ) in Bonn have announced that their country will belatedly join the Paris Climate Accord, German media dpa and Spiegel reported on Tuesday. The secretariat of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change said it was not yet able to confirm media reports. The decision would leave Washington isolated as the only state registered by the United Nations (UN) not to ratify the treaty. The Trump administration intends to formally leave the Paris Climate Accord by the year 2020. The Paris treaty obliges its signatories to drastically reduce their greenhouse gas emissions by 2050, in an attempt to stave off the worst effects of climate change. In order to draw attention to the acute threat of rising sea levels, this year's COP is presided over by the Pacific island nation of Fiji whilst technically being hosted by Germany. The key objective of the two-week conference is to formulate uniform standards for measuring and reporting greenhouse gas emissions with a view to the objectives agreed to in Paris. Syria was unable to participate in the 2015 conference which first witnessed the entry of states into the Paris Climate Accord due to its simultaneously raging civil war and UN sanctions against the government of President Bashar Al-Assad. France is organizing another multilateral climate summit in Paris which will take place on the second anniversary of the original conference, Dec 12. A spokesperson for French President Emmanuel Macron said that US President Donald Trump was "not invited so far". HYPERLINK http://imgs.syndigate.info/498/1493/24/151011126912.jpg http://imgs.syndigate.info/498/1493/24/151011126912.jpg d8cb8a5155b01b6ca38207.jpg \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China4" COP="COP23" country="China" date="August 22, 2017 Tuesday 11:02 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Defining a Pacific Blue Economy and developing a roadmap for it is at the top of agenda at the Pacific Islands Development Forum's first high-level meeting, which opened in Suva's Grand Pacific Hotel on Wednesday. President of the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 ) to the UN Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) and Fijian Prime Minister, Voreqe Bainimarama, told members of the Forum to act together on sustainable oceans and better management of its resources. In a follow-up from the UN oceans conference in June, Bainimarama highlighted the importance of the seas not only to the economic development of the region but also to its people, cultures and histories which are deeply rooted in this environment. The conference will hold discussions and break-out sessions to identify areas of the blue economy that has successfully been piloted in other parts of the world. At the end of the two-day conference there would be an outline of a blueprint for a Pacific Blue Economy to guide sustainable development of ocean resources. Bainimarama told delegates they needed to pause and consider, at every level of development, how their actions impacted the natural world around them. He said their identity as Pacific Islanders was tied intimately to the health of their oceans and to the marine plant and animal life that inhabit them. "We are oceanic peoples, with cultures, histories and ways of life that are all rooted in the ocean environment. And, make no mistake it is we in the Pacific who face the most severe consequences of the widespread degradation of our oceans and seas." But this is not only a Pacific problem. The growing threat to our oceans is affecting every person on earth, and the movement towards more "blue" economies is global, he said, adding the Pacific people needed to manage their oceans and marine resources in a more sustainable manner. He told the delegates they needed to find ways to usher in new technologies, business models and industries to restore the health of their oceans and advance the objectives of blue economic development. COP23 will be organized by Fiji and hosted at the headquarters of the UNFCCC Secretariat in Bonn, Germany, in November. The prime minister added it was their collective concerns, struggles and experiences that would be placed at the forefront of the negotiations under the Fijian presidency of the COP23 . "Our presidency is also very much tied to promoting blue economic development, as the ocean, marine eco-systems and our changing climate are inextricably linked to one another." Bainimarama said Pacific nations needed to keep up pressure for demanding the international community to take serious action. "We need to be relentless, we need to remain unified and we need to keep our interests at the top of the global agenda," Bainimarama said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China5" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday 1:47 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
China's special representative on climate change affairs Xie Zhenhua stressed south-south climate cooperation, and expressed hopes that the ongoing United Nations (UN) climate talks here would generate substantial results addressing issues that concern developing countries and an unequivocal arrangement for implementing the Paris Agreement. Xie made the remarks while addressing the high-level forum on south-south cooperation on climate change held in the China pavilion at COP 23 Wednesday. Xie said as COP 23 was crucial to implementing the Paris Agreement and to consolidating mutual trust and multilateral processes, China hoped that substantial results would be achieved at the current climate talks to address issues that concern developing countries, including adaptation, funds, technology and capacity building. Besides, an unequivocal arrangement on detailed plans to implement the Paris Agreement is also expected to be nailed down in Bonn, Xie said. Apart from these trust-building actions, Xie also proposed "development for all" and "bridging cooperation" to strengthen international cooperation in the climate field. "Developing countries, though at different stages of development, are all confronted with multiple challenges, ranging from economic growth, people's livelihood, poverty eradication, to environmental and climate protection," said the special representative. Therefore, while carrying out north-south climate cooperation and leveraging funds offered by developed countries, developing countries can boost exchanges under south-south cooperation, sharing their best practices and policy measures against climate change, Xie proposed. Recognizing the proactive roles of various international organizations, Xie said he hoped they would continue playing the bridging or binding roles in the fight against climate change. Xie said, as a responsible developing country, China conscientiously takes on its international obligations that match both its development stage and actual capacity, and implements the Paris Agreement with concrete action. To this end, China will carry forward actions including walking the promises it submitted concerning the nationally determined contribution, pursuing industrial restructuring, optimizing energy mix, promoting energy-conserving products, launching various low-carbon demonstration projects, and inaugurating the nationwide emission-trading scheme, among other actions. "The efforts made to fulfill all these above mentioned targets count as significant contribution to the global endeavor to fight climate change, which requires not only tremendous efforts from the Chinese side, but also international cooperation," Xie said. He further introduced China's efforts in helping developing countries cope with climate change under south-south cooperation. He said, through donating energy conserving or renewable-energy facilities as well as climate change surveillance instruments, and promoting climate-friendly techniques, China has offered funds, technologies and capacity building to the least developed countries, small-island countries and African countries. Since 2011, Chinese government has channeled 580 million yuan (about 85 million U.S. dollars) to help other developing countries to cope with climate change, through various initiatives ranging from low-carbon and adaptation projects to capacity building activities. China has signed 32 MOUs with 28 developing countries on the donation of materials needed in battling climate change, including over 1.2 million energy-saving or solar-energy lamps, some 13,000 solar photo-voltaic power generating facilities, and over 10,000 clean stoves, among other donations. China also donated satellite monitoring facilities to help these countries with early warning of extreme weather. Moreover, China helped train thousands of climate officials as well as technicians from more than 120 countries on five continents, according to Xie. The 23rd Conference of Parties ( COP23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) is being held in Bonn from Nov. 6 to 17. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China6" COP="COP23" country="China" date="February 19, 2018 Monday 7:47 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
About 500 education ministers and their delegations from around the world gathered on Monday in Nadi, the third largest city in Fiji, to attend the 20th Conference of Commonwealth Education Ministers (20CCEM) from Feb. 19-23. CCEM is a series of high-level meetings gathering education officials from the over 50 Commonwealth countries to discuss key education issues in the context of climate change. This is the first time the meeting is being hosted by a Pacific Island nation. The theme of 20CCEM is "Sustainability and Resilience: Can Education Deliver?" Fiji is currently holding the presidency of the United Nations climate change conference ( COP23 ). "Fiji is incredibly proud to stand as a leader among the Commonwealth as the first Pacific Island nation to host this important gathering," said Fijian Prime Minister Voreqe Bainimarama. "We offer a fitting location for 20CCEM, and not just because of our global climate leadership. Fiji is in the midst of an education revolution," said the prime minister. "We look forward to continuing this progress, sharing our learnings, and gaining new perspectives through collaboration with our fellow Commonwealth nations at this year's event," he said. The outcomes of 20CCEM will be presented at the Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting in London in April. The triennial Conference of Commonwealth Education Ministers (CCEM) is the second largest meeting organized by the Commonwealth Secretariat following the Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting. Ministers gather to share knowledge and good practices in the education sector, receive updates on actions achieved in CCEM mandates, as well as identify areas of action for the next three years for education in the Commonwealth. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China7" COP="COP23" country="China" date="May 8, 2017 Monday 9:17 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
WASHINGTON -- U.S. President Donald Trump on Monday spoke with French President-elect Emmanuel Macron to congratulate him on his victory in the French presidential election, the White House said. Trump emphasized his desire to work closely with Macron in confronting shared challenges, and noted the long and robust history of cooperation between the United States and France, the White House said in a statement.(U.S.-France-Ties) - - - - FRANKFURT -- The United Nations Climate Change Conference kicked off Monday in the western German city of Bonn. Around 3,000 delegates gathered here for talking over further implementation of the Paris Agreement on climate change, as well as for preparation for the next session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 ) to the UN Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) which is to be held November in Bonn. (Germany-UN-Climate talks) - - - - MOSUL, Iraq -- Iraqi forces battling Islamic State (IS) militants on Monday pushed further into northern Mosul on the fifth day of a new push that initiated a new front in the northwestern edge of IS stronghold in the western side of Mosul, the Iraqi military said. The army's 9th Armored Division and elite forces of the federal police, known as Rapid Response, freed the neighborhood of Harmat and raised the Iraqi flag over some of its buildings after heavy clashes against IS militants, the Iraqi Joint Operations Command (JOC) said in a statement. (Iraq-Mosul-Push) - - - - MOGADISHU -- At least five people, among them a senior Somali military commander, were confirmed killed in a car bomb explosion that hit a restaurant in Mogadishu on Monday. Reports said Gen. Abdi Adan was among the dead.(Somalia-Explosion) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China8" COP="COP23" country="China" date="May 7, 2017 Sunday 9:32 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
The Asian Development Bank (ADB) will invest 1.5 million U.S. dollars to assist Fiji's presidency of the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC), and join the Fijian government's COP23 Advisory Panel. ADB's support for Fiji's presidency of COP23 comes as ADB doubles the total financing provided for climate change to 6 billion U.S. dollars, said Stephen Groff, ADB's vice president for East Asia, Southeast Asia, and the Pacific. The ADB contribution was welcomed by Aiyaz Sayed-Khaiyum, attorney general and minister for economy and minister responsible for climate change. Khaiyum said COP23 would be critical to keep up the momentum for decisive action to reduce carbon emissions and arrest the current state of global warming. ADB's support to Fiji's COP23 presidency will include technical advice worth at least 500,000 dollars to assist the Pacific country become a global leader on green transport issues and explore options to expand insurance coverage for households, farmers, and businesses to cover potential losses from natural disasters. Recognising that small island developing countries are the most at risk from climate change, ADB will, through the COP23 Presidency Trust Fund, also provide 1 million dollars in grants to the Fijian government to ensure Pacific island countries have a strong voice in the lead up to COP23 . Established in 1966, ADB is celebrating 50 years of development partnership. It is owned by 67 members, 48 from the Asia-Pacific region. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China9" COP="COP23" country="China" date="October 25, 2017 Wednesday 7:47 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
The Fijian government and Deutsche Post launched their official partnership Wednesday, two weeks before the start of the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 ) to the UN Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) in Bonn, Germany. The "rhythm of the past is used to create resource-friendly solutions," as Deutsche Post unveils a traditional canoe - drua - that was shipped to Bonn in a carbon neutral manner, Peniana Lalabalavu, chief coordinator of COP told the press. The COP23 In line with the goal of keeping a global temperature rise this century well below 2 degrees Celsius established at the 2015 UN Paris Climate Conference (COP21), Deutsche Post DHL Group has been seeking to reduce all transport-related emissions to net zero by 2050. According to the company, it was the first global logistics service provider with a quantified CO2 efficiency target, or as Christof Ehrhart, executive vice president of German Corporate Communications, puts it "climate change has come home." The COP23 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China10" COP="COP23" country="China" date="June 1, 2017 Thursday 7:17 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Governor Jerry Brown of California, a state on the U.S. West Coast, vowed Thursday to resist President Donald Trump's withdrawal from Paris agreement on climate change. "California will resist this misguided and insane course of action," Brown said in a statement released before Trump finished his speech at Rose Garden of White House announcing his decision to withhold U.S. obligations under the international accord. "Trump is AWOL but California is on the field, ready for battle," according to the written statement. AWOL stands for Absent Without Official Leave, a term in the U.S. military, meaning away from military duties without permission. As the sixth-largest economy in the world, California has advanced its nation-leading climate goals while also growing the economy, Brown noted, adding that in the last seven years, California has created 2.3 million new jobs, outpacing most of the United States, cut its unemployment rate in half, eliminated a 27 billion U.S. dollars budget deficit and has seen its credit rating rise to the highest in more than a decade. "Donald Trump has absolutely chosen the wrong course. He's wrong on the facts. America's economy is boosted by following the Paris Agreement. He's wrong on the science. Totally wrong," said Brown, who has been working to broaden collaboration among subnational leaders, under what is known as the Under2 MOU, a memorandum of understanding signed or endorsed by 170 jurisdictions around the world to limit global warming to less than 2 degrees Celsius by the end of this century. Representing 33 countries and six continents, the Under2 Coalition claims to represent more than 1.18 billion people and 27.5 trillion dollars in gross domestic product (GDP), equivalent to 16 percent of the global population and 37 percent of the global economy. Eighteen U.S. jurisdictions have joined the Under2 Coalition, representing 89 million people and 28 percent of the U.S. population. Brown is scheduled to start Friday a travel to China to strengthen the Golden state's climate, clean energy and economic ties with the nation. In an interview with Xinhua before his departure, Brown explained his sense of urgency for action against climate change: "It is urgent. It is urgent because what we do today will create irreversible consequences in the years ahead. Time is running out. This is very serious. If the Himalayas start melting their ice more quickly, more dramatically, this will cause a lot of tension, a lot of suffering." He pointed to the fact that in California, fires are not just in the summer, but are in "most of the year." "We are experiencing already the effect of climate change," he said. "In 10, 15 or 20 years, the seas will be rising, the weather will be becoming far less benign, so it is imperative that we act." The statement also announce that Brown will attend the 2017 United Nations Climate Change Conference ( COP23 ) in Bonn, Germany, to represent subnational jurisdictions that remain committed to climate action. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China11" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 19, 2017"source="China Daily - Africa Weekly" >
As the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP 23 ) winded up here Saturday, China's special representative on climate change affairs, Xie Zhenhua, said the major dialogue on climate change, "though still not 100 percent satisfactory", had succeeded in reflecting the concerns of all sides in a balanced manner and he hoped developed countries would shoulder their obligation. Xie said a balanced negotiation document had been worked out covering all related issues in implementing the Paris Agreement. The COP 23 also clarified plans to organize facilitative dialogues in 2018 and endorsed a slew of arrangements to speed up the implementation of the pre-2020 climate action and commitments to reduce CO2 emissions. Xie said the flexibility and constructive actions adopted by the participating countries had laid a foundation for completing negotiations on the implementation of the Paris Agreement as scheduled. Pointing out the tough tasks lying ahead, he said China will support the work of the Fijian presidency to ensure negotiations on detailed plans for implementing the Paris Agreement could be completed according to schedule. "We hope that all sides adhere to the principles of equity, 'common but differentiated responsibilities and respective capabilities', and take actual conditions of each country into account while pushing forward negotiations on the implementation of Paris Agreement," Xie said. He also hoped that all sides would speed up ratification of the Doha Amendment that establishes the second commitment period of the Kyoto Protocol, and that developed countries would continue to execute their obligation to provide funds, technologies and capacity-building to developing countries. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China12" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 7, 2017 Tuesday 4:17 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
SEOUL -- South Korean President Moon Jae-in personally greeted U.S. President Donald Trump at a U.S. military base in South Korea on Tuesday as the U.S. leader began his two-day state visit to the country. Trump, on the second stop of his 12-day Asian tour, landed around noon at the Osan Air Base outside of the capital Seoul and was greeted by Kang Kyung-hwa, the foreign minister of South Korea. (South Korea-Trump-Visit) - - - - DA NANG, Vietnam -- Trade officials, ministers and economic leaders from 21 members of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) are gathering here this week for a series of meetings and an annual summit with regional integration, inclusive development and a post-2020 vision. Against a backdrop of rising trend of deglobalization and protectionism especially in the industrialized world, such as the U.S. withdrawal from the Trans-Pacific Partnership (TPP) and Brexit, APEC leaders need to reiterate their commitment to a free and open world trading system, observers and experts said. (Vietnam-APEC-Agenda) - - - - UNITED NATIONS -- The UN Security Council on Monday issued a presidential statement both complimenting and criticizing Myanmar for its action and inaction in its violence-wracked Rakhine State and gave the government a month to get its act together. In response, Myanmar's representative to the United Nations Hau Do Suan complained that the statement put undue political pressure on his country. (UN-Myanmar) - - - - BONN -- The 23rd Conference of Parties ( COP 23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) kicked off here on Monday with a call to adhere to the path of Paris Climate Change Agreement. The COP 23 COP23 -Opens) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China13" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday 11:17 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
China's special representative on climate change affairs Xie Zhenhua said he hoped the ongoing United Nations (UN) climate talks here would generate substantial results addressing issues that concern developing countries, and an unequivocal arrangement for implementing the Paris Agreement. Xie made the remarks at the high-level forum on south-south cooperation on climate change held in the China pavilion at COP 23 Wednesday. Xie said as COP 23 was crucial to implementing the Paris Agreement and to consolidating mutual trust and multilateral processes, China hoped that substantial results would be achieved at the current climate talks to address issues that concern developing countries, including adaptation, funds, technology and capacity building. Besides, an unequivocal arrangement on detailed plans to implement the Paris Agreement is also expected to be nailed down in Bonn, Xie said. Apart from these trust-building actions, Xie also proposed "development for all" and "bridging cooperation" to strengthen international cooperation in the climate field. "Developing countries, though at different stages of development, are all confronted with multiple challenges, ranging from economic growth, people's livelihood, poverty eradication, to environmental and climate protection," said the special representative. Therefore, while carrying out north-south climate cooperation and leveraging funds offered by developed countries, developing countries can boost exchanges under south-south cooperation, sharing their best practices and policy measures against climate change, Xie proposed. Recognizing the proactive roles of various international organizations, Xie said he hoped they would continue playing the bridging or binding roles in the fight against climate change. The 23rd Conference of Parties ( COP 23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) is being held in Bonn from Nov. 6 to 17. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China14" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 23, 2017 Thursday"source="China Daily" >
Climate organizations, NGOs and environmentalists have already been criticizing the slow progress made by the rich countries, and, as things stand today, the rich economies will not have contributed $100 billion to the fund by 2020. General view shows the opening session of the COP23 United Nations Climate Change Conference On a staid note, that's how the UN Climate Change Conference ended in Bonn, Germany, over the weekend, framing just the skeleton of the rulebook of the 2015 Paris Agreement and leaving it to the 2018 climate conference in Poland to put flesh and muscles on it. Many believe the Paris climate accord, if implemented to the letter, will keep the rise of global temperatures to below 2 degrees Celsius by the end of this century. But contrary to popular belief, the Paris pact is important not because of its science, but because of its timing and framework. The targets each country agreed to keep the global temperature rise to 2 C were not binding. And since the global temperature will rise to 3 C\u-243 at the least\u-243 even if all the countries meet their targets, the world needed the Paris Agreement. Moreover, as the Paris pact cannot be implemented without a rulebook, which in turn has to be completed by 2018, world leaders have no choice but to get their acts together to finalize it by next year's climate conference. And while finalizing the rulebook, the negotiators must keep the needs of the vulnerable countries in mind, and ensure the rich nations pay their promised share of funds and transfer the necessary technologies to poorer countries to help them adapt to and combat climate change. The Bonn conference was not altogether sedate though; it had its high points, such as when 12-year-old Fijian boy Timoci Naulusala gave an emotional yet calm description of how Cyclone Winston devastated his village last year. His most emphatic words: "Climate change is real, not a dream." Fiji, in a way, characterized the conference as delegates adopted the "Talanoa Dialogue". Under this Fijian concept, negotiators listen to each other, respect each other's opinions, and seek solutions that benefit everyone. Which came as a surprise, because isn't that what the climate negotiators were supposed to be doing in the first place? Dialogue brings us to US President Donald Trump. Not satisfied by just pulling out of the Paris Agreement, Trump sent a delegation to Bonn to promote "clean coal". Leading Trump's charge were White House energy aide George David Banks and officials from Peabody, the US coal company that for years has, as court documents show, been funding climate deniers. Their attempt to promote coal, however, drew boos and jeers from the delegates, many of whom walked out of the White House-sponsored panel discussion. Still, the sad reality is, even though the US cannot formally withdraw from the Paris Agreement before November 2020\u-243 when Trump's presidency will perhaps, given the opinion polls, practically end\u-243 without Washington contributing its share to the Climate Fund, it will be difficult for the other rich economies to fill the fund gap. Climate organizations, NGOs and environmentalists have already been criticizing the slow progress made by the rich countries, and, as things stand today, the rich economies will not have contributed $100 billion to the fund by 2020. Worse, the increasing use of coal in the United States and large emerging countries, including India among others, is likely to push global temperature rise to above 2 C well before 2100. Unfortunately, an end to this trend cannot be seen even on the distant horizon. By the way, if air pollution caused by greenhouse gas emissions is not drastically curbed, the horizon, as we know it, will be seen only in photographs. The Paris climate talks gave the indication that perhaps dirty fossil fuels were on their way out. Ironically, the next climate talks will be held in Katowice in Poland, a country that is highly dependent on coal due to geographical and economic factors. Will Katowice make good on the climate promise? Or, like other climate meetings, will it end with a whimper? We have to wait for the curtains to fall on that story. The author is a senior editor with China Daily. HYPERLINK mailto:oprana@hotmail.com oprana@hotmail.com HYPERLINK http://imgs.syndigate.info/498/1493/26/152956479492.jpg http://imgs.syndigate.info/498/1493/26/152956479492.jpg b083fe955fbe1b804c7b18.jpg \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China15" COP="COP23" country="China" date="December 25, 2017 Monday"source="Shanghai Daily (Benchmark)" >
LAST year, three of the world\' s largest meat companies  JBS, Cargill, and Tyson Foods  emitted more greenhouse gases than France, and nearly as much as some big oil companies. And yet, while energy giants like Exxon and Shell have drawn fire for their role in fueling climate change, the corporate meat and dairy industries have largely avoided scrutiny. If we are to avert environmental disaster, this double standard must change. To bring attention to this issue, the Institute for Agriculture and Trade Policy, GRAIN, and Germany\' s Heinrich B\'f6ll Foundation recently teamed up to study the  supersized climate footprint of the global livestock trade. What we found was shocking. In 2016, the world\' s 20 largest meat and dairy companies emitted more greenhouse gases than Germany. If these companies were a country, they would be the world\' s seventh-largest emitter. Obviously, mitigating climate change will require tackling emissions from the meat and dairy industries. The question is how. Around the world, meat and dairy companies have become politically powerful entities. The recent corruption-related arrests of two JBS executives, the brothers Joesley and Wesley Batista, pulled back the curtain on corruption in the industry. JBS is the largest meat processor in the world, earning nearly US$20 billion more in 2016 than its closest rival, Tyson Foods. But JBS achieved its position with assistance from the Brazilian Development Bank, and apparently, by bribing more than 1,800 politicians. It is no wonder, then, that greenhouse-gas emissions are low on the company\' s list of priorities. In 2016, JBS, Tyson and Cargill emitted 484 million tons of climate-changing gases, 46 million tons more than BP, the British energy giant. Meat and dairy industry insiders push hard for pro-production policies, often at the expense of environmental and public health. From seeking to block reductions in nitrous oxide and methane emissions, to circumventing obligations to reduce air, water, and soil pollution, they have managed to increase profits while dumping pollution costs on the public. One consequence, among many, is that livestock production now accounts for nearly 15 percent of global greenhouse gas emissions. That is a bigger share than the world\' s entire transportation sector. Moreover, much of the growth in meat and dairy production in the coming decades is expected to come from the industrial model. If this growth conforms to the pace projected by the UN Food and Agriculture Organization, our ability to keep temperatures from rising to apocalyptic levels will be severely undermined. At the United Nations Climate Change Conference ( COP23 ) in Bonn, Germany, last month, several UN agencies were directed, for the first time ever, to cooperate on issues related to agriculture, including livestock management. This move is welcome for many reasons, but especially because it will begin to expose the conflicts of interest that are endemic in the global agribusiness trade. To skirt climate responsibility, the meat and dairy industries have long argued that expanding production is necessary for food security. Corporate firms, they insist, can produce meat or milk more efficiently than a pastoralist in the Horn of Africa or a small-scale producer in India. Unfortunately, current climate policies do not refute this narrative, and some even encourage increased production and intensification. Rather than setting targets for the reduction of total industry-related emissions, many current policies create incentives for firms to squeeze more milk from each dairy cow and bring beef cattle to slaughter faster. This necessitates equating animals to machinery that can be tweaked to produce more with less through technological fixes, and ignoring all of this model other negative effects. California\' s experience is instructive. Pursuing one of the world\' s first efforts to regulate agricultural methane, the state government has set ambitious targets to reduce emissions in cattle processing. But California is addressing the issue by financing programs that support mega-dairies, rather than small, sustainable operators. Such  solutions have only worsened the industry\' s already-poor record on worker and animal welfare, and exacerbated adverse environmental and health-related effects. Solutions do exist. For starters, governments could redirect public money from factory farming and large-scale agribusiness to smaller, ecologically focused family farms. Governments could also use procurement policies to help build markets for local products and encourage cleaner, more vibrant farm economies. Many cities around the world are already basing their energy choices on a desire to tackle climate change. Similar criteria could shape municipalities\' food policies, too. For example, higher investment in farm-to-hospital and farm-to-school programs would ensure healthier diets for residents, strengthen local economies, and reduce the climate impact of the meat and dairy industries. Dairy and meat giants have operated with climate impunity for far too long. If we are to halt global temperature spikes and avert an ecological crisis, consumers and governments must do more to create, support, and strengthen environmentally conscious producers. That would be good for our health  and for the health of our planet. Shefali Sharma is Director of Agricultural Commodities and Globalization at the Institute for Agriculture and Trade Policy. Copyright: Project Syndicate, 2017. HYPERLINK http://www.project-syndicate.org www.project-syndicate.org \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China16" COP="COP23" country="China" date="June 8, 2017 Thursday 1:17 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
French President Emmanuel Macron on Thursday announced the creation of a web platform "Make Our Planet Great Again" in a bid to bolster efforts to combat deteriorating climate after the United States, one of the world's biggest polluters, said to withdraw Paris deal on climate change. "This platform aims at helping to mobilize all those wishing to commit themselves to projects, carry on research, take action, seek funding or move to France for the protection of our planet," Macron said in a statement released by his office. Supported by Business France, a state-run institution, the web was the outcome of civil society efforts, including scientists, teachers, entrepreneurs, associations and NGOs and students "to mobilize and join France to lead the fight against global warm." The web platform, available in both French and English languages, "provides a single tool that is challenging, practical and action-oriented," the statement added. Last Thursday, U.S. President Donald Trump said he has decided to pull the United States out of the Paris Agreement, a landmark deal to stop global warming. Agreed by 195 member economies which attended the 2015 United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP21) in Paris, the accord aims to cut greenhouse gas emissions in a way to keep the rise in the average temperature no higher than 2 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China17" COP="COP23" country="China" date="June 2, 2017 Friday 5:47 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Governor Jerry Brown of the U.S. state of California vowed Thursday to resist President Donald Trump's withdrawal from the Paris agreement on climate change. "California will resist this misguided and insane course of action," Brown said in a statement released before Trump finished his speech at Rose Garden of White House announcing his decision to withhold U.S. obligations under the international accord. "Trump is AWOL but California is on the field, ready for battle," according to the written statement. AWOL stands for Absent Without Official Leave, a term in the U.S. military, meaning away from military duties without permission. As the sixth-largest economy in the world, California has advanced its nation-leading climate goals while also growing the economy, Brown noted, adding that in the last seven years, California has created 2.3 million new jobs, outpacing most of the United States, cut its unemployment rate in half, eliminated a 27 billion U.S. dollars budget deficit and has seen its credit rating rise to the highest in more than a decade. "Donald Trump has absolutely chosen the wrong course. He's wrong on the facts. America's economy is boosted by following the Paris agreement. He's wrong on the science. Totally wrong," said Brown, who has been working to broaden collaboration among subnational leaders, under what is known as the Under2 MOU, a memorandum of understanding signed or endorsed by 170 jurisdictions around the world to limit global warming to less than 2 degrees Celsius by the end of this century. Representing 33 countries and six continents, the Under2 Coalition claims to represent more than 1.18 billion people and 27.5 trillion dollars in gross domestic product (GDP), equivalent to 16 percent of the global population and 37 percent of the global economy. Eighteen U.S. jurisdictions have joined the Under2 Coalition, representing 89 million people and 28 percent of the U.S. population. Hours after releasing the first statement, Brown, New York Governor Andrew Cuomo and Washington State Governor Jay Inslee announced the formation of the United States Climate Alliance, a coalition that will convene U.S. states committed to upholding the Paris agreement and taking action on climate change. "The President has already said climate change is a hoax, which is the exact opposite of virtually all scientific and worldwide opinion," Brown said in the second statement of the day. "I don't believe fighting reality is a good strategy -- not for America, not for anybody. If the President is going to be AWOL in this profoundly important human endeavor, then California and other states will step up." Together, representing over one-fifth of the country's GDP and about 68 million people, or nearly one-in-five Americans, the governors from California, New York and Washington said they will commit to achieving the U.S. goal of reducing emissions 26-28 percent from 2005 levels and meeting or exceeding the targets of the federal Clean Power Plan. "New York State is committed to meeting the standards set forth in the Paris accord regardless of Washington's irresponsible actions," said Cuomo. "We will not ignore the science and reality of climate change which is why I am also signing an Executive Order confirming New York's leadership role in protecting our citizens, our environment and our planet." The U.S. Climate Alliance will also act as a forum to sustain existing climate programs, promote the sharing of information and best practices, and implement new programs to reduce carbon emissions. "I am proud to stand with other governors as we make sure that the inaction in (Washington) D.C. is met by an equal force of action from the states," said Governor Inslee of Washington state in the U.S. Pacific Northwest. "Today's announcement by the president leaves the full responsibility of climate action on states and cities throughout our nation. While the president's actions are a shameful rebuke to the work needed to protect our planet for our children and grandchildren, states have been and will continue to step up," Inslee added. On his part, Brown will travel to China to strengthen the Golden State's climate, clean energy and economic ties with the nation, which he identified as a Pacific neighbor. In an interview with Xinhua before his scheduled Friday departure, Brown explained the need to take action on climate change: "It is urgent. It is urgent because what we do today will create irreversible consequences in the years ahead. Time is running out. This is very serious. If the Himalayas start melting their ice more quickly, more dramatically, this will cause a lot of tension, a lot of suffering." He pointed to the fact that in California, fires are not just in the summer, but are in "most of the year." "We are experiencing already the effect of climate change," he said. "In 10, 15 or 20 years, the seas will be rising, the weather will be becoming far less benign, so it is imperative that we act." Brown's office said the governor will also attend the 2017 United Nations Climate Change Conference ( COP23 ) in Bonn, Germany, to represent subnational jurisdictions that remain committed to climate action. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China18" COP="COP23" country="China" date="September 11, 2017 Monday 3:02 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Fijian Prime Minister Voreqe Bainimarama said on Monday that no country in the world can be spared the impact of climate change and industrialized countries should be put into action to reduce carbon emissions. Speaking in the parliament, Bainimarama, whose country is currently chair of the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 ) to the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change, said he had taken up the responsibility because no corner of the planet would be spared the fury of climate change, and climate-vulnerable people around the world were crying out for help. "If we are to avoid events like Cyclone Winston, and Hurricane Harvey and Irma, then we need to put the industrialized world into action to reduce carbon emissions and spare us from the worst effects of climate change," he said. "Given the extreme threat we faced, Fijians should not make Fiji's Presidency a political issue," he said, adding that "this is not a fight for any one party or any one community, it is a fight for Fiji, the Pacific and every nation on earth." The prime minister also confirmed that in late September, Fiji would hold a weekend of prayer for the COP23 Presidency through the churches, mosques and temples, and he hoped to see as many people in attendance as possible. According to Bainimarama, he will travel to Montreal, Canada, on Tuesday to attend a ministerial dialogue on climate action and meet with the Canadian leadership to rally support for COP23 . The COP23 The 2017 Ministerial Dialogue, known as Pre-COP, will be held in Nadi, a city of Fiji, on Oct. 17-18. It is designed primarily as a series of closed sessions for political leaders and key advisers. The objective of the Pre-COP is to allow the leaders of member parties to frankly exchange views of key political deliverables, rather than technical details, for the upcoming COP23 . \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China19" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 17, 2017 Friday 3:32 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
The UN climate talks in Bonn is scheduled to conclude on Friday. As the world once again focused on climate change, China, as the largest developing country, also attracted worldwide attention for how it acted. Through statements made in official speeches, active participation in the Bonn talks, and various side events the country organized to exchange ideas and practices, China has reasserted itself a responsible player in global battle against climate change at the 23rd Conference of Parties ( COP23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). China's special representative on climate change affairs Xie Zhenhua stated at an event of the COP 23 , that as a responsible developing country, China conscientiously takes on its international obligations that match both its development stage and actual capacity, and implements the Paris Agreement with concrete action. OVER DELIVERED ON CLIMATE TARGETS In terms of domestic efforts, "China has over delivered on achieving its targets in fighting climate change, and reversed the rapid rise of CO2 emission that had lasted for years," Xie stated while addressing a high-level meeting of COP 23 . Moreover, the share of coal in the total consumption of energy had decreased from 72 percent to 64 percent in the 2005-2015 time frame, while the share of non-fossil fuels in primary energy consumption rose from 7.4 percent to 12 percent, and at the same time, the country's forest reserve had expanded by 3 billion cubic meters, according to Xie. "This year, we will jumpstart the nation-wide carbon-trading market," Xie said during his speech. China's domestic climate actions have been widely recognized in the international community. Barbara Hendricks, German environment minister, told Xinhua that she is aware that China planned to build far fewer thermal power plants than five years ago, and to generate more and more power from renewable energy, which means China is on a good path of development. Dylan Murray, policy advisor with the Nature Conservancy, told Xinhua "China is taking real steps to peak emissions". In the future, China's economy will further decouple with fossil fuels, and tougher controls on the efficiency, or even on the total consumption of coal are foreseeable, estimated Liu Qiang, director of Strategy and Planning Department of the National Center for Climate Change Strategy and International Cooperation. GUARDIAN OF MULTILATERAL PROCESSES Globally, China has promised to peak its CO2 emission by around 2030, and made crucial contributions to the signing of the Paris Agreement that seeks to limit a rise in temperatures to "well below" 2 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial times. Norbert Salomon, deputy director of the Emission Control, Safety of Installations and Transport at the German Federal Ministry for Environment, said "China's engagement and contributions to combat climate change is itself an inestimable value for global community." Xie Zhenhua pledged at a high-level meeting of the COP 23 that China is ready to play the role as a guardian of multilateral processes and will work with other countries to ensure the implementation of the Paris Agreement. At the COP 23 , China has played a proactive role, Gu Zihua, a Chinese negotiator, said in an interview with Xinhua. "We have been substantially engaged in the talks on each agenda, and contributed China's proposals," Gu said. Moreover, China has been acted as a mediator of the developing countries to coordinate their stances and kept close consultations with the president on facilitative dialogue. DRIVING SOUTH-SOUTH COOPERATION China has set aside a total of 100 million U.S. dollars for South-South cooperation with 27 developing countries over the years, Xie announced at a high-level meeting at the COP 23 . Best practices of many such projects are shared at the side events of COP 23 . Among them, a project of low carbon town in Gampola, Sri Lanka, showed how China helped developing countries with adaptation. Global Environmental Institute (GEI), a Chinese NGO, has completed assessment of solar energy and biomass potential of Gampola and introduced the Sri Lanka side to the fund for south south cooperation. Ranish Hettige, deputy assistant secretary of Sri Lanka's Mahaweli Development and Environment Ministry, told Xinhua that the GEI offered them toolkits, mechanisms and technologies to adapt to climate change. "It is very hard for Sri Lanka to afford many new technologies, like introducing solar energy or electric vehicles. There are funds from other countries like China that helped us to make sure we are adapting to climate change. The help of China is very important to us," Hettige said. Now, with the China-proposed Belt and Road Initiative, a new opportunity arises for south-south climate cooperation. Robert Ddamulira, with the World Wildlife Fund in Uganda, said the initiative offers a great opportunity especially considering that China is a leading country in renewable energy. Looking into the future, Wang Shi, a former real estate tycoon and now Chair of the Board of Vanke Foundation, said he is optimistic. Having followed the UN climate talks since Copenhagen in 2009, Wang said he had witnessed that the Chinese government is getting more and more proactive. Moreover, when the foundation is promoting environmental projects in various Chinese localities, he found the green and low-carbon concept had been ingrained in everybody's mind. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China20" COP="COP23" country="China" date="July 17, 2017 Monday"source="China Daily European Edition" >
PARIS - French President Emmanuel Macron said Sunday he hoped his American counterpart Donald Trump would reverse his decision to withdraw the United States from the Paris climate accord. "Donald Trump listened to me, he understood the meaning of my approach, including the link between global warming and terrorism. He told me that he would try to find a solution in the coming months," Macron said. "It is important to maintain the dialogue so that the United States can eventually reintegrate the field of action against global warming and play the game of multilateralism," said Macron, who pleaded for continued talks with Washington despite divergence over the climate issue. During his first visit to Paris, Trump on Thursday hinted at a possible change in his position over the Paris climate accord from which he pulled out weeks ago. "Something could happen with respect to the Paris accord, let's see what happens," he said. "We will talk about that over the coming period of time and if it happens, that will be wonderful, and if it doesn't, that'll be okay too," he added. Agreed by 195 member economies which attended the 2015 United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP21) in Paris, the accord aims to cut greenhouse gas emissions in a way to keep the rise in the average temperature no higher than 2 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China21" COP="COP23" country="China" date="July 6, 2017 Thursday 12:02 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
French ecology minister Nicolas Hulot expressed his hopes on Thursday to meet the commitment of reducing the share of nuclear energy in the country's electricity output by 2025. Unveiling an action plan for the country's energy transition, the environmental activist said cutting electricity generated by nuclear power to 50 percent by 2025 from the current 75 percent was France's "objective." "I hope (the target) will be held. My wish is to engage irreversible trajectories and dynamics," Hulot told reporters. France operates 58 reactors and has been a leading international proponent of nuclear energy. However, closing nuclear plants has been a controversial issue in the country as France is the most nuclear-energy reliant country in the world, with more than three quarters of its power coming from nuclear. In a move to "accelerate the implementation of the Paris climate agreement," France aims to go carbon neutral by 2050, Hulot announced. Furthermore, he pledged to phase out the sale of petrol vehicles by 2040. To do this, the French government will offer people financial incentives to scrap their polluting vehicles -- including diesel cars dating before 1997 or petrol cars made before 2001 -- in exchange for clean units, the minister added. In 2015, France hosted the United Nations Climate Change Conference \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China22" COP="COP23" country="China" date="July 10, 2017 Monday"source="Xinhua Financial News" >
France planned to close up to 17 nuclear reactors by 2025 as part of its energy transition, to trim nuclear power to 50 percent of the country's electricity generation, ecology minister Nicolas Hulot said on Monday.quotFrom the moment it has been confirmed to reduce nuclear energy of electricity production to 50 percent, everyone can understand that in order to achieve this objective, we will close some reactors, and not only one reactor,quot Hulot told RTL radio. quotIt could be up to 17 reactors we'll have to see,quot he added.France operates 58 reactors and has been a leading international proponent of nuclear energy. However, closing nuclear plants has been a controversial issue in the country as France is the most nuclear-energy relying country in the world, with more than three quarters of its power coming from nuclear.Last Thursday, Hulot raised the curtain on the government's quotClimate Planquot in order quotto make France leader of green economyquot. With it, the environmentalist activist aims to reach carbon neutrality by 2050.Furthermore, he pledged quotthe end of the sale of petrol or diesel vehicles between now and 2040quot.The French government, instead, will offer financial incentives to scrap their polluting vehicles including diesel car dating before 1997 or petrol from before 2001, for clean units, the minister added. In 2015, France held the United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP21) in which 195 member economies agreed an accord to cut greenhouse gas emissions in a way to keep the rise in the average temperature no higher than 2 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China23" COP="COP23" country="China" date="May 25, 2017 Thursday 12:02 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
French President Emmanuel Macron on Thursday hinted that he failed to woo U.S. President Donald Trump's support on Paris agreement on climate change. Speaking at a joint press conference with European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker on the heels of their meeting in Brussels, Macron said :"As for climate, President Trump can assert his position. I respect the fact that he has a review of the Paris agreement." "It's (the agreement) an important thing for international community. We have a political responsibility to assume, and we have to think also about jobs and economic development." he said. "No hasty decision should be taken on this subject by the United States... our collective responsibility is to ensure that this commitment remains a global commitment." he added. The Paris Agreement was agreed by the 195 member economies which attended the 2015 United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP21) in Paris. It went into effect last November. Trump, on his first overseas trip as U.S. president, on Thursday met with European Council President Donald Tusk and Juncker, before holding a lunch meeting with Macron. However, Macron claimed that the lunch meeting with Trump was "a very good, frank and warm discussion". "It's necessary for the United States of America to remain an essential partner as regards collective security, development and the fight against terrorism." he said. Later on Thursday, Trump and leaders of other NATO countries are set to meet for the first time to map out the future of the organization, and try to narrow their differences on its budget. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China24" COP="COP23" country="China" date="December 13, 2017 Wednesday 5:02 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
French President Emmanuel Macron on Tuesday met with Chinese Vice Premier Ma Kai, who was in Paris to attend the One Planet Summit as the special envoy of President Xi Jinping. Ma conveyed greetings to Macron from the Chinese president, who wished a great success for the one-day summit focusing on mobilizing public funds to achieve climate goals. Ma said that President Xi attaches great importance to China-France relations and their cooperation on climate change. China is determined to honor its commitments made under the framework of the Paris Agreement, and is willing to work with relevant parties, including France, to push forward the multilateral process of combating climate change, he said. China appreciates Macron's support for the Belt and Road Initiative, and expects to continue high-level dialogues with France on mutually beneficial cooperation in various fields such as nuclear energy, aerospace, green finance and advanced manufacturing, said Ma This will inject new momentum into the China-France comprehensive strategic partnership, he added. Macron said that developing relations with China is of great importance for France. France hopes to maintain high-level exchanges with China, be actively engaged in the Belt and Road Initiative, and work with China to contribute more to global multilateral governance processes including the fight against climate change, the president said. In a speech at the summit, Ma stressed that China will continue to support the Paris Agreement and contribute to the global efforts to curb climate change through concrete actions. The One Planet Summit was convened by Macron on the occasion of the second anniversary of the Paris Agreement, a landmark climate deal reached at the 2015 United Nations Climate Change Conference in Paris. The summit brought together leaders and high-ranking officials from some 50 countries and nearly 4,000 representatives from non-government actors including international organizations, enterprises and research institutions. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China25" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 16, 2017 Thursday"source="Shenzhen Daily" >
THE Chinese mainland will continue to enable Taiwan compatriots on the mainland to enjoy equal treatment in terms of study, businesses and earnings as mainland residents, a spokesperson said yesterday. This would be done in accordance with the spirit of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, which was convened last month, said Ma Xiaoguang with the State Council Taiwan Affairs Office at a press conference. Earlier this year, the mainland introduced policies supporting Taiwan-funded enterprises investing on the mainland, encouraging them to take part in the Belt and Road Initiative, and allowing qualified Taiwan lawyers to handle a wider range of civil cases. High school students with qualified college entrance exam scores in Taiwan can apply directly to universities on the mainland from Oct. 1 and Taiwan students are now eligible for more scholarships thanks to new policies, according to Ma. The Ministry of Education also required universities to offer employment guidance to Taiwan students if they are willing to work on the mainland. When answering a question about Taiwan\' s failure to participate in the United Nations Climate Change Conference held in Germany, Ma said Taiwan\' s refusal to adhere to the 1992 Consensus is the crucial reason for its problems in participating in international affairs. Taiwan authorities refuse to adhere to the 1992 Consensus, which has led to the suspension of communication with the mainland and made it impossible for the two sides to solve problems, Ma said.  The Taiwan side should reflect on its own mistake, rather than falsely accuse the mainland, he said. Ma said the mainland has always firmly opposed any country it has diplomatic relations with to sign any agreement with Taiwan that implies the island is a sovereign country. The mainland and Taiwan belong to the same China and the handling of relevant affairs must strictly follow this principle, Ma said when answering a question about Taiwan\' s plans to draft a law on mutual aid in international criminal justice. (Xinhua) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China26" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 16, 2017 Thursday 8:32 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
German Chancellor Angela Merkel and President Frank-Walter Steinmeier Wednesday urged the international community to make greater efforts to fight climate change at the ongoing 23rd Conference of the Parties to the United Nations Convention on Climate Change ( COP23 ) in Bonn. Calling climate change a question of humanity's fate, Merkel said additional efforts were needed to fulfil the 2015 Paris climate accord, stressing that the current endeavors were not sufficient. In the landmark Paris accord, the participating countries agreed to keep global temperature increase in this century below 2 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels and seek to decrease it further to 1.5 degrees Celsius. Before her speech, Steinmeier warned that the "dramatic" consequences of climate change were already apparent in the melting of Alpine glaciers as well as recent extreme weather patterns that had destroyed the homes of thousands. Consequently, he said, the community of states needs to act swiftly and decisively to implement the Paris agreement. The German president was optimistic that the current momentum of international cooperation on climate change would be maintained, suggesting that even the United States could rejoin the multilateral effort at a later stage. U.S. President Donald Trump announced withdrawal from the Paris accord on June 1, making the United States the only UN member that does not support the landmark deal. Attended by 25,000 delegates from 195 countries, COP23 is the largest in history since the first edition was held in Berlin in 1995. Since COP23 According to German media reports, a first success has been achieved in drafting a regulatory framework to implement the Paris accord. The organizers of COP23 hope that a formal agreement on it would be achieved at the next UN climate conference to be held in Poland. Merkel has drawn criticism from Greenpeace and German environmental organizations for her alleged failure to fulfill her promises regarding climate change. As COP23 opened, environmental activists blocked access to the Weisweiler coal plant near Germany's westernmost city of Aachen. Data from the German Environmental Ministry indicate that Weisweiler emits 18 million tons of CO2 each year, making it one of the five most polluting power plants in the country. RWE, the firm operating Weisweiler, told the press that it was forced to partially shut down the plant. Police have sent special forces to end the blockade, which was called an act of sabotage, and said they would arrest the dozens of protesters involved. The parallel incident at Weisweiler has attracted considerable attention in Berlin, where the Christian Democratic Union (CDU), Christian Social Union, Free Democratic Party and Greens are in the middle of coalition negotiations. The Greens are demanding that the next German government shut down 20 coal plants to achieve national climate policy objectives. The proposal has been met with heavy resistance from the other three, who have voiced concerns over the impact of an exit from coal power on domestic employment and energy security. Further discussions on the subject, which has become a key stumbling block in coalition negotiations, are due when Merkel returns from Bonn to Berlin Wednesday night. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China27" COP="COP23" country="China" date="October 6, 2017 Friday 12:17 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Nanise Rainima, the Miss World Fiji 2017, is keen to attend the upcoming world beauty pageant in Sanya, China. In an exclusive interview with Xinhua on Friday, Rainima, 25, said all her costumes and gowns, talent preparations, traditional dance practices, training and swimming sessions were completed to prepare her for the Miss World 2017 pageant scheduled to be held in Sanya, a city in China's Hainan province on Nov. 18. As part of her preparations of travelling to China, Rainima, who is from Fiji's Tailevu province based in Viti Levu, Fiji's largest island, has taken up Mandarin social classes and hopes to use what she has learnt to get around China and even speak with the locals there as far as her Chinese language could take her. Rainima, a bachelor of science graduate from the University of the South Pacific in Fiji, was crowned Fiji's Miss Hibiscus in 2014 and represented her country to the Miss Pacific Islands pageant in the same year. Rainima was ready for the rollercoaster ride ahead of her in the international arena. "Preparations have been widespread. I've been having opportunities to speak at schools and events, training and dieting to prepare myself well physically," she said. "There's been talent and song recording, traditional dance practices at the Conservatorium of Music, meeting with designers and sponsors for styling, fittings and photo shoots." As for the new format of Miss World with a "greater emphasis" on social media and interactivity, she said that one of the challenges she faces was getting the exposure she needs through social media and gathering up votes as the advantage was towards the bigger countries competing in the Miss World contest. "I'm posting as much as I can on all my social media sites before I am leaving for China," she said, adding that she goes prepared with her message to the world about climate change, as Fiji is now the President of the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 ) to the UN Convention on Climate Change, which is to take place in Bonn, Germany, in November this year. With Fiji as the President of COP 23 this year, the Pacific region will show the world what true climate leadership is and they will also highlight for the world what climate change in the Pacific looks like and how inaction on climate change exacerbates that threat. Rainima believes that this year's Miss World stage will be a great platform for her to say something about the importance of climate change and urge countries to work together to deal with climate change. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China28" COP="COP23" country="China" date="July 2, 2017 Sunday 10:47 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Fijian Prime Minister Voreqe Bainimarama said on Monday that while the United States had abandoned its leadership on climate change, the door remained open to U.S. President Donald Trump, given the commitment by other Americans to climate action. Bainimarama, who is also president of the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 With the head of states from the Federated States of Micronesia and Tuvalu, as well as nearly 300 delegates from across the Pacific, Bainimarama made a clear statement for a re-dedication to the endeavor. He said while there would be refugees of climate change, the people of Kiribati and Tuvalu need not worry, because Fiji would take them in. In the lead-up to the COP23 meeting and having a collective Pacific agenda, Bainimarama has formally endorsed the "Under2 Coalition" with the appointment of Jerry Brown, the governor of U.S. state of California, as a Special COP23 Envoy to the States and Regions. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China29" COP="COP23" country="China" date="October 17, 2017 Tuesday 3:47 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
UN Deputy Secretary General Amina J. Mohammed warned here on Tuesday that extreme weather crisis will continue to happen if actions are not taken to meet climate change challenges. "Extreme weather events show in graphic detail the risks we all face if ambition, action and commitment are not raised to meet the challenges of climate change," Amina said at the opening ceremony of the Pre- COP23 in Denarau, an island near Fiji's third largest city of Nadi. She said that they highlight the urgency of building resilience, investing in adaptation and bending the emissions curve by 2020. For the United Nations, these events also underline the need to press forward, in line with the mandate from member states, on the UN secretary-general's reforms to reposition the UN Development System to better support countries to achieve their commitments under the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development. These include the Sustainable Development Goals, the Paris Agreement on Climate Change, and the Sendai Framework for Disaster Risk Reduction, all landmark agreements reached in 2015, she said, adding that implementation of the three must go together. She urged governments, businesses and citizens to work together and do their duties to fight climate change. Describing the Paris agreement as a remarkable achievement, she said that to deliver on its full potential, and assist governments and society to go further, faster together, it needs a complete and uncluttered set of guidelines that ensure collective responsibility for the achievement of the long term objective of the agreement. These guidelines should ensure that the agreement fosters transparency on action and support, how parties will take stock of the global situation and how mechanism to facilitate implementation and promote compliance will operate, she said. "We have the agreement. Now we need to raise ambition. 2020 should mark a turning point in the global economy, especially in key sectors. The secretary-general will continue to press member states to bend the emissions curve and scale up efforts to build resilience so that this turning point can indeed be reached," she said. "As we look towards Bonn and beyond, this Pre-COP is a crucial planning opportunity. Besides the guidelines, the COP should agree on a package of modalities to convene Facilitative Dialogue aimed at assessing and ramping up ambition." She noted that there should be no doubt that "we are entering a new chapter on climate change" and "Our task is to ensure that it is adequate to the challenge." A total of 300 delegates from over 60 countries and regions, international institutions, civil society organizations and business leaders are gathering here to attend the two-day conference, namely Pre- COP 23 , which officially started here on Tuesday. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China30" COP="COP23" country="China" date="December 20, 2017 Wednesday 2:17 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Fiji, a small developing island state in the South Pacific region, is now playing a leading role in fighting climate change widely considered to be one of the biggest threats facing mankind. For Fiji, 2017 is certainly a significant year as the state has done a lot in dealing with climate change, including co-hosting the U.N. Oceans Conference in New York in June and presiding over COP23 -- the U.N. climate negotiations in Bonn, Germany in November. In fact, Fiji has made history by becoming the first such state to preside over COP23 . COP23 and Minister for Agriculture, Rural and Maritime Development and National Disaster Management, the future of Fiji is at stake. The future of our planet is at stake. And Fiji has taken on these climate change-linked responsibilities not only for every Fijian and every Pacific islander but for all 7.5 billion people on earth. For Fiji and the rest of the world, it is imperative to act now to save the planet by reducing carbon emissions and reducing the impact of climate change. Voreqe Bainimarama, president of COP23 and Fijian prime minister, has stressed that "We have only one planet to call home and now is the time to move forward together to save it." "I appeal to the entire world to support Fiji's efforts to continue building the global consensus to confront the greatest challenge of our age. We owe it not only to ourselves but also to future generations to tackle this issue head on before it is too late," he said. "Unless the world acts decisively to begin addressing the greatest challenge of our age, then the Pacific, as we know it, is doomed." For Fiji, climate change is really a "to be or not to be" question because the consequences of inaction will be catastrophic. A study released in Bonn this November showed that by 2050, Fiji's annual losses due to extreme weather events could reach 6.5 percent of Gross Domestic Product (GDP) because of the impact of climate change, with more than 32,000 people pushed into hardship every year. According to Fiji's National Climate Change Policy, global sea level changes will more than double by the end of this century. Fiji has since 1993 recorded a 6mm increase in its sea level per year, larger than the global average. The rapid rise of sea levels and the resulting saltwater intrusion that stems from the increased ferocity of coastal floods have made portions of the island nation uninhabitable. As a small state with more than 300 islands and a population of around 900,000, Fiji is highly vulnerable to the effects of climate change and the unsustainable exploitation of the oceans. Fiji very keenly feels the negative effects of climate change, including unpredictable storms of extreme intensity, such as Tropical Cyclone Winston. Winston lashed the island state and killed 44 people and caused serious economic losses in February 2016. In addition, the sea levels rising has caused the Fijian government to identify quite a number of villages to be relocated to higher ground. Meanwhile, warming seas have caused changes in fish populations and the bleaching of coral reefs. Currently, Fiji has relocated three villages to higher ground, and the country has another 42 to 43 villages earmarked to be moved to higher ground from coastal areas. Having assumed the presidency of the the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) negotiations at COP23 , and being the first nation to ratify the 2015 U.N. Paris Agreement, Fiji fully understands the pivotal role "green growth" plays in creating a sustainable economy. The COP23 Fiji and the countries involved, launched the Ocean Pathways Partnership to further action to protect their oceans from climate effects. They also reached an historic agreement on agriculture, an action plan on gender and a decision that benefits local communities and indigenous peoples. They secured greater funding for critical climate adaptation work, and took the next step in ensuring that the Adaptation Fund shall serve the Paris Agreement. Finally, they launched a global partnership to provide millions of climate-vulnerable people around the world with affordable access to insurance. Fiji, which has pledged to transition completely to renewable energy sources by 2030, has adopted a reforestation policy intended to store carbon from freshly planted trees. Working alongside the Global Environment Facility, the Green Climate Fund and several United Nations agencies, Fiji has initiated efforts to monitor and launch rapid responses to climate-related risks. Fiji has, this October, hosted high-level delegations from around the world to begin dialogues to find ways of addressing the impact of climate change. As one of the 43 nations on the Climate Vulnerable Forum, Fiji has been a vocal proponent of limiting the temperature rise from global warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius. In 2017, Fiji became the first small island developing state to join the Under2 Coalition, which is an international pact among cities, states and countries committed to limiting the increase in the global average temperature to below 2 degrees Celsius by either reducing their greenhouse gas emissions from 80 percent to 95 percent below 1990 levels, or holding emissions to less than 2 annual metric tons per capita by 2050. Besides Fiji's first-ever National Climate Change Week being launched in September, the island state also became the first country in the Pacific, the first emerging economy and the first small island state to issue this November a 100 million Fiji dollars (about 48 million U.S. dollars) Green Bond. The Green Bond will fund projects for climate mitigation and adaptation to build a stronger, more resilient Fiji. In fact, Fiji is also the third in the world to issue the sovereign Green Bond, after France and Poland. The successful COP23 and the measures Fiji has taken have made the world aware of Fiji in a way that has never been experienced in the nation's history. Fiji is now more than a vacation spot and a rugby powerhouse, it is a global leader which is at the forefront of the most pressing issue of our time, climate change. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China31" COP="COP23" country="China" date="May 23, 2017 Tuesday 4:17 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
BERLIN, May 22 (Xinhua)-- China is preparing to address the issues related to the implementation of the Paris Agreement to push forward global climate governance, China's Special Representative on Climate Change Xie Zhenhua said here Monday Xie made the remarks at the 8th Petersberg Climate Dialogue in Berlin. China's plan aims to seek the broadest consensus among the signatories to the Paris Agreement, reflecting the principle of "common but differentiated responsibilities," climate equity, and matching action and support, Xie said. In 2016, China's carbon intensity dropped 6 percent from the previous year, much higher than the original goal of 3.9 percent, Xie said. China has taken a series of restrictive measures in the 13th Five Year Plan, including reducing 18 percent of carbon intensity and raising the proportion of non-fossil energy in primary energy to 15 percent from 2016 to 2020, according to Xie. China has launched the South-South Cooperation Foundation on climate change and cooperated with 27 countries to help improve their adaptability to climate change as well as their management and financing capabilities, Xie said. To carry out the Paris Agreement, China proposes enhancing political mutual trust and accelerating the implementation of the Paris Agreement, turning the efforts to implement the agreement into endeavors to promote economic transition and develop new energy industries, boosting win-win cooperation and setting up incentive mechanisms to ensure sustained implementation of the agreement, Xie said. China will stick to its concept of development marked by innovation, coordination, green development, opening up and sharing, and cope with climate change actively no matter how the international situation changes, Xie said. China will fully support Fiji to host this year's UN Climate Change Conference (COP) and promote the formulation by the conference of a draft resolution on subsequent negotiations following the implementation of the Paris Agreement, Xie said. The Petersberg Climate Dialogue, an annual informal ministerial meeting launched by Germany in 2010, mainly focuses on preparing for the COP each year. The Paris Agreement was agreed by the 195 member economies which attended the 2015 United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP21) in Paris. It went into effect last November. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China32" COP="COP23" country="China" date="May 17, 2017 Wednesday 3:17 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
The Commonwealth is to outline a strategy to tackle climate change across the planet. Some of the world's leading environmental experts will meet at a Commonwealth conference on Thursday to see how they can take forward an innovative strategy to reverse the human impact of climate change. The Commonwealth's aim, according to Secretary-General Patricia Scotland, is to create a new approach which will influence the debate among world leaders when they meet at the United Nations Climate Change Conference in Bonn, Germany this November. The Commonwealth's Regenerative Development to Reverse Climate Change Conference, organized in collaboration with the Cloudburst Foundation, is the second meeting of experts convened by the Commonwealth, whose member nations are mostly former nations of the British Empire. Scotland said: "A pronounced increase in violent storms, floods, drought, desertification and devastating sea level rises -- extreme events such as these are the realities that many people across the Commonwealth wake up to every day." She said that it was a "truly historic moment" for the Commonwealth as the first inter-governmental organisation to take on the challenge of "flipping the narrative" on climate change. Scotland said that last October funders and leading experts on climate change, came to the Commonwealth headquarters in London to give a verdict on the feasibility of making reversal rather than mitigation our goal. "We looked at existing working examples of the regenerative development approach, which mean actions to heal the damage we have caused to the earth and working with nature instead of against nature," said Scotland. Examples included tapping into the power of volcanic hot springs for electricity, geothermal power plants, regenerating coastal wetlands and constructing buildings that mimic trees in the way they dispose of carbon. "The unanimous agreement was that, if we have the political will and work together, we can drastically reduce carbon emissions and reverse the human impact of climate change while accelerating economic growth and boosting development," said Scotland. Scotland will present their findings at the Commonwealth Secretariat's London headquarters on Thursday. This includes submissions from Project Drawdown, a comprehensive plan with the potential to reverse global warming. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China33" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 8, 2017 Wednesday 4:47 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
During the annual Benelux summit, this time in The Hague, the Prime Ministers of the Netherlands, Belgium and Luxembourg on Wednesday expressed the ambition to more extensive cooperation on dealing with cross-border crime and terrorism. "We are convinced that we have to further extend our police cooperation and we are preparing to strengthen this cooperation," said Belgian Prime Minister Charles Michel during a press moment in The Hague. "The Benelux partnership is a way for our three countries to tackle transnational challenges and play a pioneering role in Europe," Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte stated. "The Benelux is an incubator for further action in moving forward in the European Union," Xavier Bettel, Prime-Minister of Luxembourg added. The last Benelux treaty on the cross-border fight against crime dates from 2004, the Senningen Treaty, and the Benelux countries already agreed last year to get more possibilities to chase criminals across their common borders. Now Rutte, Michel and Bettel urged their Ministers of Interior and Justice and Security to come with an update and prepare a new treaty for 2018. The three PM's started the Summit of the Benelux, a politico-economic union of the three neighboring states, on Wednesday at the Catshuis in The Hague, the official residence of Dutch PM Rutte, to speak about cross-border issues, such as the economy, transport and security. After that they had a working dinner at the Gemeentemuseum, an art museum in The Hague, in which they mainly spoke on sustainability and innovation, the central themes of the Summit, with business and science experts. With the United Nations Climate Change Conference currently taking place in Bonn, Germany, the Benelux countries expressed a common ambition in making an energy transition, from polluting emissions to a world of more sustainable energy. "The Climate Agreement of Paris is, as liberal Prime Ministers, an enormous opportunity to tackle global warming, while creating additional growth and jobs," Rutte said. "The global cooperation is still in the early stages on climate change, but the Benelux also wants to take a leading role in the European Union on this subject." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China34" COP="COP23" country="China" date="June 13, 2017 Tuesday 8:17 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Governor Jerry Brown of the U.S. state of California was named Tuesday special advisor for states and regions at the forthcoming 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties, or COP23 , to the U.N. Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). The appointment by Fiji's Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama took place at a ceremony where Fiji became the latest government to join the Under2 Coalition, an international pact among cities, states and countries to limit the increase in global average temperature to below 2 degrees Celsius. While Bainimarama will be incoming president of COP23 , and Brown has announced his decision to attend the gathering in Bonn, Germany, to represent subnational jurisdictions under the Under2 Coalition that remain committed to climate action despite the recent U.S. withdrawal from the Paris Agreement on climate change. The ceremony in Sacarmento, state capital of California, was attended by Governor Kate Brown of Oregon and Governor Jay Inslee of Washington state, who announced that they too will attend the COP23 scheduled for November 6 through 17. While the Paris Agreement, which builds upon the UNFCCC, calls on all nations to respond to the threat of climate change by keeping a global temperature rise this century well below 2 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels and to pursue efforts to limit the temperature increase even further to 1.5 degrees, the Under2 Coalition was formed in 2015 by California and the German state of Baden-Wurttemberg to help galvanize subnational action in the same direction. On his part, Bainimarama said "Fiji looks forward to working with this group of states and regions in the global effort to advance climate action at every level of society. This is true now more than ever following the Trump Administration's announcement that the U.S. will be withdrawing from the Paris Agreement. This decision has redoubled our commitment to forge a Grand Coalition that includes all levels of government, businesses and civil society, to take climate action forward with the urgency it deserves." Brown has been vocal against U.S. President Donald Trump's environmental policies and vowed on June 1, the day the administration announced to withdraw from the Paris Agreement, that California will "resist." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China35" COP="COP23" country="China" date="August 31, 2017 Thursday"source="China Daily" >
Yemen Airstrike hits oil truck, kills 5 A Saudi-led coalition airstrike hit an oil truck on Yemen's Sanaa-Hodiedah road on Wednesday, killing five civilians including the driver, a security official said. It is the latest coalition airstrike to hit civilians in the war-torn Arab country. On Friday, coalition fighter jets struck three houses in Faj Attan quarter in downtown Sanaa, killing 14, including six children. A day later, the coalition admitted responsibility for the airstrike, describing it as a "technical mistake". Libya About 700 migrants rescued off coast Libyan coast guards over the past two days rescued nearly 700 migrants on their way to European shores, a spokesman said on Tuesday. Spokesman Ayob Qasem said more than 450 migrants were rescued off the coast of Sabratha in western Libya on Tuesday. Qasem also said that two boats with 222 migrants on board were rescued on Monday, with the help of the Italian Navy. France Macron to host climate summit French President Emmanuel Macron announced Tuesday that France will host an international summit on Dec 12 to ensure the implementation of the Paris Agreement on climate change. The summit is scheduled to take place two years to the date when the historic agreement was reached at the 2015 United Nations Climate Change Conference in Paris. The summit is expected to "make a key progress" and "mobilize the necessary funding" for the implementation of the agreement, Macron said in a speech on foreign policy to ambassadors. India 217 children died in August: hospital A government hospital in northern India where dozens of babies died within two days earlier this month says at least 217 children have died during the month of August for a variety of reasons including an encephalitis outbreak. The head of the BRD Medical College in Gorakhpur city, Doctor P.K. Singh, said on Wednesday that 42 children had died in the hospital in the last 48 hours. Seven of the deaths were from encephalitis. Thirty-three children died on Aug 10 and 11 at the hospital. Australia Number plate sells for nearly $2m A black-and-white vehicle number plate with the single digit"4" has sold at a Sydney auction for a record-breaking near $2 million. The sale shattered pre-sale estimates of up to A$1.5 million, with the auction hammer coming down at A$2.45 million - more than twice the average cost of a Sydney home. "Just nine of these New South Wales number plates were ever issued, making them ultra-collectible and irreplaceable," said Shannons auction manager Christophe Boribon. Xinhua - afp - ap (China Daily 08/31/2017 page12) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China36" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 16, 2017 Thursday"source="Shanghai Daily (Benchmark)" >
TAIWAN authorities should abandon their hostile mentality and respect the choice of its residents, a Chinese mainland spokesman said yesterday. Ma Xiaoguang, of the Taiwan Affairs Office of the State Council, was answering a question about a Shanghai-based Taiwan native who was elected a delegate to the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. Lu Li-an, an English literature professor from Fudan University who was born and raised in Taiwan, was deprived of her household status by Taiwan authorities after she attended the congress as a Party member in October.  No matter what measures the Taiwan authorities take, Lu\' s love for her hometown and the Chinese mainland will not be damaged, Ma said.  No matter whether she has household status in Taiwan or not, the mainland and Taiwan are both her home. Noting she was proud of her heritage, Lu called on other islanders to take part in the great cause of realizing the Chinese Dream when meeting reporters on the sidelines of the congress. Ma said:  The experience of witnessing remarkable changes in the mainland has increased certain Taiwan compatriots\' admiration and recognition of the CPC. It\' s very natural. The Chinese mainland will continue to enable Taiwan compatriots on the mainland to enjoy equal treatment in terms of study, business and earnings as mainland residents, Ma said. Earlier this year, the mainland introduced policies supporting Taiwan-funded enterprises investing in the mainland, encouraging them to take part in the Belt and Road initiative, and allowing qualified Taiwan lawyers to handle a wider range of civil cases. High school students with qualified college entrance exam scores in Taiwan have been able to apply directly to universities on the mainland from October 1 and Taiwan students are now eligible for more scholarships thanks to new policies, Ma said. The Ministry of Education also required universities to offer Taiwan students employment guidance if they are willing to work on the mainland. Ma said Taiwan\' s refusal to adhere to the 1992 Consensus  that both sides belong to the one China  is the crucial reason for its problems in participating in international affairs. Ma had been asked about Taiwan\' s failure to participate in the United Nations Climate Change Conference in Germany. Taiwan authorities refuse to adhere to the 1992 Consensus, which has led to the suspension of communication with the mainland and made it impossible for the two sides to solve problems.  The Taiwan side should reflect on its own mistake, rather than falsely accuse the mainland, Ma said. He said the mainland has always firmly opposed any country it has diplomatic relations with to sign any agreement with Taiwan that implies the island is a sovereign country. The mainland and Taiwan belong to the same China, Ma said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China37" COP="COP23" country="China" date="July 2, 2017 Sunday 11:17 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
About 300 leaders and experts from Pacific Island countries gathered in Suva Monday to discuss enhancing cooperation in the fight against climate change. The event, organized by Climate Action Pacific Partnership (CAPP), brought together relevant stakeholders to promote the exchange of ideas, innovations and solutions, Fiji Broadcasting Corporation said on its website. It will seek to produce transformative outcomes and initiatives to boost fight against climate change in the Pacific, and urge more actions and enthusiasm on the fight elsewhere in the world. The agenda features interactive sessions with contributions from Pacific leaders, civil society and the private sector. Inia Seruiratu, Fiji's climate champion minister, urged the participants to exchange ideas, innovations and solutions to initiate and accelerate transformative actions that result in credible and sustainable greenhouse gas emissions reductions. The government of Fiji will be the president of the 23rd Climate Change Conference ( COP23 ) to be held in Bonn, Germany. Fiji's Prime Minister Voreqe Bainimarama has given high priority to COP23 , aiming to continue the momentum for action since the entry into force of the Paris Climate Change Agreement in 2016. The entire region is highly vulnerable to climate change impacts. The London School of Economics estimated that across the Pacific Islands, home to 10 million people, up to 1.7 million could be displaced due to climate change by 2050. Fiji, like other Pacific Island states, faces challenges in fully implementing government policies due to limited technical, human resource and financial capacities. Home to over 870,000 people in the central South Pacific Ocean, Fiji's 300 volcanic islands include low-lying atolls that are highly susceptible to cyclones and floods. The country is no stranger to the devastation wrought by climate change. Sea flooding is usually associated with the passage of tropical cyclones close to the coast. Heavy swells, generated by deep depressions and/or intense high pressure systems some distance away from Fiji, have also caused flooding to low-lying coastal areas. According to a World Bank report, climate threats to Fiji's society and economy include higher rates of disease as average temperatures rise; increasingly destructive storms as oceans get warmer and weather patterns become more severe; disruptions to agriculture as the intrusion of saltwater damages existing farmland, among others. On Fiji's main island of Viti Levu, these factors are expected to contribute to economic damages of up to 25 million U.S. dollars per year, or roughly 4 percent of Fiji's gross domestic product. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China38" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday"source="Shanghai Daily (Benchmark)" >
WITH the United Nations \' climate change conference underway in Bonn, Germany, rising global temperatures are once again at the top of the world\' s agenda. But why care about the increase in temperature, if not because of its impact on life on Earth, including human life? That is an important question to consider, in view of the relative lack of attention devoted to a closely related and equally important threat to human survival: the startling pace of global biodiversity loss. The availability of food, water, and energy  fundamental building blocks of every country\' s security  depends on healthy, robust and diverse ecosystems, and on the life that inhabits them. But, as a result of human activities, planetary biodiversity is now declining faster than at any point in history. Many policymakers, however, have yet to recognize that biodiversity loss is just as serious a threat as rising sea levels and increasingly frequent extreme weather events. This lack of sufficient attention comes despite international commitments to protect biodiversity. In October 2010, global leaders met in Aichi, Japan, where they produced the Strategic Plan for Biodiversity 2011-2020, which included 20 ambitious targets  such as halving global habitat loss and ending overfishing  that signatories agreed to meet by 2020. Safeguarding biodiversity is also specifically included in the UN\' s Sustainable Development Goals. Yet progress toward these global biodiversity goals is likely to fall dangerously short of what is needed to ensure an acceptable future for all. Policymakers have largely agreed on the importance of holding the increase in global temperature to less than two degrees celsius above pre-industrial levels  the goal of the Paris climate agreement. But too few leaders have shown any sense of urgency about stemming biodiversity losses. The sustainable future we want depends on ending this indifference. Toward that end, the Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES), which I chair, will release a series of landmark reports next March on the implications of biodiversity decline. Prepared over three years by more than 550 experts from some 100 countries, these expert assessments will cover four world regions: the Americas, Asia and the Pacific, Africa, and Europe and Central Asia. A fifth report will address the state of land degradation and restoration at regional and global levels. The reports will highlight trends and plausible futures, outlining the best policy options available to slow the degradation of ecosystems, from coral reefs to rainforests. Taken together, the IPBES assessments will represent the global scientific community\' s consensus view on the state of biodiversity and ecosystem services. Moreover, the reports will highlight the close links between biodiversity loss and climate change, which should be addressed simultaneously. The world will not be able to meet the goals of the Paris agreement  or many of the SDGs, for that matter  unless it takes into account the state of biodiversity and ecosystem services. Today, most governments separate their environmental authorities from those focusing on energy, agriculture, and planning. This makes it difficult to address climate change or biodiversity losses in a holistic way. New types of innovative governance structures are needed to bridge these policy silos. If the full consequences of climate change are to be addressed in our lifetime, we must recognize that human activity is doing more than just adding a few degrees of temperature to the annual forecast. Robert Watson, Strategic Director of the Tyndall Center for Climate Change Research at the University of East Anglia, is Chair of the Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES). Copyright: Project Syndicate. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China39" COP="COP23" country="China" date="June 2, 2017 Friday 6:02 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Leading climate experts and advocates in Europe reacted in outrage, following the announcement on Thursday by U.S President Donald Trump to withdraw the country from the Paris climate accord. "The world's biggest historic emitter walking away from its climate change commitments is gravely unjust, but we must respond by redoubling our efforts. Those on the frontlines of climate change demand nothing less," said Winnie Byanyima, executive director of Oxfam International, a UK-based confederation of charitable organizations. Jonathan Church, lawyer with Europe-based environment law organization ClientEarth, called the decision of the Trump administration "an act of global environmental vandalism that has the potential to do great harm to current and future generations." The Paris climate agreement represents a "best chance of avoiding severe and destabilizing climate change," Church said, noting that now without the United States, the commitment of other leading nations is "more important than ever." The experts believe that the absence of the U.S. will strengthen the bonds among other powers on the frontline against climate change. Wendel Trio, director of Climate Action Network (CAN) Europe said unlike the view of the sitting U.S. administration, countries all over the world see the Paris Agreement as an engine for growth and jobs. "The European Union (EU) is already strengthening its alliances with countries like China and Canada, as well as those most affected by climate change," said Trio. "The EU needs to step up its game now, to trigger more climate action and smooth the way for scaling up the Paris climate pledges." Federico Brocchieri, vice president of Italian Climate Network (ICN) called the decision "shortsighted and against history." "However, this will not stop the transition: from countries to cities, from businesses to citizens, the world has taken a very clear path which must gradually lead to a full decarbonization of the economy, in line with the targets set by science, to leave current and future generations a sustainable planet," he underlined. "Trump is surrendering U.S. global leadership to real world leaders who are seizing the momentum to protect their country and the climate by transforming their economies to clean energy," said Jennifer Morgan, Greenpeace International executive director. "We are witnessing a seismic shift in the global order as Europe, China and others lead the way forward," she added. With such a decision, Trump administration has cast America adrift from the global community and the reality of climate change, according to Susann Scherbarth, climate campaigner for Friends of the Earth Europe. "The fossil fuel industry and climate change deniers have set up shop in the White House, and they're putting the lives and livelihoods of millions of people on the line," said Scherbarth, who called for increased action on climate in Europe. Erich Pica from environmental network Friends of the Earth shares a similar view of the role of the fossil fuel industry behind the decision. "Trump is on a mission to sacrifice our planet to the fossil fuel industry. By pulling out of the Paris Agreement, Trump has turned the U.S. into the world's foremost climate villain," he said, adding that the majority of Americans demand climate action. According to him, the rest of the world must "move forward aggressively without the world's leading historical contributor of greenhouse gas emissions." The Paris Agreement was agreed by the 195 member economies that attended the 2015 United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP21) in Paris. The U.S. ratified the climate change accord in September, 2016 under the Barack Obama administration. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China40" COP="COP23" country="China" date="July 12, 2017 Wednesday 6:02 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Governor of U.S. state of California Jerry Brown and former Mayor of New York city Michael Bloomberg on Wednesday jointly launched a new initiative, known as "America's Pledge," to continue the cause set by the Paris Agreement on climate change. "Today we're sending a clear message to the world that America's states, cities and businesses are moving forward with our country's commitments under the Paris Agreement -- with or without Washington," said Brown, who announced last week that the Golden State on the U.S. West Coast would convene in San Francisco the world's climate leaders for the 2018 Global Climate Action Summit. The top official in California was recently named Special Advisor for States and Regions ahead of the United Nations' 23rd Conference of the Parties to the Framework Convention on Climate Change, or COP23 . "In the U.S., emission levels are determined far more by cities, states, and businesses than they are by our federal government -- and each of these groups is taking action because it's in their own best interest," noted Bloomberg, the U.N. Secretary-General's Special Envoy for Cities and Climate Change. "Reducing emissions is good for the economy and good for public health. The American government may have pulled out of the Paris Agreement, but American society remains committed to it -- and we will redouble our efforts to achieve its goals." Reached in late 2015 and signed so far by more than 190 U.N. members around the world, the Paris Agreement calls on all nations to respond to the threat of climate change by keeping a global temperature rise this century below 2 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels and to pursue efforts to limit the temperature increase even further to 1.5 degrees. However, U.S. President Donald Trump announced in early June his decision to withdraw from the agreement. Since then, a number of U.S. states, cities, businesses, and colleges and universities have reaffirmed their support for the Paris Agreement through collaborations including the "We Are Still In" declaration, the Climate Mayors coalition of cities and the U.S. Climate Alliance group of states. Through America's Pledge, Brown and Bloomberg said they would work to demonstrate that subnational action can significantly reduce U.S. greenhouse gas emissions at a time of limited federal leadership. The two have commissioned the Rocky Mountain Institute and the World Resources Institute to lead an analytical effort supporting the initiative, and have planned to compile and showcase existing climate commitments of U.S. subnational and non-state actors at COP23 scheduled for November in Bonn, Germany. The initiative will also work to quantify the aggregate impact of these commitments on projected future emissions, comparing against both a business-as-usual (BAU) trajectory of projected greenhouse gas emissions under likely policies of the current U.S. federal government, and the U.S. Nationally Determined Contribution submitted by the administration of former U.S. President Barack Obama in 2015, during the lead-up to the Paris Agreement, which called for 26-28 percent U.S. reductions against a 2005 baseline by 2025. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China41" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 21, 2017 Tuesday"source="China Daily" >
The United Nations Climate Change Conference in Bonn, Germany, which concluded over the weekend was no different from the other annual gatherings since 1995, when the world leaders decided to sit together to find ways to cope with climate change. The negotiators in Bonn burned the midnight oil on the last day of the conference to come up with the final document. But once again the rich countries didn't commit to paying the $100 billion they had promised to developing economies by 2020 to help the latter cope with and adapt to climate change. And, as they have done earlier, some Western outlets said the Bonn talks made "little progress". However, the Bonn talks can be seen as a "success" if we consider it a critical step toward completing the "rule-book" for the 2015 Paris Agreement. This conference was organized at a time when the international community seems "increasingly divided", mainly because some of the Western powers have not fulfilled the commitments they made at some previous climate talks. For example, US President Donald Trump has withdrawn from the Paris climate accord, although the European Union was an active player at the Bonn talks. The international community, it seems, needs some positive energy to work together to deal with the common threat to humanity. Some of that energy was evident in Bonn, though. Moreover, the international community accepted the Pacific island's wisdom by including the "Talanoa Dialogue", a Fijian concept that encourages people to listen to each other, respect each other's views, and seek solutions that benefit everybody - in other words, a process of inclusion and transparent dialogue that will lead to the "rule book" to be adopted at next year's conference in Katowice, Poland. This encouraging cooperation-oriented approach is likely to enrich global climate politics, which have long been dominated by the pressure, finger-pointing and dilly-dallying tactics of some Western countries and media outlets. Certain factors are essential to climate talks. First, which country, or countries, has contributed most to global warming? Second, joint efforts are needed to fight climate change but the process of seeking solutions should be inclusive and democratic. And, most importantly, promises made on paper should be honored and fulfilled. In this regard, the Talanoa Dialogue can help build mutual trust and understanding, which the international community badly needs. The Paris Agreement, ratified by 170 economies, is part of an ambitious global effort to deal with global warming in the period after 2020. To realize this agreement, the UN had asked every country to submit its plan for voluntary contribution to reducing global greenhouse gas emission. This approach gave enough room to each country to raise its targets while implementing the Paris Agreement. Now, the Talanoa Dialogue process is expected to help each participant to share its knowledge of low-carbon development model with the others, and vice-versa. Such dialogue could inspire countries to embark on a green path of development, which the negotiators in Bonn described as a post-2020 ambitious plan, which will also need the transfer of low-carbon technology and funds from the rich countries to the poorer ones to succeed. Also, as agreed in the Kyoto Protocol and the second phase of this landmark global deal, the rich countries have to honor their promises both in letter and spirit. And if that happens, the transition from Kyoto Protocol to the Paris Agreement will be smooth even if the US, the world's largest economy, remains a non-party to the two historic climate pacts. The author is deputy chief of China Daily European Bureau. HYPERLINK mailto:fujing@chinadaily.com.cn fujing@chinadaily.com.cn (China Daily 11/21/2017 page9) HYPERLINK http://imgs.syndigate.info/498/1493/27/151122698355.jpg http://imgs.syndigate.info/498/1493/27/151122698355.jpg f04da2db11221b7dba7b34.jpg HYPERLINK http://imgs.syndigate.info/498/1493/77/151122698447.jpg http://imgs.syndigate.info/498/1493/77/151122698447.jpg f04da2db11221b7dba8035.jpg \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China42" COP="COP23" country="China" date="June 10, 2017 Saturday 8:17 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Governor Jerry Brown of U.S. state of California met Friday in San Francisco visiting German Environment Minister Barbara Hendricks, hours after returning from a climate mission to China, and continued his international outreach on climate action. "China and Germany - two of the most powerful countries in the world - are working with California and with other states to deal with climate change," Brown said, noting that "the current withdrawal from the Paris Agreement by the Washington administration is being overcome and countermanded by people throughout the whole world." "Together with California, Germany will provide strong leadership for the Under2 Coalition in the COP23 in Bonn this November," Hendricks said. "The United States' withdrawal from the Paris Agreement," Hendricks noted, "underscores the significance of subnational actors in particular in our joint efforts to achieve the overall objective and goals." Under2 Coalition is a diverse group of cities, states or provinces, and countries around the world who set ambitious targets to limit the increase in global average temperature to below 2 degrees Celsius, while the COP23 refers to the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties to the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). The Paris Agreement, which builds upon the UNFCCC, is a document adopted at climate change talks in Paris, France, on Dec. 12, 2015, which calls on all nations to respond to the threat of climate change by keeping a global temperature rise this century well below 2 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels, or further to 1.5 degrees. It now has been signed by 197 parties worldwide and ratified by 148 of them. The Under2 Coalition was formed in 2015 by California and the German state of Baden-Wurttemberg to help galvanize subnational action in the same direction. The alliance includes 175 jurisdictions on six continents representing more than 35 countries and regions, 1.2 billion people and 28.8 trillion U.S. dollars gross domestic product (GDP), equivalent to over 16 percent of the global population and over 39 percent of the global economy. It currently includes 18 U.S. jurisdictions representing 89 million people or 28 percent of the U.S. population. After their meeting in San Francisco, the German minister and California governor issued a joint statement on climate cooperation, emphasizing that climate change action is not only a necessity but also an opportunity for economic growth. Brown flew to China last weekend, where he met Chinese President Xi Jinping, and expanded the Golden State's long-standing climate and clean energy ties with China through a series of bilateral meetings, and agreements signed with China's central government as well as Sichuan and Jiangsu provinces respectively. Last week, a day before his departure to China, in response to U.S. President Donald Trump's decision to withdraw from the Paris Agreement, Brown joined New York State Governor Andrew Cuomo and Washington State Governor Jay Inslee to form the U.S. Climate Alliance. The U.S. alliance now has included 13 U.S. states committed to achieving the U.S. goal of reducing emissions 26-28 percent from 2005 levels, which complements the goals of the Under2 Coalition. Before his trip to China, Brown told Xinhua about his sense of urgency for action against climate change, saying "it is urgent. It is urgent because what we do today will create irreversible consequences in the years ahead. Time is running out. This is very serious." About his international outreach efforts, Brown said: "We need to collaborate. It is not about one nation being the winner. It is about all nations dealing with the common threat. This is mutually beneficial. You have to think one world, not this country fighting that country." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China43" COP="COP23" country="China" date="March 5, 2018 Monday 4:32 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Fiji, a South Pacific Island state with a population of more than 880,000, will need 9.3 billion Fijian dollars (about 4.6 billion U.S. dollars) to deal with climate change in the coming 10 years, a Fijian government official said on Monday. According to Fiji Broadcasting Corporation (FBC), this was said by Fiji's Attorney-General Aiyaz-Sayed Khaiyum while responding to climate change-related questions raised in the Parliament. As the President of the 23rd Conference of the Parties to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change ( COP23 ), Fiji is highly vulnerable to the effects of climate change and the unsustainable exploitation of the oceans. According to a study released last November in Germany, By 2050, Fiji's annual losses due to extreme weather events could reach 6.5 percent of the Gross Domestic Product (GDP), with more than 32,000 people pushed into hardship every year. Fiji's National Climate Change Policy also says that global sea level changes will more than double by the end of this century. Fiji has since 1993 recorded a 6mm increase in its sea level per year, larger than the global average. The rapid rise of sea levels and the resulting saltwater intrusion that stems from the increased ferocity of coastal floods have made portions of the island nation uninhabitable. Currently, Fiji has relocated three villages to higher ground, and the country will have another 42 to 43 villages earmarked to be moved to higher ground who have been on coastal areas. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China44" COP="COP23" country="China" date="June 23, 2017 Friday 2:17 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Top executives in Fiji on Friday called for more efforts to tackle climate change. The business leaders taking part in a two-day workshop organized by Fiji Commerce and Employers Federation (FCEF) said there was a need to get behind the Fijian government's efforts on climate change. This is in line with Fiji's focus on climate change and with Fiji's important presidency role at the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 ) in Bonn, Germany in November, they said. FCEF President Himen Chandra said for businesses in Fiji, the adverse effects of climate change were becoming real and there was a need to explore mitigation and adaptation strategies in order to remain viable. Chandra said climate change had been an issue of concern and the challenges of climate change were dawning on the private sectors with a much greater impact. He said the private sector would now rather than later have to rise to the challenges of ensuring a brighter future for Fijians. "It is a recognized fact that the changing climatic conditions and weather patterns that have brought devastating floods, cyclones and rising sea level are causing and will further cause serious negative impacts to our economy and our environment one way or another, the challenge lies before us to ensure the growth of a nation both economically and to remain environmentally sustainable," he said on Friday. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China47" COP="COP23" country="China" date="October 18, 2017 Wednesday 12:17 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
ISLAMABAD -- At least seven people, including six policemen, were killed and over 22 injured when a suicide blast hit a security forces truck in Quetta city in Pakistan's southwestern province of Balochistan on Wednesday, reported local media. Sarfraz Bhugti, Home Minister of Balochistan, said the attack happened when a suicide bomber rammed his explosive-laden vehicle into the security forces truck in Saryab area of Quetta, killing seven people on the spot and wounding 22 others. (Afghanistan-Suicide Blast) - - - - NADI, Fiji -- Fijian Prime Minister Voreqe Bainimarama and Austrialia's Minister for International and the Pacific Concetta Fierravanti stressed on Wednesday the importance of the role played by women in addressing climate change problems. Speaking on women's leadership in climate change diplomacy at the two-day Pre- COP23 , also known as ministerial dialogue, in Denarau, an island near Fiji's third largest city of Nadi, Bainimarama said women and girls are both critically vulnerable to some of the worst effects of climate change and vital to an effective response. (Fiji-Women-Climate Change) - - - - NEW DELHI -- At least eight people were killed and over a dozen others injured on Wednesday after a blast inside fireworks factory triggered a fire in India's eastern state of Odisha, police said. The fire broke out Wednesday evening at Bahabalpur in Balasore district, about 224 km northeast of Bhubaneswar, the capital city of Odisha. (India-Fireworks Factory-Blast) - - - - SRINAGAR, Indian-controlled Kashmir -- At least eight people were wounded Wednesday after troops of India and Pakistan fired upon each others positions and frontier areas on the Line of Control (LoC) dividing Kashmir, police said. The two sides resorted to heavy firing and mortar shelling in Poonch and Rajouri districts, southwest of Srinagar city, the summer capital of Indian-controlled Kashmir. (Kashmir-Firing) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China48" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 10, 2017 Friday 1:17 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
The Chinese delegation to the ongoing UN climate talks here on Friday voiced concerns on behalf of developing countries, calling for focused discussions on pre-2020 actions. "There has been heated debate on pre-2020 ambition in Bonn. Actually it is not a new issue, rather, an unfinished business," Chinese negotiator Chen Zhihua told a press briefing held by the delegation. COP23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) is drawing to an end. "There are only two years to 2020 so we don't have the luxury of time, and we really need to accelerate domestic processes to ratify the Doha amendment so as to put it into effect as soon as possible," Chen said. He added, as countries agreed in the Bali process that developed countries should enhance their ambition in terms of support to developing countries, "it is time to take stock of what they have done and where the gap is and how to close the gap." The global fight against climate change, starting from 1992 with the inception of the UNFCCC, can be divided into pre-2020 phase which was guided by the Kyoto Protocol and years afterwards which will be directed by the Paris Agreement. However, the Doha amendment, establishing the second commitment period of the Kyoto Protocol (2013-2020) and including quantified emission limitation or reduction commitments by several developed countries, have just been ratified by some countries. Developing countries also called for a ceremony to celebrate the adoption of the Kyoto Protocol as this year marks the 20th anniversary of the historical event, according to Chen. "We need to do something to memorize this very important historical moment, and action is the best way to commemorate the adoption," Chen said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China49" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 10, 2017 Friday 6:30 AM EST"source="China Business News" >
Nov. 10 -- On the occasion of the COP23 in Bonn (Germany), the CMA CGM Group, a world leader in maritime transport, confirms to the China State Shipbuilding Corporation (CSSC) - CSTC and Shanghai Waigaoqiao Shipbuilding Co., Ltd. and Hudong-Zhonghua Shipbuilding (Group) Co., Ltd - its decision to equip the 9 future ships of 22,000 TEUs (Twenty-foot Equivalent Unit), designed by MARIC, with engines using liquefied natural gas. This type of Vessel is a real technological breakthrough for the protection of the environment, LNG allows for, compared to current ships using heavy fuel oil:  up to 25% less CO2  99% less particulate matters  85% less nitrogen oxides emissions Moreover, the Energy Efficiency Design Index (EEDI), which measures a ship's environmental footprint, is improved by 20% compared to ships only propelled by fuel oil. As an active player and pioneer, CMA CGM ordered these nine vessels with LNG as a fuel, which is the first and largest container Vessels order with dual fuel propulsion in the world so far. The CMA CGM Group is firmly committed to the reduction of its carbon footprint for the protection of the environment and the preservation of the oceans and biodiversity. By choosing LNG, the CMA CGM Group goes beyond current and future regulations that limit the sulphur cap to 0.5% in 2020. The successful undertaken of the dual fuel container vessel symbolized the strategic cooperation between CMA CGM Group and CSSC Group, which also proved the recognition of the capability of CSSC Group by the world's top ship owners, the leading position of the Chinese shipbuilding industry in the world, and its ambition to be the industry's leading force in the design and production of high-tech and high value-added Vessels. Source: China Shipbuilding Trading \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China50" COP="COP23" country="China" date="June 26, 2017 Monday 2:17 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
The Fijian government said Monday it recognized the importance and impacts that geo-science has played in engineering strategies to mitigate the unrelenting and imminent threats of climate change from the perception of geoscientists. Faiyaz Koya, minister for Industry, Trade, Tourism, Lands and Mineral Resources, highlighted this while opening the 2017 conference of Pacific Science, Technology and Resources (STAR) Network in Nadi. "I urge you all to contribute positively to allow for concrete resolutions being reached to outline the value in refreshing and animating scientific alliances to showcase useful work, techniques and instrumentation that may be adapted to address development issues of the Pacific region," Koya told regional participants at the workshop. "This is by no means a small undertaking. It requires collaborative efforts to ensure that the Pacific realizes opportunities for sustainable ocean development focusing on targeted growth that can be measured upon scientific principles and data." Founded in 1984 by South Pacific Applied Geo-science Commission (SOPAC) and UNESCO, the forum is an annual gathering of the region's experts in geo-science. The forum plays a vital role in mapping out local and regional adaptation programs to further the region's collective struggles against the unforgiving effects of climate change. With Fiji presiding at the COP23 (Conference of Parties) in Germany, Koya said there is a need for a collective focus on showcasing climate action initiatives and innovation was all the more relevant here and now. "The future of the whole Pacific rests on all of our shoulders and we need to manoeuvre ourselves to ensure that viable advancements are experienced now, tomorrow and onwards to effectively address this world threatening risk," Koya added. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China51" COP="COP23" country="China" date="October 18, 2017 Wednesday 7:32 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Fijian Prime Minister Voreqe Bainimarama and Austrialia's Minister for International and the Pacific Concetta Fierravanti stressed on Wednesday the importance of the role played by women in addressing climate change problems. Speaking on women's leadership in climate change diplomacy at the two-day Pre- COP23 , also known as ministerial dialogue, in Denarau, an island near Fiji's third largest city of Nadi, Bainimarama said women and girls are both critically vulnerable to some of the worst effects of climate change and vital to an effective response. As the world experiences the extreme weather events, rising seas and changes to agriculture caused by climate change, women often have the least resources to cope. And this can add an extra burden to the poverty and lack of opportunity that billions of women around the world already face, he said. Women are also powerful agents for change, he said, adding that "We also know that when women are well represented in decision-making processes, their ability to share skills and knowledge strengthens our collective effort to face the challenge of climate change." He said that Fiji's delegation to Bonn consists of close to 50 percent women and they would obviously encourage other delegations to aspire to increase the proportion of women on theirs. "Improving the status of women is a core imperative in tackling the effects of climate change. That is what we are doing in Fiji. And that is what we must do around the world," he said. Meanwhile, Austrialia's Minister for International and the Pacific Concetta Fierravanti said the successful implementation of the historic Paris Agreement depends upon effectively engaging women and girls. Based on current trends women will not be equally represented in the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change until 2040, in parliaments until 2065, and will not make up half the world's leaders until 2134, the minister said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China52" COP="COP23" country="China" date="February 7, 2018 Wednesday 8:02 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Representatives from South Pacific Island states and international organizations discussed how Fiji can reduce greenhouse gas emissions and help keep the global temperature rise below 1.5 degrees Celsius here on Wednesday. The three-day Pacific Maritime Technical Officers workshop is organized by Pacific Islands Development Forum (PIDF), supported by the Fijian government and the University of the South Pacific (USP). Fiji's Assistant Minister for Transport and Infrastructure Vijay Nath said the adoption of an initial strategy on greenhouse gas emissions reduction will take place in Fiji in April. As President of the 23rd Conference of the Parties to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change ( COP23 ), Fiji was all too aware of how critical it was for all sectors to play their part to maintain global temperature rise at no more than 1.5 degrees Celsius, Nath said. He said the participants of this workshop were expected to make formal contributions on technical papers that could be further discussed for adoption at the International Maritime Organization meeting in April. The renewable initiatives outlined as part of the three sub-sectors are expected to reduce Fiji's carbon dioxide emissions by 627,000 tons of carbon dioxide per annum against the business as usual baseline. The largest contribution for carbon dioxide mitigation up through 2030 in this sub-sector comes from biomass-based power generation which includes sustainable biomass plantations and waste-to-energy, followed by hydro-power generation, solar PV generation and grid extension/improvement and grid storage. Other renewable energy generation technologies such as wind, geothermal, and wastewater treatment and biogas have the potential to further contribute to mitigation and transformational change in Fiji. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China53" COP="COP23" country="China" date="August 23, 2017 Wednesday 2:17 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
NEW DELHI -- Over 450 people were injured, some of them critically, during a traditional stone pelting festival in central Indian state of Madhya Pradesh on Tuesday, local media reports said. The festival is locally called Gotmar and is an annual ritual. (India-Festival) - - - - ISLAMABAD -- A Chinese company constructing the Karakorum Highway in northern Pakistan has donated over 8.5 million Pakistani rupees (around 80,000 U.S. dollars) to an orphanage of the SOS Children's Villages in Mansehra to improve the orphans' lives. The donation included funding to renew the orphanage's dormitories, which accounts for major part of the total amount, and living appliances such as water heaters, uninterruptible power systems and solar panels. (Pakistan-China-Orphanage) - - - - SUVA -- Defining a Pacific Blue Economy and developing a roadmap for it is at the top of agenda at the Pacific Islands Development Forum's first high-level meeting, which opened in Suva's Grand Pacific Hotel on Wednesday. President of the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 ) to the UN Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) and Fijian Prime Minister, Voreqe Bainimarama, told members of the Forum to act together on sustainable oceans and better management of its resources. (Fiji-Climate change) - - - - YANGON -- Former Secretary-General of the United Nations Kofi Annan, who arrived in Yangon Tuesday, is scheduled to hold talks with State Counselor Aung San Suu Kyi later on Wednesday on the release of the commission's final report on Rakhine state, according to the Information Ministry. Kofi Annan is chair of the Myanmar-government-appointed Advisory Commission of Rakhine state, while Aung San Suu Kyi heads the Central Committee for Implementation of Peace, Stability and Development in Rakhine state. (Myanmar-Annan-Report) - - - - NEW DELHI -- At least 74 people were injured after a passenger train derailed early Wednesday in the northern Indian state of Uttar Pradesh, officials said. According to officials, 10 coaches of Delhi-bound Kaifiyat Express derailed in Auraiya district, about 180 km from Lucknow, the capital city of Uttar Pradesh. So far no causality has been reported in the accident. (India-Train derailment) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China54" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 13, 2017 Monday"source="Global Times (China)" >
Illustration: Liu Rui/GT Ahead of the COP23 Climate Conference, which opened November 6 in Bonn, Germany, new reports on the impact of greenhouse gases have been released, including a multi-agency report by the US government. Although COP23 is mainly to hash out the nitty-gritty of the Paris climate agreement that was signed in 2015, all eyes have been on what the US' contribution to the talks will be. War-torn Syria signed up to the Paris agreement a day after the meeting started, and Nicaragua signed on in October, making the US feel out of step with the world.Environmental organization Sierra Club responded to the news of Syria's joining by issuing a statement, "As if it wasn't already crystal clear, every other country in the world is moving forward together to tackle the climate crisis," the BBC reported.Former US vice president Al Gore, a passionate climate campaigner, rued being unable to persuade incumbent President Donald Trump over climate change. The Trump administration's plans to promote coal as a solution to man-made climate change at Bonn had already left delegates from other nations and scientists aghast. A White House spokesperson said that fossil-fuel use could be "efficient and clean," outraging environmental experts. Observers agree that the US is isolating itself, and this means other nations such as China, Canada and the EU will start to move the agenda. Media reports suggest that far from being "America First," on climate change it will be "America Alone." The US has not been invited to a summit to be held in Paris in December. The World Meteorological Organization reports that 2017 is set to be one of the top three hottest years on record. Another report from the Environmental Justice Foundation (EJF) predicted that tens of millions of people would be forced from their homes by climate change. Retired US military experts told the EJF that Europe will need to prepare for a new influx of climate refugees from sub-Saharan Africa. Many experts think we have already seen the start of the first big waves of climate refugees - some point to an extreme drought in Syria as being one of the precipitating factors of the conflict, with large numbers of rural people forced to migrate to cities. The World Health Organization has warned that climate change is causing health problems. As if this weren't enough, a damning report from the US government cited a multi-agency study saying it was extremely likely that climate change was man-made. Volume II of the National Climate Assessment said that more of the predicted impacts of climate change were becoming a reality, The New York Times reported.The US administration sought to downplay this report, which directly contradicts views of top US officials, who have voiced skepticism about the role of greenhouse gases produced by human activity, including Environmental Protection Agency Administrator Scott Pruitt. But with the entire world standing against one nation - the world's second-largest emitter of greenhouse gases - can the US alone derail this global consensus? The "We Are Still In" coalition, led by former New York mayor and billionaire businessman Michael Bloomberg, and Jerry Brown, current California governor, has set up their own pavilion at Bonn, an altogether flashier affair than the official US presence, according to reports. Bloomberg, The New York Times reported, has put $1 million of his own money into the initiative, which represents states, cities, businesses and other institutions, which, if added together, would comprise the world's third-largest economy at $6.2 trillion in economic output. It says it represents 130 million Americans. Added to this, at least seven out of 10 Americans believe climate change is man-made, the report said. This is of course good news. But the fragmented US response is confusing. Who can we believe, especially as you have an administration working against other civil society movements? Brown told media that he is trying to step into the vacuum led by other high-ranking officials. States and cities enacting pro-green policies certainly will have an effect, but in the end, it may just be big business that is the deciding factor. We Are Still In has over 1,000 state governors, mayors and CEOs in the non-partisan coalition. Businesses not only need natural resources - the supply of which may be disrupted as the effects of climate change kick in - from crops, to water to energy - they also need customers. Policies at national and multilateral levels will also force change. As many nations, including China, have pledged to phase out vehicles that run on fossil fuels, the auto industry knows it must adapt. If US car makers wish to compete with their Asian and European rivals, they should start making electric vehicles, or risk being left behind. It is to be hoped that whatever Trump says or does during his term will not be able to derail the global, political and business-led consensus on climate change.The author is a Beijing-based freelance writer who is doing postgraduate studies in sustainability at SOAS, University of London. HYPERLINK mailto:opinion@globaltimes.com.cn opinion@globaltimes.com.cn HYPERLINK http://imgs.syndigate.info/478/1448/100/151053333119.jpeg http://imgs.syndigate.info/478/1448/100/151053333119.jpeg \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China55" COP="COP23" country="China" date="April 13, 2018 Friday 2:47 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
African environmentalists on Friday launched a plan of action towards achieving United Nations goals on tackling climate change. African climate change policy makers who ended their two-day meeting in Nairobi set out National Determined Contributions (NDCs) proposals that if implemented will see the continent achieve its target of reducing the continent's share of global emissions. "We intend to implement our NDCs by giving priority to financing the initiative, technology transfer and capacity building to communities," the delegates said during the first Africa Telanoa dialogue. The experts further agreed to prioritize on green finance, carbon market, clean energy and engagement with the private sector. Launched at the COP23 , Talanoa dialogue aims at collective assessment of the progress made on climate action and increase action to reach the Paris Agreement goals. The dialogue sets activities to be undertaken by every country ahead of the COP24 climate conference set for Poland in November. Talanoa dialogues also help build trust and advance knowledge through empathy and understanding for the collective good in the regions. The COP set a facilitative dialogue among Parties to begin in 2018 to take stock of the collective efforts of Parties in relation to progress towards the long-term goal. According to Charles Mutai, Kenya's Director Climate Change in the Ministry of Environment and also the Chairperson of the meeting said that the delegates agreed to link the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) and climate change actions. "Collaboration across the continent is crucial given that countries face similar climatic effects," Mutai added, noting that the delegates also agreed to foster the corporation between public and private sector. "For climate change policies and strategies to succeed, they must be people centered and translated to the local communities and school children," Sharif noted. She promised to help the countries in developing climate change gender responsive participatory planning in their cities. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China56" COP="COP23" country="China" date="December 5, 2017 Tuesday 3:47 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
The United Nations on Tuesday launched the Global Soil Organic Carbon Map on World Soil Day, calling for "caring the ground we walk on." Soil is a major carbon storage system, essential for sustainable agriculture and climate change mitigation, the United Nations agriculture agency said, launching the comprehensive global map showing the amount of carbon stocks contained in soil. "Soil is the foundation of agriculture, it is where food begins," said Maria Helena Semedo, Deputy Director-General of the UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO). "Maintaining the soil's important functions and ecosystem services to support food production and increase resilience to a changing climate calls for sustainable soil management practices," she added. The world's soils act as the largest terrestrial carbon sink, reducing greenhouse gases. Intensifying its role could significantly offset the rapid rise of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere. In an historic decision on agriculture, the 2017 UN Climate Change Conference in Bonn ( COP23 ) recognized the need for improved soil carbon, soil health and soil fertility. The Global Soil Organic Carbon Map, the most comprehensive to date, illustrates the amount of organic carbon stock in the first 30 cm of soil, revealing natural areas with high carbon storage that require conservation along with regions where further sequestration would be possible. This information can prove a powerful tool to guide decision-making on practices aimed to preserve and increase the current soil carbon stocks, helping win the fight against climate change. The map shows that globally the first 30 cm of soil contains around 680 billion tons of carbon, almost double the amount present in our atmosphere. The degradation of one third of the world's soils has already prompted an enormous release of carbon into the atmosphere. Restoring these soils can remove up to 63 billion tons of carbon, significantly reducing the effects of climate change. The next step is for countries to monitor their national soil information systems for organic carbon levels to make evidence-based decisions on how to manage and monitor their soils. December 5 is World Soil Day, a day set aside by the United Nations to acknowledge the importance of healthy soil and to advocate for the sustainable management of soil resources. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China57" COP="COP23" country="China" date="July 3, 2017 Monday 2:17 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
NEW DELHI -- At least six people have been killed and seven others injured in a road accident in the western Indian state of Maharashtra, a police official said Monday. "The accident occurred when a private passenger bus in which the victims were travelling collided head-on with a water tanker near Lonikand on Pune-Ahmednagar Road, some 40 km from the city of Pune, late Sunday night," he said on condition of anonymity. (India-Road Accident) - - - - JAKARTA -- Rescuers have removed eight bodies from the scene of Sunday's helicopter crash in western Indonesia, a spokesman of the national search and rescue office said on Monday. The chopper operated by the national search and rescue office hit a hill in Temanggung district of Central Java province while flying near Dieng volcano to evacuate the victims of a steam eruption, spokesman Marsudi said. (Indonesia-Helicopter Crash) - - - - CANBERRA -- Australia's Deputy Prime Minister Barnaby Joyce on Monday expressed confidence that Australia and the European Union (EU) can quickly reach a free trade agreement (FTA) post-Brexit. Speaking to Australian Broadcasting Corporation (ABC) radio on Monday, Joyce said he had attended both formal and informal meetings with the EU's trade commissioner Phil Hogan this week, discussing the details of a food and agriculture FTA between the EU and Australia in coming years. (Australia-EU-FTA) - - - - SUVA -- Fijian Prime Minister Voreqe Bainimarama said on Monday that while the United States had abandoned its leadership on climate change, the door remained open to U.S. President Donald Trump, given the commitment by other Americans to climate action. Bainimarama, who is also president of the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 - - - - HONG KONG -- Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited held a ceremony on Monday to launch the "northbound" mainland-Hong Kong bond connect. With the northbound trading kicking off after the ceremony, qualified overseas investors will be able to invest in the Chinese mainland interbank bond market via the mainland-Hong Kong bond connect program. (HK-Mainland-Bond Connect) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China58" COP="COP23" country="China" date="May 16, 2017 Tuesday 10:32 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
Chinese President Xi Jinping said Tuesday that China is ready to enhance all-round cooperation with Fiji for the benefit of the people in both countries. China is willing to expand cooperation with Fiji on agricultural technology, green development, investment and trade, Xi said during a meeting with Fijian Prime Minister Josaia Voreqe Bainimarama, who attended the Belt and Road Forum for International Cooperation held in Beijing from May 14 to 15. China and the Pacific island country forged a strategic partnership based on mutual respect and common development in 2014, lifting bilateral relations to a new height. Xi noted that the two countries are enjoying deeper political mutual trust, stronger pragmatic cooperation and closer people-to-people exchanges, while calling for continued mutual support on issues concerning each other's core interests and major concerns. China will encourage more tourists to visit Fiji, and support Chinese enterprises to expand business in the country, he told Bainimarama. Xi expected closer communication and cooperation with Fiji in such areas as education and culture, as well as more local-level exchanges and cooperation. He expressed China's willingness to boost coordination and cooperation with Fiji under the United Nations framework, and maintain communication and coordination on major issues such as climate change. Bainimarama said Fiji will stick to the one-China policy. Fiji will deepen cooperation with China in areas including agriculture, infrastructure, trade and people-to-people exchanges, while furthering coordination on climate change and sustainable development, Bainimarama said. While meeting Bainimarama, Chinese Premier Li Keqiang said the two countries should align their development strategies, expand cooperation, and push forward common development. Li said China has always been a responsible player in the global fight against climate change and actively implementing the Paris Agreement on Climate Change, in an effort not only to fulfill the country's obligations, but also to restructure its economy. Li expressed China's willingness to support Fiji's presidency of the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change. Bainimarama welcomed China's long-term support for Fiji and expected greater industrial and trade cooperation between the two countries. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China59" COP="COP23" country="China" date="August 2, 2017 Wednesday 3:17 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
By the end of this century, summer heat waves could exceed the upper limit of human survivability at "a few locations" in South Asia, a region of deep poverty where one-fifth of the world's people live, a new study said Wednesday. The most affected regions would be the Chota Nagpur Plateau, northeastern India, and Bangladesh, according to the study published by the U.S. journal Science Advances. "Our findings have significant implications to the ongoing considerations regarding climate change policy," said the study, which is based on detailed computer simulations using the best available global circulation models. The new findings were conducted by Professor Elfatih Eltahir of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Assistant Professor Eun Soon Im of the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology and Professor Jeremy Pal at Loyola Marymount University in Los Angeles. Scientists have known that hot weather's most deadly effects for humans come from a combination of high temperature and high humidity, an index which is measured by a reading known as wet-bulb temperature. At a wet-bulb temperature of 35 degrees Celsius, the human body cannot cool itself enough to survive more than a few hours. A previous study found that the wet-bulb temperature has rarely exceeded about 31 degrees Celsius anywhere on Earth in the past decades. However, when it does happen, "the most detrimental human impacts of climate change on heat waves could potentially be those in developing nations because of the vulnerability of their populations," the study said. In much of India and Pakistan, an apparent rising trend in the frequency of deadly heat waves has been observed, it said. For example, the fifth deadliest heat wave in recorded history affected large parts of India and Pakistan, claiming around 3,500 lives in 2015. The new study showed that by century's end, absent serious reductions in global emissions, wet-bulb temperatures are projected to approach the threshold of survivability over most of South Asia, including the Ganges river valley, northeastern India, Bangladesh, the eastern coast of India, Chota Nagpur Plateau, northern Sri Lanka, and the Indus valley of Pakistan. And the temperatures could exceed the upper limit at a few locations in the Chota Nagpur Plateau, northeastern India, and Bangladesh. In today's climate, about 2 percent of the Indian population sometimes gets exposed to extremes of 32-degree wet-bulb temperatures. According to this study, by 2100 that will increase to about 70 percent of the population, and about two percent of the people will sometimes be exposed to the survivability limit of 35 degrees. And because the region is important agriculturally, it's not just those directly affected by the heat who will suffer, Eltahir said. "With the disruption to the agricultural production, it doesn't need to be the heat wave itself that kills people. Production will go down, so potentially everyone will suffer," he said. However, under a moderate mitigation scenario, which is roughly comparable to the goals pledged by the 2015 UN Conference on Climate Change in Paris, these dramatic, deadly effects can largely be averted, the researchers noted. "With mitigation, we hope we will be able to avoid these severe projections. This is not something that is unavoidable," Eltahir said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China60" COP="COP23" country="China" date="June 26, 2017 Monday"source="China Daily European Edition" >
PARIS - French President Emmanuel Macron has promised to bring an international draft agreement dedicated to environmental issues to the United Nations (UN) in September. Written by dozens of international legal experts, the draft agreement aims to set out an international framework in the fight against climate change and for the protection of the environment. "On the planetary scale, we must reach a new step after the Paris agreement," said the president on Saturday, speaking in a large amphitheater in the Sorbonne at the close of a day-long working session on the environment which brought together some dignitaries, including former UN secretary general Ban Ki-moon, founding president of the R20 (Regions for Climate Action) and former governor of California Arnold Schwarzenegger, along with French officials, law experts and ecology activists from different countries around the world. Calling for further fight against climate change, the French president said "the United Nations is the correct venue." The text, composed of 26 articles, reemploys major legal principles already adopted in other international declarations on the environment, such as the polluter-payer principle, the right to an ecologically healthy environment, the right to access to information, the principle of non-regression, and others. Once adopted, it will serve to complement the first two international pacts adopted by the United Nations in 1966, of which one deals with civil and political rights, the other concerning economic, social and cultural rights, in addition to international environmental law which is today fragmented into dozens of thematic agreements. But Macron admitted that the adoption may still take time. "The process which is waiting for us in order to have this world agreement ratified...will be slow, difficult," said President Macron, while underlining that it is no longer possible to wait, because "the world cannot wait." He reminded listeners that the G20 summit to be held on July 7-8 in Hamburg, Germany would be a key meeting in order to reach full implementation of the Paris Agreement, and that the COP23 in November would also be an occasion to raise commitments taken on the international level on greenhouse gas emissions. Saturday's international meeting, where the draft "world pact for the environment" was presented, was developed on the initiative of the French think tank "Club des jurists" in collaboration with some 80 experts from 40 different countries and regions. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China62" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 9, 2017 Thursday"source="China Daily" >
The Belt and Road Green Development and Climate Governance Side-Event Series were launched on Wednesday at the 23rd Conference of Parties ( COP 23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). BONN - The Belt and Road Green Development and Climate Governance Side-Event Series were launched on Wednesday at the 23rd Conference of Parties ( COP 23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). The side event will focus on how to leverage the China-proposed Belt and Road Initiative and other multilateral cooperation mechanisms to achieve the 2.0 and 1.5 degree targets and implement the 2030 UN Sustainable Development Goals. The side event includes six sessions covering topics such as nationally determined contributions in Belt and Road countries, Chinese renewable energy development, green energy cooperation under the Belt and Road Initiative, multilateral development banks and climate-compatible investments, south-south climate cooperation to drive Paris Agreement Implementation at national and regional levels, among other topics. The side event is organized by the Belt and Road Green Development Partnership. The Partnership, inaugurated in 2016, was designed to provide policy recommendations for sustainable development under the Belt and Road Initiative by bringing together Chinese and global think tanks, environmental NGOs and foundations. Yang Fuqiang, Steering Committee expert of the Belt and Road Green Development Partnership, said, "As a developing country, China offers valuable experiences to be learned by Belt and Road nations. While China works to implement the Belt and Road Initiative, it can also share with Belt and Road countries the technology and best practices from its own efforts to address climate change." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China63" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 30, 2017 Thursday"source="Beijing Review" >
China's determination to address climate change stands out The High-Level Segment of the United Nations climate talks is held in Bonn, Germany, on November 15 (XINHUA) 2017 appears to be not a smooth year for combating climate change. On the opening day of the United Nations Climate Change Conference , which was held in Bonn, Germany, from November 6 to 18, the World Meteorological Organization released a report announcing that 2017 was set to be in the top three hottest years since meteorological records began in 1850 and to have record-breaking extreme weather. The severity of the situation has also been exacerbated by U.S. President Donald Trump's decision in June to withdraw the United States from the Paris Agreement. Against this background, Fijian Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama, also President of the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP 23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC), said at the opening ceremony of the conference, "All over the world, vast numbers of people are suffering, bewildered by the forces ranged against them. Our job as leaders is to respond to the suffering with all means available to us ... This means to meet our commitments in full, not back away from them," he said. Patricia Espinosa, Executive Secretary of the UNFCCC, also stressed that millions of people around the world have suffered and continue to suffer extreme weather events. "Never have we met with a greater sense of urgency" to deal with climate change, she said. After hard negotiations, this year's UN Climate Change Conference closed on November 18 following over 20 hours of bargaining. On the positive side, the conference succeeded in adopting the Fiji Momentum for Implementation decision, forming negotiating text for various aspects of the implementation of the Paris Agreement, further clarifying how the facilitative dialogue would be organized in 2018, and passing a series of arrangements to accelerate pre-2020 actions. Achievements Xie Zhenhua, China's special representative on climate change affairs, said though the conference was "not 100 percent satisfactory", it succeeded in reflecting the concerns of all sides in a balanced manner. And it also laid a foundation for completing negotiations on detailed plans to implement the Paris Agreement as scheduled and for continuing enhancing support and action to cope with climate change. To be specific, progress has been made in three ways, said Xie. First, detailed plans for implementation of the Paris Agreement were put on the agenda. Xie hoped the conference would pave the way for future negotiations to work out an outcome document which can effectively bring the Paris Agreement into reality and balance all factors and demands. Now, divergences and differences are being narrowed. Second, the implementation of the Paris Agreement, which would facilitate the continuance of negotiations in 2018, was appraised. China appreciates Fiji's proposal to exchange best practices in a facilitative dialogue conducted in the spirit of the Pacific tradition of Talanoa. However, the biggest obstacle is still the issue of funding, on which developed and developing countries have not yet reached a consensus. At the Copenhagen climate conference in 2009, developed countries promised to provide developing countries with $100 billion every year to reduce greenhouse gas emissions, and that was also confirmed with the signatures of the 196 parties to the Paris Agreement. However, after the U.S. withdrew from the Paris Agreement, the implementation of funding once again became the main topic of concern, especially for developing countries, at this year's conference. Developing countries require developed countries to fulfill their commitment to jointly provide $100 billion annually by 2020 for mitigation, adaptation and new technological support development and to make plain how they will increase the amount after 2020. While some developed countries tried to pass the buck, Germany and France expressed EU's willingness to provide financial support. Third, divergences existed over the topics to be added to the discussion agenda before 2020. In an effort to urge all countries to keep their promises, developing countries demanded that everyone should report their actions to tackle climate change, a call echoed by China and the Group of 77. A consensus was reached accordingly. Xie also stressed that the negotiation would be still hard next year, and all sides should follow the principles of "equity and common but differentiated responsibilities and respective capabilities", in order to advance negotiations on the implementation of the Paris Agreement. He hoped that developed countries could continue to fulfill their obligations to support developing countries with funds, technologies and capacity building. China-Africa Renewable Energy Cooperation and Innovation Alliance Chairman Shi Dinghuan and Ghana Energy Commission Executive Secretary Alfred Ahenkorah sign a general planning memorandum for Ghanaian renewable energy on the sidelines of the climate change talks in Bonn, Germany, on November 16 (XU BEI) China on the move As one of the first nations to ratify the Paris Agreement through a legislative process, China was also among the first to submit to the UN a national program to tackle climate change. As early as 2015, China pledged to peak its carbon dioxide emissions in 2030 and began striving to realize the goal still earlier. In the context of global energy saving and emission reduction, China proposed to limit its annual carbon dioxide emissions to within 10 billion tons from 2016 to 2020. To achieve this goal, a series of strong policies and measures were introduced to promote green and low-carbon development. The Central Government issued a series of strategies to respond to climate change, assessed whether local emission reduction targets were achieved, evaluated the implementation of objectives, and encouraged local governments to combat climate change by launching pilot projects and providing them with policy support. According to the 2016 report on China's Policies and Actions for Addressing Climate Change, during the 12th Five-Year Plan (2011-15) period, China's carbon intensity was reduced by 20 percent, exceeding the previous target of 17 percent; its energy structure was further optimized such that the proportion of non-fossil energy in primary energy consumption climbed to 12 percent, surpassing the previous target of 11.4 percent; and its forest stock volume was increased to 15.137 billion cubic meters, achieving in advance a goal initially set for 2020. China has become the world's largest renewable energy producer, consumer and investor. According to the 2017 report on China's Policies and Actions for Addressing Climate Change, in 2016, its consumption of non-fossil fuels accounted for 13.3 percent of its primary energy consumption, and its energy consumption and carbon dioxide emissions per unit of GDP decreased by 5 percent and 6.6 percent respectively, both exceeding the relevant annual target. China's carbon dioxide emissions per unit of GDP were 42.6 percent lower in 2016 than in 2005, and the comparative reduction is expected to exceed the upper target of 40-45 percent by 2020, laying a solid foundation for achieving the peak carbon emission targets by 2030. Xie believes this progress demonstrates China's determination to combat climate change through action. Many Chinese local governments made efforts to reach assessment goals by absorbing the objectives for dealing with climate change into their economic and social development plans. At present, a diversified pilot scheme involving 87 cities or provinces, 51 industrial parks, 400 communities and eight towns is taking shape to explore on various levels how to promote models that stick to low-carbon development. Officials from Zhenjiang, east China's Jiangsu Province, are frequent guests at the UN climate change conference. The local government adopted innovative measures to reduce emissions and save energy. As early as 2013, the city set the target of peaking its carbon emissions in 2020, 10 years ahead of the national target date. Through actively carrying out international exchanges, China is also taking the initiative to learn from other nations' experiences and methods and to share with them China's examples of low-carbon development. Moreover, China is vigorously promoting South-South cooperation and helping other developing countries improve their capabilities to deal with climate change. To this end, the Chinese Government has since 2011 invested 580 million yuan ($85 million) to conduct low-carbon and adaption programs and to organize capability-building activities. Such actions fully demonstrate China's determination to work with other developing countries to curb climate change and protect our planet. Looking forward to the future, China will unswervingly step up its domestic actions, promote progress in global climate governance and deepen pragmatic cooperation to respond to climate change, Xie said. When being asked whether China will play a leading role in coping with climate change after the U.S. withdrew from the Paris Agreement, Xie said China had its own position and would stick to it. China will actively participate in, contribute to and lead the fight against climate change. Xie noted that the United States is expected to participate in climate change talks over the next four years, in accordance with relevant rules. The United States is an important member of the Paris Agreement family and contributed much to the conclusion of the Paris Agreement. In the future, it's expected to play a constructive role in pushing forward the progress. China is willing to reinforce cooperation with the United States in energy efficiency promotion, technological innovation and low-carbon city development. According to Xie, the United States is evaluating its climate change policies, and after that, it will specify its viewpoint and position. Xie called on the United States to return to the fold and contribute further to the future of human society. A symbolic model made by an environmental group stands on the UN Campus in Bonn, Germany where this year's Climate Change Conference was held, as a way to call on people to preserve forest and minimize the use of timber (XU BEI) Chinese wisdom When divergences emerged at the UN Climate Change Conference in Bonn, China came up with the "bridge scheme," which means trying to find the greatest common ground from opposing viewpoints to reconcile different parties. Xie said that during this conference, China strengthened communication and coordination with the other BASIC nations (Brazil, South Africa, India and China), the "Like-Minded Developing Countries" group and the "G77 plus China" bloc, and in particular enhanced exchanges with European Union countries and the Umbrella Group (non-EU developed countries). "And finally, we found solutions and agreed to leave the unresolved issues to the conference of next year," Xie said. At home, China's concept of ecological development also embodies Chinese wisdom, which is a special contribution to the global effort to subdue climate change. In the report to the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC), General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee Xi Jinping proposed the establishment of a sound economic structure that facilitates green, low-carbon and circular development. Xie held that the global economy should transform from traditional to green, low-carbon and recycling patterns of development. Only in this way can economic development, better livelihoods and a good ecological environment be simultaneously realized. To this end, authorities should advance their philosophy and release related supporting policies and measures. Some countries think emissions cut will hinder economic growth, but Chinese experience suggests that the two are not contradictory. If climate actions, economic growth and employment increase, and environmental protection, health improvement and poverty reduction can be coordinated, synergetic effects will be generated. If climate change is properly dealt with, other problems will be solved more easily. As Xie observes, climate change is exerting an increasingly negative influence on human development, and the threat brought by it is looming. All the peoples of the world should do their best and closely cooperate with each other on this issue. In accordance with Xi's report to the 19th CPC National Congress, efforts should be made to promote balanced economic, political, cultural, social and ecological progress. Global recognition At the opening ceremony of the Bonn climate change conference, Chinese efforts to reconcile actions to curb climate change with sustainable development were repeatedly cited by leaders of other countries, indicating that the contributions made by China had won extensive recognition among the international community. At the high-level segment of the COP 23 to the UNFCCC, German President Frank-Walter Steinmeier pointed out that although China still has a long way to go in climate protection, its determination to implement the Paris Agreement is great. He also described China's climate change efforts as "encouraging." According to UN Under Secretary General for Economic and Social Affairs Liu Zhenmin, after China became the world's second largest economy and biggest emitter of greenhouse gases, its role in climate negotiations gained attention from other nations. In fact, China emerged as a very important player in combating climate change. In Liu's opinion, the Paris Agreement reached in 2015 was a turning point, since when China has fully participated in the international actions to curb climate change and has undertaken voluntary emission reduction. At the same time, China's developments in new energy and new technologies have also drawn international attention. Liu said what China is doing and what it promised are highly praised by all other nations, and in the future, China will still shoulder greater responsibility. He believes that dealing with climate change will be a very important area in China's future development and part of the entire industrialization process. The South-South cooperation to respond to climate change promoted by China was highly appreciated by developing countries, especially small island ones. Bainimarama, Fijian Prime Minister said South-South cooperation provided cooperation platforms and resources for developing countries dealing with climate change. He also expects the Belt and Road Initiative could serve as a model in aspects of global climate governance such as green financing. Bainimarama attended the Belt and Road Forum for International Cooperation held in May in Beijing. Edna Molewa, Minister of Water and Environmental Affairs of South Africa, said the four BASIC nations developed active cooperation and led the world in fulfilling the emission reduction obligations set by the UNFCCC. China's contribution is the most significant, she added. United Nations Environment Program (UNEP) Deputy Executive Director Ibrahim Thiaw believes that China played a vital role in dealing with climate change. On the one hand, a nation like China with such a large economy, population and emission volume voluntarily participating in fighting climate change could serve as a model. On the other hand, China's striving to implement a sustainable development path also contributes to the global ecological progress. Germany's Environment Minister, Barbara Hendricks, said that China shifted its investment focus to renewable energy and issued restrictions on coal-fired power generation in the past five years, which indicates that it is now on a healthy development path. (Reporting from Bonn, Germany) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China64" COP="COP23" country="China" date="October 3, 2017 Tuesday 1:17 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
South Africa on Tuesday urged the United States to reaffirm its commitment to the Paris consensus on climate change. COP 23 , to be held in Germany in November. The recent unprecedented hurricanes in the Caribbean and the Gulf of Mexico, and floods and droughts in Sierra Leone and Ethiopia, remind the world that the impacts of climate change are being felt today, the minister said. The recent catastrophes also make it clear that there can be no turning back on the collective effort in the fight against climate change, and the hard-won consensus in Paris can not be re-negotiated, Molewa stressed. "We must maintain the political momentum and demonstrate through our collective actions that we will stay the course, honor our commitments, and deliver future cycles of progressively more ambitious contributions," Molewa said. COP 23 U.S. President Donald Trump on June 1 announced his decision to withdraw from the Paris Agreement, citing concerns about the accord's threat to the U.S. economy. However, the U.S. State Department said later the United States is "open to re-engaging in the Paris Agreement if the United States can identify terms that are more favorable to it, its business, its workers, its people, and its taxpayers." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China66" COP="COP23" country="China" date="March 29, 2018 Thursday 6:30 AM EST"source="China Business News" >
March 29 -- Hydrogen Council issued its new comers on March 13. There are 6 steering committees like GWM, 3M and National Energy Administration and 5 supporting members like Hexagon. It should be noticed that GWM is the first Chinese automobile enterprise member of Hydrogen Council. Meanwhile, Audi, BMW, Daimler, GM, Honda, Hyundai, Toyota and other well-known multinational auto corporations are members of Hydrogen Council. Hydrogen Council was set up in 2017 Davos World Economic Forum and it aims to promote development of hydrogen technology in global energy structure transition and curb global warming. In addition to famous automakers, Anglo American plc, Air Liquide (France), Iwatani, Linde, Shell, Statoil, Total, etc. are also members of Hydrogen Council. Hydrogen Council believes that with ever-increasing attention paid to hydrogen energy by governments and investors of global countries, widespread application of hydrogen technology is expected to get a decisive breakthrough in next five to ten years. It is predicted through research that by the middle of this century, hydrogen energy is expected to meet 18% of global energy demands, help to reduce 6Gt carbon dioxide emissions, create a gross output of USD 2.5 trillion, and offer 30 million jobs. Activities held by Hydrogen Council become parts of major international events, including World Economic Forum, Climate Week NYC, "One Planet, One Blue Sky" Summit, COP23 , etc., and their participants are heads of countries and governments. Wei Jianjun, as the Chairman of the first Chinese auto enterprise member of Hydrogen Council, believes that hydrogen will play a critical role in energy and transportation fields in China, even in the world. Hydrogen energy, as a carrier of renewable energy and clean energy of HFCVs, can help humans to utilize intermittent energy as renewable energy and realize true zero-emission traffic. Facing such important tasks as easing air pollution and reduction of greenhouse gas emissions, China is expected to be the leader of a renewable energy society of the world. Through being a member of Hydrogen Council, GWM will assume corresponding responsibilities and make contributions to establishing a global hydrogen society. It is known that auto electrification, including development of vehicles with hydrogen cell as power system, has become one of the R&D cores of GWM. GWM has dedicated himself to developing high-power FCVs which will enjoys such advantages as low-cost design, light-weight vehicle body, high energy efficiency and low carbon emission. Through building a world-class team of experts and a top hydrogen test center, GWM has focused on technical research and development in such aspects as hydrogen production, hydrogenation and fuel cell drive system, striving to manufacture highly competitive products in China and even the world. From signing Letter of Intent to set up a new energy vehicle company with BMW, launching the R&D Center in Austria to going to release pure electric vehicle brand in Beijing Auto Show, GWM has walked faster in the field of new energy and 2018 will witness its rapid development. Source: Great Wall Motors Company Limited \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China68" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 4, 2017 Saturday 5:47 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
The following are news highlights in Ethiopia's major media outlets on Saturday. -- Ethiopia's year-on-year inflation increased to 12.2 percent in October from 10.8 percent in September, said the Central Statistical Agency (CSA) of Ethiopia. (Fana Broadcasting Corporate/FBC) -- Ethiopia and Germany sign a 3-year framework agreement amounting to 22.6 million euros. The two countries have agreed to collaborate mainly on agriculture, education and biodiversity conservation in Ethiopia. (Ethiopian Broadcasting Corporation/EBC) -- Ethiopia will reflect the stand of Least Developed Countries in the upcoming 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP 23 ) to the UN Climate Change Conference, according to the Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change. (Fana Broadcasting Corporate/FBC) -- Ethiopia is preparing a strategy that would enable it to enhance the development of bamboo forest so as to maximize benefit, the Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change said. Senior Forest Development Expert, Ashebir Wondimu told ENA that the 10-year strategy will enable it to properly develop, manage and utilize bamboo forests. (Ethiopian News Agency/ENA) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China70" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 10, 2017 Friday 3:17 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
A Chinese negotiator at the ongoing UN climate talks here said Friday that the U.S. withdrawal from the Paris Agreement might have some implications on the "already significant financing issues". Gu Zihua, the negotiator, made the remarks responding to a question about whether the United States' withdrawal have any implications on climate financing at a press briefing held by the Chinese delegation. COP 23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) is drawing to an end. Chen Zhihua, another Chinese negotiator, said financing is a concern of not only China but all the developing countries, "because the gap is there". "If the United States is going to make less contribution, the gap is going to get bigger," Chen said. Gu made clear the stance that the obligation of financing is a collective one of the developed countries. "So if one developed country withdraws, we hope that other developed countries enhance their contributions to fill that gap, and we also believe that local government, corporations and non-state actors in the United States can play a role to fill that gap," Gu said. Gu pledged China would continue to make contributions on a voluntary basis and through south-south cooperation to help other developing countries to address climate change. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China71" COP="COP23" country="China" date="January 10, 2018 Wednesday 11:32 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
5. China and France emphasize that terrorist threat knows no borders. They reaffirm their commitment to the central coordinating role of the United Nations in international cooperation. They will continue to support international initiatives to mobilize under the auspices of the United Nations all forces in the fight against terrorism in all its forms. They also recall the importance of combating terrorism financing. On 26 April 2018, France will organize an international conference in Paris on this theme, to which it will be pleased to see China participate. 6. China and France reaffirm that international law, and in particular, the Charter of the United Nations, applies in cyberspace. They are committed to promoting the development of internationally accepted standards of responsible behavior in cyberspace, in particular within the framework of the United Nations. They will strengthen their cooperation against cybercrime and other malicious activities in cyberspace, including attacks on key infrastructure and the theft of intellectual property by using information and communication technologies to acquire competitive advantages. They agree to continue to strengthen their exchanges and cooperation through the China-France dialogue mechanism on cyber issues. 7. China and France reaffirm their commitment to deepen and broaden their cooperation on environmental protection and climate change. China welcomes the convening of the "One Planet" Summit in Paris. France welcomes the official announcement by China on 19 December 2017 of the launch of its national emissions trading scheme. China and France are satisfied with the progress made on green finance since the work was initiated under the Chinese presidency of the G20. As a continuation of the work of COP23 of the UNFCCC, they will strengthen their collaboration with a view to reaching operational implementation rules for the Paris Agreement at COP24 of the UNFCCC, and will take concrete steps to push for its full, effective and timely implementation of the Paris Agreement. China and France will work together with other parties to raise state ambition before 2020. The Paris Agreement must be implemented in accordance with the principles of equity, common but differentiated responsibilities and respective capabilities, taking into account different national conditions. China and France will strengthen their exchanges on COP15 of the Convention on Biological Diversity and the IUCN World Conservation Congress 2020. 8. China and France intend to continue their constructive dialogue on the formulation of the Global Pact for the Environment. They welcome the signing of an action plan for the protection of the environment (2018-2020) and a cooperation agreement on national parks and support the conservation of marine fauna and flora. They decide to launch a "China-France Year of the Environment" to strengthen their dialogue on the subjects concerned. China and France will also continue to identify and implement joint projects on sustainable cities. 9. China and France will strengthen their exchanges and cooperation on the implementation of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development bilaterally and under the framework of multilateral fora such as the United Nations and the G20. They will continue to intensify their exchanges in this area via the Strategic Dialogue and will hold their development assistance working group meeting in 2018. China will continue to participate regularly in Paris Club meetings and to play a constructive role. 10. China reaffirms its support for the integration of the European Union. China and France will continue to work actively to implement the China-EU 2020 Strategic Agenda for Cooperation and deepen the China-EU comprehensive strategic partnership in areas of mutual interest, in a spirit of mutual and reciprocal benefit. They reaffirm their commitment to support the development of trade and investment relations between China and the EU, based on the principles of openness, transparency and fair competition and WTO rules. They support the swift conclusion of an ambitious comprehensive investment agreement between China and the EU, including market access and investment protection. 11. China and France intend to further develop their comprehensive strategic partnership, on the basis of mutual respect for each other' s sovereignty, territorial integrity, major interests and independently chosen paths of development, by strengthening their bilateral dialogue in a spirit of trust and mutual benefit. France reaffirms its commitment to the one-China principle. The two heads of state reaffirm the importance of the Strategic Dialogue, the High-level Economic and Financial Dialogue and the High-level Dialogue on People-to-People Exchanges between the two countries. (more) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China72" COP="COP23" country="China" date="December 7, 2017 Thursday"source="Beijing Review" >
Climate-friendly solutions benefit both investors and the environment Water-saving irrigation devices irrigate fields in Liaocheng, east China\' s Shandong Province, on April 29 (XINHUA) Whereas in Europe the concept of environmentally friendly feed has been known in the industry for some time, in China it has taken quite a while for firms to consider it, since the feed they have been using is already sufficient for livestock to grow big. Anyou is one of the pioneers making change in the Chinese mainland. The Taiwan-funded company developed a new kind of feed which helps pigs absorb more nutrition, reduces the amounts of excreta they produce and costs less than some other feeds that are widely available. "Many companies are focusing on earnings, it's important that good corporate citizens focus on the long term, because that's creating value, and stay in sustainable business," said Vivek Pathak, Director for East Asia and the Pacific at the International Finance Corp. (IFC), at a forum with the theme Creating Markets for China's Climate Business Innovation held in Beijing on November 13. Being a member of the World Bank Group and the largest global development institution focused on the private sector in emerging markets, IFC is centering its attention on promoting climate change-related business solutions, or "climate-smart business," by mainly cooperating with private companies such as Anyou in emerging markets like China. A model of an energy-conserving building on display at the Third Green Building and Energy-Saving Technologies and Products Expo in Jinan, Shandong Province, on October 27, 2016 (XINHUA) Driving innovation As technological development of the new feed matured, Anyou expanded its research to new fields such as the use of solar energy in pigsties, rainwater recycling and reuse, and alternative uses for livestock manure. However, creating environmentally friendly products and production methods requires much research and experimentation as well as weighing pros and cons. For example, researchers at the company used to cultivate algae with livestock waste. But they soon found that although it is a circular process, which seemed to be sustainable and environmentally friendly, in practice it requires a lot of space and water, resulting to another form of energy waste. Through further trials, the company found a more sustainable concept the use of pig excrement to raise black soldier fly, an insect high in protein that can be fed to livestock. "The entire process has zero release [of emissions], and we are promoting the method to our customers," Dr. Hong Yifen, head of Anyou's low-carbon research department, said at the forum. Anyou is one of many private Chinese companies making a contribution to protecting the environment in their business operations. Guangxi Fenglin Wood Industry Group, one of the earliest manufacturers of wooden floorboards in China, has developed technology to also turn wood offcuts and chips, by-products of the manufacturing process, into wooden flooring. Mlog, a company focused on meteorological science and technology and IT technology research and development, helps its customers reduce production losses due to whether changes using big data analysis, cloud computing and the Internet of Things to provide customized weather services and solutions. In 2015, China indicated that it is targeting "zero growth" in consumption of nitrogen and phosphate fertilizers by 2020. In response, Kingenta, a leading producer of fertilizer in the country, started transforming its business model from just manufacturing fertilizer to providing integrated solutions supporting farmers with high quality and locally tailored fertilizers and advice. Many environment-conscious companies like them have joined hands with IFC in promoting climate-smart agriculture. IFC is investing $200 million to help Kingenta implement a $1-billion program that will upgrade 10 conventional fertilizer plants to produce more efficient and specialty fertilizers and establish a platform of 300 crop-production service centers across eight Chinese provinces. These investments may reduce carbon dioxide emissions by the equivalent of 377,000 tons per year through the use of appropriate fertilizer, according to an IFC Climate Investment Opportunities report. Business opportunities Jos\'e9 Graziano da Silva, Director General of the UN Food and Agriculture Organization, noted that emissions from the agriculture sector are set to increase in the future, further contributing to climate change, unless the world adopts sustainable, climate-smart ways of producing, transporting, processing and consuming food, at the United Nations Climate Change conference in Bonn on November 14. According to the IFC report, food and agriculture are a $5-trillion global industry that represents 10 percent of consumer spending and 30 percent of greenhouse gas emissions. The report also points out that a majority of agricultural investments are not yet climate-smart. This means climate-smart agriculture presents large business opportunities. Other climate-related technologies including renewable energy, green buildings, sustainable urban transport, climate-smart urban water infrastructure and urban waste management, also offer great business potential, with the combined market already worth $1 trillion, according to the IFC report. Investment in the sector is accelerating, as an increasing number of companies are delivering solutions that reduce their customers' greenhouse emissions and help protect the environment for a profit. "The customers have better products, companies get better returns, and investors are proud that they've done the right thing," Pathak said. According to the IFC report, energy service companies have emerged as a key business model for improving energy efficiency in buildings. They typically invest in energy-efficient technologies for commercial buildings and earn royalties on the energy savings without owning the buildings. This model is particularly prominent in China, with Chinese energy service companies earning revenues amounting to $13 billion in 2015, compared to U.S. revenues of $6 billion and EU revenues of $3 billion for the sector the same year. China provides an example of a national market that uses a combination of financing, economic instruments, PPPs and feed-in tariff to drive growth in waste-to-energy plants. The government allows private partners to build, finance and operate waste-to-energy plants. China's 12th Five-Year Plan (2011-15) targeted more than $12 billion worth of investment for waste-to-energy about half of the nation's total investment in municipal solid waste. Waste-to-energy plants also benefit from a 5-percent reduction in tax. These policies make China an attractive waste-to-energy market for the private sector. Role of government The Chinese Government is doing its bit to cope with climate change and to protect the environment. As one of the first nations both to ratify the Paris Agreement and to submit to the UN a national program to tackle climate change, China has made great contributions to the endeavor. As early as 2015, China pledged to peak its carbon dioxide emissions in 2030, and began striving to realize the goal earlier still. The IFC report says that China has become a green energy leader since the government designated renewable energy as a strategic industry. It now has more than one third of the world's wind power capacity and a quarter of its solar power, and is leading a revolution in battery technology. China also leads the way in greener finance. It introduced Green Credits in 2012 and is, to date, the only nation to have introduced standardized mandatory reporting on green loans for its largest banks. It has established the world's biggest green credit market, valued at more than $1 trillion. The loans cover energy saving, green transport, pollution treatment and resource recycling. The Chinese Government has also created guidelines to encourage private capital to invest in green sectors while restricting investment in polluting industries. It plans to use public funds to improve the returns on green projects, through interest subsidies for example, while raising taxes on polluting industries. Protecting the environment is vital to China's sustainable development in the future. In the report delivered to the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC), General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee Xi Jinping said, "We must pursue a model of sustainable development featuring increased production, higher living standards, and healthy ecosystems. We must continue the Beautiful China initiative to create good working and living environments for our people and play our part in ensuring global ecological security." According to the Planning and Finance Department of the Ministry of Environmental Protection, China has set aside 49.7 billion yuan ($7.5 billion) to fund environmental protection this year. Pathak said that China deserves more credit for the work it has done in addressing climate change. "The government is playing a critical role in terms of regulations, creating a sound environment and encouraging the private sector to invest in these areas. It should also lead by example by giving financial support directly," he told Beijing Review. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China73" COP="COP23" country="China" date="August 29, 2017 Tuesday 9:02 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
French President Emmanuel Macron announced Tuesday that France will host an international summit on Dec. 12 to ensure the implementation of the Paris Agreement on climate change. The summit is scheduled to take place two years to the date when the historic agreement was reached at the 2015 United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP 21) in Paris. The summit is expected to "make a key progress" and "mobilize the necessary funding" for the implementation of the agreement, Macron said in a speech on foreign policy to ambassadors. The event will be organized in cooperation with the World Bank, and "all our partners who wish to be associated," Macron said. Recalling the success of hosting the COP 21, the president said he would do everything to "preserve this agreement and ensure its best possible implementation." "It is important to develop a close dialogue on this subject with partners who have decided to carry out an ambitious action in this area," he added. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China75" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday 3:02 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
A Chinese mainland spokesperson said Wednesday that Taiwan's refusal to adhere to the 1992 Consensus is the crucial reason for its problems in participating in international affairs. Ma Xiaoguang, spokesperson for the Taiwan Affairs Office of the State Council, made the remarks at a regular press conference when answering a question about Taiwan's failure to participate in the United Nations Climate Change Conference held in Germany. Taiwan authorities refuse to adhere to the 1992 Consensus, which has led to the suspension of communication with the mainland and made it impossible for the two sides to solve problems, Ma said. "The Taiwan side should reflect on its own mistake, rather than falsely accuse the mainland," he said. Ma said the mainland has always firmly opposed any country it has diplomatic relations with to sign any agreement with Taiwan that implies the island is a sovereign country. The mainland and Taiwan belong to the same China and the handling of relevant affairs must strictly follow this principle, Ma said when answering a question about Taiwan's plans to draft a law on mutual aid in international criminal justice. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China76" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 16, 2017 Thursday 3:02 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
China's special representative on climate change affairs, Xie Zhenhua, pledged that China will deliver its promises in full, and will continue contributing "Chinese wisdom" and "Chinese proposals" to the global fight against climate change, while addressing a high-level meeting of UN climate talks held here on Thursday. "While restructuring economy domestically, China will deliver its promises in full, and will demonstrate the country's readiness to take on responsibility for building a community of shared future for mankind," Xie said at the 23rd Conference of Parties ( COP 23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). "China is ready to play the role, all along, as a participant and contributor in global climate governance, sustainable development, as well as a guardian of multilateral processes," said Xie. The special representative pledged that China will work with other countries to speed up works in three aspects, including accelerating follow-up negotiations on the Paris Agreement, making arrangement for facilitative dialogues to be held in 2018, and implementing pre-2020 actions and commitment so as to lay solid foundation for trust-building. To implement the pre-2020 actions, developed countries are supposed to carry out and improve their roadmap for mobilizing 100 billion U.S. dollars of climate financing per year to developing countries by 2020, and to further review their pre-2020 targets, Xie said. Xie also introduced China's low-carbon development in the speech, saying from 2005 to 2015, China's economy had grown by 1.48 times, and at the same time the carbon intensity, the measure of CO2 emission per unit of GDP, had dropped by 38.6 percent, adding the country had avoided emitting 4.1 billion tonnes of CO2. Moreover, the share of coal in the total consumption of energy had decreased from 72 percent to 64 percent in the same period, while the share of non-fossil fuels in primary energy consumption rose from 7.4 percent to 12 percent, and at the same time, the country's forest reserve had expanded by 3 billion cubic meters, according to Xie. "China has over delivered on achieving its targets in fighting climate change, and reversed the rapid rise of CO2 emission that had lasted for years," Xie said. In 2016, despite downward pressure on economic growth, China managed a year-on-year decrease of carbon intensity by 6.6 percent, and its share of non-fossil fuels in total consumption of primary energy reached 13.3 percent, an increase of 1.3 percentage points, Xie continued. "This year, we will jumpstart the nation-wide carbon-trading market," Xie said, adding China has set aside a total of 100 million U.S. dollars for South-South cooperation with 27 developing countries over the years. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China77" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 9, 2017 Thursday 1:47 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
At the ongoing United Nations (UN) climate talks in Bonn, global environment organizations and climate experts and officials recognized opportunities and the potential China presented to global climate cooperation and to scaling up various climate actions they are pursuing. Dylan Murray, policy advisor with the Nature Conservancy, told Xinhua that China can be a "net exporter of opportunities, lessons learned and best practices for countries in Asia or beyond", when participating the side-event in China Pavilion at the 23rd Conference of Parties ( COP 23 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). "China has big plans for renewable energy, nationally determined contributions, forest restoration and forest carbon. We see a lot of opportunities with the Chinese government when it comes to policy issues and also opportunities for bottom-up projects," Murray said. The U.S.-based Nature Conservancy is working on leveraging nature to pull carbon out of the atmosphere. Murray said a recent report of the organization found that up to 2030, or in the next 13 years, 37 percent of opportunities to tackle climate change comes from the nature. "But we are nowhere near to get the work done. We see China as really a good opportunity for us to scale up quickly," said Murray, eyeing greater presence in China for the organization. Ottmar Edenhofer, a leading climate expert in Germany and Deputy Director & Chief Economist at the Potsdam Institute for Climate Impact Research (PIK), sees great opportunities of cooperation between China, Germany and Europe. In an interview with Xinhua, Edenhofer expected that China and Germany step up cooperation in electric mobility, photovoltaic industry, and city planning to enable electronic mobility as well as to address congestion and local pollution. "As China is now pushing for electric cars, regulations in China will have strong impact on European and German industry, so in that sense, China is influencing our regulations and pushes us also to invest more in electric mobility because China is an increasing market," said Edenhofer. Moreover, Edenhofer expected best practices about the carbon emission trading scheme can be shared among China and Europe. "China should not replicate mistakes made by Europe" when implementing the scheme, said the scholar. For Brad Page, CEO of Global CCS (carbon capture and storage) Institute, he sees great potential in China to boost the global efforts in tackling climate through Carbon Capture Utilization and Storage (CCUS) as China is accelerating very quickly in this field. Page said the institute published each year a report showing where the CCUS projects are worldwide. "When I started this job six years ago, China had none. This year, in the catalogue we are going to publish next week, China comes the second in terms of the number of CCUS projects, just behind the U.S.," said Page. "Every time I hear updates when I visit China about what is happening in China, I think China is a very exciting place for climate change actions," Page said. Developing countries also held high expectations for South-South cooperation with China. Mr. Nguyen Tuan Anh, with the Vietnamese Ministry of Planning and Investment, said climate change adaptation is a challenge that must be jointly faced by developing nations, island nations, and least-developed countries. "Both China's financing and development experience are of great significance to us." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China78" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 2, 2017 Thursday"source="China Daily" >
US likely to meet Paris deal goals, says UN program head GENEVA - The head of the United Nations environment program said on Tuesday that the United States is likely to live up to the Paris climate deal despite President Donald Trump's planned pullout, because "all the big American companies" are working toward greener operations. The comments from UNEP executive director Erik Solheim came as the UN agency presented its latest "Emissions Gap" report, which gives a scientific assessment about how national efforts are affecting the greenhouse gas emission trend. The report's release ahead of a crucial climate meeting next week in Bonn, Germany, aims to inject new momentum to the Paris accord and even strengthen it in 2020. Trump, however, has vowed to pull out because he insists it's unfair to the US. UN officials are citing the role of companies in the fight against climate change. "There is one question that I get more often than any other question wherever I go on the planet and it is a very simple one. It is: 'What about Donald Trump?'" Solheim told a panel in Geneva by videoconference from Nairobi. "In all likelihood, the United States of America will live up to its Paris commitment, not because of the White House, but because of the private sector," he said. "All the big American companies are dedicated to go in the green direction." But UNEP said countries and industries still need to do more to meet targets to cut greenhouse gas emissions that experts say contribute to global warming. The report criticizes coal-fired electricity plants being built in emerging economies, and insists that investment in renewable energies will pay for itself - and even make money - over the long term. "The Paris agreement boosted climate action, but momentum is clearly faltering," said Edgar Gutierrez-Espeleta, Costa Rica's Environment Minister, who heads the UN Environment Assembly. "We face a stark choice: up our ambition, or suffer the consequences." The Paris accord aims to cap global temperature increases to 2 C by the year 2100 compared to average world temperatures at the start of the industrial era - and even hopes to limit the increase to 1.5 C. UNEP says trends suggest that even if current national commitments are met, a temperature increase of 3 C by the end of the century is "very likely - meaning that governments need to deliver much stronger pledges when they are revised in 2020". A new round of UN climate talks known as COP 23 starts in Bonn, Germany, on Monday, when countries will take stock of their achievements and prepare more ambitious goals. On the positive side, UNEP highlighted "rapidly expanding mitigation action" and says carbon-dioxide emissions have remained stable since 2014, thanks partly to renewable energy use in China and India. It cautioned that other greenhouse gases like methane continue to rise, however. UNEP has trumpeted solar and wind energy, efficient appliances and cars, and efforts to preserve forests. Solheim cited tests this week on the world's first solar-powered railroad in Australia and the launch of a hydrogen-run subway system in northern China. "We are at the watershed moment: We have stopped the rise in CO2 (carbon dioxide) emissions - there is every reason to believe we can bring them down," Solheim said. "The train is on the right track, but our duty is to speed it up." Agence France-presse (China Daily 11/02/2017 page11) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China79" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 13, 2017 Monday"source="China Daily" >
The Chinese delegation has vowed to put pre-2020 actions on the formal negotiating agenda of the Bonn climate talks to put further pressure on developed countries to deliver on carbon reduction promises, otherwise global cooperation on implementing Paris Agreement will face severe setbacks. Bonn summit delegation ramps up pressure on developed countries The Chinese delegation has vowed to put pre-2020 actions on the formal negotiating agenda of the Bonn climate talks to put further pressure on developed countries to deliver on carbon reduction promises, otherwise global cooperation on implementing Paris Agreement will face severe setbacks. Senior representatives with the Chinese delegation said there is an urgent need to put the agenda on the table, as a lack of concrete action before 2020 from developed nations may dent global confidence in further implementing the Paris Agreement. "There are only two years to 2020, so we don't have the luxury of time," said Chinese negotiator Chen Zhihua. "Clearly the gaps are there. If they are not being filled, the gaps will ultimately transfer to the post-2020 period." Unlike the Paris Agreement made in 2015, where nearly 200 signatories set clear targets to combat climate change starting from 2020, the onus is on developed nations in the pre-2020 Actions, in which it requires developed countries to meet quantified targets to reduce greenhouse gas emissions. Rulebook draft Signatories to the Paris Agreement around the world are striving to draft a rulebook for implementing the Paris pact in Bonn, which is expected to be finalized at next year's climate conference. But the ongoing negotiations face "a crisis of trust" if developed nations refuse to agree to formally address pre-2020 actions during the talks, according to Gu Zihua, another senior Chinese negotiator. "We're not asking for unrealistic commitment from developed countries. We simply want developed nations to fulfill pledges that have already been made," said Gu. "Pre-2020 is really a trust-building issue for developing countries," he said, "If they turn down all proposals, then how could developing countries have trust in future discussions?" China and other developing countries have submitted a request to the UN climate change secretariat to organize an event to commemorate the 20th anniversary of adoption of the 1997 Kyoto Protocol, an earlier key document setting binding targets on greenhouse-gas emissions for the world's leading economies which have accepted it. As for financing gap left by the United States, China hopes other developed countries are able to enhance their contributions to fill that gap, according to Gu. "Despite with the US withdrawal, there is still progress being made. Non-state actors in the US can play a role to fill that gap," said Gu. China will continue to make financial contributions through south-south cooperation scheme, he added. HYPERLINK mailto:wangyanfei@chinadaily.com.cn wangyanfei@chinadaily.com.cn People dressed as polar bears march during a demonstration in Bonn against the COP 23 UN Climate Change Conference hosted by Fiji but held in Bonn, Germany, on Saturday.Wolfgang Rattay / Reuters (China Daily 11/13/2017 page11) http://imgs.syndigate.info/498/1493/21/151053418138.jpg http://imgs.syndigate.info/498/1493/21/151053418138.jpg a41f726b05111b732a3233.jpg \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China80" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 16, 2017 Thursday 8:47 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
China has made a series of landmark achievements in science and technology recently as the country quickens its pace in becoming a science and tech powerhouse by the middle of the century. The biannual ranking of the world's fastest 500 supercomputers published Monday showed China's Sunway TaihuLight in the lead for the fourth time, with Tianhe-2 the second. China has overtaken the United States in the total number of ranked systems by a margin of 202 to 144. As China's computers run faster, its Antarctic research expedition is going further. Icebreaker Xuelong headed south from Shanghai last Wednesday bound for Antarctica, where the country's fifth station will be set up within five years. The new base will provide year-round support for researchers conducting tasks such as observations of land, ocean, atmosphere, ice shelf and biology, establishment of an observation and monitoring network in the Antarctic, and survey of marine environmental protection. China is also dealing with global issues with science and technology. On Wednesday, a new meteorological satellite, Fengyun-3D, was launched to work in tandem with Fengyun-3C, already in orbit, improving atmospheric sounding and monitoring greenhouse gases. At the ongoing 23rd conference of parties ( COP 23 ) to the United Nations framework convention on climate change (UNFCCC) in Bonn, China was commended for its action in combating climate change. German environment minister Barbara Hendricks said that she was aware that China planned to generate more power from renewable energy. Norbert Salomon, deputy director of emission control, safety of installations and transport at the German Federal Ministry for Environment, praised China for expansion of electric mobility. China stressed innovation in the 13th Five-Year Plan (2016-2020), with the aim of becoming an "innovation nation" by 2020, an international leader in innovation by 2030, and a world powerhouse in scientific and technological innovation by 2050. In recent years, China has commissioned the dark matter probe satellite Wukong, launched the Tiangong-2 space lab, quantum science satellite Mozi and carrier rocket Long March-6, which took 20 micro-satellites for space testing. With two BeiDou-3 satellites taken into space on a single carrier rocket this month, China is on track to create a global BeiDou Navigation Satellite System by around 2020, which will make it the third country after the United States and Russia with its own navigation system. In its step toward unravelling the mystery of the universe, China's Five-hundred-meter Aperture Spherical Radio Telescope (FAST), the world's largest single-dish radio telescope, has identified multiple pulsars after one year of trial operations, the National Astronomical Observatories of China (NAOC) announced in October. Li Di, chief scientist of the NAOC radio astronomy division, predicted that when FAST starts formal operations in 2019, it will find over 100 pulsars each year. The telescope is expected to discover twice the number of pulsars currently known. All this, along with the success of deep-sea manned submersible Jiaolong, shows China leading the world in a number of fields, but still with weaknesses. Large sums are spent on chip imports every year -- 227 billion U.S. dollars in 2016, twice that spent on crude oil, data from the General Administration of Customs showed. Increased investment and new technology must be devoted to domestic chip research, development and production. According to a national plan on science and technology innovation during the 2016-2020 period, high-end common chip R&D is still on the list of key projects. Other projects include a deep-sea space station, space probes, quantum telecommunications, brain science, artificial intelligence and clean energy. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China81" COP="COP23" country="China" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday 8:47 AM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
New Zealand Climate Change Minister James Shaw has endorsed the communique agreed at the ongoing COP23 climate change conference in Bonn, Germany, a government release said on Wednesday. "Endorsing this Bonn communique recognizes the important role that New Zealand plays internationally looking for ways to tackle agricultural climate pollution," Shaw said in the release. "Tackling agricultural climate pollution and other sources of air pollution are critical to addressing climate change and ensuring we leave a stable climate for future generations," Shaw said. The Green Party's confidence and supply agreement with the Labor Party commit to significant reductions in waste to landfill by 2020, and this Bonn communique recognizes how important work to reduce waste emissions is, the minister said. Auckland, New Zealand's largest city, has committed to a very ambitious target of zero waste by 2040, he said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China82" COP="COP23" country="China" date="April 30, 2018 Monday 9:22 PM GMT"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
SUVA, April 30 (Xinhua) -- The Fijian government is taking steps towards replacing cash with electronic payments after it introduced an e-ticketing public transport payment system in October last year which the population is now accepting to live with. Many commuters have adapted well to the eticketing system while some miss handling cash daily because in their view it remains a cheaper exercise. Atasa Marama, a single mother of one who lives with her baby son, parents and brother, said that eticketing card is expensive for her and her family. She tops up daily and must have 4 Fijian dollars (about 1.93 U.S. dollars) in his card to be able to travel to and from work to Suva as she lives about 15 minutes drive away in a settlement in Tacirua, a place near Suva. Before she only needed was 1.15 Fijian dollars (55 U.S. cents) each way. She said that she tops up only when she needs to travel and still hates the idea because for her it is not as cheap as using cash. Harold Koi, a father of five with three kids attending different schools in Suva, likes the new eticketing card system because all he does is to top up each child's card with 10 Fijian dollars (about 4.84 U.S. dollars) a fortnight. He said that it was hard when one loses the card because there are forms that needed to be filled and he had to take time off work to do that. Another commuter Adi Losalini said that every fortnight she budgets 10 Fijian dollars (about 4.48 U.S. dollars) for her bus fare card. "Sometimes the remaining money can be like 10 Fijian cents (about 0.48 U.S. cents) but I don't seem to know where it goes," said Levi Tabakau, a farmer and father of three, who likes the new system. He said that it helps him budget his money well. "Before I travel, I would think if I really need to go somewhere so it's good that way. When I used cash I didn't seem to really plan my travelling." In last October the eTransport system was introduced in Fiji which has a population of more than 880,000. The system was introduced to counter pilferage by bus companies and also help Fijians adapt to a cashless society as the world is changing that way. The overhaul of the fare collection system was recommended by the Swiss consultants after the bus strike crisis of 2008 in Fiji. According to this report, bus drivers pilfered 7 million Fijian dollars (about 3.38 million U.S. dollars) annually from 66 registered operators who had a total of 1000 buses running. The report stated drivers were in total control of the cash and the receipt butts and the bus company's revenue was whatever the driver took to the owner. So the recommendation was for eTicket machines to be installed in buses where fare is prepaid and the company will know exactly how much they should collect. It was predicted that the new system would mean more revenue for bus companies. This new eTicketing system that came into effect on October 1, 2017 dawned signs of a new age of a cashless public bus industry in the island nation. Vodafone Fiji's Head of Commerce and Corporate Affairs Shailendra Prasad said that Vodafone was certain the fare programmed in the system for each stage was the regulated fare approved by Fiji's Land Transport Authority (LTA). "These have been thoroughly tested. Every time a fare is processed, a ticket is issued instantly which details of the date, the time of travel, the bus registration number on which the passenger travels, the fare the passenger has been charged and the remaining balance on the card," he said. "For any wrong fares charged to the passenger, there is a redress mechanism in place through LTA as the regulated enforcement body. It is advised that passengers keep their tickets to substantiate their claims for wrong fare being charged." Fiji Bus Operators Association (FBOA) said that there are some 600,000 cards out there for Fiji's bus commuters. Fijian Prime Minister Voreqe Bainimarama, who is the president of COP 23 (the 23rd Conference of the Parties to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change), is determined to reduce carbon emissions and in the island nation by using less paper. Since last December, all payments made by the Fijian government departments have been switched to be done electronically without issuing cheques, adding to Fiji's change of becoming a cashless society. Head of the Australia and New Zealand (ANZ) Bank in Fiji Saud Minam said that the Fijian people were adapting well to the switch of using electronic platforms, and businesses were also conforming to limiting the use of paper. Enditem \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China84" COP="COP23" country="China" date="January 19, 2018 Friday"source="China Daily European Edition" >
Despite annual and seasonal fluctuations, the real game changer might be clean energy China's coal consumption has steadily decreased by a few percentage points a year since 2013, prompting our pronouncement of a coal consumption peak in an article published in the summer of 2016 in Nature Geoscience. However, in 2017, the beast of coal seemed to be quite untamed. Coal prices rose sharply, production and consumption went up, and the coal inventory was in sharp decline. Coal consumption appears to have made a quick rebound. In a recent report by the Global Carbon Project published during COP 23 - the informal name for the 23rd Conference of the Parties to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change - the authors predicted a 3 percent increase of coal consumption in China, leading to a 3.5 percent increase in China's carbon emissions, a key contributor to a 2 percent increase of global emissions in 2017. Many are concerned about the robustness of China's energy decarbonization and its implication for climate change. Has China's coal consumption really peaked? First of all, the 3 percent increase of China's coal consumption was likely to be an overestimate. The estimation was based on data from the China Coal Industry Association and the National Energy Administration for the first half of 2017, when China's coal consumption experienced a sharp rebound. The CCIA reported 5 percent growth, while the NEA said it was 1 percent, with a difference of 100 million metric tons between the two. The Global Carbon Project report seems to have taken a simple arithmetic average of the two data sources. This treatment is inconsistent with convention for inter-annual comparison. The CCIA data is not used in official data reporting, since it includes only larger coal producers, which respond quite differently from smaller ones. In addition, its treatment of inventory is quite different from national coal statistics. In 2016, the CCIA calculated the inventory decrease to be about 240 million tons, or 2 percent greater than the official data on total consumption. Thus, the CCIA data can be quite informative in understanding coal production of large producers, but not the best source to cite for approximating coal consumption, especially for inter-annual comparison. The NEA data tends to be consistent with the official release from the National Bureau of Statistics and thus more appropriate for inter-annual comparison. According to the NEA, in the first three quarters of 2017, coal consumption in China reached 2.81 billion metric tons, an increase of less than 1 percent from 2016. A similar estimation of 2.82 billion to 2.83 billion tons is corroborated by the Energy Research Institute of the NDRC. We support the conclusion that coal consumption is likely to have experienced a rebound of around 1 percent in 2017. Total consumption would be 3.82 billion metric tons - 150 million tons less than that of 2015, or 420 million tons less than the 2013 level. Even if coal consumption increased by 3 percent to 3.90 billion tons in 2017 as the Global Carbon Project report said, it is still far less than the 4 billion tons in 2015, let alone challenging the 4.24 billion tons peak in 2013. Given the inappropriate use of the data sources, the Global Carbon Project estimation of global emissions and contribution from China, especially from its coal consumption, may be misleading. Using the GCP estimation approach, we calculate that China's overall emissions increase in 2017 would be closer to 1 percent, instead of 3.5 percent - still lower than the 2014 level. Countering the market effect of rebounding coal use in power and industry, the government has been implementing strong policies to substitute natural gas and electricity for coal use, mainly to address the air pollution problem. As a result, gas consumption increased by 17 percent in the first 10 months of the year. It is estimated that the substitution effort would replace about 47 million metric tons of coal use in 2017. Entering the last quarter of the year, the momentum of coal use growth faded. In September, coal-fired electricity output and steel production, together representing about 75 percent of overall coal consumption, declined by 0.5 percent and 1.4 percent, respectively, and further dropped by 2.8 percent and 1.3 percent in October. In November, coal-fired power production continued to decrease by 1.4 percent from last year. Looking ahead, we do not anticipate significant new growth of coal consumption this year or in the next few years. First of all, the Chinese government is not setting a higher target of growth for 2018. The traditional drivers of coal growth - construction and manufacturing - will continue to give way to the service sector in economic growth. Real estate development is experiencing the coldest winter ever due to restrictive regulations by the central and local governments. Anticipation of a property tax would make speculators switch from "buy" to "sell" mode. Additionally, investment in infrastructure construction by local governments is now haunted by the local debts and is unlikely to grow quickly. In fact, some provincial governments have gone public to acknowledge and correct their overestimations of GDP and revenue. We stick to our conclusion made in 2016: Coal-fired growth is over, despite the fact that coal remains the primary fuel for the Chinese economy. In addition, the regional coal-cap policy will continue to squeeze coal out of the energy mix, especially in the haze-intensive regions in the north. It is expected that even less coal will be used next winter, when more gas pipes are in place for heating. The real game changer is clean energy. The price of solar photovoltaic is at an all-time low, enough to compete against coal for power generation. Additionally, wind power is well positioned to play an even bigger role. Nevertheless, China is still the single largest coal user in the world, and coal represents more than 60 percent of its energy mix. But in the long run, coal consumption will continue declining - with current policies and the structural transformation of the economy from being a heavy industry-led, export-driven model to one sustained by services and domestic consumption - despite the annual and seasonal fluctuations. We have no doubt that China's coal consumption has peaked and coal-fired economic growth has come to an end. The authors are from the Brookings-Tsinghua Center for Public Policy at Tsinghua University. The views do not necessarily reflect those of China Daily. (China Daily European Weekly 01/19/2018 page10) Load-Date: \~January 19, 2018 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_China85" COP="COP23" country="China" date="September 22, 2017 Friday 5:47 PM EST"source="Xinhua General News Service" >
World leaders attending the UN General Assembly here have reached an unseen degree of unity and solidarity on two major things: firmly protecting and upholding multilateralism and the Paris Agreement on climate change as they believe only by pooling efforts of all countries can they tackle the unprecedented challenges and threats facing the human beings. MULTILATERALISM: ON LIPS OF LEADERS Multilateralism was a major theme of the speech delivered by French President Emmanuel Macron when he addressed the General Debate of the 72nd session of the UN General Assembly. He noted that the world's greatest problems, from climate change to the problems of "unregulated capitalism," could only be solved by nations working together. "We can only try and address those challenges through multilateralism, not through the law of the survival of the fittest," he said. Macron's perspective and determination were echoed by almost all presidents, prime ministers and other senior national representatives gathering at the UN's annual most important event discussing ways and solutions to thorny problems facing the world. President of Cyprus, Nicos Anastasiades, said Thursday that multilateralism is "the only way to preserve the planet." Anastasiades spoke extensively about multilateralism in his speech, stressing that sticking to the path of multilateralism is the only way "to preserve the planet; peacefully resolve conflicts; end terrorism and extremism; prevent natural disasters and alleviate humanitarian crises around the world." Romanian President Klaus Werner Iohannis mirrored his views, noting that multilateralism is "the only clear path" in tackling today's challenges. Lohannis said that "rising tensions over cultural identity and faith along with terrorist attacks" are deepening insecurity. "People across the globe suffer from war, poverty, inequality and injustice," he said, adding that "no other path serves us better than multilateralism in finding viable solutions for the current global challenges." Not only leaders from small and less developed countries hold the stance, those from the West exhibited similar perspective. Germany warned the United Nations not to be lured by the siren song of "our country first," calling it a recipe for more conflict and less prosperity that must be eschewed in favor more international cooperation and the strengthening of the UN. "A world view which puts one's own national interests first and is no longer engaged in a balancing of interests between the nations and countries of this world is gaining ever more ground," German Foreign Minister Sigmar Gabriel told the debate. The motto "our country first not only leads to more national confrontations and less prosperity. In the end, there will only be losers," said Gabriel. Looking over the General Assembly Hall packed with world leaders and other senior officials anxious to search for solutions to common threats and challenges, UN chief Antonio Guterres said "multilateralism is more important than ever" when there are competing interests and even open conflict. "We call ourselves the international community; we must act as one," he said. China, one of the five permanent member of the UN Security Council, has always been a staunch supporter of multilateralism. Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi said that the country will bring more dividends of peace, of development and of governance to the world, noting that China is "a propeller for multilateralism." China is willing to work with other countries to build a better future for mankind, he said. Multilateralism, international cooperation, unity and other words calling for collective action against common challenges and threats are like air filling every inch of the UN headquarters these days, while almost all hate to talk about unilateralism which has become a taboo at the ongoing high-level meeting. PARIS AGREEMENT: ACCORD FOR COMMON GOOD "As small island Pacific countries, we are no longer protected by our isolation," said Samoa's Prime Minister Tuilaepa Sailele Malielegaoi. "Climate change, like other global challenges, cross borders seamlessly. It has no respect for sovereignty and does not discriminate countries between rich or poor." Joining the Pacific leaders expressing concern over the threat posed by climate change, Enele Sosene Sopoaga, Prime Minister of Tuvalu, also underscored the importance of the Paris Agreement, especially for the tens of millions living in low-lying islands and coastal areas around the world. "The Paris Agreement is our common hope of a decent life on a sustainable planet. For Tuvalu, it is our hope of security and survival," said the prime minister. However, the hope is "dimmed with the announcement by the United States that it will abandon the Agreement," Sopoaga said. Catastrophes such as the most recent devastating earthquake in Mexico and the successive hurricanes that have hit the Latin American and Caribbean region "remind us that we are at a key moment in human history in which the notion of development that has prevailed until now has been shaken by the relentless reality of climate change," President of Chile Michelle Bachelet warned in her speech. "We can close our eyes and deny a reality whose devastating effects will become more frequent and intense, or assume our responsibility," Bachelet said, reiterating the need to join the fight against climate change, because in fact: "there is no space for denial." Devastating hurricanes and other extreme weather events are worrying almost all world leaders, but fortifying their determination to join hands. Prime Minister of Fiji, Josaia Voreqe Bainimarama, said his people share a special sense of solidarity with those affected by the recent hurricanes and earthquakes, recalling that Fiji lost a third of its economy last year when struck by the biggest cyclone ever to make landfall in the southern hemisphere. As the incoming president of the 23rd session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP 23 ) to the UN Convention on Climate Change, Bainimarama is deeply conscious of the need to lead a global response to the underlying causes of these events. "Unless we tackle the underlying causes of climate change, we already know that some places will become unlivable and others will disappear altogether," he stressed, saying that Fiji has offered refuge to the people of Kiribati and Tuvalu, its neighbors at risk. Climate change affects Fijian lives, whether it is entire villages being moved away from rising seas; the loss of ancestral burial grounds; salinity affecting crops; or the constant threat of destruction to homes and infrastructure. Climate is changing and has changed. Extreme weather events as showcased by recent deadly and frequent hurricanes, floods and droughts have made world leaders, especially those from countries severely inflicted by the climate change-caused disasters, firmly believe: we the peoples are in the same boat. "Act now!""Let's waste no time!" All firmly believe that urgent action must be taken to keep the earth a paradise for human being, which might be the best legacy for future generations. \</doc>
