<doc ID="COP23_Australia1" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 14, 2017 Tuesday"source="Mornington Peninsula Leader (Australia)" >
HOT TOPIC Shire 'junket' anger RE: Council CEO embarks on ratepayer-funded 20-day Europe trip(Mornington Peninsula Leader, October 24): No COUNCILLOR or council employee should ever get an overseas holiday paid for by ratepayers. Study tours, networking, learning, are all a lot of rot. Elected councillors, often one term, are all there to do a very simple part-time job. The $16,000 expense account should be reduced to zero. This is the insignificant Mornington Peninsula Shire, not New York City. It is my hard-earned money being exploited. Brian a. Mitchelson, Mornington It IS not ratepayers' money. It is in fact Mr Cowie's money, as it formed part of his salary package, negotiated with councillors. There is a history of such trips bringing information that has directly influenced shire policy and outcomes, more than justifying the trip expenses. The programs at events such as COP 23 (an annual United Nations climate change conference ) deliver far more than any internet search would provide. Talking one-on-one with like-minded people from around the world is invaluable. The Nepean Ratepayers Association, which represents ratepayers in the Nepean Ward, commends Mr Cowie travelling to the COP 23 conference in Bonn. With his experience running commercial businesses he will definitely bring back some fresh ideas which will benefit ratepayers all over the shire. colin watson, Nepean Ratepayers Association Adi came to us three years ago, after five years as a puppy farm breeder. She was very traumatised by her early life, and it has taken us years to bring her out of her shell, but she still has some issues with people and loud noises. We live in Nunawading, and went down to Rosebud for a few days for a holiday. On November 3 we went to the Woolworths on Nepean Rd, where an aggressive German shepherd was barking in the back seat of a parked car. Adi was getting freaked out and when the aggressive dog went off she jerked out of her collar and ran. She made it safely through the carpark and across Point Nepean Rd (somehow) and disappeared in to the foreshore scrub. We searched for nearly 12 hours but, given her history, suspected she would be in deep hiding. After 19 hours (at 4.15am), Adi turned up at the front door, a bit cold and wet, but otherwise OK. We want to thank all the people who helped us in that time - especially the couple shopping at Woolworths. He helped Mum and Oli get home, while she raced across the road to help look and then they later got in their car to look further afield. Thanks also to the Woolworths employee who took off after Adi and followed her to the foreshore; Shelley, who posted a photo and missing notice on the 'Reuniting Lost and Found Pets - Mornington Peninsula' Facebook group; Emma from Kaya's Mission Traralgon (who rescued Adi three and a half years ago), who posted on the 'Kaya's Mission' Facebook page and paid to promote it for the Mornington Peninsula area. Thanks to the many people we encountered along the foreshore during our search - what a friendly, caring community! And Whitehorse Veterinary Hospital in Blackburn, who have been with us right through Adi's journey, and squeezed her in for a thorough check-up after her ordeal.Nicole Ackland, Nunawading \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia2" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 2, 2017 Thursday 7:06 AM AEST"source="MediaNet Press Release Wire" >
Oxfam Australia's climate change policy advisor Simon Bradshaw said the impact on the world's most vulnerable communities was even more severe when accounting for drought, sea-level rise and other 'slow-onset' events. "For many, including Torres Strait Islanders and Aboriginal communities in Australia's far north, and the Pacific atoll nations of Kiribati, Tuvalu and the Marshall Islands, climate change is a fight for survival. The United Nation's climate conference, COP 23 , kicks off on Monday, 6 November, in Bonn, Germany. The conference will be chaired by Fiji, the first small island nation to do so, and a country on the frontline of extreme weather disasters and the impacts of climate change. During Cyclone Winston in 2016, around 55,000 people in Fiji were forced from their homes and one-fifth of the island's gross domestic product was wiped out. "Pacific Island communities are leading the world in action on climate change; it's time for Australia to follow their lead," Dr Bradshaw said. "To meet its obligations under the Paris Agreement, including helping limit warming to 1.5???C, Australia must achieve zero emissions before 2040, say no to new coalmines - including Adani's proposed Carmichael mega-mine - and increase support for climate change adaptation in developing countries." The report shows how people on the frontline of climate change are dealing with the threat of displacement. For example, communities in the Torres Strait Islands in Australia's far north intend to do everything possible to remain on their islands, despite the rising seas and higher storm surges. "When we talk about relocation, it's very clear that this is an option of last resort," said Hilda Mosby from Masig Island in the Torres Strait. "We want to try everything we can to keep our community here." While not all displacement from extreme weather disasters could be attributed to climate change, there is no question that without stronger action, increasing numbers of people will be forced from their homes. Oxfam says COP23 COP23 must help set the world on a path to limiting warming to 1.5???C. Rich countries also have a long way to go to meet their promises of finance for climate action in developing countries, and must show how they'll get there. COP23 must also make progress on providing finance to address loss and damage from climate change. "Inaction has gotten us to this point, but it's not too late yet to do what's needed to ensure a safe, just and dignified future for all," said Dr Bradshaw. "While it might sometimes seem like the odds are insurmountable, the brave determination of so many of our Pacific neighbours inspires us all; it's time for everyone to follow their lead and fight for our future." For interviews with report author Dr Simon Bradshaw, or more information, please contact Dylan Quinnell on 0450 668 350 or HYPERLINK dylanq@oxfam.org.au Photos Download photos here of the people Dr Bradshaw met in the Torres Strait Islands whose home and communities are being damaged by rising sea levels: HYPERLINK https://wordsandpictures.oxfam.org.au/?c=16590&k=0fc5fb76a6 https://wordsandpictures.oxfam.org.au/?c=16590&k=0fc5fb76a6 \~ http://www.medianet.com.au/releases/release-details.aspx/?id=888411 http://www.medianet.com.au/releases/release-details.aspx/?id=888411 SOURCE: Oxfam Australia \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia3" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="August 16, 2017 Wednesday"source="Brisbane News (Australia)" >
AN INCONVENIENT SEQUEL: TRUTH to POWER (PG) hhhkDirectors: Directors:Bonni Cohen, Jon Shenk Starring:Al Gore Running time:98 minutes More than a decade after Al Gore galvanised popular opinion on climate change in the strangely compelling documentary about his travelling slide show, he's back. While the message hasn't changed, the former US vice president's delivery has. There are times, in the sequel to An Inconvenient Truth, when he appears bruised and battle weary. "If I said there weren't times where this felt like a personal failure on my part, I'd be lying," he says in relation to the glacial pace of change. In Greenland, Gore walks over a melting ice cap. In Miami, he inspects submerged streets. The filmmakers also revisit a controversial prediction in the original film that a combination of sea-level rise and storm surge would flood the 9/11 memorial site, cutting to news footage of Hurricane Sandy doing exactly that in 2012. Gore works overtime, however, to balance what is shocking doomsday science with messages of hope and examples of practical optimism. In one segment, he visits Georgetown, Texas, a city that is powered by 90 per cent renewable energy. In the second half of the film there's a narrative arc, of sorts, that plays out against the backdrop of the 2015 United Nations Climate Change conference in Paris, where the filmmakers suggest Gore played a pivotal role in getting a hard-fought-for accord across the line. (The documentary was re-edited following US President Donald Trump's subsequent withdrawal from the Paris Agreement.)As a piece of filmmaking, Truth to Power is not as focused as its predecessor, but it feels very timely. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia4" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="July 21, 2017 Friday"source="Yass Tribune" >
The Yass Valley Council was one of the councils represented at the launch of the Cities Power Partnership in Canberra on Wednesday. Deputy Mayor Kim Turner took part on behalf of Yass Valley, and believes that it is crucial that local councils are the leaders in clean energy. "As far as I'm concerned, it's council's role basically to set the pace for the community," Cr Turner said. "If council doesn't show the example in the first place, you can't really expect private individuals to follow. "We have an opportunity in Yass, we've got an opportunity to look at certainly reducing our power costs through solar on the council chambers or the government buildings. "It would be very nice to encourage some of the businesses in town to take it up too. "We've got solar providers in town, the cost of batteries is coming down. I think it's the way of the future." The Partnership, created by the Climate Council, seeks to fast-forward Australia's plans to cut down on emissions by placing the onus on local councils instead of waiting for the Federal Government to act. The alliance between the 35 local governments will represent over three million Australians, and the Climate Council estimates that "cities, urban centres and rural townships have the potential to slash energy emissions by a staggering 70 per cent." ACT Environment Minister Shane Rattenbury attended the launch as well, and spoke about the discussions that took place during his trip to the United Nations Climate Change Conference in Marrakech in November last year. "What was very clear there [in Marrakech] was the important role that sub-national governments are playing," Minister Rattenbury said. "It was particularly interesting to see that it's very strong in the countries where our national governments have not taken the leadership. "Canada, the United States, and Australia were three countries where that sub-national leadership has been so important." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia5" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 19, 2017 Sunday 07:00 PM GMT"source="Canberra Times Online" >
The role of cities like Canberra in affecting progress against global warming has been considered in the latest United Nations climate talks, with experts welcoming "a groundswell" of innovation. World leaders including German Chancellor Angela Merkel, French President Emmanuel Macron and environment advocates gathered in the former German capital of Bonn last week for the 23rd conference for signatories to the UN Convention on Climate Change. University of Canberra chair of Urban and Regional Planning Barbara Norman said a key message from the talks had been how mayors, governors and regional leaders could work together to create large-scale change, boosting wider efforts on a national and international basis. Professor Norman said powering cities with 100 per cent renewable electricity, building integrated transport systems, designing green precincts and environmentally sustainable developments were key to meaningful progress. "Sustainable solutions such as these need green financing mechanisms and support from national governments if they are to deliver real outcomes on the ground," she said. "At COP 23 , the World Bank unveiled a new program designed to provide cities with a vehicle to raise necessary funding and investment, in partnership with private enterprise. "In one of the conference's key finance sessions, the former leader of the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change, Christiana Figueres, stressed that green finance will be the key to urban change, with a current industry target of $US1 trillion, and more in green bonds by 2020." In a piece for HYPERLINK https://theconversation.com/cop-23-three-ways-cities-are-leading-the-fight-against-climate-change-87277 The Conversation , Professor Norman wrote national governments should enable the coming wave of urban innovation to move forward, including through the Paris Agreement and UN Sustainable Development Goals. "While a few states may choose to ignore international agreements, this groundswell of collaborative action across businesses, governments and communities is sending a strong message that national governments would be wise to heed. "Embracing and investing in urban transformation that improves the health of people and the planet is clearly a winning strategy." Chair of the ACT Climate Change Council, she said Canberra stood out among cities involved in an international cooperation network, including because the territory was on track to achieve its target of 100 per cent renewable electricity by 2020. Environment Minister Josh Frydenberg and Foreign Minister Julie Bishop used Fiji's presidency of the conference to announce Australia would provide additional support to key climate initiatives in Pacific countries. Pleased to deliver our National Statement to HYPERLINK https://twitter.com/hashtag/COP23?src=hash&ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw # COP23 on our strong track record on reducing emissions, and our practical support for global action through initiatives like the Green Climate Fund and Blue Carbon Partnership \~ HYPERLINK https://t.co/GCTx6IoM4f pic.twitter.com/GCTx6IoM4f ??? Josh Frydenberg (@JoshFrydenberg) HYPERLINK https://twitter.com/JoshFrydenberg/status/931156850015330304 November 16, 2017 The ecosystems, which include mangroves, tidal marshes and sea grasses, capture carbon and help mitigate costal erosion. The federal government said Australia has committed to spend $300 million on climate change and resilience activities in countries in the Pacific Islands by 2020, including $75 million for disaster preparedness. HYPERLINK http://www.facebook.com/tcmcilroy Facebook and \~ HYPERLINK http://www.twitter.com/tommcilroy Twitter \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia6" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="October 20, 2017 Friday 11:03 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~As 10,000 people living on Vanuatu's island of Ambae wait to return home after the Manaro volcano threatened to erupt, there's already fears another natural disaster looming. \~\~ The Pacific islands, just like Australia's northern tropics, are about to enter cyclone season. \~\~ At the inaugural Pacific Week of Agriculture in Vanuatu's capital of Port Vila this week, it was highlighted that climate change is increasing the risk of damage by destructive winds. \~\~ Following on from Cyclone Pam in 2015 and Cyclone Winston in 2016, Mr Halavatau predicted the region will be "getting another one very soon". \~\~ "Climate change poses a threat to the very survival of the South Pacific nations," he said at the conference. \~\~ But there is another group working behind the scenes on preventative projects, some of which are aimed at reducing the impact of climate change and cyclone events. \~\~ ACIAR chief executive Andrew Campbell says several projects are targeted at lessening the damage caused by natural disasters, including better forecasting and the planting of more trees. \~\~ Prof Campbell says as well as providing a long-term investment for families, the trees stabilise the soil and stop erosion. \~\~ He predicts the Pacific island nations will use next month's United Nations Climate Change Conference to "amp up the pressure on the big countries" to increase global targets. \~\~ The Paris Agreement's aim to keep global warming to "well below two degrees" this century is not good enough for the region, Prof Campbell stressed. \~\~ "Two degrees won't be twice as bad as one degree it'll be more like 10 times as bad." \~\~ AAP travelled to Vanuatu with the support of the Crawford Fund. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia7" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="June 22, 2017 Thursday 11:16 AM AEST"source="MediaNet Press Release Wire" >
Mia Oenoto from Jakarta, Indonesia, is studying BSc Environmental Science at Xi£n Jiaotong-Liverpool University in Suzhou, China. HYPERLINK https://photos.prnasia.com/prnh/20170621/1881345-1 https://photos.prnasia.com/prnh/20170621/1881345-1 Mia's mother inspired her to focus on environmental issues "It's an interdisciplinary subject," she said, "I need to know about law, international relations, and science. It can be challenging, but I really enjoy it." Mia attended high school in Jakarta, the capital of Indonesia and a very densely populated city. She originally planned to study law or medicine at university, but became interested in environmental science through the influence of her mother. environmental science had been available as a major at the time she did her undergraduate degree, she definitely would have taken it." Mia's mother works as an accountant. She shared with Mia her love for the outdoors and her concern for environmental issues, giving her Al Gore's books on climate change when she was a teenager. "She asked me to read them to improve my English," she said, "I think the real reason was to raise my awareness about global warming. My mother encouraged me to think about the future and how I can contribute to it, not just to find a job and make money." In 2015, Mia represented XJTLU at the United Nations Climate Change Conference in Paris, France, where delegates from over 190 countries discussed reducing greenhouse gas emissions that pollute the air and contribute to global warming. She also delivered a Youth Climate Declaration to the international Conference of Youth held in advance of the main conference. It was Mia's mother who first gave her a brochure from XJTLU in which she read about the modules she would later go on to study as part of BSc Environmental Science. "We don't just read journal articles," said Mia, "We read the real documents that form the basis of agreements between countries about how to prevent climate change." "The Department incorporates a lot of different perspectives and collaborates she continued, "We've had guest lectures by academics from Urban Planning and Design and Architecture." Jiaotong University and the University of Liverpool. SOURCE\~\~Xi£n Jiaotong-Liverpool University Load-Date: \~June 22, 2017 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia8" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="June 10, 2017 Saturday"source="Bega District News" >
While President of the United States Donald Trump, has officially pulled his country out of the Paris climate agreement, a founding member of Clean Energy for Eternity says Australia must do more to meets its climate change targets. Philippa Rowland was in Paris during the 2015 United Nations Climate Change Conference . "One thing about [Donald] Trump pulling out is there is no doubt the US is a big emitter, so pulling out is not helpful," Ms Rowland said. "So far 195 countries signed up, and 146 have ratified. I think that speaks that climate change is no longer theoretical, it is a lived experience." She said while the move was an election promise, and "no secret in the Twittersphere", states have taken the slack and are setting their own targets. "There is a sense America has isolated itself. Though many states are following through despite his decision," she said. Ms Rowland made the trip as a member of the community delegation with UN accreditation through the Climate Action Network Australia. While Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull called the American president's decision "disappointing", Ms Rowland said "we have a shameful side of the coin ourselves". "Our Prime Minister made a deal with Adani, and that's in our home at the moment," she said. "There has been a knee-jerk reaction from government away from things that appear to have failed in the past such as a carbon price, and a move towards including gas and coal as clean energy. "2020 is less than three years away, it's outrageous." She said while the town of Tathra appears on track to meeting its 2020 target of reducing the town's power needs by 50 per cent, and generating half its energy needs from renewable sources, others are not so close. The motivation for the creation of the Clean Energy for Eternity group came about while local orthopedic surgeon Matthew Nott was sitting on Tathra Beach, reading Dr Tim Flannery's book The Weather Makers in scorching 40 degree heat. These days Dr Flannery is head of the Climate Council, and will be visiting Bega on Tuesday to host a forum alongside Bega Valley Shire mayor Kristy McBain on ways communities and councils can work together to combat climate change. Earlier this year council was just one of 15 councils invited by the Climate Council to participate in the Cities Power Partnership. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia9" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday 9:05 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~World leaders and environment ministers are arriving in Germany as the UN climate talks move into their more serious and political stage. \~\~ It?s expected COP23 president Fiji will end the talks with the significant victory of getting agreement on the design of the Talanoa dialogue - discussions throughout 2018 for the world to assess how it?s tracking on climate action and what more has to be done quickly. \~\~ The deadline for the rulebook's completion is next year?s conference so this is all that was really expected from 2017. \~\~ ?This building block is really about trust from developing countries to developed countries,? Greenpeace East Asia?s Li Shuo told reporters on Bonn on Tuesday, highlighting limited progress on the adaptation fund and financing, both of which would help poorer countries cope with climate change. \~\~ The decisions to come out of COP23 should open up concrete opportunities to look at how to help vulnerable countries bring down emissions in agriculture through sharing methods and solutions that had been found to work, she said. \~\~ Chief executive Peter Castellas said there had been good progress in deciding how the rules should be framed and the sector was also pleased Australian officials had taken on board its suggestions and reflected those during negotiations. \~\~ Mr Castellas said that was significant news for Australia and for the COP23 negotiations. \~\~ Environment Minister Josh Frydenberg is expected to make his statement on Thursday. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia10" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 13, 2017 Monday 7:24 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~Fiji has warned countries at the UN climate talks it is overseeing that they must put aside their differences and work together if the world is to limit climate change. \~\~ ?We are encouraging all parties to provide the political will necessary to achieve an ambitious outcome at COP23 , which includes of course the pre-2020 commitments and actions,? Fijian Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama told reporters in Bonn on Sunday. \~\~ Splits have developed at the COP23 talks during the past week over the inclusion on the formal agenda of discussions about lifting climate action ambitions before 2020, and over financing arrangements to help developing countries act on and adapt to climate change. \~\~ The European Union rejected this notion while Australia?s environment ambassador Patrick Suckling, speaking for developed countries outside Europe, said persistent efforts to add extra items to the COP agenda were ?hampering the very progress we are seeking?. \~\~ But he reminded parties the only way any one country could protect itself from climate change was by joining with all others and moving together. \~\~ ?No one is immune to climate change and we must focus not on our differences but on the absolute imperative to move this process forward.? \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia11" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="April 13, 2018 Friday"source="Herald Sun (Australia)" >
A GLOBETROTTING inner-city Greens councillor has been blasted over another overseas trip to be partly paid for by ratepayers. In June, ex-mayor of Yarra Amanda Stone will fly to Canada for an environmental and "urban sustainability" talkfest. That trip comes just seven months after her attendance at a United Nations climate change conference in Bonn, Germany, at a cost of $2250. As City of Yarra mayor last year, Cr Stone presided over the controversial decision to dump Australia Day, as a gesture to Aborigines. She will be a guest speaker at the International Council for Local Environmental Initiatives World Congress, to be held in Montreal from June 19-22. A report to council this week said the event would "spotlight local governments and their most successful initiatives, innovative polices and remarkable results in achieving urban sustainability". Cr Stone will pay half of the estimated $3732 cost of airfares and accommodation and conference and other expenses. In Bonn last year, Cr Stone told a seminar on low-carbon transport that "Melbourne was lagging behind the approaches taken in other cities worldwide" owing to its continuing reliance on cars. She posted several photos, including of a climate change protest and a shot of actor and ex-governor of California Arnold Schwarzenegger and former US vice president Al Gore at an art museum. Evan Mulholland, from free market think tank the Institute of Public Affairs, dubbed the trips ridiculous, especially as rates were higher than ever. "Victorians have had a gutful of Green-Left councillors across inner-city Melbourne using ratepayers' money to go on extravagant overseas trips just so they can come back and lecture us about the planet. "Australia contributes just 1.5\'e2\€  per cent to global greenhouse gas emissions," he said. "The area of Yarra City Council would be a tiny fraction of that, which means whatever the council does, it will make no noticeable difference to the world's climate. "Instead of spending money on overseas junkets, council should be looking at ways to save money and reduce costs." Greens Melbourne lord mayoral candidate Rohan Leppert has announced that if he won May's election, he would give up the mayoral car and ride his bike on city business. Last October, he jetted off on a 10-day "world cities" jaunt to Hamburg, Brussels and Barcelona that cost City of Melbourne ratepayers $7198. His Greens colleague, Cathy Oke, attended last Nov-ember's Bonn conference at a cost to council of $1133. Councillors are expected to approve her attendance in Montreal at a meeting next week. HYPERLINK mailto:john.masanauskas@news.com.au john.masanauskas@news.com.au GREEN WITH ENVY YARRA COUNCILLOR AMANDA STONE MONTREAL (CANADA) June 2018 BONN (GERMANY) November 2017 MELBOURNE COUNCILLOR CATHY OKE MONTREAL (CANADA) June 2018 proposed BONN (GERMANY) November 2017 MELBOURNE COUNCILLOR AND LORD MAYOR CANDIDATE ROHAN LEPPERT BARCELONA (SPAIN) HAMBURG (GERMANY) BRUSSELS (BELGIUM)October 2017 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia12" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 6, 2017 Monday 11:06 PM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~Fiji has launched the UN?s climate change conference with a plea for the world to do more to protect its most vulnerable people. \~\~ Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama - whose country holds the Conference of Parties ( COP23 ) presidency - said the need for urgency was obvious. \~\~ ?All over the world vast numbers of people are suffering, bewildered by the forces ranged against them,? he told the conference?s opening session in Bonn, citing destructive hurricanes, fires, floods and droughts. \~\~ ?This is our moment of truth when all of us in this room will be tested. We must not be found wanting. \~\~ The World Meteorological Organisation says the global temperature has already risen 1.1 degrees. \~\~ Secretary-general Petteri Taalas told the conference the latest science indicated that as things were now, the world was on track to warm by 3-5 degrees - well above the level considered acceptable - and the trend of increasing natural disasters would likely continue until the 2060s. \~\~ ?The message can not get any clearer; we no longer have the luxury of time, we must act now,? Patricia Espinosa said. \~\~ Environment Minister Josh Frydenberg and Ambassador for the Environment Patrick Suckling are leading Australia?s delegation to COP23 . \~\~ Fiji?s intention to use its presidency to focus attention on the Pacific region is expected to bring scrutiny to Australia?s actions both in cutting emissions and helping island nations mitigate and adapt to climate change. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia13" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 10, 2017 Friday 9:15 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~Amid the excitement of nearly 20,000 environmental campaigners gathered in one space, the world?s diplomats are getting on with the job. \~\~ The negotiations at the UN's COP23 climate conference are largely technical and slowly filling in details of the rules that will govern implementation of the 2015 Paris agreement. \~\~ But it?s never been anticipated those rules will be finalised - or even be more than a skeleton to be fleshed out over the next year - by the end of this two-week conference in Germany. \~\~ ?For the Fijian presidency, it?s a difficult year to demonstrate real celebration of progress when the Paris work program is expected to be delivered in 2018,? Ms Bardram told AAP in Bonn. \~\~ ?What we want and what we need is fairly clear; how to achieve it is really a matter of detail,? he told AAP. \~\~ One of the tensions is striking the right balance between making sure the rules are detailed enough to be useful but not excessively prescriptive - a point Australian officials have made in several sessions. \~\~ One of the key things COP23 is expected to achieve is a structure for the so-called facilitative dialogue, which the Fijians want to rename the Talanoa dialogue. \~\~ This is a year-long process to establish where countries are up to in working towards their Paris commitments, where they should be and how to get there. \~\~ Ms Bardram says the EU would see landing that - and making sure there is a specific time at the interim meeting in May where countries and stakeholders can share their progress - as ?a very significant deliverable? for COP23 and Fiji. \~\~ ?But again, it?s about perception and kind of pressure,? she says. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia14" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 6, 2017 Monday 3:30 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~Australia heads to the United Nations climate conference with its policy to cut emissions effectively in stasis and facing international pressure to do more. \~\~ Environment Minister Josh Frydenberg and Ambassador for the Environment Patrick Suckling will lead Australia?s delegation to the gathering, known as COP23 . \~\~ The meeting is the first of the global community since President Donald Trump announced he wanted to pull the US out of the landmark Paris agreement on climate change reached in 2015. \~\~ Fijian Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama has noted his region is already bearing the brunt of climate change. \~\~ Other Pacific nations, including Kiribati and Tuvalu, have been vocal about what they see as Australia?s inaction. COP23 . \~\~ ?But Australia?s emissions policies combined with the federal government subsidising Adani, big public debates saying we need more coal-fired power for longer - it?s really just rubbing the Pacific?s nose in it that Australia?s in no way even participating in climate action.? \~\~ Those recommendations will shape how Australia will achieve its Paris commitment of cutting emissions by 26-28 per cent on 2005 levels by 2030, a target Mr Frydenberg describes as "ambitious but responsible". \~\~ ?Australia is looking at going to these talks looking abysmal,? Mr Campbell said. \~\~ The same UN report did note Australia would meet its 2020 target from the Kyoto protocol - something Mr Frydenberg likes to highlight when asked how the country?s emissions are looking. \~\~ However, there is some unease at the way Australia?s climate policy has flip-flopped over the past decade depending on who holds power. \~\~ The official negotiations for COP23 will largely continue work on rules for implementing the Paris agreement, with the final rulebook expected to be agreed in 2018. \~\~ After Mr Trump?s announcement of the US withdrawal there will also be a strong focus on climate finance contributions. \~\~ Greens member of the European Parliament Claude Turmes says it?s vital to keep the conference on track to reassure developing countries. \~\~ ?EU is working with Canada and China to make it so Trump?s strategy to derail the Paris convention is not successful.? \~\~ Nevertheless, they still see the Paris agreement as the cornerstone of climate action and - with no other country following the US out and Nicaragua?s recent decision to join - believe it will hold. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia15" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 12, 2017 Sunday 9:21 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~American leaders say the US is getting on with the job of cutting emissions and may still achieve its reduction target despite President Donald Trump. COP23 \~\~ An unofficial coalition of American senators, state governors, mayors, business leaders and environmental groups has set up shop next to the conference venue in Bonn, highlighting the action they are taking to reduce emissions. \~\~ ?The American government may have pulled out of the Paris agreement, but the American people are committed to its goals and there is nothing Washington can do to stop us,? he said in Bonn on Saturday. \~\~ Fijian Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama, who holds the COP23 presidency, said it is a fantastic show of how progress could be made through the leadership of non-state actors. \~\~ ?We will continue measuring and reporting our progress on reducing emissions, just as every other nation has committed to do, so the world can hold the United States accountable for reaching our commitment,? he said, applauding efforts from Fiji to open up the negotiations to non-state actors. \~\~ ?This week we have seen the US as active as it used to be, as obstructive as it used to be,? Action Aid?s Harjeet Singh told reporters. \~\~ ?We thought that after facing a season of devastating hurricanes in the US, the government would be far more empathetic to the people and countries who are being battered by climate impacts, but we were wrong,? Mr Singh said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia16" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 12, 2017 Sunday 3:31 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~Environment Minister Josh Frydenberg will arrive at the UN climate conference in Germany next week keen to tout Australia?s leadership on land use and developing low-emission technologies. \~\~ But with significant Pacific Island representation at the conference he could find himself instead answering questions about Australia?s continued support of fossil fuels. \~\~ The word that?s muttered around side events at COP23 when Australia is mentioned? Adani. \~\~ Mr Tong has personally visited several banks in Australia and around the world to ask them not to finance the mega Adani mine in Queensland. \~\~ ?If it?s not fossil fuels, if it?s not coal, what else are you willing to put on the table in order to meet the commitments you have made?? he told AAP. \~\~ Ahead of travelling to Germany, Mr Frydenberg said Australia strongly supported Fiji?s presidency of the COP23 conference and the focus it has brought to the Pacific. \~\~ The beach they played on as a child that?s disappearing. The villages that have had to relocate or be flooded by rising seas. The massive devastation wreaked by more frequent storms, like 2016?s cyclone Winston that killed 44 people in Fiji. \~\~ Pacific Island Development Forum secretary general Francois Martel says there has to be a complete shift in thinking if the world is to act fast enough to substantially slow climate change. \~\~ ?We know that to reach the 1.5 degrees Celsius (limit on warming) we really need to keep the coal in the ground.? \~\~ He and Mr Tong are among those calling for a moratorium on new coal developments. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia17" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 17, 2017 Friday 9:24 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~Some of Australia?s closest allies are pushing for an end to coal power, increasing pressure on richer countries to do more to curb climate change. \~\~ One of Australia's neighbours says it seems only a change of governments will make the nation end its coal obsession. \~\~ New Zealand, the UK and Canada are among 20 countries which have signed up to the Global Alliance for Powering Past Coal, a surprise addition to the COP23 UN climate conference in Bonn, Germany on Thursday (local time). \~\~ UK?s conservative Climate Change Minister Claire Perry said reducing global coal consumption should be an urgent priority for all countries. \~\~ ?Unabated coal is the dirtiest, most polluting way of generating electricity,? she told the launch. \~\~ The alliance covers developed and developing countries, including some of Australia?s Pacific island neighbours who are especially vulnerable to the effects of climate change: COP23 president Fiji, the Marshall Islands, and Niue. \~\~ At an earlier event, President Hilda Heine said the country was very disappointed in Australia?s continued pursuit of coal mining and energy. \~\~ Greens MP Adam Bandt said the Turnbull government seemed to be getting Australia caught in a pincer movement and it was ?posing an existential threat to many of our neighbours?. \~\~ ?Each will do it in their own different way but that commitment suggests it?s now crossing party lines. \~\~ He pointed out the energy mix in those countries that had signed on was very different to Australia, with hydro in some cases and nuclear in others. \~\~ The government?s new energy policy is expected to lead to coal and gas combined making up nearly two-thirds of Australia?s power generation by 2030. \~\~ "Tens of thousands of Australians ... rely on our coal industry and it does help lift people out of energy poverty in other parts of the world and provides billions of dollars of export income to Australia," he told ABC radio. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia18" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 17, 2017 Friday"source="The Advertiser (Australia)" >
\'e2\- \~ THE 23rd Conference of the Parties to the United Nations Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) is the world's biggest climate change meeting. \'e2\- \~ The UNFCCC was adopted in 1992 at the Rio Earth Summit, which marked the beginning of the international community's first concerted effort to confront climate change. \'e2\- \~ Known also as the Rio Convention, the UNFCCC established a framework for action to stabilise concentrations of greenhouse gases in the earth's atmosphere. \'e2\- \~ The UNFCCC came into force in 1994, and nearly all of the world's nations - a total of 195 - have now signed on. \'e2\- \~ Each year the parties to the agreement convene to assess progress in implementing the convention and, more broadly, dealing with climate change. \'e2\- \~ In 1997, the participants established the Kyoto Protocol, which included legally binding obligations for developed countries to reduce greenhouse gas emissions. \'e2\- \~ In Paris in 2015, the parties negotiated what is known as the Paris Agreement, which established specific actions and targets for reducing greenhouse gases emissions and adapting to the effects of climate change globally. \'e2\- \~ Fiji is presiding over COP23 in Bonn with the support of the German government. The summit's principal aim is to track how each nation is tackling climate change.\'e2\- \~ US President Donald Trump attracted international criticism last year when he announced the USwas withdrawing from the Paris Agreement. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia19" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 14, 2017 Tuesday 11:56 AM GMT"source="The Age (Melbourne, Australia) - Online" >
London: Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg??? says his national energy guarantee could bring an end to Australia's acrimonious climate wars, despite South Australia declaring it will scuttle the idea when it is presented to a meeting of the nation's energy ministers later this month. Mr Frydenberg is attempting to introduce the guarantee, which will require energy retailers to have enough dispatchable power as well as meet emissions reductions targets to help Australia meets its international promise to reduce its carbon output by 26-28 per cent by 2030. But South Australian energy minister Tom Koutsantonis???, whose government will seek a record fifth term in office, has said SA "cannot support" the guarantee. "The reason is because at its core, it is an attack on renewable energy," he HYPERLINK http://reneweconomy.com.au/koutsantonis-slams-neg-says-it-is-an-attack-on-renewables-71267/ is reported to have told a conference in Adelaide . "It's not a national energy guarantee at all, it is a guarantee for coal. It is an attempt to subsidise and keep alive coal-fired generation in the largest state in country." But Mr Frydenberg, speaking in London, called on the state energy ministers to come to the Council of Australian Governments meeting with an "open mind." "We'll be taking modelling proposals to the COAG energy ministers meeting at the end of November," he said. "I would ask those ministers to come to that meeting with an open mind and have a healthy debate. We have a long way to go with this policy but certainly early responses from the states [have] been positive.. "Obviously [South Australian Premier] Jay Wetherill has different issues and a different agenda but I would hope that he and Tom Koutsantonis??? would see the merit in this proposal and would be happy to consider it in the context of energy pricing," he said. Round and round in circles? Earlier, Mr Frydenberg told an Australia-UK Chamber of Commerce breakfast gathering that the national energy guarantee proposal is the "simple piece of the [climate policy] jigsaw that has been missing for so long". "The NEG, representing the best advice of the energy experts, and a system which involves no taxes, no subsidies, no trading schemes and which meets the reliability requirements, and also the emissions reductions requirements and drives down prices at the same time, has been described for example by Bloomberg Energy Finance as a world-leading solution to a problem that is being faced by jurisdictions right around the world." But questions remain whether the government's solution would be sustainable given previous attempts to curb emissions, such as the carbon pollution reduction scheme introduced by former prime minister Julia Gillard, have all fallen victim to politics. "How do you see the politics lining up behind this or are we just going to go round and round in circles once again and find another solution with promise that ultimately fails?" one attendee asked. Mr Frydenberg singled out for praise his Labor opponent Mark Butler, whom he said he respected and was able to talk to in a "frank and bipartisan" way. "And I think they understand that this is the chance, this is the chance to end the so-called climate wars - in fact Mark wrote a book called Climate Wars," he said. Mr Frydenberg said his government's guarantee proposal has "near-unanimous" support from businesses and the energy sector. "I think the political debate has come a long way, I think people are tired of the argy-bargy that has gone on and I think when you see both supporting the NEG it does offer you an opportunity for a real breakthrough," he said. But Mr Butler has strongly criticised the guarantee as an "incredibly rushed job" that culminated in an "eight-page letter" that would take investment in clean energy backwards, as it does not lock in any commitments to either renewables or carbon reduction beyond 2030. "We are taking a pretty negative view of at least the underpinnings of the NEG so far," Mr Butler HYPERLINK http://reneweconomy.com.au/neg-a-rushed-job-that-takes-us-backwards-not-forwards-57932/ said in a recent speech "It doesn't mean we are opposed to the principle of bringing a stable investment scheme into the national energy market architecture combining emissions and dispatchability imperatives." On Tuesday Mr Frydenberg will represent Australia the United Nations climate change conference in Bonn, Germany which began on Monday. HYPERLINK https://www.facebook.com/LatikaMbourkeJournalist/ Follow Latika Bourke on Facebook \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia20" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="October 28, 2017 Saturday"source="Canberra Times (Australia)" >
Canberra's local politicians have spent more than $140,000 of taxpayer funds on travel since last year's election, including trips to Singapore, Britain, the US, Finland, Canada and Cook Islands. The latest official reports on backbenchers and ministerial travel, for the first six months of this year, have been tabled in the Legislative Assembly. While the figures exclude the costs of political and public service officials who may have joined the trips, the report, together with a previous report for the October-December period last year, show ACT politicians spent $141,731 on travel since the 2016 election. The total also excludes $20,799 worth of domestic and overseas trips taken by non-ministerial politicians during that period, to attend Commonwealth Parliamentary Association events, for which the association reimburses the Assembly. Chief Minister Andrew Barr outspent all his colleagues, at $35,446 since the election, while Health Minister Meegan Fitzharris spent $29,328, outspending senior colleague Deputy Chief Minister Yvette Berry by about $14,000. Since the election, Mr Barr has visited Sydney six times, Singapore twice, Hong Kong, Japan, Adelaide, Darwin, Hobart and Wellington in New Zealand, for meetings with interstate counterparts, an investment mission, an infrastructure speech and a leadership forum. The most expensive trip went to Ms Fitzharris, who as transport minister spent $24,255 to attend the UITP global transport summit in Montreal, Canada, followed by a "North American study tour", with airfares costing $8111 and combined accommodation and travel allowances of $16,143. Other notable overseas trips included Mr Barr's $12,754 investment mission to Singapore, Japan and Hong, and Ms Berry's $10,947 sojourn to "engage with international best practice in education and other portfolios" to Singapore and Finland, $7041 of which went on airfares. Greens leader and climate change minister Shane Rattenbury also spent some $7585 in November last year to attend the UN Conference on Climate Change in Marrakech, Morocco. ACT backbenchers spent a total of $56,832 on overseas and domestic trips, largely for CPA events and committee hearings, $36,032 of which was covered by taxpayers and the remainder reimbursed by the CPA. Top five spenders How much have our politicians spent on travel since the election? " Chief Minister Andrew Barr, who spent $35,446 (not including his current $43,000 US space trip) " Health Minister Meegan Fitzharris ($29,328) " Deputy Chief Minister Yvette Berry ($15,313) " Police Minister Mick Gentleman ($6,857) \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia21" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 18, 2017 Saturday 4:49 PM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~The world will gather in 2018 to work out exactly what must be done to limit warming to 1.5 degrees. \~\~ But talks dragged on into the early hours of Saturday morning with last minute arguments over developed countries' funding of poorer nations to meet their climate targets. \~\~ It might not have happened if not for Fiji?s creative, inclusive leadership, says Mohamed Adow, from Christian Aid, part of the Climate Action Network. \~\~ ?The switch for the Talanoa dialogue has been switched on and it?s now alive and it?s not static,? he told reporters at COP23 on Friday. \~\~ ?It?s going to help countries actually get back to the table over time to be able to help us achieve the Paris ambition.? \~\~ Australia also believes the presidency has done a good job with the design and winning all countries over. \~\~ It has posed three questions for the world to ponder. Where are we now? Where do we want to be? And how do we get there? \~\~ Tensions emerged in the first half of the conference over the desire of developing countries for a formal discussion of climate action before the Paris agreement starts in 2020. \~\~ But the Fijian efforts saw this resolved as leaders and minister arrived in Bonn on Wednesday, with early actions to mitigate climate change and support developing countries to do the same forming part of the Talanoa dialogue and being specifically assessed in 2018 and 2019. \~\~ ?Australia has already established ambitious targets and our goal is to meet and beat them, just as we did with the first Kyoto target,? he told AAP. \~\~ ?When other countries meet their targets early, they see it as a good thing and they then use that as an opportunity to consider ratcheting up their ambition in future years,? he told AAP. \~\~ Other wins for Fiji?s leadership were landing UN Climate?s first gender action plan and deciding how to include indigenous voices in the process. \~\~ ?The worst case would have been for this conference to end with just empty pages. This is not the case,? senior German official Jochen Flasbarth said. \~\~ However, tensions remain and the formal COP23 decision urges that work accelerate ahead of the 2018 deadline, a point underscored by several countries in their closing statements. \~\~ Notably, discussions on transparency around how richer countries would fund climate action in developing nations and the role of the adaptation fund in this occupied most of Friday, pushing negotiations well past their scheduled finish. \~\~ Many NGOs were also disappointed talks on compensation for loss and damage from climate change had been shunted to a side meeting in 2018, especially for a COP led by a Pacific island nation that is already feeling its harsh effects. \~\~ ?What Fiji and other vulnerable countries require more than anything are more ambitious emissions reduction commitments so they can avoid further losses and damages,? he said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia22" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 17, 2017 Friday 4:08 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~Snowy Hydro 2.0 has had its moment on the world stage. \~\~ ?Australia is committed to the Paris agreement and strong, meaningful international action on climate change,? the minister said in his official statement to COP23 in Bonn. \~\~ And Australia was ?making headway? on its 2030 commitment to reduce emissions by 26 to 28 per cent below 2005 levels. \~\~ ?Whether it?s large-scale wind and solar, battery development, demand- side response, or Snowy Hydro 2.0, the largest pumped hydro project in the southern hemisphere, we are harnessing new technology to create a better energy system,? he said. \~\~ Those rules had to offer clear guidelines for each country to set its emission reduction target and a strong transparency framework that would give the public confidence. \~\~ Mr Frydenberg welcomed the UN conference adopting its first gender action plan and deciding how to give indigenous people a voice during climate negotiations. \~\~ ?We welcome the progress made under your leadership, are pleased to see the increased pace of our work, and will continue to work hand in hand with you - in the spirit of Talanoa - to harness global momentum to deliver effective climate action.? \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia23" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 8, 2017 Wednesday 7:28 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~The influence of Fiji?s presidency permeates the UN climate conference in many ways - the canoe in the foyer, the kava ceremony at the opening, the efforts to build open debate in the Pacific?s Talanoa spirit. \~\~ But away from the official delegations and decorations, the influence and hopes of ordinary Fijians are manifested in Samuela Kuridrani and Alisi Rabukawaqa. \~\~ The pair have arrived in Germany - thanks to crowdfunding efforts largely from Australian Greenpeace supporters - to try and demystify the negotiations on behalf of their fledgling environmental group, Pacific Island Represent. \~\~ ?Most discussions are looking at 2020, 2050 and for us it?s happening now,? Ms Rabukawaqa said. \~\~ ?As far back as five years ago, that?s when the first village was relocated because of rising sea levels.? \~\~ ?We hope that?s not going to be the way forward, to keep adapting to it,? he told AAP. \~\~ However, they?re hopeful Fiji?s presidency of COP23 will make the world listen to the Pacific Islanders? message of urgency. \~\~ And their message to Australia? \~\~ ?Keep fossil fuels in the ground,? both say almost simultaneously. \~\~ ?And stop opening these coal mines because climate change is already here, we are experiencing it in the Pacific.? \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia24" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="October 2, 2017 Monday 08:03 PM GMT"source="AFR Online" >
China will launch a national emissions trading scheme (ETS) by the end of the year, joining major regional economies India and South Korea in putting a price on carbon and placing further long-term pressure on Australian coal exports. While the scope of the proposed trading scheme will be more modest than Beijing originally planned, it marks another major step in China's evolution from climate change laggard. Zhang Xiliang from Tsinghua University, who has advised the government on the scheme, said it would begin with power generators at the very minimum and be expanded to encompass eight key sectors by 2020, including steel making and aluminium. "We will launch the national emissions trading scheme this year," he told The Australian Financial Review. China's move comes as HYPERLINK the Turnbull government continues to tear itself apart on energy policy and as Australia's major regional trading partners move rapidly to reduce their reliance on fossil fuels. Coal is Australia's second biggest export to China, a trade worth $8 billion last year. HYPERLINK http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/budget-2016/industry/Union-Budget-2016-Govt-doubles-Clean-Energy-Cess-on-coal-to-Rs-400-per-tonne/articleshow/51191619.cms India doubled its coal tax to 400 rupees per tonne ($7.76) last year and its draft national electricity plan calls for a halt in construction of new coal-fired plants and an investment of more than $US300 billion in renewable energy capacity over the next decade. Philippines President Rodrigo Duterte has threatened to tear up the Paris climate change agreement but, despite this, is debating whether to introduce a coal tax of above $US10 a tonne. Peter Castellas, chief executive of the HYPERLINK http://carbonmarketinstitute.org/ Carbon Market Institute Aussie emissions in China's sights "[They will] sit directly in the supply chains of Chinese companies that will have a carbon price in this market" he said. "It's a significant change." While China has not set a date for launching its ETS, there is speculation it could provide an update around the time of the annual HYPERLINK http://newsroom.unfccc.int/cop-23-bonn/ United Nations HYPERLINK http://newsroom.unfccc.int/cop-23-bonn/ climate change conference HYPERLINK http://newsroom.unfccc.int/cop-23-bonn/ , which will take place from November 6 in Bonn , Germany. "This is a very large undertaking," says Li Shuo, senior climate and energy policy officer at Greenpeace China. "It's not easy from a tactical or a political point of view. There is a lot of data to collect and the quality of that data must be robust." Early last year, the HYPERLINK http://www.ieta.org/resources/China/Chinas_National_ETS_Implications_for_Carbon_Markets_and_Trade_ICTSD_March2016_Jeff_Swartz.pdf Chinese government identified eight sectors that would be covered by the scheme; petrochemicals, construction materials, chemicals, iron and steel, non-ferrous metals, pulp and paper, power generation and aviation. However, after concerns were raised about the economic impact on some of these industries, the list was whittled down to three for the scheme's start; power generators, cement and aluminium. The scheme is being overseen by the National Development Reform Commission (NDRC). It has been speculated the scheme will initially cover just the power generators with scope to be expanded over time. Twice the size of EU ETS Even if that's the case the China ETS will still be more than twice as large as the European Union's at the outset. "It is still uncertain how many sectors will be covered in the early stages but power generation will definitely be covered," said Mr Zhang, who is director at Tsinghua University's Institute of Energy, Environment and Economy, which is advising the NDRC on the scheme. Another source told the Financial Review the NDRC was ready to go with three sectors, but was waiting on approval from the State Council, China's cabinet and senior Communist Party leaders. A so-called "cap and trade" scheme works by the government placing a "cap" on annual emissions and then allowing companies which fall below their designated limit to sell permits, while those above the limit would need to buy permits. "By starting slowly [on the ETS], it suggests the NDRC is taking it very seriously and wants to make sure everything is well prepared," said Princeton Peng, chief executive of Climate Bridge, a firm running emissions reduction programs in China. "The most important thing is making it happen." Tim Buckley from the HYPERLINK http://ieefa.org/ Institute for Energy Economics and Financial Analysis in Sydney said the region was moving very quickly and Australia was once again getting left behind. "Australia's current energy policy position looks extremely untenable when viewed from the international perspective, particularly with respect to our key trade partners across Japan, South Korea, China, Taiwan and prospectively India," he said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia25" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="July 21, 2017"source="Bribie Weekly (Queensland)" >
YOUR WEEKLY SERVE with Bundaberg Fruit and Vegetable Growers THE Wide Bay Burnett is home to a wide range of agribusinesses supplying domestic and international markets with fresh and processed food products. Our subtropical climate provides the ideal opportunity for year-round growing of many commodities and windows of opportunity for some commodities that are traditionally grown at other times. Resilience and the ability to learn and adapt to changing climates is a regular trait of our growers and one which other regions are keen to learn from. This region has experienced its fair share of testing climatic conditions and the growers' ability to continue to provide exceptional produce through adversity is recognised. The region regularly plays host to visiting ministers and key delegates keen to connect with the community and Bundaberg Fruit and Vegetable Growers assists in developing our visitors' understanding and appreciation of the industry through farm visits and round-table discussions. Hosting our international guests provides an opportunity to learn from and share our methods and technology. This also ensures the export lines of communication are kept open as they get to see first-hand the safe, clean produce on farm that could be delivered to their door. Fiji's Minister for Agriculture, Rural and Maritime Development and National Disaster Management Inia Seruiratu, recently visited key agricultural businesses in Bundaberg to learn from our disaster resilience and management strategies. The Minister is also Fiji's high-level champion for COP23 , so was also focused on climate change issues. "What better business to showcase than a 365-day farming agribusiness that is leading the way in sweet potato production," BFVG's managing director Bree Grima said. Greensill Farming Group general manager Damien Botha agreed the ongoing challenge of mitigating risk was important in any business. "As a supplier of sweet potatoes all year round we continue to learn through knowledge sharing with industry partners and contacts. Meeting the Minister was a great chance to take that collaboration one step further," Mr Botha said. BFVG will continue to collaborate with the Department of Foreign Affairs and Trading to ensure this region is a priority for visiting ministers and businesses. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia26" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 8, 2017 Wednesday 7:10 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~The United States is becoming isolated in its opposition to international action on climate change and other countries, especially China, are stepping up to fill the gap. \~\~ The decision follows Nicaragua signing up a fortnight ago, prompted in part by US President Donald Trump?s June announcement he would seek to withdraw from the deal unless a better arrangement could be reached for America. \~\~ Meanwhile, China has been stepping up its role, after its Communist Party national congress in October for the first time formally declared the country a leader in global climate action. \~\~ But he said China has been working towards greater confidence in climate negotiations for some years. \~\~ "But that vacuum in fact solidified other countries' commitment to Paris and has propelled China, as well as other countries, towards filling that leadership gap." \~\~ Talks to establish the body started during last year?s UN conference, COP22 - when it became clear Mr Trump would win the US election - and it met for the first time in September with representatives from 34 nations, including Australia. \~\~ However, Mr Li said it still needed clarity around its mission. \~\~ A US delegation is attending the current climate talks and the Fijian COP23 presidency says it has been willing to engage and be constructive. \~\~ One, the University of Minnesota?s Ellen Anderson, said much could be done at state and city level to combat climate change. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia27" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday 8:24 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~Within hours of arriving at the UN climate talks in Germany Environment Minister Josh Frydenberg was handing out cash. \~\~ Blue carbon projects, such asreplanting mangroves and seagrass or protecting crops from storm surges, aim to improve coastal ecosystems. \~\~ ?If they are degraded, if they?re not preserved then the impact on our carbon footprint is very, very significant,? he told an event hosted by Fiji at the COP23 on Tuesday. \~\~ It?s also hoped that by having long-term monitoring of coastal environments communities will become more aware about the knock-on benefits, such as improved health of their fisheries. \~\~ He spoke of one project in Palau that aimed to find salt-resistant crops to help the community protect their agricultural sector from storm surges and sea-level rises. \~\~ ?While the community was quite happy about getting salt-resistant taro that they could grow, they could make $50 per crab,? Mr Ronneberg said. \~\~ It?s also hoped the injection of Australian money will lead to more private investment, something Fiji?s environment minister Aiyaz Sayed-Khaiyum said was crucial to ensuring long-term sustainability. \~\~ The minister said Australia looked to play a constructive role at international conferences and there would always be different arguments about our involvement in the coal industry. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia28" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 25, 2017 Saturday"source="Central Western Daily" >
For the past 23 years, representatives from participating countries across the globe have met under the United Nations Convention on Climate Change to discuss measures aimed at halting dangerous global warming. This year, the conference was held in Bonn, Germany from November 6 to 13. Known as ' COP23 ', it is especially significant, because it is through the Bonn conference that the rules are negotiated to put the Paris Agreement of 2015 into practice. The responsibilities of those involved in the development of the rulebook include setting the framework for the participating countries' pledges, reporting of adaptation efforts, setting the guidelines for the reporting of action at a global stocktake in 2023, and how to monitor compliance. Although America has been withdrawn from the Paris Agreement by President Donald Trump, there was present at the conference an alternative 'we are still in' delegation, consisting of a coalition of states, cities and businesses headed by former New York mayor Michael Bloomberg and California Governor Garry Brown. The group claimed to represent half of the US economy and was present at the conference to send a strong message that many US citizens are supportive of the Paris Agreement. A major event at the COP was the 'powering past coal alliance' led by the UK and Canada. More than 20 countries have joined the alliance so far, including Denmark, Finland, Italy, New Zealand, Ethiopia, the Marshall Islands and the US states of Washington and Oregon. The aim of the group is to phase out the use of coal by the year 2050, in accordance with research which states that this is necessary if we are to restrict global warming to less than two degrees above pre-industrial levels. Countries who are currently not signatories are Australia, India, China, Germany, Poland, and the US. Other major achievements of the conference have been the acknowledgement of the role of women in climate action, and the contribution that the ancient wisdom of first nation peoples throughout the world can make in climate change mitigation and adaptation. Although progress has been made in Bonn, we still have a long way to go if we are to be successful in dealing with dangerous climate change. Our global efforts to date indicate that our current climate trajectory places us in danger of exceeding the two degree danger zone. Australia lags behind most of the world, being placed 57th out of 60 countries on the Climate Change Performance Index. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia29" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 16, 2017 Thursday 9:11 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~Australia isn?t concerned about calls from one of Europe?s heavy hitters to halt trade deals with nations that have less ambitious climate targets. \~\~ ?We need a border tax in which we?ll make it possible for us to protect economic sectors as there are imports from countries who do not respect these goals and are not supporting the environmental transition.? \~\~ Environment Minister Josh Frydenberg said Australia - which has just started formal trade talks with the EU - was a great beneficiary of free trade. \~\~ ?We beat our first Kyoto target, we?re on track to beat our 2020 target and I?m confident we?ll meet and beat our 2030 target.? \~\~ The UN Environment Program?s emissions gap report agrees Australia is on track to beat its 2020 target, but says without further action it faces being at least 152 million tonnes above its 2030 emissions target. \~\~ The federal government is nearly finished a 12 month climate policy review, which Mr Frydenberg said was a good way to examine future requirements. \~\~ All countries are under pressure to increase their emissions targets and that urgency has been repeatedly expressed at the COP23 talks. \~\~ Mr Macron said it was especially important for developed countries to step up. \~\~ ?Rich countries have imposed on the world their universal values,? he said. \~\~ German chancellor Angela Merkel told the conference industrialised nations had an historical responsibility to cut emissions. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia30" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 11, 2017 Saturday 4:10 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~The UN climate negotiations are picking up pace after a sluggish start but an emerging split between developed and developing countries has some warning it could derail talks. \~\~ At issue is whether formal discussion of increasing action on climate change before the Paris agreement starts in 2020 should be included on the COP23 conference agenda. \~\~ The talks come with a sense of urgency as the impact of climate change is felt in destructive cyclones, floods, fires and droughts around the world and recent reports highlighting the gap between what emissions need to be cut and what countries? efforts to date will achieve. \~\~ Senior European Union official Elina Bardram says this point has been turned into a ?misperception that the EU or other countries don?t consider pre-2020 action very important? when they in fact do and are acting. \~\~ ?Whether introducing a new COP agenda item is the right way to go about it, that?s what we are not entirely convinced about.? \~\~ But Brazil - one of the countries pushing for a formal discussion - is dismayed by this. \~\~ ?Unless we advance very clearly in the tasks before us, the possibility of meeting the deadlines can be jeopardised,? he told reporters. \~\~ WWF?s global climate policy manager Fernanda Viana De Carvalho hoped the conference would find a way to have the discussion but also cautioned it was important developing countries not turn it into a finger-pointing exercise. \~\~ The problem can potentially arise in a few areas, including more than one country counting the same cut to emissions against their target. \~\~ ?Any trading system on emissions can only work if there is reliability and confidence on one tonne reduced here being equivalent to a tonne reduced there,? she said. \~\~ ?We are making it very clear ? the dangers, the risks of such moves in how much they could affect the capacity of developing countries to keep their ambitions or raise their ambitions,? Mr Marcondes said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia31" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 13, 2017 Monday 9:52 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~Fiji appears likely to finish the UN climate talks this week with an agreement on how a year-long discussion should take place that will convince countries to strengthen their emission targets. \~\~ That might not sound hugely exciting, but in the world of diplomacy it amounts to a significant win. \~\~ Fijian prime minister Frank Bainimarama, who holds the COP23 presidency, intends to announce the final design for what is now known as the Talanoa dialogue at the conference?s final session on Friday. \~\~ With the agreement coming into effect in 2020, the first such stocktake is set down for 2023. \~\~ A UN report released in October showed that the world is currently on track to warm by 3 degrees. \~\~ As Fiji holds the presidency from now until the COP24 in December 2018 when Poland assumes responsibility, it will oversee that process, which it wants to follow the Pacific tradition of ?talanoa?. \~\~ ?In order to achieve higher ambition ? we really need to have a very constructive conversation,? she told reporters. \~\~ Fiji?s proposal involves meetings next May for leaders, experts and environmental groups to discuss where the world is now, where it wants to go, and how it gets to that goal. \~\~ The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change expert scientific report on the impacts of 1.5 degrees warming, due next October, will also feed into the discussions. \~\~ Senior EU official Elina Bardram described it as a ?very significant deliverable? while environmental group WWF said it would leave Fiji with a good legacy. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia32" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 1, 2017 Wednesday"source="Sydney Morning Herald (Australia)" >
National pledges to cut carbon emissions fall well short of what's needed to avoid dangerous climate change, with Australia likely to miss its 2030 commitment by a wide margin, a United Nations body said. The UN Environment Program's Emissions Gap 2017 report found pledges to cut pollution made at the Paris climate summit two years ago are only about one-third of what's needed to be on a "least-cost pathway" to stopping the worst effects of climate change. The target is to stop global average temperatures rising 2 degrees or more above pre-industrial levels. Change on the scale is expected to cause major droughts, food shortages and damaging sea level rises. "There is an urgent need for accelerated short-term action and enhanced longer-term national ambition, if the goals of the Paris Agreement are to remain achievable," the report stated. The positive news is that global emissions have flatlined for the past three years, thanks in large part to a plateauing in China. Still, other potent greenhouse gases such as methane are rising, and carbon dioxide emissions could accelerate if global economic growth picks up. Frank Jotzo, a professor at the Australian National University's Crawford School and a contributor to the report, said tumbling costs of renewable energy and other low-carbon technologies suggest nations could increase their emissions cuts "and it won't be terribly hard". "More climate action and deeper commitments are needed, but it's eminently possible to achieve [the Paris climate goal] from the economic and technical perspective," he said. "It's the politics that get in the way." COP23 - that begins next week in Bonn, Germany. A new health and climate report by The Lancet, meanwhile, has found the number of vulnerable people exposed to heatwaves had increased by about 125 million from 2000 to 2016, with infants and the elderly especially at risk. Labour productivity among outdoor workers has also fallen by about 5 per cent since 2000, while the frequency of weather-related disasters jumped 46 per cent over the period, The Lancet said. The UNEP report, though, also named Australia as one of the G20 nations that "are likely to require further action" to achieve its 2030 goals. Australia's goal is to reduce 2005 emissions 26 to 28 per cent by 2030. The report noted government projections point to Australian emissions reaching 592 million tonnes of CO2-equivalent a year by 2030, compared with the targeted range of 429-440 MTCO2 needed by then. Independent analyses "confirm that the emissions are set to far exceed" the target, it said. Environment and Energy minister Josh Frydenberg has repeatedly stated the Turnbull government's "strong commitment" to the Paris accord, and it had a "suite of policies" to meet its 2030 goal. However, Labor's climate spokesman Mark Butler said Australia was on course for 2030 emissions to be in line with 2005 ones, implying no progress. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia33" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="June 2, 2017 Friday 6:23 PM AEST"source="ABC Premium News (Australia)" >
US President Donald Trump's decision to pull out of the Paris climate agreement is a selfish move that ignores the plight of low-lying island nations, Pacific leaders say. However they hope the fight against climate change will continue without American leadership. Anote Tong, the former president of Kiribati and one of the prominent Pacific voices during the Paris agreement negotiations, said while he was not surprised by Mr Trump's decision to withdraw, it was still deeply disappointing. "There was a lot of hope and expectation that he would change his view," Mr Tong told Pacific Beat. "The withdrawal I think has huge repercussions for something that's taken quite a long time to put together." He likened the withdrawal to the actions of a selfish bully. "It's pretty selfish, I think there's no other way to explain that," Mr Tong said. "In any classroom, there's always the bully, but hopefully there will always be somebody who will stand up against the bully." "But in this case, the one with the greatest capacity to ensure justice is served is in fact becoming the bully," he said. Mr Tong said Mr Trump's justification that the agreement would undermine the US economy and sovereignty are particularly galling to small Pacific island nations, that are on the frontline of the impacts of climate change. "On a global issue like climate change, there are no national borders. I think a lot of people are missing the point, including Mr Trump," Mr Tong said. "Climate change is not about the United States, it's about this planet, it's about our values as human beings." Climate change not 'negotiable' in the Pacific Fiji's Prime Minister, Frank Bainimarama, said the loss of America's leadership is unfortunate but the fight to rein in climate change will go on. Mr Bainimarama will serve as president of the UN climate talks - known as COP23 - in Bonn, Germany in November and in a statement said he will work to form a grand coalition. "I am also convinced that the United States Government will eventually re-join our struggle because the scientific evidence of man-made climate change is well understood," he said. "The issue is settled, the impacts are obvious and humankind ignores these facts at its peril." In a statement, Marshall Islands President Hilda Heine said the decision was highly concerning for her country, which has long believed in the importance of US global leadership. "Our children and their children deserve not only to survive but thrive," she said. "That is why the rest of the world remains firmly committed to the Paris Agreement, and our own commitment will never waiver." Mr Trump also said his administration would stop contributing to the UN's Green Climate Fund which provides funding and resources to help vulnerable countries adapt to the impacts of climate change. He said the US could potentially look to negotiate a new climate agreement, but Anote Tong said no Pacific island countries would be willing to go back to the negotiating table. "I think that's what we've been doing for too long, negotiating, because we regarded this as a negotiable issue, and it's not." "I don't know what the US really is worried about. They already have the largest share of the world's wealth, and here we are just trying to survive." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia34" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 17, 2017 Friday"source="Hobart Mercury (Australia)" >
Australia is at the forefront of numerous global initiatives THIS week, representatives of nearly 200 countries are gathered in Bonn, Germany, for COP23 , the major climate change conference of the year. While the corridors were filled with talk of the Trump Administration's decision to withdraw from the 2015 Paris Agreement, support for the agreement remains firm. About 170 countries ratified Paris and they represent more than 70 per cent of the world's emissions and GDP, and more than 80 per cent of the world's trade and population. Big emitters like China and India are at the table. While Australia's share of the carbon footprint is small at 1.3 per cent, we are highly active in these international meetings. Some of the initiatives that Australia is driving include: The Asia-Pacific Rainforest Partnership FORMED in Sydney in 2014, the partnership brings together leaders from government, private sector and civil society to implement policies that prevent deforestation and forest degradation. About one billion tonnes of C02 is released each year in our region as a result of deforestation and land degradation, nearly double the emissions Australia produces annually from every sector of the economy combined. Indonesia has agreed to host the 2018 partnership meeting and our two countries are working closely together. The International Partnership for Blue Carbon ANOTHER Australian initiative, this partnership strengthens co-operation between 20 formal members, including research bodies, intergovernmental organisations and governments themselves, to protect mangroves, tidal marshes and seagrasses. It's a little-known fact these water-based ecosystems can sequester up to four times as much carbon as a traditional land-based forest ecosystem. If degraded or destroyed, significant amounts of greenhouse gases are released, making their conservation critical. With Australia home to about 10 per cent of the world's blue carbon, our role leading this region-wide effort to build awareness of blue carbon and encourage inventory standards to report and manage it has been well received. Climate finance AUSTRALIA is co-chair with Saudi Arabia of the Green Climate Fund and has spearheaded the Climate Finance Roadmap with the United Kingdom. Both initiatives seek to leverage support from government and private sector for investment in emissions reduction technologies and measures to build climate change adaptation and resilience. Australia has committed at least $1 billion in climate finance over five years, including $300 million to projects working with our neighbours in the Pacific. Mission innovation AUSTRALIA is a member of a 21-nation group committed to doubling its investment in clean energy technology by 2020. This has particular resonance for Tasmania where the Turnbull Government is investing in projects such as a feasibility study into 2500MW of pumped hydro storage at 13 different sites, a University of Tasmania stocktake of the country's tidal energy resources and a smart grid project on Bruny Island. The work Australia's Clean Energy Finance Corporation and Renewable Energy Agency is doing on pumped hydro, including Snowy 2.0, battery storage and large-scale wind and solar has been acknowledged globally. There is interest in CSIRO's research into new hydrogen technology which involves using the power of the sun to store energy in hydrogen molecules. The COP will also be a good opportunity to outline the National Energy Guarantee. As I have found in discussions with my UK counterpart this week, Australia is not alone in facing reliability and affordability issues. The NEG offers an innovative approach to integrating climate and energy policy and is attracting significant interest. After a decade of partisanship and domestic disputes over climate change, Australians could be forgiven for being a little jaundiced over this issue. But against this backdrop Australians should know the Government is making a real difference at the international level.Josh Frydenberg is Australia's Minister for the Environment and Energy and is leading the Australian delegation in Bonn. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia35" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 14, 2017 Tuesday 11:21 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~Australia?s energy policy is a great example to the world, according to the US coal industry. \~\~ The Turnbull government?s national energy guarantee would return balance to energy developments, she said. \~\~ It had put high-efficiency coal and carbon capture and storage back in the discussion in Australia, where Peabody has nine mines. \~\~ ?They?re not giving up on their emissions goal but they are going to look at technologies that are affordable and that are reliable and can meet emissions.? \~\~ Peabody spokesman Vic Svec later told AAP financing and construction for coal power continued substantially around the world. \~\~ ?It is very healthy to see a true debate on the cost, reliability and benefits of those elements for Australia?s consumers.? \~\~ ?Coal will remain an important part of Australia?s energy mix along with gas, hydro, wind and solar in providing an affordable and reliable energy system,? he told AAP. \~\~ The COP23 \~\~ People queued for about two hours to get in amid tight security. \~\~ ?We see right through your greed, it?s killing all across the world for that coal money and we proudly stand up until you keep it in the ground,? went their adaptation of Lee Greenwood?s song God Bless the USA. \~\~ The final questioner demanded each presenter give a yes or no answer to whether they supported Mr Trump?s announcement he would pull the US out of the Paris deal for climate action. \~\~ US Energy Association head Barry Worthington said the deal wasn?t needed. \~\~ Mr Hochstein thanked those who stayed to hear them out. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia36" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 12, 2017 Sunday 9:10 AM AEST"source="AAP Newsfeed" >
\~\~Iran has delivered a blistering assessment of the world?s richest countries? performance during UN climate negotiations, accusing them of eroding trust and censoring developing nations. \~\~ ?So soon after the Paris agreement entered into force we are already seeing that trust and good faith being eroded by constant attempts to move away from prior agreements, solemn pledges and treaty obligations,? he said. \~\~ And in negotiations over finance, technology and building the capacity of nations to cut emissions, suggestions put forward by developing country blocs were ?immediately rejected outright by developed countries?. \~\~ ?Censoring other parties? views from being included into negotiating text as the basis of negotiations is clearly not in good faith.? \~\~ The Saturday evening session was designed as a mid- COP23 update on the various negotiation bodies that have been working on different aspects of implementing the Paris agreement. \~\~ While the chairs of each of the bodies generally gave the impression good progress was being made, almost all the country groups said they were disappointed or concerned about the slow pace. \~\~ This concern was echoed by Mali on behalf of African countries. \~\~ ?One component is still missing - not from (Fiji) but from our developed country parties - and that is the political will that is needed to engage constructively towards the highest priority of ensuring a balanced progress on all agenda items,? Ecuador official Walter Schuldt said. \~\~ Australian environment ambassador Patrick Suckling said its Umbrella Group of non-EU developed countries - including the US, Canada and New Zealand - was generally heartened that everyone at the negotiations wanted to see progress. \~\~ Tension has arisen over adding extra items to the official agenda, including a formal discussion about increasing pledges for action before the Paris deal starts in 2020. \~\~ The European Union said it did not recognise any lack of political will during negotiations and there was no disagreement about the urgency of pre-2020 action - only what form discussions should take. \~\~ It said there was no consensus yet but was convinced once could be reached. \~\~ ?These discussions need to take place now, not only on climate action but also on issues such as the adaptation fund, to build trust and ensure that vulnerable countries will get the help they need,? he told AAP. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia37" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="October 31, 2017 Tuesday 10:05 AM GMT"source="The Age (Melbourne, Australia) - Online" >
The level of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere rose by a record rate last year, reaching levels that have in the past been associated with global temperatures 2 to 3 degrees warmer and sea levels 10 to 20 metres higher than present, according to the World Meteorological Organization. The WMO released its HYPERLINK https://ane4bf-datap1.s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/wmocms/s3fs-public/ckeditor/files/GHG_Bulletin_13_EN_final_1_1.pdf?LGJNmHpwKkEG2Qw4mEQjdm6bWxgWAJHa annual Greenhouse Gas Bulletin Last year's increase was driven by human activities, such as burning of fossil fuels, and the strong El Nino event in the Pacific. "From the most-recent high resolution reconstructions from ice cores, it is possible to observe that changes in CO2 have never been as fast as in the past 150 years, and the natural ice-age changes in CO2 have always preceded corresponding temperature changes," the bulletin said, noting the rate of increase was almost 100 times faster than at the end of the last ice age. The release of the annual data comes just a week before the 23rd UN Climate Change Conference ( COP23 The meeting will provide an update on progress of the Paris Climate accord in 2015 and identify gaps between national pledges to cut emissions and the target of keeping global warming to less than 2 degrees above pre-industrial levels. President Donald Trump has vowed to pull the US out of the agreement although any exit cannot take place for several years. The Turnbull government is due to complete its review of climate policies by the end of 2017. Rising emissions from most sectors - including a resurgence in carbon releases from land clearing - are likely to show Australia will have to do much more to meet its Paris promise of reducing 2005 levels of pollution by 26-28 per cent by 2030. The WMO noted current CO2 levels were last reached during the mid-Pliocene era. At that time, Greenland and West Antarctic ice sheets had melted, lifting sea levels by as much as 20 metres from current levels. The WMO said CO2 levels are now 145 per cent higher than the rate in 1750. The 3.3 ppm increase last year was about 50 per cent faster than the average rate of 2.21 ppm over the past decade. Methane, a more potent greenhouse gas than CO2, had increased even faster since 1750, rising 257 per cent since then to 1853 parts per billion in the atmosphere. It increased 9 ppb last year, and while less than the increase in 2015, the rise was much higher than the average 6.8 ppb annual increase over the past decade. The added greenhouse gas levels mean the so-called radiative forcing - the warming effect on the climate - has risen 40 per cent since 1990, according to the US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). Last year alone, the forcing rose 2.5 per cent. "Without rapid cuts in CO2 and other greenhouse gas emissions, we will be heading for dangerous temperature increases by the end of this century, well above the target set by the Paris climate change agreement," WMO Secretary-General Petteri Taalas??? said in a statement. "Future generations will inherit a much more inhospitable planet, " he said. Global temperature records were broken each year from 2014 to 2016, as the El Nino event combined with background warming. With conditions tilting towards the opposite pattern in the Pacific - a La Nina - 2017 is likely to be marginally cooler than last year but still be second or third warmest on record, NOAA estimated last month. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia38" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 9, 2017 Thursday 03:13 PM GMT"source="Canberra Times Online" >
Deutsche Bank has developed a tool to forecast where its investments across the globe may be impacted by natural disasters brought on by climate change. Although tools have existed in the insurance industry to model the impact of climate change, this is the first time this sort of data has been systematically applied to investments. Deutsche Asset Management created the map with climate change intelligence firm Four Twenty Seven, covering more than one million individual locations in order to see how changes to climate will threaten its investment portfolios. The group currently has about ???711 billion ($1.06 trillion) under management. Economic modelling estimates that if carbon emissions aren't reduced throughout this century, per capita GDP will decrease by 23 per cent from what it otherwise would be. "The effects of climate change will be ubiquitous but uneven, ranging from those that disrupt daily life, such as damaged or flooded infrastructure, to more gradual impacts like declines in labour productivity and widespread threats to global welfare through decreased crop yields," Four Twenty Seven stated. Deutsche Bank said the development of this tool meant that exposure to catastrophic events for individual companies can now be calculated. "It tackles physical risk head-on, giving credible insight into the vulnerability of corporate production and retail sites to climate change. Factors such as sea level rise, droughts, flooding and cyclones pose an immediate and measurable threat to investment portfolios," Deutsche Bank Asset Management said. These issues have already been seen in Australia, where heatwaves have caused spikes in power prices, directly impacting business operating costs. Energy price shocks are the number one concern for Australian businesses, according to a global survey. The World Economic Forum Global Risks 2018 report, published by Zurich Insurance Group and Marsh and McLennan companies, surveyed more than 12,400 executives from 136 countries, and HYPERLINK http://www.smh.com.au/business/energy/energy-prices-top-risk-for-australian-business-says-global-survey-20171005-gyv5co.html put energy pricing as the leading concern for businesses operating in Australia within the next 10 years. Australia was the only country to rank energy costs as its major concern, and the only other nation apart from Canada to include adapting to climate change within its top five risks. Climate change will wreak economic havoc, greatly reducing nations' GDPs. Illustration: Marshall Burke, Solomon M. Hsiang & Edward Miguel, Nature 527 Deutsche Asset Management calculates the impact of climate change by categorising an investment's location, its activity and business sensitivity to climate hazards. It then applies Four Twenty Seven's climate science models to provide asset-level risk assessments by calculating the potential disruption to operations, supply chain and logistics, and market risks. It can also provide climate risk modelling at a country level. "The data can be analysed, for example, to look at how rising sea levels could affect coastal and offshore oil and gas infrastructure, how floods could disrupt supply chains, or whether extreme heat affects labour productivity in the agricultural and construction sectors," Deutsche Bank Asset Management said. Early research has pinpointed Asia as highly vulnerable, stating that 80 per cent of people occupying the most £t risk' climate zones globally reside in Asia, with 145 million people in China alone living on land threatened by rising seas. "The availability of this new data on physical climate risk is a major step forward to addressing a serious and growing risk for investors," said Nicolas Moreau, head of Deutsche Asset Management. "Climate risk is now centre stage, however, we believe the investment industry needs to champion the disclosure of annual and once-in-a-lifetime climate risks by companies. We have a duty to understand what more hurricanes or heatwaves mean for valuations and investment returns," he said. According to Four Twenty Seven, the next step for this modelling will be the development of corporate resilience indicators, which "constitute the next frontier to gain a more comprehensive and nuanced understanding of all facets of company vulnerability to climate change". The release of the project comes as nations meet to address climate change and carbon emissions at the COP23 climate conference in Bonn, Germany. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia39" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 17, 2017 Friday"source="The Advertiser (Australia)" >
Environment Minister Josh Frydenberg is in Germany for a key international conference on climate change. Here, he explains what Australia is doing to help combat the global problem. REPRESENTATIVES of nearly 200 countries have gathered in Bonn for COP23 , the major climate change conference of the year. While the corridors will no doubt be filled with talk of the Trump Administration's decision to withdraw from Paris, support for the agreement remains firm. In record time, around 170 countries have ratified Paris. Collectively they represent more than 70 per cent of the world's emissions and GDP and more than 80 per cent of the world's trade and population. Big emitters like China and India are at the table. Some of the initiatives that Australia is driving include the Asia-Pacific Rainforest Partnership, which brings together leaders from government, the private sector and civil society to implement policies that prevent deforestation and forest degradation. To put it in perspective, about one billion tonnes of CO2 are released each year in our region as a result of deforestation and land degradation. This is nearly double the amount of emissions Australia produces annually from every sector of its economy combined. Indonesia has agreed to host the 2018 partnership meeting. Our two countries are working closely together on capacity building, verification methods and enhancing private sector financing opportunities to support concrete outcomes in this important area. Second, the International Partnership for Blue Carbon. Another Australian initiative, this partnership strengthens cooperation between 20 formal members, including research bodies, intergovernmental organisations and governments themselves, to protect mangroves, tidal marshes and seagrasses. It's a little known fact that these water-based ecosystems can sequester up to four times as much carbon as a traditional land-based forest ecosystem. If degraded or destroyed, significant amounts of greenhouse gases are released, making their conservation critical to the emissions management effort. With Australia home to about 10 per cent of the world's blue carbon, our role leading this regional-wide effort to build awareness of blue carbon and encourage inventory standards to report and manage it has been well received. Third, climate finance. Australia is co-chair with Saudi Arabia the Green Climate Fund and has spearheaded the Climate Finance Roadmap with the United Kingdom. Both initiatives, the Fund and the Roadmap, seek to leverage support from government and the private sector for investment in emissions reduction technologies and measures to build climate change adaptation and resilience. Australia itself has committed at least $1 billion in climate finance over five years, including $300 million to projects working with our neighbours in the Pacific. Fourth, mission innovation. Australia is a member of a 21-nation grouping that is committed to double its investment in clean energy technology by 2020. Already a leader in the field, Australia has much to gain from sharing experiences and knowhow with other countries. This has particular resonance for South Australia, where the Turnbull Government has invested in a range of innovative new projects such as the virtual power plant in Adelaide which links 1000 premises with solar and storage, a $30 million battery project on the Yorke Peninsula and a pumped hydro feasibility study at Cultana. No one country needs to reinvent the wheel or to confine the application of their technology successes to their own domain. To the contrary, reducing emissions is a global effort and must be done at lowest cost which can only be achieved through technology transfer. The work Australia's Clean Energy Finance Corporation and Renewable Energy Agency are doing around pumped hydro, including Snowy 2.0, battery storage and large scale wind and solar has been acknowledged globally. The COP will also be a good opportunity to outline the recently announced National Energy Guarantee (NEG). As I have found in discussions with my UK counterpart earlier this week, Australia is not alone in facing reliability and affordability issues in the energy sector. The NEG offers an innovative approach to integrating climate and energy policy and in doing so is attracting significant interest. After a decade of partisanship and domestic disputes over climate change, Australians could be forgiven for being a little jaundiced over this issue.But against this backdrop Australians should know there Government is making a real difference at the international level, leading a number of new innovative initiatives which are supporting our neighbours and contributing to the global climate change effort. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia40" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 2, 2017 Thursday"source="The Australian" >
The Minerals Council of Australia has slammed the UN's environment arm over its decision to block the nuclear -industry from the organisation's upcoming clean energy forum. The Australian revealed on Tuesday that the UN Environmental Program had vetoed the World Nuclear Association's proposed sponsorship of next month's Sustainable Innovation Forum in Bonn, Germany, prompting accusations of institutionalised bias within the UN group. Daniel Zavattiero, the council's executive director of uranium, said the decision was "surprising" given other bodies within the UN - including the Intergovernmental Panel on -Climate Change - had found nuclear energy had an important role to play in reducing greenhouse gas emissions. Mr Zavattiero noted that a growing number of environmental campaigners were starting to support greater use of nuclear energy, given its ability to generate large dispatchable volumes of energy with little to no associated carbon emissions. "To exclude nuclear from the Sustainable Innovation Forum undermines its credibility, particularly in light of increasing calls from environmentalists and conservationists for green groups to reconsider their opposition to nuclear energy," Mr Zavattiero said. He noted the IPCC had previously found in 2014 that the world would need more intensive use of technologies such as renewables, nuclear and carbon capture and storage if it was to achieve deep cuts in emissions. "Achieving this collaboration will not be assisted by the decision to exclude the World -Nuclear Association." Next month's forum takes place on the sidelines of the UN's COP 23 climate change conference, where government representatives from around the world will discuss progress towards meeting international emission-reduction targets. The forum will be hosted in the purpose-built Climate -Action Dome, which itself will be powered by energy generated using food waste from the conference.The forum's approved sponsors include BMW and Toyota - responsible for a large portion of the world's petrol- and diesel-powered vehicles - as well as utilities such as Orsted, which continue to own coal-fired power plants. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia41" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 6, 2017 Monday 07:44:01 GMT"source="Crikey" >
ABSTRACT Good morning, early birds. FULL TEXT LEAKS FROM PARADISE A new investigation published and distributed by the International Consortium of Investigative Journalists (ICIJ) has revealed a network of hidden investments and offshoring used by wealthy politicians, businesspeople and celebrities to minimise tax and cover up compromising financial relationships. The so-called Paradise Papers, released today, were uncovered by German newspaper Suddeutsche Zeitung and have been shared with papers including HYPERLINK http://www.afr.com/news/paradise-papers-offshore-leak-exposes-donald-trumps-russia-links-20171102-gze0p8 The Australian Financial Review The Guardian , and The New York Times Among the first people unmasked by the disclosure of over 13 million files from 19 tax havens is Donald Trump 's Commerce Secretary Wilbur Ross , who owns a stake in a shipping company discreetly doing business with a Russian gas company part-owned by Vladimir Putin 's son-in-law\~ Kirill Shamalov . Ross has kept his share in the company since joining Trump's cabinet. The files also show that Russian-backed companies have quietly invested in Facebook and Twitter, that HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/news/2017/nov/05/justin-trudeau-adviser-stephen-bronfman-offshore-paradise-papers a close adviser to Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau has hidden millions in an offshore haven, and that the personal estate of the Queen of England has \~ HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/news/2017/nov/05/revealed-queen-private-estate-invested-offshore-paradise-papers invested in a company LIBERAL 'BASTARDS' WHACKED The fallout from the section 44 constitutional crisis continues to fuel a public spat between the two parties of the Coalition, with Nationals Senator John "Wacka" Williams https://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/politics/victoria/citizenship-saga-batters-pm-as-nats-prepare-to-battle-libs-over-senate-job-20171105-gzf7i2.html lashing out at Liberal MPs for backgrounding the media as he seeks to replace Stephen Parry as Senate president. "You bloody cowards," Williams said. "Put your name to it you bastards." With Senator Ian Macdonald \~reportedly interested in the gig as well, there is HYPERLINK speculation Labor and the Greens could help roll the Liberals and put Williams in the post. That would be less likely if Liberals David Bushby or David Fawcett put their hands up to replace Parry, who resigned from parliament last week. The citizenship issue continues to dog the government, with Labor now pushing for a universal disclosure from all MPs. Over the weekend it was\~Assistant Immigration Minister Alex Hawke's turn to face suspicion, though government sources told Fairfax they are confident he is not a dual citizen. "I am an Australian citizen only and have never held or acquired or sought Greek or any other citizenship," Hawke said. ARDERN REBUFFED, FOR NOW Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull \~has HYPERLINK http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-11-05/turnbull-wont-accept-nz-offer-to-resettle-refugees-at-this-time/9120028 rejected an offer from New Zealand's Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern\~ to resettle 150 refugees from offshore detention centres. Around 600 men continue to hold out in the officially closed, shuttered centre on Manus Island, where utilities have been turned off. But Turnbull, who met with Ardern over the weekend, said Australia would prioritise its deal with the US for resettlement, leaving the door open to changing his position by saying he would not take up Ardern's offer "at this time". Labor is encouraging the government to say "yes" to the proposal, while Greens MPs Adam Bandt \~accused Immigration Minister Peter Dutton of being a "terrorist" at a rally over the weekend. Backbencher and ally\~ Kevin Andrews has also encouraged the government to look to the New Zealand option. READ ALL ABOUT IT\~ HYPERLINK http://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/questions-hang-over-senate-replacement-hollie-hughes/news-story/b29a34661210bc75b314891983a9f95e Questions hang over senate replacement Hollie Hughes HYPERLINK http://www.smh.com.au/business/energy/negs-ability-to-cut-energy-costs-divides-analysts-20171102-gzdoo8.html NEG's ability to cut energy costs divides analysts HYPERLINK http://www.smh.com.au/business/mining-and-resources/oil-hits-more-than-us62-a-barrel-20171104-gzf0nc.html Petrol prices to spike as oil hits two-year highs HYPERLINK http://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/queensland-election-2017-premier-says-adani-veto-shows-leadership/news-story/dcd0cc5b89db3a326bb81156cdbd49d2 Queensland election 2017: Premier says Adani veto shows leadership WHAT'S ON TODAY : Mark McGowan's WA Labor government will hold a community cabinet. Canberra : The Australian Electoral Commission holds its special count to replace senators ruled ineligible under section 44 of the constitution. Brisbane : The man charged over an alleged assault on \~godson after a dispute about same-sex marriage faces court. Germany : 2017 COP23 Climate Change Conference begins. THE COMMENTARIAT HYPERLINK http://www.afr.com/opinion/columnists/dualcitizenship-fiasco-is-flaying-malcolm-turnbulls-government-alive-20171105-gzf18w Dual-citizenship fiasco is flaying Malcolm Turnbull's government alive \~-- Jennifer Hewett ( Australian Financial Review $): "Despite the reluctance of the government to give in to a 'witch-hunt' and the practical difficulties of an audit of citizenship that can only be determined by the High Court, it's hard to see how Turnbull can withstand this sort of daily assault to do something, anything, to resolve the problem." HYPERLINK http://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/queensland-election/queensland-election-2017-adani-decision-demands-answers/news-story/c14805b1eacc2cde929785ea19d2bcb1 Queensland election 2017: Adani decision demands answers \~-- Sarah Elks ( The Australian $):\~"Instead of absenting herself from any decision about every Northern Australia Infrastructure Fund applicant, she unilaterally made the biggest decision of them all: torpedoing possible NAIF funding to Adani." HYPERLINK https://www.crikey.com.au/2017/11/03/we-are-now-numb-to-a-government-that-has-normalised-chaos/ We are now numb to a government that has normalised chaos \~-- Bernard Keane: "A little like the way Trump has normalised all manner of sickening and bizarre behaviour in US politics, we've become numbed by repetition to the incompetence of this government.\~" HYPERLINK https://www.crikey.com.au/feature/holy-wars-australian-targets-attacks-enemies/#the-war-against-yassmin-abdel-magied The war against the female Muslim agitator Yassmin Abdel-Magied -- Emily Watkins: "The paper hounded the ABC about whether she would be sacked, covered her talk to students at a Sydney Writers' Festival event, and launched a barrage of criticism against her July\~op-ed in\~Guardian Australia\~about her experience in the public eye." HYPERLINK https://www.crikey.com.au/2017/11/03/is-the-actu-telling-the-whole-truth-about-a-living-wage/ Is the ACTU telling the whole truth about a 'living wage'? \~-- Charlie Lewis: "Reforms put in place by federal Labor in 1993, basically at the behest of the ACTU, moved the minimum wage to a safety net role and put more emphasis on enterprise bargaining in setting wages." \~ \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia42" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 14, 2017 Tuesday"source="The Cairns Post (Australia)" >
Yes why isn't #StopAdani the big issue when #Qldvotes @TheCairnsPost @JoshFrydenberg @TurnbullMalcolm @TimNichollsMP Queensland's future depends on a healthy reef #keepitintgeground # COP23 @Jackthelad1947 @TheCairnsPost editorial: "People don't trust Canberra because it looks like a game where keeping power is more important than anything else." @osbornep We depend on our planet for everything. # COP23 #StopAdani #ClimateAction #Qldvotes #CoralnotCoal @TheCairnsPost@StopAdaniCairns \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia43" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 28, 2017 Tuesday"source="The Australian" >
Politicians will not do anything about global warming Say one thing about Australia's dawdle towards an agreed energy policy: it's matching the pace of the global process. A few days before the COAG Energy Council met last week to put off agreeing to the government's National Energy Guarantee, the latest UNFCCC conference of parties ( COP23 ) wound up in Bonn with a similar outcome. Not that either Hobart or Bonn were failures - far from it! Energy Minister Josh Frydenberg put out a press release on Friday that the Turnbull government welcomed the decision to do "further design work" on the National Energy Guarantee. And the Bonn talks were always meant to take steps towards implementing the agreement at COP21 in Paris two years ago, when almost all countries on earth agreed to do their best to reduce global warming to less than 2 degrees, sometime soon. The US announced this year that it was going to pull out of the whole thing but hasn't actually done so yet. US delegates did turn up in Bonn, and used a side event to try to sell the benefits of coal and nuclear energy, which went down like a uranium balloon by all accounts. Anyway, negotiations on the Paris "Rulebook" are now meant to take place in 2018 in the lead up to COP24 in Poland at the end of next year and something called the Talanoa Dialogue was set up to discuss the contributions that parties would submit to carbon abatement by 2020. Not make mind, submit. The reason it's all got a bit slow is money. In Paris, $US100 billion was agreed to be paid by developed nations to developing ones to help meet their targets. But with the US out, everyone else will have to pay more, a lot more. China is moving swiftly to fill the global moral leadership vacuum on combating global warming, but there's no sign yet of them making the switch from developing to developed nation and coughing up cash rather than receiving it. Meanwhile in Hobart, COAG met to consider the Turnbull government's proposal for the National Energy Guarantee (NEG), submitted by the Energy Security Board (ESB) to replace the chief scientist's Clean Energy Target (CET). As discussed here previously, the CET had the wrong name to get through the Coalition party rooms - the word "clean" was never going to fly. When the ESB replaced "clean" with "national" and "target" with "guarantee", the Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull and Frydenberg fell on it with a glad cry and held it aloft as the shining solution. But alas Labor is still against it. Between the CET - which Labor would go along with - and the NEG - which the Coalition's right-wingers will cop - there is little difference in reality but a vast gulf in politics, which, as we know, is not reality. In Hobart, past grievances and alliances were on the table in plain sight. The Labor governments of SA and ACT voted against, the Liberal governments of NSW and Tasmania voted for, Queensland had no government at all at that point so it didn't vote and Victoria said it was open to finding out more about it. So in the end, Victoria won - they're going to find out more, or do more design work, or something. Most of the modelling done so far shows that the NEG will do absolutely nothing either to bring down emissions, enhance security or reduce energy prices, and the price reductions predicted with a rhetorical flourish by Frydenberg last week were apparently due to the Renewable Energy Target, not the NEG, which was a bit awkward. It seems the "further design work" agreed upon by COAG in Hobart will mainly be needed to ensure that the NEG is actually neutral in its impact and doesn't make emissions and security worse rather than better, in which case it will be back to square one, since Turnbull's political opponents on both sides will have every excuse to gleefully knock it back. The way things are going, Australia's first bipartisan energy policy might be ready to go by the time the Paris Rulebook is finalised in 2020. Or maybe not. Overall, it's becoming clear that action on climate change is the last thing any politician wants to take, and the focus of all political work on the matter is to appear to be doing something, without doing anything. The reason for this is not hard to find: earlier this year Nobel-prize winning economist Joseph Stiglitz and former World Bank chief economist Nicholas Stern said that the only way to prevent catastrophic global warming would be to tax carbon dioxide at $40-$80 per tonne by 2020, and up to $100 by 2030. That sort of carbon tax would increase the prices of fossil fuel energy so much that the world would very quickly dump oil and coal in favour of wind, solar and batteries. Thankfully, renewables are now cheap enough that there wouldn't be a global recession as a result, but coal and oil-rich countries like Australia would definitely lose big. Meanwhile the UN's World Meteorological Organisation said last week that 2017 is the hottest on record and that the concentration of greenhouse gases is the highest in 800,000 years, thanks partly to a big increase in methane because of fracking in the US and the growth in livestock numbers. And scientists are now increasingly coming out and saying that the impact of global warming will be far worse than thought. So thank goodness the whole thing is a Marxist conspiracy by those scientists and their fellow travellers, otherwise the fact that politicians are on a deliberate go-slow in dealing with it might be a serious problem.Alan Kohler is the publisher ofThe Constant Investor. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia44" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 17, 2017"source="South Burnett Times and Rural Weekly (Queensland)" >
AUSTRALIA has strengthened its role in the global shift to decarbonised transport, following an announcement at the UN Climate Change Conference that a program to replace fossil fuels with low-emission biofuels is expanding across three continents. The Queensland Renewable Fuels Association (QRFA) joined the World Business Council for Sustainable Development (WBCSD) at COP23 in Bonn, Germany for the announcement that regional hubs for below50 - an initiative accelerating the transition to low-carbon fuels with half the greenhouse gas emissions - will begin operating in Australia, North America and South America. In a first for the Australian biofuels sector, QRFA was invited to join in the UN climate summit after signing an agreement with WBCSD at Montreal, Canada in July to host the inaugural regional hub. " COP23 has provided a unique opportunity for us to tap the international expertise and investment available to rapidly boost Australia's production, use and export of below50 fuels," QFRA founder and managing director Larissa Rose said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia45" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 15, 2017 Wednesday 3:36 PM  EST"source="Australian Government News" >
Barton, ACT, Nov. 15 -- Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade issued the following news release: This week during Fiji's COP23 Presidency, Australia will provide additional support to key climate initiatives to help Pacific countries mitigate and adapt to climate change and meet their climate goals. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:content.services@htlive.com content.services@htlive.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia46" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="October 31, 2017 Tuesday"source="The Australian" >
The United Nations has blocked the nuclear industry from participating in an international forum on clean energy, sparking accusations of institutional bias within the global body. The London-based World Nuclear Association was originally accepted by the organisers of next month's Sustainable Innovation Forum as a \'c2\£340,000 ($68,340) gold sponsor, but the deal was -rescinded a week later after intervention by the UN environment program. The organisers then offered a watered-down sponsorship that would include no branding presence, but that deal was also vetoed by UNEP. David Hess, communications manager and policy analyst with the WNA, said the group had hoped the conference could be the start of a "mature conversation" about the role nuclear energy could play in supporting the transition to a zero-emissions world. He said the group was very disappointed to be excluded. "We certainly weren't expecting UNEP to transform overnight or change its messaging or come out in support of nuclear energy, but we did want to make the outreach as part of a high-level environmental discussion," Mr Hess told The Australian. "We thought we'd make a breakthrough and thought we'd be there, but it turned out we were subjected to the bias that we had wondered whether it existed in the first place." Next month's forum takes place on the sidelines of the UN's COP 23 climate change conference, where government representatives from around the world will meet to discuss progress towards meeting international emission-reduction targets. The Sustainable Innovation Forum will be hosted in the purpose-built Climate Action Dome, which itself will be powered by energy generated using food waste from the conference. The forum's approved sponsors include BMW and Toyota - responsible for a large portion of the world's petrol- and diesel-powered vehicles - as well as utilities such as Orsted which continue to own coal-fired power plants. Last year's sponsors included German utility Vattenfall, which generates much of its electricity from coal. Mr Hess said nuclear energy was one of the few realistic solutions to the UN's competing goals of decarbonising the world while also lifting more than a billion people out of energy poverty. "How are you supposed to seriously address these really complicated problems when you completely ignore or exclude a major low-carbon, low-land-footprint energy technology from the equation? It just doesn't make sense but this is what we see taking place, because a lot of these high-level policy bodies seem to be afraid of backlash. They seem to be afraid of the attention that would be generated by green groups. They need to be able to talk about this seriously." Nays\'c3\£1n Sahba, a spokesman for UNEP, said that within the UN system the environment arm deferred to the International Atomic Energy Agency on nuclear issues. "We prioritise the renewables revolution, such as wind and solar energy, as well as encouraging the ongoing shift from fossil fuel," Mr Sahba said. "Our work on the nuclear sector is limited." Ben Heard, an energy researcher with the University of Adelaide and an advocate for the climate benefits of nuclear energy, described the UN's intervention as "frightening" and an example of "outright prejudice". "This family of technologies has been the principal source of carbon-free energy for the last four decades. Along with hydro-electricity, they have been the two big hitters that have actually delivered, and you're running a climate change conference and you won't let the representatives of that industry through the door," he said."For me it's gobsmacking to see this. I'm an advocate for this technology on environmental grounds but it struggles, and part of the reason is time after time it faces this kind of institutional bias which means no-one can even have a conversation about it." \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia47" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="November 16, 2017 Thursday"source="The Advertiser (Australia)" >
THE Turnbull Government will spruik its new energy policy on the global stage at the pre-eminent climate change conference being held in Germany this week. Environment Minister Josh Frydenberg has landed in Bonn for COP 23 and said it would be a good opportunity to outline National Energy Guarantee to his international counterparts. "As I have found in discussions with my UK counterpart earlier this week, Australia is not alone in facing reliability and affordability issues in the energy sector," he said. "The NEG offers an innovative approach to integrating climate and energy policy and in doing so is attracting significant interest." The Government hopes state ministers will sign up to the NEG at a meeting of the nation's energy ministers later this month.Mr Frydenberg said he expected Australia to continue to show leadership in tackling climate change. It had initiated the Asia-Pacific Rainforest Partnership and International Partnership for Blue Carbon to protect vulnerable habitats. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP23_Australia48" COP="COP23" country="Australia" date="October 4, 2017 Wednesday"source="ABC Transcripts (Australia) Background Briefing 12:24 PM AEST" >
Hagar Cohen : In a nondescript building a few minutes' drive from downtown Suva is the headquarters of the current affairs publication, Islands Business . It has a tiny team of journalists. One of them, Nanise Volau, is on a particularly controversial assignment. Nanise Volau : We're going to call Mr Sitiveni Qiliho, he's the Commissioner for Police. And we'll try and get some information on the case regarding the 77 Chinese nationals that were deported last month. Hagar Cohen : She's working on the same story that Background Briefing covered last week. We revealed details of a secretive operation to deport 77 alleged Chinese criminals, who the Chinese government claimed were 'fraud suspects' who took part in illegal internet gambling. But locals on the ground disputed these claims and told us the majority of the deportees were teenage girls and we understand that the girls were brought into Fiji as sex workers. For journalist Nanise Volau in Fiji, asking questions about this case is contentious. Nanise Volau Islands Business magazine. I'm hoping to arrange an interview with you regarding the issues of the 77 Chinese nationals. We're not allowed to speak to you? Is there any other recent development to that case? No. Okay. Thank you so much sir. [Hangs up] They are not speaking. They are not doing any investigations and they're not going to speak to anybody. The only statement they issued, that's it for now. Okay, let's try immigration. : The immigration spokesperson didn't pick up the phone. This journalist's unsuccessful attempts at getting any kind of information about China's secret operation isn't unusual. It's part of how Fijians were kept in the dark about what actually happened. But last week Background Briefing revealed extraordinary new information. Aman Ravindra Singh : I received a phone call from my client and he said, 'There is a policeman from China in uniform, together with the Fiji police, they're here right now, standing outside my home.' And I was totally shocked and in disbelief as to how police from China were operating within the Fijian jurisdiction. Biman Prasad : The questions I raised, why the secrecy? How do we know that they were criminals? I mean, unless we have a very clearly explained narrative, with evidence of what happened and why this was allowed to happen, these questions will remain. Aman Ravindra Singh : For mighty China to come and march its policemen up and down the streets of Fiji, this was so unreal, almost like there had been an invasion of our jurisdiction. Hagar Cohen : This week, Background Briefing is going to take you into the secret world of geopolitical PR machinations. We will reveal documents and hear from two former permanent secretaries in the Bainimarama government who will describe exactly how the public service and the media in Fiji are being controlled. And why almost no one in the media in Fiji investigated the Chinese deportation story. Netani Rika : What is of concern about this story is what little attention has been paid to it by the local media. Hagar Cohen : Netani Rika is one of the most respected journalists in Fiji, with close to 30 years' experience. He reckons there's a lot more in this story still to be discovered. Netani Rika : It would be uncomfortable for some people in Fiji if it became known what these people were actually doing here, and how they came in in the first place, and how they were able to stay longer than their tourist visas allowed them. Hagar Cohen : So what do you think they actually did in this country? Netani Rika : I think there has to be a link to prostitution, and that is one of the angles that we are pursuing at this time. We don't expect too much help from police in this matter, so it could become quite a drawn-out affair. Hagar Cohen : But you're not giving up? Netani Rika : No, one must never give up. Hagar Cohen newspaper. He refused to buckle to the almighty government censors. Once, instead of running an edition full of heavily censored stories, Rika published a blank newspaper edition. He says he wanted the public to know their right to information was under attack. Netani Rika : Of course the paper came out the next day with a lot of blank spaces. That really set them off. We played a bounded pushing game I suppose from then until November 2010. They put a lot of pressure on people. Hagar Cohen : It was a risky game. Rika says he became a target. Netani Rika : There were a number of incidents: there's the stoning of my home and my car, and the attempt to burn the home, there's three separate incidents. Abusive phone calls from the Prime Minister, being sworn at, and detention. Hagar Cohen : He recounts how in 2009 his team were investigating a number of sensitive stories about Commodore Bainimarama, now the Prime Minister, including the Commodore's purchase of a house. The paper also published critical opinion letters about the military rule. Rika alleges that Bainimarama threatened him to stop publishing these stories, or else: Netani Rika : The words in English would be, 'Do you want to put an end to this or do you want me to end it for you?' Hagar Cohen : And what did you say? Netani Rika : I said that he was entitled to his opinion and that we will run his views if he wanted to, whereupon he swore at me. Hagar Cohen : He swore at you? What did he say? Netani Rika Hagar Cohen : The Prime Minister? Netani Rika : Yes. Hagar Cohen : The next day, Netani Rika says his car was smashed. No link has been established between the two incidents. Netani Rika : Of course complaint was made to the police after that incident. Hagar Cohen : You complained to police? Netani Rika : Yes. I made a complaint to the police, and the officers who came and took the statement said, 'You know this is not going to go anywhere.' I said, 'Well, all that aside, let's just follow the process and see where it goes.' Of course seven years later I'm still waiting for any outcome from the police. Hagar Cohen : has contacted the office of the Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama and Fijian police for a response, but we've received no comment. In 2006, when he was head of the military, Commodore Frank Bainimarama overthrew the democratically elected government of Laisenia Qarase. Journalist [archival] : It had been threatening for weeks and this evening it was declared Fiji's fourth coup. Frank Bainimarama [archival] : As of six o'clock this evening the military has taken over the government, has executive authority and the running of this country... Hagar Cohen : At that time it was common for journalists to be detained and beaten. Today, the suppression of the media is slightly more subtle. : I think there's still this latent fear of being dealt with by the military. But for others it's not that so much, but people are afraid of losing their government assignments, their work with government companies, they are just afraid of being blackened or tarred by the government in any way because that's going to affect their incomes, their jobs, they could be blacklisted, they could be investigated. Hagar Cohen : This is Richard Naidu. Richard Naidu : I'm a former journalist, so I've been around the media scene for quite a long time in Fiji. I've advised over the last 20 years various media organisations. I'd probably say that I don't think I've ever seen the media at quite such a low ebb as it is now. Hagar Cohen : Naidu is Fiji's most respected human rights lawyer. His opposition to the coup even got him into trouble with the military, and let's just say he's lucky to be alive. Naidu is a partner with Munro Leys legal firm in Suva, and he's represented the Fiji Times newspaper in its many legal stoushes with the government. Naidu says prosecuting journalists became much easier in 2010 when a draconian media decree was introduced. Richard Naidu : If you look at particularly perfidious provisions in the media decree such as Section 22 which criminalises the reporting of anything which is against the national interest, for example. That's a classic. We've managed to put the whole of what in Australia would be understood as the media code, a voluntary set of rules that people comply with, that's been made law now. So for example, it's the law that you must report in a balanced way. Now, how on earth can that be the law? Because to say that you must report in a balanced way is of course an aspiration, and it's one that all media should try to achieve, but to suddenly say it's the law that you report in a balanced way well, who enforces the law? Of course every news media organisation is effectively chilled by those provisions, their lawyers advise them to take extreme care to ensure that they stay on the right side of those laws, which means that there are a whole lot of areas that are just no-go zones for journalists. Hagar Cohen : So the main interpretation that I've seen is, for instance, if an event has happened that involves a government department and criticism of that government department, unless the journalist receives on-the-record statements from that particular department, without this statement their reporting won't be balanced and therefore they are not allowed by law to publish this article. Is that right? Richard Naidu : Well, that's not my view of it. My view of it is that balance is fine if you deliver a balancing view the following day, for example, or in another story. But it's not so much what people like me think, it's more what media organisations are advised, including by the government, of what the government thinks is balanced. Generally speaking, the media here do not want to get offside with the authorities, notwithstanding that in many cases it's the media's job to be offside with the authorities. Hagar Cohen : Two years after these strict media laws were introduced, the Bainimarama government in Fiji engaged one of the world's most influential media and lobbying companies to manage the press. That American multinational company is Qorvis. Its clients have included Saudi Arabia in the wake of the 9/11 attacks, Bahrain, Kurdistan part of Iraq, and Sri Lanka. In the recent budget paper it was disclosed that Fiji paid Qorvis an annual fee of 1 million Fijian dollars. On the face of it, this is normal practice for many governments around the world. But according to documents obtained by , Qorvis has an unprecedented amount of control and power in its dealings with the Fijian public service and the media. Qorvis promotional video : At Qorvis MSLGroup we've prepared executives, ambassadors and even Nobel laureates for media appearances. In our state-of-the-art studio we help our clients prepare for their television, radio, or print interview. Hagar Cohen : An ad from the Qorvis YouTube channel spruiks the company's worldwide credentials. : Our training focuses on understanding one's role as a newsmaker, how to hone messages to make them more compelling for an audience. We show clients how to deliver those messages... Hagar Cohen : A Qorvis consultant in Fiji is Graham Davis, who was born in Fiji but lived and worked for many years as a TV journalist in Australia. His Qorvis job started in 2012 and his role is hands-on. Last year, Graham Davis complained to the editor the Fiji Sun newspaper, Peter Lomas, about his editorial decision-making in the Coconut Wireless column. In April 2016, Lomas included in the paper sarcastic commentary about human rights lawyer, Richard Naidu. Reading : Vinaka, Richard Naidu, that lawyer of many tweets, good humour and close association with the opposition. Vinaka, Richard Naidu, and yes, we do know where Pyongyang is. Good to see you still reading the Bigger, Brighter, Better paper first thing. Hagar Cohen : The column prompted this harsh email response from Graham Davis, who asked Lomas not to make Richard Naidu a martyr, something the Fijian government was concerned about. Reading : Seriously, why is this allowed in the paper at all? Who benefits from these sneering, petty ad hominem attacks on the government's opponents? Because they elicit sympathy for them and contempt for the attacker. And they are giving Richard Naidu constant fodder to persuade his 1,411 followers on Twitter that he's relevant, when he's not. If the idea is that it's helpful to the government, believe me nothing could be further from the truth. Deeply concerned about the feedback I'm getting generally around town about the Sun . 'Zero credibility', 'rag', 'cocksucker', is the general drift. Sorry to be brutal, but it's the truth. I explained many months ago that the paper is only helpful to the government if it retains its credibility. Hagar Cohen : CC'd in the email is Ewan Perrin, until recently one of the most senior public servants in Bainimarama's administration, and an Australian expat. He left his job in Fiji abruptly last year, so I gave him a call. So look, we're recording, but it's a pre-recording... Ewan Perrin : It's not live. You'll... Hagar Cohen : Exactly. Ewan Perrin : My name is Ewan Perrin. I was the Permanent Secretary for the Fiji Department of Information and Communications, Ministry of Information and Communications, from February to May 2016. Hagar Cohen : So that's a period of about four months, isn't it? Ewan Perrin : Yes. I actually counted it, it was 100 days. : Before he left, his job was to manage all government communications. Ewan Perrin : The Permanent Secretary's role is to provide oversight, guidance, efficient running of all aspects of the department. Hagar Cohen : Perrin is no longer living in Fiji. He's decided to blow the whistle on how Qorvis manages the media and the public service. Ewan Perrin : It was very clear to me that Qorvis calls the shots on all government communications. : Why do you say that? Ewan Perrin : There was an instance where a letter had been drafted by Qorvis, so I was instructed to sign the letter, and hand-deliver it to the editor and publisher of the Fiji Times . Hagar Cohen : Who were you instructed to do that by? Ewan Perrin : The head of Qorvis in Fiji, with the Attorney General's approval. Hagar Cohen : That's Graham Davis. Ewan Perrin : That's right. Hagar Cohen : Did you have any part in drafting that particular letter? Ewan Perrin : No, I did not draft it, and I was not involved in any discussion about the topic, and I was not expected to do anything except sign that letter and deliver it. : The controversy centred on what Graham Davis said were unfounded allegations that Prime Minister Bainimarama plagiarised a recent speech. The Fiji Times wrote a story about the speech, pointing out the similarities to another speech given by an official in the United States. But the newspaper did not allege plagiarism. Nevertheless, Davis accused the Fiji Times of making up false accusations: Reading : The has clearly set out to wilfully mislead its readers and damage the Prime Minister's credibility. I request an immediate retraction of this story and the publication of a prominent apology. Hagar Cohen : Ewan Perrin says even though he didn't write the email, he was expected to deliver it to the editor of the Fiji Times under his own signature. Graham Davis wrote to him in the email that the Attorney General had approved it. Reading : The AG has approved this and has asked that you send it both by email and hand-delivered to Hanks Arts as soon as possible this afternoon. Cheers. Hagar Cohen : But Ewan Perrin didn't do that. He fought back. Ewan Perrin : I didn't agree ethically with the content and the tone of the letter, I made a decision at the time that it was more important that I maintain my standards, high standards of integrity, to act without fear or favour, and to actually escalate the issue to the highest level of government, to see if we could actually resolve it in some other way, rather than just...I was feeling like I would just become a lackey, I would have no value really, and I would compromise my own integrity as well. Hagar Cohen : So you were...there was an attempt by Qorvis to control you as well? Ewan Perrin : Yes, yes, and I don't think it was about personally controlling me, it was controlling the position of the Permanent Secretary. That particular instance was part of a pattern that had been started emerging, which was the Permanent Secretary was not being treated as a respected advisor to the minister. The Permanent Secretary was 'sign the document, make the statement, and don't bother trying to think about anything or contributing to the discussion'. Hagar Cohen : Perrin says the expectation to follow instructions blindly made him particularly uncomfortable. It had happened before, when the office of the Solicitor General asked him to sign a sworn affidavit in court without even reading it. Ewan Perrin : And I wasn't expected to read it, and I wasn't expected to have any input into it, and I was also not expected to have read other documents that I was swearing that I had already read. And again, I pushed back there I said, look, I'm not going to sign this until I've read it, and I'm not going to sign it and say that I've read this other document until I've read that one too, so go and get it. So they went all over town to find these documents, and they also had to keep the High Court open for an extra half an hour so that they could actually get the signed affidavit in on the closing date. Hagar Cohen : That is extraordinary. Ewan Perrin : It is extraordinary. Hagar Cohen Ewan Perrin : Yes, very much do as you're told. Hagar Cohen : But the alleged plagiarism issue with the was the last straw. Ewan Perrin : Yes. I did take that up with the Attorney General, and interestingly he just refused to speak to me for the next two or three weeks. And then I went back to Graham Davis, who kind of exploded and had a heart attack over the phone, and sort of started shouting and ranting at me. Hagar Cohen : What did he say? Ewan Perrin : He was quite insulting, I mean, he was obviously quite wound up, and he was quite insulting. I can't recall the exact...I can recall some things, but I'm not going to share some of those words on public radio. : Perrin says he was sacked and had to leave. After he left, he says the role of the Permanent Secretary wasn't advertised, and a number of key communications positions were staffed by relatives of the Prime Minister and the Attorney General. Ewan Perrin : What they have done is they've put an Acting Director of Information, which is the Prime Minister's daughter, and the man who runs the newsroom is the Prime Minister's nephew. And the man who runs the national broadcaster is the Attorney General's brother. Some of these people are quite talented, but again, there is no transparency in terms of some of these appointments. You can call it nepotism or cronyism or whatever you want to call it, but it's unhealthy. Hagar Cohen : The Prime Minister's daughter is no longer in that position. Ewan Perrin says he is very concerned about journalists in Fiji, in particular the suppression of freedom of speech. He says there are serious and immediate consequences for people who refuse to toe the line. Ewan Perrin : Foreign journalists are often banned from returning to Fiji, and local journalists are moved on or suspended or transferred out of more sensitive jobs as well. Hagar Cohen : Are you aware of a particular media blacklist of journalists? Ewan Perrin : In my conversations with Graham Davis over the time, there was a consistent...I wouldn't call it an official blacklist but there are media organisations and individual journalists who I was encouraged not to speak with, including ABC, particularly Pacific Beat , but also, Fiji Times , and also Radio New Zealand. Hagar Cohen : Right, so if you were still in government and I gave you a call, you wouldn't be able to talk to me? Ewan Perrin : I would be expected to politely decline. Hagar Cohen : I see. Would that apply to all government officials and ministers? Ewan Perrin : Yes, yes, it does. Hagar Cohen : Despite a number of warnings about the government's disdain for answering questions, I decide to track down the Attorney General in the capital Suva, to see whether he might do an interview. I find him at the opening session of a human rights training workshop for local journalists, put on by the United Nations. Its subject: 'Reporting Human Rights'. In his speech, the Attorney General Aiyaz Sayed-Khaiyum lectures local journalists about their reporting. He urges them to be more sceptical in their reporting of human rights violations, rather than simply reporting them. During his speech he suddenly points his finger at me and talks about my employer, the ABC, and our understanding in Australia about the complexities around reporting human rights. At the end of his speech, the Attorney General stops for a chit chat with UN officials. I politely request to have a word with him, but I'm stopped by one of his legal advisors. Legal advisor Hagar Cohen It's one of my numerous attempts at getting any government official to talk. But I'm not allowed to go anywhere near the Attorney General, not even to introduce myself. He doesn't want to talk to me at all? Legal advisor : Yes, sorry. Hagar Cohen : Because I feel awkward, he has referred to me in his speech. Just to say hello and who I am, that's all, I promise I'm not going to ask any questions. Political advisor : Sorry, he said he won't do the interview. Hagar Cohen : A few minutes later, I meet the Attorney General. Aiyaz Sayed-Khaiyum : Like 'Hagar' as in Hagar the Horrible...? Hagar Cohen : No, 'Hagar' as in the Old Testament Hagar. After explaining the origins of my name, I ask for an interview. So he asks what did I want to talk about. Aiyaz Sayed-Khaiyum : What do you want to talk about? Hagar Cohen : About reporting human rights. : By the ABC? Hagar Cohen : No, by Fiji media. Aiyaz Sayed-Khaiyum : I'd love to do an interview about how the ABC misreports human rights in Fiji. Hagar Cohen : Okay, you tell me about it... Aiyaz Sayed-Khaiyum : Send us your questions. How long are you here for? Hagar Cohen : Until Thursday. Aiyaz Sayed-Khaiyum : Send us your questions...thank you. Hagar Cohen : I email my questions to his minder and ask for an interview, but my request is declined. In the two months I've been working on this Fiji investigation, no government official agreed to be interviewed. One of the questions I wanted to put to them is about an email from October 2016 which was leaked to Background Briefing . It was addressed to the Attorney General by Qorvis consultant Graham Davis. In it Davis advises the Attorney General not to trust Australia in its negotiations with Britain over the military training of Fiji forces. Britain had been supplying this training and, according to the Graham Davis email, Australia and New Zealand had asked for this to cease. In this email, Davis urges the Attorney General to keep a watchful eye on Australia and New Zealand. Reading : There's evidence that they are still trying to undermine Fiji. The attitude towards Australia and New Zealand to Fiji hasn't changed and they are doing what they can to derail our engagement with Britain. Telling Britain not to support capacity building in the police is particularly damaging. They keep saying our institutions are weak but then do everything they can to undermine them. We need to keep a wary eye on them. : Two hours after receiving it, the Attorney General forwards this advice to the Prime Minister. Robin Nair : Hello, my name is Robin Nair. My career in government is a bit long and very unusual. Hagar Cohen Robin Nair : By 2008 I was appointed by his Excellency the President as one of the three members of the independent monitoring group. Hagar Cohen : In this role, Robin Nair helped form the basic structures that would help Fiji transition from military rule and into a democratic government. Later in April 2016, as a trusted public servant, he was appointed as Permanent Secretary of the Department of Foreign Affairs in Suva. It was then that he says he developed a close relationship with the Prime Minister Bainimarama. Robin Nair : I felt quite secure in that respect. Fiji is politically very charged, and from time to time I continued to get hostility from some quarters and undermining and so on, and the Prime Minster knew about this and he used to reassure me that I had his confidence and that he was backing me fully in my decisions. Hagar Cohen : But only months into his new role, Nair says things went sour. He says it became impossible for him to provide frank and honest advice. He quit his job in May this year, and returned to Australia. His resignation made big headlines. Journalist [archival] : A former senior public servant in Fiji says there's a climate of fear in his country ahead of next year's elections. Robin Nair is the former permanent secretary of Fiji's department of foreign affairs. He recently resigned from his position and says there was interference in his work at the department from the highest levels of government. Hagar Cohen : Now, for the first time, Robin Nair is speaking out, claiming the PR company Qorvis has on a number of occasions attempted to influence Fiji's diplomatic relationship with Australia and New Zealand. He says he remembers a meeting he attended in September last year where advice from Graham Davis to the Prime Minister nearly resulted in the expulsion from Fiji of the current New Zealand High Commissioner. : At one stage he passed on a message to the Prime Minster, which made the Prime Minister go and admonish the New Zealand High Commissioner and castigated him for things that he had purportedly told him, and the Prime Minister was scathing and threatened the High Commissioner with some drastic actions that he might take against him... Hagar Cohen : What was the drastic action? Robin Nair : That he sent a few of his ambassadors back home and he could be liable to such certain action. Hagar Cohen : So that the New Zealand High Commissioner would be one of those people that could be sent back home to New Zealand.? Robin Nair : Yes, back home, and... Hagar Cohen Robin Nair : Advice that he passed on about something that the High Commissioner had allegedly said, but the High Commissioner was really taken aback and very distressed and he came to me and he told me, 'Robin, these are false statements, I never said that.' Hagar Cohen : But what were those statements? Robin Nair : He was alleged to have said, the High Commissioner was alleged to have said that this man, meaning the Prime Minister, should be behind bars. Hagar Cohen : So Graham Davis told the Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama that the New Zealand High Commissioner had told him that Frank Bainimarama should be behind bars. Robin Nair : Yes. Hagar Cohen : And in response to that, Frank Bainimarama told the New Zealand High Commissioner to...he warned him. Robin Nair : To pull up, yeah. Hagar Cohen : And that he could be sent home. : Yes. Hagar Cohen : And how do you know that? Robin Nair : I was present. Hagar Cohen : So you were a direct eyewitness to this conversation? Robin Nair : A direct eyewitness to the conversation, yes. : The New Zealand Department of Foreign Affairs have declined to comment on the incident, saying 'New Zealand and Fiji enjoy a productive and positive relationship'. But Robin Nair says the incident with the High Commissioner wasn't a one-off. He critiques the advice emailed by Graham Davis to the Attorney General (the one leaked to Background Briefing ) about Britain's training work with Fiji police, and says it's evidence of meddling by Qorvis. Robin Nair : I find it outrageous, and I found it outrageous because he was interfering in giving the government proper and considered advice, which was really the work of the government's advisors. He had no accountability in the place. If I gave advice I had full accountability in terms of the government there and in terms of the structures of democracy there. But this man has got no accountability whatsoever and he was going around and giving, in a way, unsolicited advice and prejudicing the hard work that's been done on both sides to bring about normalcy and to be able to be good allies in the region. Hagar Cohen : What is he actually trying to do to the diplomatic relationship between Australia and Fiji? : He was trying to strain the relationship. Hagar Cohen : Why would a PR consultant with a background in Australia do such a thing, would seek to destabilise the relationship? Robin Nair : It was very interfering as far as I was concerned, and he was trying to continue this destabilisation of relations with our immediate neighbours. : In July this year, the website Fijileaks published an email written by Robin Nair to Bainimarama. In this email he raises concerns about the speed at which Fiji is normalising its relations with Australia. It says he believes Australia is still resentful of the military coup. This email was written in 2015 when Nair was Fiji's ambassador to the United Arab Emirates. But Robin Nair says that unlike the advice from Qorvis, his advice as an official member of Fiji's diplomatic staff was tough but appropriate. Robin Nair : Australia and New Zealand would expect me to give honest and fearless advice to my Prime Minister as one of his advisers, even if the advice was one that ANZ might not agree with. They would not have expected me to do otherwise. It was a well-argued and considered advice and not one line of gossip piece. Hagar Cohen : According to Robin Nair, Qorvis also took a keen interest in Fiji's global negotiations efforts on the issue of climate change. This year Fiji will be presiding over the ongoing UN climate negotiations in Bonn, called COP 23 . It's arguably the most important global meeting seeking to address climate change, where governments will meet to implement uniform greenhouse gas emissions targets following the Paris Agreement from 2015. In a recent address to Fiji's heads of mission, the Prime Minister Bainimarama stressed that the success of this event is 'do or die' for Fiji. The transcript of the speech was posted on the government's website. : It is the biggest job the world has ever given to us to do. While the stakes for the whole world have never been greater, the stakes for the Pacific are even higher because we are among the most vulnerable. We must use the COP presidency to do what we can to persuade the world to step back from the abyss. Hagar Cohen : The stakes are high and the conference is due to start next month. Robin Nair says he wanted the best person in his diplomatic staff to go to Bonn and represent Fiji, but Graham Davis from Qorvis had other ideas. Nair says Graham Davis installed a Qorvis employee to be Fiji's representative in the UN in Bonn. Robin Nair : Graham Davis had, to my horror, casually suggested to the Attorney General and the Prime Minister to appoint one of their own staff to this position. I had earlier argued to my minister, which happened to be the Prime Minister, that that the position of liaison officer in Bonn was critical to the presidency and it needed a local person, and also a local person preferably with foreign policy skills, and preferably with climate change negotiation experience. Hagar Cohen : Did this particular position require diplomatic skills? Robin Nair : Surely, the key diplomatic position in the UN secretariat representing Fijian interests. Hagar Cohen : Robin Nair then complained to the Prime Minister. But it didn't help. A PR consultant with Qorvis was appointed to the job. Since leaving the government, Robin Nair has joined the opposition's National Federation Party. Background Briefing has contacted Graham Davis and Qorvis in Washington a number of times. We emailed Mr Davis detailed questions which included all the allegations made in this program about his work as a Qorvis consultant in Fiji. Mr Davis refused to comment for this program. Our questions can be found on our website. Qorvis executive vice president, Greg Lagana, who's based in Washington, also refused to respond to our specific questions. He sent a statement saying that their work in Fiji is to help the government deliver clear, truthful and consistent information and messaging. He said he is professionally bound not to discuss any more details. Biman Prasad : In a democracy, the opposition is as important as the government. The government makes policies, the government governs, and the opposition calls the government to account. Hagar Cohen : Professor Biman Prasad is one of the only people in Fiji who has publicly questioned the role of Qorvis. He's the leader of the opposition's National Federation Party. Biman Prasad : I moved a motion in parliament in the last budget session calling for the removal of the allocation of funding to Qovris, an American PR firm that this government has hired. We were told initially that the government needed the PR firm during the military rule, to create PR for the government. We believe that there is no need for a PR firm like that, and we believe that the government is actually wasting taxpayers' money paying this organisation, and all this organisation, in our view, does is government propaganda. Hagar Cohen : He says the emails written by Qorvis consultants and obtained by Background Briefing are important public information. Biman Prasad : Because no media in Fiji would cover anything like that. No media. Hagar Cohen : Professor Prasad says he believes that it's not only the media that's being oppressed. He says everyday Fijians are also being silenced. Biman Prasad : Let me say this quite categorically: there is a culture of fear, there is a culture of intimidation, there is a culture of bullying, when it comes to questioning the government on critical issues. Hagar Cohen : But I want to be clear, there is no longer fear about ending up in a military barracks? Biman Prasad : I don't know, I don't know. We were taken in and locked up in a police cell, allegedly for having a political meeting last year. I spent a night in a police cell because we were meeting to discuss the constitution. Hagar Cohen : Professor Prasad's meeting contravened the public order decree which required a special permit for political meetings with more than ten attendees. His detention led to an international outcry and the decree has since been amended. But he and others remain concerned about the future of press freedom and essential democratic rights in Fiji while Qorvis is contracted by the government. Ewan Perrin is formally the Permanent Secretary of the Department of Communications and Information Technology. Ewan Perrin : These guys...go and have a look on the web, have a look on Wikipedia, these guys were credited with turning around Saudi Arabia's image after the 9/11 attacks in America. These guys worked with the government of Bahrain after they were cracking down on Doctors Without Borders. You know, and this is the company that now has a very close relationship with the Fijian government. Hagar Cohen : But journalist Netani Rika says he and his colleagues will fight on regardless. : If those who come after us ask why we did not do enough, how will we answer? I'd like to think that during my time we were able to provide as critical an analysis and as independent type of reporting that we could, given the circumstances, and not have to hang our heads in shame for not upholding media freedom at a time when it was most necessary for this country. Hagar Cohen : 's co-ordinating producer is Linda McGinness, our sound engineer this week is Isabella Tropiano, Jess O'Callaghan is our series producer, supervising producer is Kirsten Garrett, and fact check by Emma Lancaster, Suzanne Smith is our executive producer. You can subscribe to Background Briefing wherever you listen to podcasts or hit explore and listen via our new ABC Listen app. I'm Hagar Cohen. \</doc>
