<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh1" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 13, 2016 Sunday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
The high-level segments of the Conference of the Parties ( COP-22 ) begins here on Tuesday with the participation of some heads of government and many ministers of different countries. The top leaders from various nations will present their country's position papers and put forward suggestions to tackle the growing climate change impacts, mainly caused by greenhouse emissions by developed countries. COP22 will be the first chance to explore and expand the historic climate agreement signed in Paris during the COP21. Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina leaves Dhaka for Morocco on Monday morning on a three-day official visit to attend the COP-22 . She is scheduled to reach Menara Airport, Marrakech at 4.30 pm (local time). Foreign Minister AH Mahmood Ali, Environment and Forests Minister Anwar Hossain Manju, Water Resources Minister Barrister Anisul Islam Mahmud, high officials of the government and climate experts will accompany her. Sheikh Hasina will deliver her statement at the high-level segments of COP-22 on Tuesday 15 where she may highlight Bangladesh's position to address the climate challenges and urge global leaders to intensify the national and collective efforts to address this huge challenge. COP-22 , which began on November 7 and runs through November 18 in Bab Ighli of Marrakech, Morocco, is the first such meeting since the historic adoption of the Paris Agreement at COP-21 in December last year. Meanwhile, the primary discussion of the COP22 formally concluded on Saturday with highlighting by climate experts on turning ambition into action and achieving the goals of the Paris Agreement. The primary discussion also focused on negotiating key elements, such scaling up the technical, financial and capacity building support that will facilitate action at the country level. In December 2015, over 190 countries convened in France to adopt the Paris Agreement on climate change at the 21st Conference of the Parties (or COP21). This Agreement was the culmination of years of hard work by countries, UN agencies, scientists, the private sector and civil society, and represented a long-term vision for a zero-carbon, resilient and sustainable world. At different meetings on the sidelines of the conference, global civil society leaders called upon for new political policy regimes to protect and promote the human rights of climate induced displaced people. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh2" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 13, 2016 Sunday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Bangladesh's participation in the high-level segment of COP-22 carries a special significance considering the 'bold and leading role' played by the country in overcoming climate change challenges. 'Bangladesh's participation in the conference led by Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina will further boost our image at the global stage,' Foreign Minister AH Mahmood Ali told a press conference at the Foreign Ministry on Sunday afternoon. Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina leaves for Morocco on Monday to attend the high-level segment of the Conference of the Parties ( COP-22 ) in Marrakech on November 15-16 at the invitation of King Mohammed VI. The Foreign Minister, Environment and Forests Minister Anwar Hossain Manju, Water Resources Minister Barrister Anisul Islam Mahmud, high officials of the government and climate experts will accompany her. Minister Ali said the participation will help Bangladesh highlight Bangladesh's firm commitment to addressing climate change challenges, multifaceted successes and contributions to that end. 'I believe the bilateral relations between Bangladesh and Morocco will reach new heights through the conference,' he said. The Foreign Minister said some 109 countries, including Bangladesh, out of total 197 countries have so far ratified the Paris Climate Agreement that came into force on November 4. 'Considering this development, this year's COP is important.' Responding to a question, Ali said some 56 head of states and governments are participating in the conference this year. Asked what will be the government's position if Rampal issue comes up there, he said this is in no way part of the conference. The Foreign Minister said the government has its answers ready if the issue comes up for discussion. The COP22 is described as the COP of action as it will focus on the implementation modalities of the Paris Agreement, said the Foreign Ministry here. 'This will provide us with the right platform to reiterate our commitments and negotiate towards achieving a robust, balanced and meaningful action plan to address climate change impacts under the framework of Paris Agreement,' said the Foreign Minister. He said Bangladesh is one of the countries most vulnerable to climate change adversities. 'We've been playing a significant role in global climate change negotiations, including the adoption of Paris Agreement.' In her national statement at the Marrakech Summit, the Prime Minster is expected to re-emphasise Bangladesh's resolve and determination in this regard, highlighting the initiatives and measures undertaken by the government in tackling the menaces of climate change, said the Foreign Ministry. The Prime Minster is expected to attend a luncheon hosted by King Mohammed VI of Morocco and have interactions with various world leaders during the Summit. A VVIP flight of Biman Bangladesh Airlines carrying the Prime Minister and her entourage is scheduled to depart HazratShahjalal International Airport here for Marrakech on Monday morning. She is scheduled to return home on Wednesday. Bangladesh first created Climate Change Trust Fund worth US$ 400 million with its own financing. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh3" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 16, 2016 Wednesday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Ministers and senior officials at Conference of Parties ( COP ) 22 in Marrakech, Morocco have promised to take steps to reduce the deaths caused by environmental pollution. Gathering at the COP22 climate meeting in Marrakech, over two dozens of high-level officials related to health and environment sectors signed up the Declaration for Health, Environment and Climate Change, according to a message received here on Wednesday. The goal is to reduce pollution-related deaths via a new global initiative to promote better management of environmental and climate risks to health. The World Health Organization (WHO) estimates that some 12.6 million deaths a year are associated with environmental pollution. Of these, an estimated 6.5 million deaths (11.6 percent of all global deaths) are associated with air pollution, from household and outdoor sources. "This landmark declaration has raised consensus for better articulation of our efforts to find a solution to the major health, environmental and climate challenges," said Hakima El Haite, Minister of Environment, Morocco. "Together, we commit to ensuring that people - their livelihoods, wellbeing, and particularly their health - are at the centre of the response to climate change," he added. Most environmental pollution-related deaths occur in low-and middle-income countries. However, outdoor air pollution remains prevalent in high-income countries as well, with 9 out of 10 people worldwide exposed to air pollution that exceeds WHO Air Quality guidelines for fine particulate matter. Ninety-four percent of outdoor air pollution deaths are due to non-communicable diseases - notably cardiovascular diseases, stroke, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and lung cancer. "We know that most health risks from climate change are preventable," said Morocco's Health Minister Dr El Houssaine Louardi. The Declaration recognises that well-designed policies to protect the environment will result in reducing the global burden of disease attributable to the environment as well as reducing the rising rate of noncommunicable diseases (NCDs), such as stroke, heart disease, cancers and chronic respiratory diseases. NCDs account for nearly two-thirds - or 8.2 million - of deaths associated with unhealthy environments. "The devastating consequences of air pollution affect both the climate and health. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh4" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="June 30, 2016 Thursday"source="Energy & Power" >
On the final day of the climate talks in Bonn, Germany, leaders of key negotiating blocs joined in call for global action on renewable energy and energy efficiency at COP22 in Marrakech later this year. The Chairs of these groups, representing over 90 countries, highlighted the launch at COP 21 in Paris last year of the Africa Renewable Energy Initiative, a program with pledges of $10 billion in financial support, as a starting point for scaling up renewable energy worldwide. The leaders emphasized that COP22 in Marrakech offers an unprecedented opportunity to broaden this success to other developing countries, including small island, least developed, Asian and Latin American countries, as part of an enhanced global effort to support the uptake of renewable energy globally while strengthening energy efficiency. Toshi Mpanu-Mpanu, Chair of the LDCs, said that "The Marrakech COP will be an action and implementation COP. With the LDC renewable energy and energy efficiency initiative we are following up on Paris and beginning to deliver concrete solutions vital to addressing climate change." "The Least Developed Countries are committed to play our part in the global energy transformation, to provide clean and renewable energy, jobs and opportunities to vastly improve livelihoods for our people," he said. COP22 provides an unprecedented opportunity to strengthen support on renewables to the LDCs, as part of a global program of support. The energy of Paris must be channeled into real solutions to both climate change and development at COP22 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh5" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 16, 2016 Wednesday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 16 -- Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina has proposed creating a global fund to help achieve the Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) on water. She made the proposal at the COP22 United Nations Climate Change Conference Heads of government and state of 80 countries have taken part in the 22nd Session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP22 ). She stressed the need for floating the global fund on water SDG to support research, innovation and technology transfer. Of the 17 SDGs taken up in the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, the sixth one is clean water and sanitation. It sets out to 'ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all'. SDG 6 expands the Millennium Development Goal focus on drinking water and basic sanitation to now-cover the entire water cycle, including the management of water, wastewater and ecosystem resources. At the conference, Hasina also reminded the development countries of their pledge to help the vulnerable ones to tackle the effects of climate change. "Lives and livelihoods of millions of people would continue to be at risk unless we deliver to our commitments on climate change issues," Hasina said. UN Secretary General Ban Ki-moon also urged the world leaders to pay more attention to tackle climate change effects in order to protect the planet, safeguard the most vulnerable, and drive shared prosperity. "Now we have to translate words into effective policies and actions," he said, referring to the Paris Agreement on climate change, enforced earlier this month. Hasina, too, drew the participants' attention to the agreement. "Last year in Paris, we have been successful to create a solid ground for a meaningful cooperation in combating climate change impacts. Now, this is the time to move forward to implement decisions into actions," she said. The prime minister also put emphasis on tackling the climate-induced migrant issue. "Unless, we address this challenge appropriately, we would never be able to attain the objectives of Sustainable Development Goals," she said. Speaking about her government's efforts to tackle the effects of climate change as one of the countries most vulnerable to those effects, she mentioned raising a 'Climate Change Trust Fund' of $400 million from its own resources. She said Bangladesh achieved success in disaster management despite its coastal areas being highly vulnerable to climate related calamities, such as floods and cyclones. "We have put in place measures like early warning system, cyclone shelters and river weeds cultivation that have significantly reduced loss of lives and properties in Bangladesh," she said. Hasina concluded her speech by urging all to be "prepared to share equitable burden to fulfil our promises of making the world a safer and better place for our future generation". Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh6" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 30, 2016 Wednesday"source="Energy & Power" >
Chair of the Least Developed Countries (LDC) group, Tosi Mpanu-Mpanu, has called for fair and ambitious action at COP22 in Marrakech, Morocco. "We must build upon the foundations set in Paris to construct robust rules to support the Agreement's implementation," he said. The negotiations come after a year of growing international political momentum to address climate change, following the historic adoption of the Paris Agreement in December 2015. Noting with concern that full implementation of current pledges by countries to cut greenhouse gas emissions puts the world on track for 3-3.5\'b0C of warming above pre-industrial levels, Mr Mpanu-Mpanu said: "Science tells us that beyond temperature increases of 1.5\'b0C the future of our planet stands on increasingly thin ice. It is imperative for communities across the world that countries take seriously their goal to pursue efforts to keep temperatures below 1.5\'b0C. We cannot afford to treat this as an aspirational goal. An upwards spiraling of commitments to cut emissions that is both fair and proportionate to challenge rising before us is vital." LDCs plan to contribute to these global efforts through the LDC Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency Initiative (REEEI) for Sustainable Development, among other ways. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh7" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="June 30, 2016 Thursday"source="Energy & Power" >
The first UN climate change meeting since governments adopted the landmark Paris Agreement closed recently amid a suite of positive outcomes that will support the treaty's widely anticipated early entry into force and stronger, sustained action world-wide into the future. The nearly two week meeting saw countries push ahead with implementing stronger climate action and constructing the global climate regime "rule book" in order to guarantee the treaty's fairness, transparency and balance between nations. While work towards the agreed flows of USD 100 billion per annum by 2020 continues, two of the key international funding arms- the Green Climate Fund (GCF) and the Global Environment Facility (GEF)-underlined how they are supporting the Agreement. The GCF told delegates that its board had set an aspirational goal of 2.5 billion USD in 2016 for both adaptation and mitigation programs and projects. The GCF urged countries to submit ambitious proposals for funding as soon as possible. The GEF announced that it had put together forwardlooking work programs for the funding of both mitigation and adaptation projects. On mitigation, 450 million USD is available for new projects while current projects to the value of 106 million USD are already being implemented. On adaptation, some 250 million USD is available for projects. The GEF will also assist the Moroccan Government to green COP22 . \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh8" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 14, 2016 Monday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina left here for Morocco on Monday morning on a three-day official visit to attend two high-level segments of the Conference of the Parties ( COP-22 ). Environment and Forest Minister Anwar Hossain Monju, Water Resources Minister Barrister Anisul Islam Mahmud and Foreign Minister AH Mahmood Ali are accompanying the Prime Minister. The flight is scheduled to land at Menara Airport, Marrakech at 4.30 pm (local time). Bangladesh Ambassador to Morocco Sultana Laila Hossain will receive the Prime Minister there. On her arrival at the airport, the Prime Minister in a ceremonial motorcade will be escorted to Hotel La Mamounia where she will be staying during her visit to Morocco. Sheikh Hasina will deliver her statement at the high-level segments of COP-22 on November 15 where she may highlight Bangladesh's position to address climate challenges and urge global leaders to intensify the national and collective efforts to address this huge challenge. Along with other heads of state and government, Sheikh Hasina will attend the lunch to be hosted by King of Morocco Mohammed VI the same day. She is scheduled to return home on the night of November 16. COP-22 , which began on November 7 and runs through November 18 in Bab Ighli of Marrakech, Morocco, is the first such meeting since the historic adoption of the Paris Agreement at COP-21 in December last year. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh9" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="September 15, 2016 Thursday"source="Energy & Power" >
Participants in a seminar in Dhaka recently urged the government to raise the climate induced displacement issue in the coming SAARC Summit in Islamabad and Climate Conference in Marrakesh. They said this while addressing a seminar titled "Climate Issues in CoP22 and Islamabad SAARC Summit" at CIRDAP auditorium. Climate Action Network South Asia (CANSA), Christian Aid, Campaign for Sustainable Rural Livelihood (CSRL), Oxfam International COAST and EquityBD organized the seminar. Dr Qazi Kholiquzzaman Ahmed, Chairman of PKSF chaired the event while Dr Hasan Mahmud, Chairman of Parliamentary Standing Committee on Ministry of Environment and Forest was present as chief guest. Rezaul Karim Chowdhury of COAST moderated the seminar while Sanjay Vahsist of CANSA, Dr Atiq Rahman of BCAS, Badi Akhter of Oxfam and Sharmind Neelormi of CSRL took part in the discussion. Mujibul Haque Munir of Equitybd presented the keynote paper. Dr Hasan Mahmud said Bangladesh delegation gained in Durban and Cancun on climate displacement issue that has to be again placed in CoP 22 Marrakesh. He also urged for redefining UN refugee convention in view of climate displacement. He criticized GCF, as major portion of the fund is being channeled through multilateral financial institution whose basic objective is to gain profit. Dr Qazi Kholiquzzaman said Bangladesh has to be very active in Marrakesh and Islamabad SAARC summit. However, Bangladesh should not wait for external assistance rather proceed with its own resources, he said. Conference of Parties ( CoP ) 22 Climate Conference will take place in Marrakesh, capital of Morocco, in November and SAARC Summit in Islamabad in December. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh10" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 14, 2016 Monday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
A red carpet was rolled out as Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina arrived here on Monday afternoon on a three-day official visit to Morocco to attend two high-level segments of the Conference of the Parties ( COP-22 ). Morocco Minister of National Education and Vocational Training Rachid Belmokhtar Benabdellah and Bangladesh Ambassador to Morocco Sultana Laila Hossain received the Prime Minister at the airport. She was given a static guard of honour. On her arrival at the airport, the Prime Minister in a ceremonial motorcade was escorted to Hotel La Mamounia, after the ceremonial reception, where she will be staying during her visit to Morocco. Earlier, the flight carrying Sheikh Hasina and her entourage took off from Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport for Marrakech, a former imperial city in western Morocco, at 10:15 am (Bangladesh Time). On November 15, Sheikh Hasina will deliver her statement at the high-level segments of COP-22 on where she may highlight Bangladesh's position to address climate challenges and urge global leaders to intensify the national and collective efforts to address this huge challenge. Along with other heads of state and government, Sheikh Hasina will attend the lunch to be hosted by King of Morocco Mohammed VI the same day. She is scheduled to return home on the night of November 16. COP-22 , which began on November 7 and runs through November 18 in Bab Ighli of Marrakech, Morocco, is the first such meeting since the historic adoption of the Paris Agreement at COP-21 in December last year. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh11" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 13, 2016 Sunday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 13 -- Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina leaves Dhaka on Monday for Marrakech of Morocco on a three-day official visit to attend two segments of the 22nd Conference of the Parties ( COP-22 ) to the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC), said officials on Sunday. Foreign ministry officials said a VVIP flight (BG-1019) of Biman Bangladesh Airlines carrying the premier and her entourage will depart Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport for Marrakech, a former imperial city in western Morocco, at 10 am, reports BSS. The flight is scheduled to land at Menara Airport in Marrakech at 4.30 pm local time on the same day. A ceremonial motorcade would escort Hasina to Hotel La Mamounia where she will be staying during her visit to Morocco. On Tuesday, PM will attend the opening session of the High-level Segment of COP-22 at Plenary Hall at Bab Ighli, the COP-22 Conference Venue, in Marrakech from 10am-1pm. Hasina will deliver her statement at the segment of COP-22 , the 12th Conference of the Parties serving as the Meeting of the Parties to the Kyoto Protocol (CMP 12), and the 1st Conference of the Parties serving as the Meeting of the Parties to the Paris Agreement (CMA 1) as the 49th speaker of the day in the afternoon. In her statement, PM is expected to highlight Bangladesh's position to address the climate challenges and urge global leaders to intensify a campaign to advance the national and collective efforts to address this immense challenge. Along with other heads of state and government, the premier will attend a lunch to be hosted by King of Morocco Mohammed VI the same day. Sheikh Hasina is scheduled to return home on November 16 night after concluding her three-day visit to Morocco. Foreign Minister AH Mahmood Ali, Environment and Forest Minister Anwar Hossain Manju, Water Resources Minister Anisul Islam Mahmud and Deputy Minister of Environment and Forest Abdullah Al Islam Jacob, among others, will accompany the prime minister during her visit to Morocco. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh12" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 15, 2016 Tuesday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 15 -- Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina will deliver her speech at the 22nd session of conference of parties in Marrakech, Morocco on Tuesday midnight. She will speak as the 48th speaker of the high level segment which will kick off from Tuesday and continue till November 17. In her speech, the Bangladesh prime minister is expected to highlight her administration's position to address the climate challenges and urge global leaders to intensify a campaign to advance the collective national and international efforts. Hasina has left Dhaka for Marrakech on Sunday on a three-day official visit to attend two high-level segments of the 22nd Conference of the Parties ( COP 22 ) that is hosted by UN Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). Foreign Minister AH Mahmood Ali, Environment and Forest Minister Anwar Hossain Manju, Water Resources Minister Anisul Islam Mahmud and Deputy Minister of Environment and Forest Abdullah Al Islam Jacob are accompanying the PM as her entourage. She is scheduled to return home on November 16, reports agencies. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh13" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 16, 2016 Wednesday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 16 -- Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina stressed the need for creating a "global fund" to support research, innovation and technology transfer to achieve the Sustainable Development Goals (SDG) on water. Addressing the United Nations Climate Change Conference 2016 in Marrakech early Wednesday, the prime minister said this is the time to turn decisions taken in Paris into actions. She also called for global efforts to address the issue of climate-induced migrants to make the objectives of SDGs successful. Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina started to deliver her speech just after Tuesday midnight (Bangladesh time) at the high level segment-2 of COP-22 at Bab Ighli in the Moroccan city of Marrakech. She said Marrakech climate conference bears a special significance as the historic agreement signed last year in Paris "creating a solid ground for a meaningful cooperation in combating climate change impacts", is expected to be enforced this year. "Now, this is the time to move forward to implement decisions into actions," she said, adding that the Paris Agreement successfully created a solid ground for a meaningful cooperation in combating climate change. "We must be prepared to share equitable burden to fulfill our promises of making the world a safer and better place for our future generation," she said. Mentioning that Bangladesh is also the first country to set up "Climate Change Trust Fund" of US $ 400 million from its own resources, she said: "Bangladesh also achieved success in disaster management despite its coastal areas are highly vulnerable to climate-related calamities, such as floods and cyclones." Called for global efforts to ensure safe drinking water and sanitation for all through effective water governance to help achieve the SDGs on water, she said: "We must ensure safe drinking water and sanitation for all through effective water governance." Laying importance on water security, Sheikh Hasina, also a member of the UN High Level Panel on Water, reiterated her government's commitments to the action plan endorsed by the Panel in New York in September. She urged all to join hands to consolidate the global partnership to fight perilous threats of climate change. The prime minister also highlighted Bangladesh's disaster management programmes, including early warning system, construction of cyclone shelters and river weeds cultivation, saying these measures have significantly reduced loss of lives and properties during disasters. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh14" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 30, 2016 Wednesday"source="Energy & Power" >
Entry into force of the Paris Agreement on 4 November commits governments to keep the increase in average global temperature to well below 2 \'b0C and to pursue efforts to limit this to 1.5 \'b0C. This will require ambitious action across all sectors. A priority should be the de-carbonization of the electricity supply sector, using nuclear energy in harmony with other forms of low carbon generation. The next steps to achieving these goals will be taken at the COP 22 climate change conference Marrakech that started on November 7, said a press release. Agneta Rising, Director General, World Nuclear Association, said " COP22 needs to enable governments to take practical and meaningful progress towards meeting the objectives of the Paris Agreement. This should include supporting the contribution nuclear can make to achieve a low carbon global electricity generation mix." Today, the world's 450 nuclear power plants generate enough electricity to avoid the emissions of two and a half billion tonnes of carbon dioxide each year, compared to the coal-fired base load generation that nuclear typically displaces. New nuclear plants that have started operation since COP 21 will save more than 70 million tonnes of carbon dioxide emissions every year. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh15" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="October 28, 2016 Friday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Chairman of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on Environment and Forests Ministry Dr Hasan Mahmud on Thursday said the issue of climate-induced migrant will get priority in Marrakech climate conference billed for November 7-18. 'The government's policy is to give highest priority to climate-induced migrant issue in this conference,' he told a seminar titled ' CoP 22 Global Climate Conference: Proposal from Civil Society on Behalf of Most Vulnerable Population' held at the Cirdap auditorium in the city. Environment and Forests Minister Anwar Hossain Monju was present as the chief guest at the seminar organised by eight rights groups, including BAPA, BCJF, BIPNetCCBD, CDP, CSRL, EquityBD and FEJB. Chaired by Dr Hasan Mahmud, the seminar was addressed, among others by Director of the Department of Environment Md Ziaul Haque, Dr Nilufar Banu of BUP, Qumrul Islam Chowdhury of FEJB, Kawser Rahman of BCJF and Mojahidul Islam Noyan of Oxfam. Moderated by Rezaul Karim Chowdhury of EquityBD, Sharmind Neelormi of CSRL presented the keynote paper in the seminar. In his speech, Dr Hasan Mahmud said the government is not in favour of any loan or any commercial attitude in climate finance as Bangladesh is not at all responsible for climate catastrophes. 'So Bangladesh's position is to demand compensation in this regard,' he said. The government will also raise the issue of setting picking year in respect of temperature and mitigation, Dr Hassan Mahmud added. Anwar Hossain Manju said the government and civil society should work together for country's interest in Marrakech conference. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh16" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="March 29, 2017 Wednesday"source="The New Nation (Bangladesh)" >
Dhaka, March 29 -- Tahzingdong, a non-governmental voluntary organisation working on issues of the environment and socio-economic development in the Chittagong Hill Tracts (CHT), has won the Energy Globe Award in Earth category at the COP22 . COP22 -the 22nd Conference of the Parties to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). Founder of Energy Globe Foundation Wolfgang Neumann handed over the award to the Tahzingdong authority at a programme on March 17 this year. To inform people about winning of the award and the project, the organisation held a press conference at a local hotel on Sunday with CHT Affairs Secretary Nabo Bikram Kishor Tripura as chief guest. Vice-Chairman of CHT Development Board Tarun Kumar Ghosh, Executive Director of Aranyak Foundation of Bangladesh Farid Uddin Ahmed, Executive Director of Tahzingdong Ching Shing Pru and journalists of electronic and print media were present there. Sources said that Tahzingdong supported by Aranyak Foundation of Bangladesh, has been implementing this project since 2009. The project covers 12,919.64 hectares of nine community-conserved areas, which are commonly called 'village common forests', and includes more than 1,000 indigenous forest-dependent families. Tahzingdong has built two community houses as part of institutional capacity building, and installed two water supply technologies that capture more than 387,000 litres of clean water in a month from the forests using a gravitational flow system. This system has reduced water scarcity within the community and 70 per cent of waterborne diseases. Moreover, the organisation has planted 28,545 seedlings in the community-managed forests, including bamboo, cane, and endangered species, sources also said. Many fruit seedlings have been planted in homesteads to increase forest and biodiversity conservation, as well as to prevent soil erosion of the water bodies. Three hundred sets of improved cooking stoves and 20 sets of solar panels have been provided to help maintain a clean and green environment. Fifty per cent of household-based biomass and the resulting carbon dioxide emissions have gone down in the villages and improved women's health condition. Alternative livelihood-generating support initiatives have been started, which have increased the income of vulnerable communities. It is mentionable that the Energy Globe Award was founded in 1999 by the Austrian energy pioneer Wolfgang Neumann and is one of the most prestigious environmental awards today. The two other finalists for the award this year were the Inga Foundation of Honduras and AMSED of Morocco. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The New Nation. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh17" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 19, 2016 Saturday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
The 22nd session of the Conference of Parties (COP) concluded here early Saturday with a pledge to hasten the climate activities across the globe in the light of the agreement adopted at COP21 in Paris in 2015. In the Marrakech Declaration, the world leaders focused on taking initiatives over water and food security for the developing courtiers, and fixed a deadline for formulating a rulebook for the implementation of the Paris deal. In the summit, some countries agreed to provide US$81 million for the adaptation fund and US$ 23 million for the Green Climate Fund. However, the green activists expressed their frustration over the Marrakech declaration mentioning that the developed countries did not deliver any specific declaration over the finance. Climate Justice Group said funding of private sector in climate change fund cannot be an alternative to government funding. Marrakech Vision, a group of developing countries, pledged that they will attain the target of 100 percent of renewable energy to reduce carbon emission by 2020 and 2050. UNFCCC Executive Secretary Patricia Espinosa said, 'Developed countries should start work from now to fulfill their commitment to provide US$100 billion annually from 2020.' In the conference it was announced that Fiji will arrange the next United Nations Conference on Climate Change known as ' COP 23' which will be held in Bonn, Germany in 2017. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh18" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 18, 2016 Friday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Describing 2016 as a bad year for Bangladesh with the growing intensity of flood caused by climate change, Environment and Forest Minister Anwar Hossain Manju has stressed the need for implementation of the Paris Agreement to combat that climate disasters. Manju, now in Marrakech for attending the 22nd Conference of the Parties ( COP-22 ), made the call at a press conference here on Wednesday evening. 'We've already been affected by the adverse impacts of climate change. This year, 2016, has been a bad year for us. The Brahmaputra recorded the highest ever flood level. The Dharla basin faced s severe flooding. On the other hand, the rainfall during the peak of monsoon was very low, while drought like conditions prevailed in the northwestern region,' he said. The minister further said, 'Increased salinity is seriously affecting the people of southwestern Bangladesh. The Chittagong region has been hit by cyclone Ruanu. These demonstrate that climate disasters are on the rise.' Mentioning that Bangladesh has acted proactively to ratify the Paris agreement, he hoped that all the signatories to it will complete their ratification process at the earliest and thus create pressure on world leaders for accelerating the implementation of the Paris Agreement. Manju also said Bangladesh wants to see the urgency in making real progress on developing the 'Paris Rulebook' particularly finalising modalities, procedures and guidelines (MPGs) for NDCs, Transparency Framework, Global Stocktake, and Compliance Mechanism. Climate finance stands at the core of the negotiations, observed saying this is an important agenda for all vulnerable countries like Bangladesh. 'Our country is in urgent need to receive adequate and predictable finance for addressing adaptation needs.' On Adaptation Fund, the minister said Bangladesh strongly feels the importance of the continuation of the fund to support concrete adaptation projects in developing countries. 'We also urge developed countries for generating adequate resources for the LDC Fund.' Monju said Bangladesh has already submitted 5 proposals for technology transfer to Climate Technology Centre and Network (CTCN). 'The CTCN has indicated that initially they planned to support two of these proposals. But, we noticed with concern the inadequacy of funds compared to the requests submitted by parties for technology transfer. So, we urge the developed countries to provide adequate resources to facilitate technology transfer to developing countries.' The COP22 \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh19" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 16, 2016 Wednesday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina has urged global leaders to fight together the perilous threats of climate change and share the burdens equally for fulfilling the promises to make the world a safer place for the future generation. 'Let's join hands to consolidate our partnership to fight the perilous threats of climate change.share the burdens equally to fulfill our promises of making the world a safer and better place for our future generation,' she said. The Prime Minister came up with the remarks on Tuesday while speaking at the High Level Segment of the 22nd Session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP22 ) at Marrakech, a former imperial city in western Morocco. Sheikh Hasina also placed two crucial issues -- water security and climate-induced migrants -- at the meeting to achieve the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) set by the United Nations. The Prime Minister said she, as a member of the UN High Level Panel on Water, reiterated government's commitments to the action plan endorsed by the members of the High Level Panel on Water in New York in September last. 'We must ensure safe drinking water and sanitation for all through effective water governance.' She stressed the need for creating a global fund on water SDG to support research, innovation and technology transfer. About climate-induced migrants, Hasina said it will never be able to attain the SDGs without addressing this challenge properly. The Prime Minister mentioned that COP 22 Conference bears a special significance as all are celebrating the entry into force of the historic Paris Agreement. In Paris last year, she said, world leaders had been successful to create a solid ground for a meaningful cooperation in combating climate change impacts. 'Now this is the time to move forward to implement decisions into actions. Lives and livelihoods of millions of people would continue to be at risk unless we deliver to our commitments on climate change issues.' Turning to Bangladesh, Hasina said it is one of the first countries that signed and ratified the Paris Agreement. 'Bangladesh is also the first country to set up 'Climate Change Trust Fund' of US$ 400 million from its own resources,' she added. The Prime Minister also mentioned that Bangladesh achieved success in disaster management despite coastal areas being highly vulnerable to climate related calamities, such as floods and cyclones. 'We've put in place measures like early warning system, cyclone shelters and river weeds cultivation that have significantly reduced loss of lives and properties in Bangladesh.' \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh20" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 16, 2016 Wednesday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 16 -- The World Health Organisation (WHO) estimates that some 12.6 million deaths a year are associated with environmental pollution. Of these, an estimated 6.5 million deaths (11.6 percent of all global deaths) are associated with air pollution, from household and outdoor sources. Most environmental pollution-related deaths occur in low-and middle-income countries. However, ministers and senior officials at Conference of Parties ( COP ) 22 Gathering at the COP22 climate meeting in Marrakech, over two dozens of high-level officials related to health and environment sectors signed up the Declaration for Health, Environment and Climate Change, according to a message received in Dhaka on Wednesday. The goal is to reduce pollution-related deaths via a new global initiative to promote better management of environmental and climate risks to health. "This landmark declaration has raised consensus for better articulation of our efforts to find a solution to the major health, environmental and climate challenges," said Hakima El Haite, Minister of Environment, Morocco. "Together, we commit to ensuring that people - their livelihoods, wellbeing, and particularly their health - are at the centre of the response to climate change," he added. Ninety-four per cent of outdoor air pollution deaths are due to non-communicable diseases - notably cardiovascular diseases, stroke, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and lung cancer. "We know that most health risks from climate change are preventable," said Morocco's Health Minister Dr El Houssaine Louardi. The Declaration recognises that well-designed policies to protect the environment will result in reducing the global burden of disease attributable to the environment as well as reducing the rising rate of noncommunicable diseases (NCDs), such as stroke, heart disease, cancers and chronic respiratory diseases. NCDs account for nearly two-thirds - or 8.2 million - of deaths associated with unhealthy environments. The devastating consequences of air pollution affect both the climate and health. Yet virtually all air pollution is manmade - and often excessive," said WHO's Director-General Dr Margaret Chan. "By working together, across sectors, and with partners, we can help ensure that people - their livelihoods, wellbeing, and particularly their health - are at the centre of the response to climate change," the WHO DG added, according to a news agency report. - Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh21" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 3, 2016 Thursday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
The entry of the Paris Climate Change Agreement into force from Friday should spur states to be more ambitious in their commitment to tackling global warming, UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Zeid Ra£d Al Hussein said on Thursday. 'I urge all the parties that will be at the COP22 in Marrakech to ensure that the meeting is about states taking action in accordance with their international human right obligations,' the High Commissioner said, adding that the world cannot wait. A year ago, the world celebrated the passage of the first universal, binding agreement to mitigate climate change, but there is a clear disconnect between the Paris Agreement's stated ambition to limit warming to less than two degrees and the commitments countries have made. 'That gap must be closed,' Zeid said. The UN HR boss said climate change is a threat to all and to future generations, and to the enjoyment of human rights now and in the years ahead, according to a message received here from Geneva. A continually warming world will be a graveyard for entire ecosystems, entire peoples - and potentially even entire nations, the High Commissioner said. 'That each of the last three years has been the hottest on record shows why it is imperative to focus on implementing the Paris deal and to ensure that the commitments states made to respect and promote human rights in climate action are acted upon and deepened,' Zeid stressed. The Conference of Parties ( COP22 ), due to take place in Marrakech from November 7-18, is so important, Zeid said. 'States need to take urgent action at COP22 to make sure that the measures detailed in the Paris Agreement are carried out. This will require adequate financing, sharing of technology and capacity-building. States also have an obligation to work individually and collectively to foster an environment for the enjoyment of all human rights by all. For this, they need to show more ambition and more willingness to cooperate internationally.' The Paris Agreement establishes a framework to measure, review and verify states' commitments, and calls for cooperation to enhance climate change education, training, public awareness and participation, as well as people's access to information. 'This framework needs to be transparent and to integrate human rights considerations within its reporting guidelines. Accountability for action - or inaction - is essential,' Zeid said. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh22" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 22, 2016 Tuesday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 22 -- Many environmentalists, including this writer, had been observing the proceedings since the 22nd session of the Conference of Parties (COP) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) started at Marrakesh, Morocco on November 07, 2016. The Prime Minister of Bangladesh also flew to Morocco to attend the high-level segment of COP 22 . Fifty-nine heads of state and government reportedly joined the conference. Many issues related to climate change were discussed, debated and resolved in the conference. But two central themes dominated ultimately. These are: (i) curbing emissions collectively to hold global warming level at 2'C and (ii) financing adaptation and mitigation of climate change. Such agreements were also made in the climate change conference held in Copenhagen in December 2004. Attended by 194 countries and hundreds of environmental organisations and experts, the Copenhagen conference resolved to frame a legally-binding agreement to curb carbon and other greenhouse gas emissions in order to bring down global warming level below 2'C. It also recommended for providing US$100 billion every year by developed countries to meet the requirements of climate change-vulnerable developing countries. The COP 21 held in Paris in December 2015 echoed the same resolutions. The positive side was that till date, 109 countries including Bangladesh have ratified the Paris Agreement. About 15,000 negotiators, CEOs and activists were reported to be in Marrakesh for 12- day talks on climate change. The importance lay in growing impacts of climate change that have resulted in rising seas, deadly storms, floods, droughts, wildfires and pollution of water and etc. It was observed that two concerns were prevailing in the conference. The first one was the threat of US President-elect Donald Trump to withdraw from the climate change accord meaning no US contribution to the green climate fund. Secondly, only US$ 1.0 billion was committed by developed countries against US$100 billion for it. Related to this, no definite procedures and principles were yet adopted as to how this money would be disbursed. There were doubts whether the USA would ratify the Paris Declaration of COP 21. The US set this example regarding the Kyoto protocol of 1997. But President Barack Obama ratified the Paris agreement through an executive order just before the recently-held presidential election in the US. During the election campaign, Obama said in a TV talk that all progress on climate change including the Paris agreement was going to be on the ballot. During his present tour to Europe, he, however, said that there will not be major changes in the foreign policy of the USA whoever becomes the President. In Athens, Obama, among other issues, commented on Trump's position on climate change saying that climate deals would be difficult to unravel under the new President. UN secretary general Ban Ki-moon said in Marrakesh on November 15 that action on climate change has become 'unstoppable'. He predicted that Trump would drop plans to quit the global accord. European leaders are also of the same opinion. French President Francois Hollande said in Marrakesh that the 2015 accord to limit emissions 'is irreversible in law and in fact. In addition, it is irreversible in our minds". Thus, the hope prevails that the USA, being the largest economic power of the world and the second largest greenhouse gas emitter, must respect the Paris agreement. COP22 ended at Marrakesh on November 18, 2016 with a declaration that called for the highest political commitment to address the climate change. It may be termed as a political declaration. The parties (countries) agreed to combat the impact of climate change combinedly and try to reduce emission of carbon. They also agreed to try utmost for funds to meet climate change projects and programmes. In reality, the Marrakesh climate change conference- Cop 22 --appeared to have ended with no concrete framework to implement Paris accord. No substantive progress was made on any of the 11 issues discussed in the conference. The highest policy-making body, CMA, sat in a meeting one day and was prorogued after some time. The organisers said that this meeting would be held later. It is reported that it will take two years for the preparation of Rule Book (Framework) that will help implementation of the Paris agreement. It implies that COP 22 was trapped in the procedural problems which could not be sorted out. Visible progress was not also found about the management of the Green Climate Fund. The industrially developed countries agreed in Cancun and Durban conferences that finance for this fund would be unconditional. But the fund authority outlined in the Marrakesh conference that the fund would be a mixture of loan, investment and aid. Some countries including Bangladesh have made a proposal to channel resources from this fund through government organisations. But reportedly, no consensus was found in the COP 22 . People across the world expected that the Marrakesh climate conference would result in the adoption of a framework for implementation of the Paris accord agreed upon in COP 21. But the proceedings suggested that it was gripped by Trump (US President-elect) phobia and failure of the highest policy-making body, CMA, in framing the Rule Book needed for implementation of Paris accord. Added to these is poor commitment of money to the climate change fund. The positive point, however, was the highest political commitment made by the parties in addressing the climate change problems. Let us hope that the highest emitters of carbon and greenhouse gases (China, the USA, Russia, India, Japan, Germany, Iran South Korea, Canada, Saudi Arabia and others) and other developed countries would generously contribute to the climate change fund and the experts would prepare the framework for implementation of Paris accord adopted in previous COPs. The writer is an economist and a former environment secretary of GOB. HYPERLINK mailto:chowdhuryjafar@ymail.com chowdhuryjafar@ymail.com Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh23" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="April 27, 2017 Thursday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Having reached out to global audiences in Copenhagen, Paris and Marrakech, international photo exhibition 'Mind the Earth: A New Perspective' has arrived here with its founder and curator Kasper Brejnholt Bak. The Embassy of Denmark in Bangladesh, in partnership with Edge, The Foundation presents this thought-provoking journey, scheduled to open to the public on Friday at Edge Gallery and will be running till Saturday (May 6). Admission is free for all and the exhibition will be open every day from 10 am to 8 pm at the serene setting of Bay's Edgewater Building on 12 North Avenue, Gulshan 2. The gripping photos at the exhibition raise consciousness about planet Earth, how it has naturally come to be as it is today and how its inhabitants continue to change its face, for the better and for worse. Rightfully so, Mind the Earth has been exhibited at COP21 in Paris and COP22 in Marrakech, the most important global conference on climate change. While viewing the mesmerising photos of Mind the Earth, one is left bewildered at the power of perspective. Nature's physical formations can be equated to art while mankind's pursuit in creating modern instruments through which humanity can advance is nothing short of remarkable. Mind the Earth, now a non-profit organization running for two years with exhibitions held in four countries, is focusing primarily on communication through exhibitions, publications and other communication initiatives with a goal to increase awareness about the challenges the world is facing in terms of climate change, population growth, urbanization and management of the limited resources of the planet in a broader sense. The overall theme of the exhibition is the intertwined subjects of sustainable development and climate change, explored through striking photos secured via Google Earth's satellites. Hosting its first international exhibition, Edge, The Foundation seeks to create a better world through sharing knowledge and is proud to partner with the Embassy of Denmark in Bangladesh and Kasper Brejnholt Bak, said a press release on Thursday. Edge Gallery's events showcase and promote creativity, helping raise funds for educational scholarships and artist grants. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh24" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="December 15, 2016 Thursday"source="Energy & Power" >
The Marrakech climate talks concluded early November 19 after two weeks of negotiations and discussions, with countries committing to put Paris Agreement into action by 2018 - but much work remains to be done. Soon after the start of the "COP of action" was overshadowed by the results of US presidential election of November 8 and by uncertainties over the potential U-turn the world's second largest emitter might take under the new administration. After a first week played on the defensive, government representatives and climate delegates on November 17 issued a joint statement, the Marrakech Action Proclamation, calling for "the highest political commitment to combat climate change, as a matter of urgent priority". The statement was interpreted as a signal of unity and determination in sticking to the path set at COP21 in Paris last year. After Paris, the focus has shifted to implementing action, and COP22 was the first important moment to start defining mechanisms and rules to achieve the Paris targets. No conclusive developments were expected at the Marrakech talks, but some starting advancements on key issues. These are reported in a set of 35 decisions adopted at the end of the Conference. Duty Assignment The governing body of the Paris Agreement - the CMA, including all countries who have ratified the deal met for the first time on November 15. As foreseen by hypothesis circulated in the previous months, the CMA1 asked the Ad Hoc Working Group on the Paris Agreement (codename: APA) and the subsidiary bodies to continue their preparatory work and define rules and framework to make the Paris Agreement fully operational. The APA is responsible of defining the procedure related to the nationally determined contributions (NDCs), the transparency framework, the global stocktake and the compliance/implementation issues, whereas the cooperative mechanisms, the accounting framework for finance and technological support, the IPCC role in informing the global stocktake and the NDC registry are discussed within the two UNFCCC Subsidiary Bodies (SBI and SBSTA). The countries agreed to complete the overall task by 2018 at COP24 to be held in Poland, where the CMA should adopt all rules and procedures. Next year, at COP23, the CMA will reconvene to review and assess the progress made. The APA is also asked to prepare arrangements and operating modalities for the Adaptation Fund to serve the Paris Agreement. The Adaptation Fund was established under the Kyoto Protocol and its role in the post-Kyoto climate regime monopolized the discussion in several sessions at COP22 . The final document invites Parties to submit their views on the governance and institutional arrangements, safeguards and operating modalities for the Adaptation Fund to work under the Paris Agreement, by 31 March 2017. The Rules of the Game In order to track actions and progress by all countries involved, the Paris agreement will need a robust transparency and accountability system covering NDCs, finance and technical transfers. The APA is in charge of developing common rules, procedures and guidelines to enhance the UNFCCC's current Monitoring, Reporting and Verification (MRV) system by 2018. At COP22 delegates mostly discussed the degree of flexibility for requirements developing and poorer countries should comply with, reflecting "their different capabilities and national circumstances". No significant news emerged in Marrakech about the modalities and procedures of the compliance committee that will be in charge of facilitating the implementation of the Paris agreement's provisions. Leave None Behind In Marrakech richer countries reaffirmed the climate finance goal of mobilizing USD100 billion per year by 2020. Before the start of COP22 , a roadmap was released to describe how developed countries plan to deliver the promised target. However, further work is needed to define common rules and standards to track climate finance disbursed and received, and to clarify what kind of financing tools (loans, grants etc.) should be counted as for the USD 100 billion goal. On the adaptation finance side, although the Green Climate Fund (GCF) announced the approval of the first two proposals for the formulation of National Adaptation Plans ($2.2 million for Liberia and $2.9 million for Nepal) and another 20 plans are on their way to be approved, delegates denounced little progress on the effort to increase funding to help developing and vulnerable countries in coping with climate impacts. Overall developed country Parties were urged to step up efforts aimed at achieving a greater balance between mitigation and for adaptation. The capacity-building issue also received attention during the Marrakech talks. A new coalition - the NDC Partnership - was launched to support developing countries in achieving their domestic climate actions and accessing technical and financial support. Negotiators agreed on the functioning structure of the Paris Committee on Capacity Building (PCCB), that was established at COP21 and will meet for the first time in May 2017. The first annual focus of the PCCB will be the NDCs implementation. On the critical topic of Loss and Damage, delegates succeeded in reaching an agreement on the ExCom Report and Warsaw International Mechanism's review that through a new five-year framework will deal with impacts not addressed by planned adaptation. Closing the Plenary, COP22 President Mr. Salaheddine Mezouar, thanked all the Parties and the staff for "the energy, passion and solidarity" that finally prevailed on the difficulties connected to the implementation of the Paris Agreement. This demonstrated that the Paris Agreement is "irreversible and already underway". Countries overall expressed satisfaction with the final outcome, especially for the 2018 deadline for the adoption of the rulebook and the steps ahead in terms of transparency for finance and capacity building. However, developing countries groups, like the G77 + China, Nicaragua and Bolivia, remarked the need to step up efforts toward the balance between adaptation and mitigation, on clarity related to long-term financial support to developing countries as well as on pre-2020 action. Endorsing the Marrakech's outcome, the United States reassured the audience that "Momentum cannot and will not be stopped". Finally, as in the past few years, many non-Party stakeholders took the COP as the opportunity to push bottom-up initiatives forward. As reported by the UNFCCC's final release, "Multi-billion and multi-million dollar packages of support" to clean technologies, capacity building, water and food security in developing countries were announced in the two weeks. In particular, Climate Champions Laurence Tubiana and Hakima El Haite launched the Marrakech Partnership for Global Climate Action with the aim to facilitate and catalyze the pace of climate action by Parties and non-Party stakeholders in the period 2017 to 2020. To track progress but also showcase successful initiatives, the Non-State Actor Zone for Climate Action (NAZCA), a platform launched in Lima, will continue to register commitments voluntarily undertaken by cities, regions, private companies and investors to address climate change. Heads of State, UN Secretary-General Address COP 22 At the Marrakech Climate Change Conference, the opening ceremony of the joint high-level segment of the Conference of the Parties (COP), the COP serving as the Meeting of the Parties to the Kyoto Protocol (CMP) and the CMA took place with dozens of Heads of State in attendance. During the opening of the joint highlevel segment, the Heads of State and Government, delegates heard statements from King of Morocco Mohammed VI, who urged against pressing countries to agree to decisions to which they may be unable to comply. In his address, UN Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon said that a "new dawn of cooperation on climate change was upon us" with the entry into force of the Paris Agreement. He said that countries supported the Agreement because they realize their own national interest is "best secured by pursuing the common good." He called on developed countries "to honor their commitment" to mobilize climate finance (US$100 billion by 2020) to help developing countries address climate change. UNFCCC Executive Secretary Patricia Espinosa called for including business, subnational governments, indigenous peoples, youth, women and other groups in the transformation towards a low-carbon and climate resilient world, emphasizing that their contributions cannot be overlooked. Mariame Mouhoub, Youth Representative, Morocco, called on delegates to see beyond their differences, and work for a just ecological transition and solidarity with the world's most vulnerable. President Fran\'e7ois Hollande, France, stressed that the entry into force of the Paris Agreement is "irreversible." He said that the US must respect its climate commitments, adding that France would lead a dialogue with the new President, and that, "despite all our differences, what unites us is what we have in common - our planet." COP President Salaheddine Mezouar briefly opened the CMA, describing the entry into force of the Paris Agreement within <a year of its adoption as a testament to countries'commitment to addressing climate change. Under the CMP, on matters relating to Joint Implementation, parties agreed to forward the draft decision for consideration by the CMP. On matters relating to the Clean Development Mechanism (CDM), parties considered draft decision sections on: baseline and monitoring methodologies; registration of project activities and issuance of certified emission reductions (CERs); regional and sub-regional distribution; the CDM Loan Scheme; and resources for work on the CDM. Much of the text remains bracketed. At a high-level event on a sustainable economic transition and economic diversification, representatives highlighted: the need for a clear long-term plan, concrete actions and programs, and timelines in order to ensure an equitable transformation to low-carbon development; a sustainable transition to achieve the Paris Agreement; the need for buy-in from stakeholders working on climate change and sustainable development. During a closing session, one speaker called for innovative, win-win solutions in diversification that are accessible and beneficial to all, and innovative partnerships to address the challenges posed by diversification, including the loss of jobs. Another characterized the UNFCCC as a platform to exchange ideas, set goals and norms, and evaluate the adequacy of the responses. Another high-level event addressed the implementation of East Asia countries' Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) in the postParis Agreement era, with panelists discussing: the need for transformation of development modalities at the national level; carbon pricing as a critical market instrument to curb emissions and induce investments to low-carbon alternatives; and non-market instruments, including performance oriented regulations, licensing, labeling and certification. The second part of this event: provided an overview of China's low-carbon development pathway and the Green Partnership among China, Japan and the Republic of Korea; suggested reconsideration of the relationship between infrastructure spending and NDC goals£lignment; and focused on best practices in low-carbon city pilot projects, with case studies presented from cities in Japan. Another event focused on SDG 17 (strengthening means of implementation and revitalizing the global partnership for sustainable development), and building capacity for the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development through climate action solutions for regional implementation. However, the picture of Marrakech climate talks not being able to deliver the necessary boost for financial means to support poorer countries which struggle to cope with the worsening calamities is becoming clear, according to negotiators and development charities. A few pledges were made, but they are still a pittance compared with what developing countries need. These countries have made impassioned pleas in Marrakech for more financing to help their transition to a more resilient economy: so far those pleas have largely fallen on deaf ears, their representatives stated. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh25" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="May 7, 2017 Sunday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Dhaka, May 7 -- Bangladesh is ready to host the next Delta Coalition conference at ministerial level in July with main focus on water issues. The Delta Coalition conference, a forum of 12 countries, will be held along with the High Level Panel on Water (HLPW) and the Regional Water Conference (RWC). This will be the second Delta Coalition conference after the first one held in the Netherlands last year from where the coalition was officially formed. Officials said, being the chair of the second forum, Bangladesh is likely to focus on vulnerability of the delta countries and creating awareness for tackling issues of water and climate change. "The Delta Coalition is not a negotiation forum. It is the place where delta member-countries identify respective problems they are facing in terms of earning livelihoods and try to find the best practices of adaptation and mitigation," said an official. Though the Delta Coalition's focus is mainly on urban areas, Bangladesh is likely to bring rural areas in the next meeting as the delta problems affect both the regions but are of different nature. According to official website, Dhaka is focusing on action and momentum on water issues with a view to ensuring a resilient future enshrined in Sustainable Development Goal 6. The meeting will deal with issues to attain the final goal of assuring future generation fullest access to fresh and clean water, it added. The Ministry of Foreign Affairs, in association with the Prime Minister's Office, will host the event. The High Level Water Panel is being organised by the Water Resources Ministry while the Regional Conference by the Local Government and Rural Development Ministry. During the first Delta Coalition conference held in Rotterdam, the Netherlands on May 9-10, the Delta Coalition and its operational plan 2016-2017 were officially launched. The Delta Coalition is the world's first international coalition of governments that have formed a partnership to deal with inclusive sustainable development in urbanising deltas, combining economic development with adaptation and preventive measures reducing climate change risks and strengthening resilience. Most importantly, it will allow delta countries to join forces to stimulate sharing best practices and innovation, and to increase opportunities for financing in order to facilitate the implementation of projects that will reduce vulnerability to climate change. Bangladesh, Colombia, Egypt, France, Indonesia, Japan, South Korea, Mozambique, Myanmar, the Netherlands, the Philippines and Vietnam have already joined the coalition. After the coalition was formed, Bangladesh and the Netherlands got a chance to present the Delta Coalition during COP22 in Marrakesh. Published by HT Digital Content Services with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh26" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 29, 2016 Tuesday"source="The News Today (Bangladesh.)" >
A network of several civil society organizations Monday suggested formation of an independent climate change commission that would negotiate and handle issues related to global warming on Bangladesh's behalf internationally, reports BSS. It also expressed deep frustration over the achievements from the just concluded 22nd conference of parties (COP) in Morocco since it has not been able to fulfill the needs and demands of the least development countries (LDCs) and most vulnerable countries (MVCs) that include Bangladesh. The observations were made at a post-COP press conference titled 'Outcome of the CoP22 : Analysis and proposal from Civil Society' held at the Jatiya Press Club in the city, said a press release. The network observed that the nitty-gritty of a clear roadmap for the implementation of the Paris Climate Agreement was supposed to be finalized in COP22 , but the large congregation has yielded little or no tangible result to be optimistic and move forward. Rezaul Karim Chowdhury, a campaigner in the field, said despite having meritorious and skilled government officials in Bangladesh negotiation team, a clear lack of political guidance has weakened national position in the conference. He said climate change was not an issue of the Ministry of Environment and Forest alone, rather like the Philippines, an independent Climate Change Commission should be formed and given the responsibility to protect national interest. Mujibul Haque Munir, an executive of EquityBD, said there have been serious elements to be frustrated over the outcome of this year's climate conference since tendency of avoiding responsibilities from rich countries to the climate vulnerable countries were seemingly acute. He said rich countries did not even provide any clear roadmap for the 100 billion US dollar climate fund yearly from 2020. They did not agree on providing fund under the Loss and Damage issue. They made merely a commitment of 81 million US dollar for the adaptation only. This type of position by the rich countries will virtually lead to 'climate genocide' in LDCs and MVCs." Pardip Kumar Roy, an executive of CSRL, said the LDCs and MVCs clearly expect a leadership role of Bangladesh in the climate change negotiations, for which Bangladesh should be well prepared, active and vocal in time. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh27" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 30, 2016 Wednesday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 30 -- Kirill Komarov, Rosatom's First Deputy CEO for Corporate Development and International Business, spoke about the role of nuclear power in achieving objectives of the Paris Agreement and its effect on CO2 emissions in the recently held UN Climate Change Conference ( COP22 ) in Marrakesh (Morocco)."We promote nuclear stations based of VVER technology, which is safe, mature and one of the most referenced globally. Our recent project is Novovoronezh Unit 6 that was put into operation this August. We are proud that this is the first and only Generation III+ nuclear power reactor in the world. VVER-based nuclear stations have prevented 15 gigatons of CO2 from being emitted globally. This amount is equal to emissions of 40 coal-fired thermal power stations with a capacity of one GWe for 60 years. Currently, nuclear accounts for 48 per cent of low-carbon generation in Russia. This is our contribution to the low-carbon future of our planet." Komarov also noted that the nuclear industry bore a great responsibility, "We must have safe nuclear stations and efficient spent nuclear fuel and radioactive waste management technologies. Rosatom's latest innovations, including fast neutron closed cycle technologies, REMIX fuel and Gen 3+ reactors, with the first of them launched in Russia, let us succeed in these tasks." According to Dr. Hakima El Haite, Minister Delegate in Charge of Environment at the Ministry of Energy, Mining, Water and Environment of Morocco, the Russian Federation is an example of successful cooperation between the government and nuclear industry. Earlier that day Kirill Komarov and Agneta Rising, Director General of the World Nuclear Association, held a press-conference on the sidelines of COP22 . Its focus was on the role of nuclear power in achieving objectives of the Paris Agreement and global reduction of CO2 emissions. Ms. Rising noted, "As the Paris Agreement calls on countries to have greater ambition, we believe it vital to aim the decarbonization of the power supply sector by 2050, using nuclear energy in harmony with other forms of low carbon generation. The parties should follow Russia's example today and focus on nuclear solutions just as on other mitigation options," she added,according to a statement. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh28" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="December 4, 2016 Sunday"source="The New Nation (Bangladesh)" >
Dhaka, Dec. 4 -- Until recently, the international climate negotiation process revolved strictly around high-level conversations between nation states. However, this is changing in a way that may lead us to rethink the structure of global climate talks. In particular, nonstate actors, such as businesses and nongovernmental organizations (NGOs), are becoming increasingly influential players, transforming the overall conversation - something we witnessed firsthand at the COP22 summit on climate change in Marrakech, Morocco this month. This shift has the potential to not only bring new voices into discussions over how the world addresses climate change, but also create more effective forums for taking action. COP22 wasn't the first time climate talks have been held in Marrakech. The city hosted the same forum in 2001 at a time when George W. Bush had recently been elected president. He promptly removed the U.S. from the global climate treaty known as the Kyoto Protocol. That decision cast a pall over those earlier talks, but that pales in comparison to the effect of Trump winning the U.S. election. With his administration preparing to take power, there is every expectation that the United States will disengage. President-elect Trump has explicitly indicated he will end the U.S. involvement in the Paris Agreement and the climate negotiation process more generally, although some expect the disengagement may not be quite as severe. How and whether the U.S. officially pulls out of the Paris Agreement or otherwise removes itself from the formal process is still unclear (there are at least three possible scenarios). But one thing is certain: The U.S. can no longer be expected to be as active a player as it was under the Obama administration. This means a different form of engagement is needed for continued progress in addressing climate change. Fortunately, changes in the negotiation environment are taking place. Stepped-up role of nonstate actors at Marrakech For over two decades, international climate talks held under the auspices of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) were focused on coming to a long-term, comprehensive global agreement on climate change. This was achieved in 2015 with the Paris Agreement, which puts forth a comprehensive architecture designed for the long term. It requires all parties to submit voluntary "Nationally Determined Contributions" (NDCs) to reduce their national greenhouse gas emissions. These pledges are designed to assess how far we have to go toward hitting global climate mitigation and adaptation targets, and how far individual states have gone toward doing their part. Over time, countries are supposed to set more ambitious targets. The key challenge in Marrakech was to take steps to operationalize the Paris Agreement, and here we saw greater involvement of nonstate actors. As Secretary John Kerry pointed out during his address in Marrakech, market pressures and low-carbon initiatives, more than states, will play an increasingly central role. Economic agents remain important, not merely for direct financial aid and engagement with the market, but also for insurance and other mechanisms of support. Substate actors can be cities, states and provinces as well as economic institutions, such as development banks. Other groups include research bodies, such as academic institutions, and NGOs. This stepped-up role for nonstate actors was particularly notable at COP22 in Marrakech. For example, representatives from California reaffirmed their commitment to reduce the state's emissions regardless of federal policies. California Governor Jerry Brown is seen as a global leader on climate change and an example of the influence entities other than countries can play. At COP22 in Marrakech, he said California 'will continue to confront' climate change. The interaction between states, and between states and nonstate actors, has the potential for being increasingly collaborative and decreasingly confrontational. For example, the development of a program engaging High Level Champions for Climate Action, begun in Paris, came to fruition in Marrakech. This program gathered an unprecedented network of nonstate actors and put them in dialogue. These dialogues, with the intent of increasing ambition from all parties, demonstrated a remarkable shift toward collaboration. We saw these dialogues taking place in Marrakech. One example is the financial sector's engagement in the discussion of how rich countries provide money to poor countries to adapt to the effects of climate change. In one striking example, the World Bank voiced its engagement with the distinctive perspectives of indigenous peoples for sustainable development. Moreover, as part of a concerted effort to bring both public and private sectors to bear on climate change, a platform was developed to showcase collaborative efforts, and motivate new partnerships and opportunities. Three outcomes This evolving landscape has implications for how international collaborations to address climate change move forward, even with waning official U.S. engagement. First, the addition of nonstate actors brings interests not typically reflected into the policy arena. For example, subnational bodies such as the state of California can bring in new perspectives on climate action initiatives that might not otherwise be available. Or, in another example, the inclusion of indigenous voices can bring in a set of interests that have not been sufficiently represented. A broader array of resources, perspectives and expertise provides a more comprehensive approach to policy. Certainly, this diversity of perspectives brings new challenges in coordinating various groups and their interests, but it also opens new opportunities for cooperation. Second, by including interests that are at least one step removed from formal political agents, the ongoing landscape will be separated from the four- or five-year time span of typical state-level elections. As one of us (Boran) has argued previously, multilateral engagement that promotes a diversity of perspectives, expertise and know-how can become a strength of long-term climate policy. This, it may be hoped, provides a better chance of developing and implementing approaches to climate mitigation, adaptation, and financial support on longer time scales. Third, by bringing in nonstate actors there is greater potential for bilateral and multilateral engagement between drivers of climate action with overlapping interests. More agents in conversation open up new channels for collaboration, which is a better approach for the complex challenges presented by climate change. Hope beyond the state Clearly, the openness we saw in Marrakech to engage an increasingly wide range of actors in the global climate effort cannot be a substitute for the work nations have to do. But it may well prove at least as consequential in the long run as formal U.S. political engagement. And it may provide a new direction for the future of international collaboration and multilateralism. That should give us hope for progress on climate change. (Kenneth Shockley, Associate Professor and Holmes Rolston III Professor of Environmental Ethics and Philosophy, Colorado State University and Idil Boran, Associate Professor of Political Philosophy, York University, Canada) The Conversation Published by HT Syndication with permission from The New Nation. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh29" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="December 25, 2016 Sunday"source="The New Nation (Bangladesh)" >
Dhaka, Dec. 25 -- The latest round of global climate change talks - COP22 - should have been a celebratory affair. The historic Paris agreement on climate change had been ratified well ahead of schedule. However, the US election results cast a cloud over the summit in Marrakesh last month. While it remains to be seen whether President-elect Donald Trump will actually proceed with his vow to take the US out of the agreement, his recent move to appoint Scott Pruitt, a known fossil fuel defender, to head the Environmental Protection Agency is cause for concern. No country alone can solve all the problems related to climate change, but losing a key player could have seriously negative effects. Climate change poses an unparalleled, complex and urgent challenge to us all. Global businesses and their sustainable practices have a huge role to play in tackling this challenge. It is therefore encouraging that at the COP22 , parties reaffirmed their commitment to implement the Paris Agreement. Even prior to COP22 , several significant climate change deals were achieved. Early in October the much-awaited aviation climate deal was agreed in Montreal, adopting an offsetting approach to constraining aviation emissions. Starting from 2021, airlines that have opted into the measure will have to purchase offsets to balance their emissions growth above 2020 levels. Only a few weeks later, the Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer was amended, aimed at reducing the emissions of hydrofluocarbons (HFCs). HFCs are used as substitutes for ozone-depleting substances (CFCs and HCFCs) in mainly refrigeration and air conditioning. Since it has become clear that they are not only some of the most powerful, but also the fastest growing greenhouse gases. Reducing emissions of HFCs could prevent up to 0.5degC of global warming. With the Paris Agreement in place as a policy basis, more and more companies are setting science-based emission reduction targets that will impact many areas of their business operations. One area with significant carbon emissions is supply chains. Some 25 percent of total global emissions are 'embodied emissions' in exported products, which are emissions from the sourcing of raw materials, manufacturing of products and pre-export transportation. For this reason, while discussions focus on the need for legislative frameworks and more public-private partnerships, these messages must cascade down the supply chain to reach local producers. All businesses - from SMEs to multinationals - have a vital role to play in this process. Their environmental impact is often mistakenly limited to that of their direct operations. However, the indirect effect of a company's global sourcing activities - which generates the largest impact on the environment - tends to be overlooked. Taking into consideration the environmental performance of the supply chain as a whole requires collaboration and transparency. Initiatives such as the Business Environmental Performance Initiative (BEPI) are supporting companies in this undertaking, by offering a unique system applicable to all sectors and countries as well as tailored recommendations to improve their producers' environmental performance. The BEPI System covers a comprehensive set of 11 environmental performance areas, including Energy Use/GHG and Emissions to Air. BEPI supports its members on driving reductions in emissions directly into their supply chains through awareness raising, capacity building and practical improvement activities. Every reduction in greenhouse gas emissions will contribute to the collective effort of keeping global warming well below 2degC. Important though the environment is, we cannot envisage a truly sustainable future without considering the protection of human rights, many of which depend on the fulfilment of other rights such as that of safe and healthy working conditions. The Foreign Trade Association's sustainable supply chain management services, which bring together BEPI and the Business Social Compliance Initiative (BSCI) - supporting members with programmes to reduce social impacts in their supply chains for nearly 15 years - provide an effective framework to address these intertwined and pressing challenges. Yet, understandably, one may think that the challenge can be to convince businesses in these financially challenging times that sustainability is a must rather than a nice-to-have. However, nothing is further from the truth. Numbers speak for themselves: FTA's 1,900+ members and over 41,000 factories and farms worldwide working together to promote more sustainable business practices show the strong commitment of the business sector, from multinationals to SMEs, to tackle these challenges. We're looking to the future - for the planet and people living on it, and also for businesses. The value that sustainability adds to a company's bottom line may not be immediately apparent, but we strongly believe that it is essential for their long-term success and the overall growth, development and economic prosperity. As elections take place across Europe and a Trump administration begins its work, we will fight to make sure these values continue to be a top priority. (Christian Ewert is director general of the Foreign Trade Association (FTA). Published by HT Syndication with permission from The New Nation. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh30" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="April 20, 2017 Thursday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, April 20 -- Bangladesh would explore possible areas of the World Bank (WB) support in addressing its ongoing development challenges during the upcoming spring meetings of the WB and International Monetary Fund, officials have said. A high-powered Bangladesh delegation, led by Finance Minister A M A Muhith, will take part in the three-day event that begins in Washington DC, USA on Friday. Other members of the delegation include Bangladesh Bank Governor Fazle Kabir, Alternative Executive Director at the WB M Musharraf Hossain Bhuiyan, Senior Secretary of Finance Division Hedayetullah Al Mamoon and ERD Secretary Kazi Shofiqul Azam. "Our aim in the meeting will be to highlight Bangladesh's multifaceted achievements in the socioeconomic fields while exploring the avenues where the World Bank can support us in meeting existing challenges," one member of the delegation told the FE. A day before starting of the spring meeting, the finance minister is scheduled to have a formal meeting with Chief Executive Officer of World Bank Kristalina Georgieva. On April 22, he is scheduled to take part in the Development Committee Plenary at the WB headquarters. He will also hold a meeting with Executive Vice President and CEO of International Finance Corporation Philippe Le Houerou on the following day. Besides, Muhith will also hold a meeting with World Bank's Vice President for South Asian region Annette Dixon. "During the meeting, the two sides will discuss the progress of various World Bank-funded projects in Bangladesh," sources at the World Bank said. According to officials, the finance minister will also meet Executive Vice President of Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency (MIGA) Keiko Honda. MIGA, which is a member of the World Bank Group, works to promote foreign direct investment (FDI) into developing countries to help support economic growth, reduce poverty and improve people's lives. Besides, the Bangladesh delegation will take part in Carbon Pricing Leadership Coalition High Level Assembly of the Climate Action Peer Exchange. Launched in November 2016 by the World Bank and Moroccan COP22 Presidency, CAPE is a peer exchange platform of ministries of finance and planning whose focus is fiscal policy instruments for implementing the Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) -- the climate commitments by member countries. During the visit, Muhith will also have a meeting with the President of New Development Bank K V Kamath. Formerly referred to as the BRICS Development Bank, NDB is a multilateral development bank established by the BRICS states (Brazil, Russia, India, China and South Africa). The idea for setting up the bank was proposed by India at the 4th BRICS summit in 2012 held in New Delhi and the bank formally started its journey back in 2014. The finance minister is also set to take part in the Steering Committee Meeting of the Global Partnership for Effective Development Cooperation (GPEDC). Bangladesh is currently the co-chair of the GPEDC along with Germany and Uganda. The Bangladesh delegation will also take part in a high level meeting on 'Closing the Financing Gap for Water'. In addition, they will also take part in a roundtable hosted by the US Chamber of Commerce. HYPERLINK mailto:mehdi.finexpress@gmail.com mehdi.finexpress@gmail.com Published by HT Digital Content Services with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh31" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 30, 2016 Wednesday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Russia's nuclear power agency Rosatom says that nuclear power stations generate 38 percent of green energy across the world. COP22 ) that took place on 7-18 November 2016 in Marrakesh (Morocco). As part of it, Russia held a seminar titled: the Low-Carbon Development: Challenges and Opportunities event, said Rosatom in a statement released on Tuesday. Rosatom has been engaged in Bangladesh to build a 2400 MW nuclear power plant in Rooppur. Presenting the figure that 38 percent of 'green' energy in the world comes from nuclear generation the Rosatom first deputy CEO said nuclear plays a very important role for the future. 'Nuclear and renewables cannot be opposed to each other and are allies rather than rivals,' said Mr. Komarov in an interview as well. He also focused the role of nuclear power in achieving objectives of the Paris Agreement and its effect on CO2 emissions. The Paris Agreement was signed at COP21 in Paris on 12 December 2015. Its purpose is to curb the increase in the global average temperature by 2100 to well below 2\'b0C above pre-industrial levels and keep the temperature growth within 1.5\'b0C. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh32" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 16, 2016 Wednesday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina on Wednesday left Marrakech, a former imperial city in western Morocco, completing her three-day official visit to attend two high-level segments of the Conference of the Parties ( COP-22 ). Bangladesh Ambassador to Morocco Sultana Laila Hossain and Culture Minister of Morocco Mohamed Amine saw the Prime Minister off at the airport. Prior to her departure, she was given a static guard of honour at the airport. On Tuesday, Sheikh Hasina delivered her statement at the high-level segments of COP-22 where she urged global leaders to fight together the perilous threats of climate change and share the burdens equally for fulfilling the promises to make the world a safer place for the future generation. Along with other heads of state and government, Sheikh Hasina attended the lunch hosted by King of Morocco Mohammed VI. COP-22 , which began on November 7 and to run through November 18 in Bab Ighli of Marrakech, Morocco, is the first such meeting since the historic adoption of the Paris Agreement at COP-21 in December last year. The Prime Minister is scheduled to return home on November 17. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh33" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 24, 2016 Thursday"source="The News Today (Bangladesh.)" >
The country's achievement in water management has been highlighted at a programme of the United Nations' Security Council (UNSC), held Tuesday at UN headquarters in New York, reports BSS. Member of the parliamentary standing committee on the Ministry of Foreign Affairs Mahjabeen Khaled presented the country statement at the Security Council debate on 'Water, Peace and Security' issue, which was open to non-council members. UN Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon also participated in the open debate where he highlighted the value of water resources as a reason for cooperation, not conflict. According to an UN release, Ban Ki-moon underscored the need for coordination in water management especially for the more than 260 international rivers and many transboundary aquifers. Bangladesh's statement drew attention of the UNSC to the various challenges that the country has been facing for long as a lower riparian country, according to a release of Bangladesh's Permanent Mission to the UN received. 'As a lower riparian, low-lying delta vulnerable to climate change, we constantly grapple with challenges relating to availability of freshwater, especially during the lean season,' Mahjabeen said in the statement. She also noted that despite such challenges, under the guidance of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, more than 98.0 percent of population has access to safe drinking water while over 65.0 percent has access to safe sanitation. In the statement, she mentioned about the prime minister's call at the UNFCCC COP22 in Marrakech to set up a special global fund for the Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) 6 on water to support water related research, innovation and technology transfer. Mahjabeen said Bangladesh is committed to remain in the forefront of the international community's efforts in building a water secured world for the entire humanity. Referring to the forthcoming Budapest Water Summit 2016, the parliamentarian said Bangladesh would advocate efficient governance and management of water resources, access to less water-intensive technologies and crop varieties, and integrated management of shared river basins. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh34" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="October 31, 2016 Monday"source="Energy & Power" >
On 28 September, Ministers and Heads of Delegation from the Least Developed Countries (LDC) Group welcomed a new initiative designed to scale up renewable energy and energy efficiency for the world's poorest and least developed countries. The new initiative, called the "LDC Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency Initiative (REEEI) for Sustainable Development", is to be launched at the next UN climate change conference to be held in Marrakech this November. "This Initiative is a bold, collaborative effort by the LDCs to drive the global charge towards clean, renewable energy future. It will enable LDCs to leapfrog fossil fuel based energy by providing modern, clean, resilient energy systems that will generate prosperity and safeguard our futures," said the Chair of the LDC Group, Tosi MpanuMpanu. Mr. Mpanu-Mpanu presented the Initiative to LDC Ministers and Heads of Delegation, which was met by broad support. "The adoption of the Paris Agreement and Sustainable Development Goals are propelling the world towards a phase of global action and implementation. The LDC REEEI is an important part of this process, providing concrete action to address climate change while empowering the world's most vulnerable communities" said Mr. Mpanu-Mpanu. "Most of the world's 1.3bn energy-starved people live in LDCs. The LDC REEEI will ensure no LDC is left behind by strengthening the capacity of African LDCs to take advantage of the Africa Renewable Energy Initiative, while providing similar support structures for Asian and other LDCs." The Ministerial meeting was one of a number of discussions held during the gathering of LDC negotiators in Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo, in preparation for COP22 . The meeting provided an important opportunity for the LDCs to share knowledge and expertise and to further elaborate their common needs and interests in the lead up to the negotiations. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh35" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="August 20, 2016 Saturday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Speakers at a seminar on Saturday urged the Bangladeshi delegation to raise cross-border implications of climate-induced displacement at both the upcoming SAARC Islamabad summit and the UN-sponsored Climate Conference in Marrakesh. The SAARC summit is scheduled to be held in Islamabad in December, while the Conference of Parties ( CoP 22 under the UN banner is scheduled to commenc e during the last week o November the Marrakesh, the capital of Morocco. Today's seminar titled 'Climate Issues in CoP 22 and Islamabad SAARC Summit' was held at the CIRDAP Auditorium in the city jointly organized by Climate Action Network South Asia (CANSA), Christian Aid, Campaign for Sustainable Rural Livelihood (CSRL), Oxfam International, COAST and EquityBD. Dr Hasan Mahmud, MP, chairman of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on Environment and Forest Ministry, was present as the chief guest in the seminar chaired by Dr Qazi Kholiquzzaman Ahmad, Chairman PKSF. The seminar was moderated by Rezaul Karim Chowdhury of COAST. Other guest speakers were Sanjay Vahsist of CANSA, Dr Atiq Rahman of BCAS, Badi Akhter from Oxfam and Ms Sharmind Neelormi of CSRL. Mujibul Haque Munir of Equitybd has presented the key note presentation in the seminar. In the keynote presentation Mujibul Haque Munir mentioned that Bangladesh must take the opportunity of SAARC summit to raise the cross boarder perspective of climate displacement issue in SAARC summit. In his speech, Badi Akhter pleaded that Bangladesh delegation in CoP 22 Marrakech must raise the issue of insurance in Loss and Damage. Ms Sharmind Neelormi of Oxfam CSRL urged that Bangladesh government should not feel shy to raise joint river management issues in SAARC. She also urged that while Bangladesh is one of the highest remittance sender countries to the India, then India must consider accepting Bangladeshi climate migrants. Mr. Sanjay Vahsist, Director CANSA said that there is a need of strong civil society mobilization in SAARC countries especially in India to go for regional level water management and management of climate induced displacement. In his speech, Dr Hasan Mahmud mentioned that Bangladesh's gains from previous climate conferences in Durban and Cancun over the 2issue that have to be again placed in CoP 22 Marrakech. He also urged redefining th UN refugee convention in view of climate-induceddisplacement. He criticized GCF, as majority fund channeling through multilateral financial institution whose basic objectives to gain profit. Dr Qazi Kholiquzzaman, opined that although Bangladesh havs to be very active in Marrakech and Islamabad SAARC summit but Bangladesh should not wait for external assistance, the country has to proceed its own too. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh36" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 29, 2016 Tuesday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
A group of eight rights-based civil society networks on Monday demanded forming an Independent Climate Change Commission to address the problems caused by greenhouse gas emission. The demand was made at a press conference at the Jatiya Press Club. Noting that the Environment and Forests Ministry should not handle the issue of climate change and international negotiations, the group said, 'An Independent Climate Change Commission should deal with the issues.' They also voiced their deep concern and frustration over the outcome of the recently held COP 22 , Marrakech Climate Conference, as it failed to fulfill the needs and demands of the Least Developed Courtiers (LDCs) and Most Vulnerable Countries (MVCs), and work out a roadmap for implementation of the Paris Climate Agreement. The press conference titled 'Outcome of the COP 22 : Analysis and proposal from civil society' was jointly organised by Bangladesh Poribesh Andolan (BAPA), Bangladesh Climate Journalist Forum (BCJF), Bangladesh Indigenous Peoples on Climate Change and Bio Diversity (BIPNetCCBD), Climate Change Development Forum (CCDF), Coastal Development Partnership (CDP), CSRL, EquityBD and FEJB. Speaking at the programme, BCJF president and Jatiya Press Club general secretary Quamrul Islam Chowdhury said though the COP 22 was supposed to decide eight specific agenda, only one decision was taken. 'That's why we're very frustrated over its outcome.' He said transparency and accountability must be ensured in using the climate change fund to get financial support from different international funds. 'Or else, we won't able to get fund from international bodies to face the challenges of the climate change.' Rezaul Karim Chowdhury of EquityBd said Bangladeshi negotiation team has some brilliant and capable government officers, but there was clear lack of political guidance, which has weakened Bangladesh's position in the conference. 'We think climate change is not an issue of the Environment and Forests Ministry. We demand an Independent Climate Change Commission in this regard like Philippines one. We also demand the Prime Minister lead the climate negotiation process.' \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh37" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="May 15, 2016 Sunday"source="Energy & Power" >
Bangladesh signed the historic "Paris Climate Agreement" at the United Nations in New York on April 22. Minister for Environment and Forests Anwar Hossain Manju signed the deal, which was signed by a total of 175 countries in the presence of highlevel delegations. The signing day coincided with 'International Mother Earth Day'. Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina had assigned the minister to sign the agreement for Bangladesh. Bangladesh's statement at the event highlighted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's personal commitment to combating climate change, and reaffirmed her government's readiness to continue working towards mobilizing greater international efforts in support of comprehensively implementing the Paris Agreement. "Collective wisdom and commitments are essential to implement the Paris Climate Agreement...we all must consider the urgency of acting now," the statement reads. Bangladesh also flagged the various initiatives taken by the government to adapt to climate change in a pro-active manner through its own resources and international cooperation. It was particularly mentioned that a roadmap for implementing Bangladesh's Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC) was currently in the making. Bangladesh urged all countries to be united in our collective journey, keeping in mind that one's non-compliance may threaten the existence of all. However, developed countries have to take lead in this case. Following the signing of the agreement, the Bangladesh minister exchanged greetings with UN Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon and UNFCCC Executive Secretary Cristiana Figueres. Manju also had a bilateral meeting with Fatma Gulmedet Sari, Minister for Environment and Urbanization of Turkey. The two ministers agreed to work together during the lead up to UNFCCC COP22 in Morocco in November 2016 to promote issues of common interest, with focus on climate vulnerable LDCs. Dr Hasan Mahmud, the Chairman of the Parliamentary Standing Committee on the Ministry of Environment and Forests and Masud Bin Momen, Ambassador and Permanent Representative of Bangladesh to the UN in New York, accompanied the minister. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh38" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 13, 2016 Sunday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Global climate experts have lauded Bangladesh's efforts to cut carbon emissions and said the country can be an example for many developing and least developed nations to be followed by. They said Bangladesh deserves special appreciations from the global community as it has taken various steps to reduce carbon emissions to cope with the climate change impact though the country's contribution to the global volume of greenhouse gas emissions is very negligible. The experts also said Bangladesh is much more ahead than many other developing countries in terms of carbon emission reduction and building a low-carbon and climate resilient future. They came up with the observations at a seminar held here on the sidelines of Marrakech Climate Conference ( COP22 ). Bangladesh and German Development Organisation GIZ arranged the event joined by experts and representatives from Namibia, Mexico, Vietnam and Bangladesh. Representatives of the participating country presented their carbon emission-cutting plans and shared their experiences and views at the programme chaired by Dr Kamal Uddin Ahmed, secretary Ministry of Environment and Forest of Bangladesh. The Mexican representative said their country has taken both the adaptation and mitigation policy to tackle the climate change impact. The Vietnam delegation said their country is yet to work out any action plan to lessen carbon emissions, but they are implementing some small projects to cope with the bad impacts of climate change. A Namibia representative said they have made a master plan to curb greenhouse gas emissions, but they are facing financial and capacity crisis to implement it. Kamal Uddin said Bangladesh is very concerned over the rise in global temperature caused by greenhouse gas emissions as the country is one of the worst victims of it. Mentioning that it is not possible to tackle climate change impact only by adaptation policy, he said the developed nations should give more focus on cutting carbon emissions. The environment secretary said Bangladesh's capacity to face climate change impact has enhanced as the country has spent nearly $400 million on its own initiative in this regard. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh39" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 23, 2016 Wednesday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 23 -- Transparency Intern-ational Bangladesh (TIB) on Wednesday urged the government not to accept the climate fund as credit since it is supposed to come as compensation from the industrially developed countries. "There is no reason for receiving the climate fund as credit because the top carbon emitting nations have already pledged their support as compensation," TIB executive director (ED) Dr Iftekharuzzaman told a press conference at the TIB conference hall in the city. The anti-corruption agency organised the event to find out Bangladesh's accessibility to climate fund and urge the authorities to ensure transparency in utilising the money, following the climate change conference ( Cop22 ) that concluded on November 18 in Marrakech, Morocco. Mr Iftekhar explained that the people of Bangladesh, who are the victims of the impacts of the climate change caused by green house gas (GHG) emissions by the developed nations, will suffer in the long run if the government receives the credit even at a very lower rate of interest or for a long duration. "The development fund and climate fund are two different matters . Amalgamation of these two will hamper both the schemes," he said, urging the government to address the issues separately and efficiently. In accordance with the agreements signed in the global climate conferences, he said, the climate funds are totally separate and additional to other financial aid for the victim nations like Bangladesh. "This issue was not clearly explained in the just concluded Marrakech conference," he noted. Mr Iftekhar expressed concern over some international agencies' efforts in convincing the government for accepting the climate fund as credit and expected that the government would not be entrapped into the schemes offered by international lending agencies. "We have legitimate right to ask for compensation from the polluter nations as per the agreements," he added. Senior program manager of TIB's Climate Finance Governance Unit M. Zakir Hossain Khan said the fund for the Bangladesh Climate Change Trust (BCCT) has been decreasing every year. It received Tk 7.0 billion in each of the first three years after it was initiated in fiscal year (FY) 2009-10. In last fiscal year, the amount was fixed at Tk 1.0 billion only. The allocation for the Bangladesh Climate Change Resilience Fund (BCCRF) remains suspended, affecting the adaptation activities, he said. The developed nations renewed their commitment in the Marrakech conference to increase annual financing to US$100 billion by the year 2020 to support climate vulnerable poor countries for implementing the adaptation and mitigation programmes. HYPERLINK mailto:Saif.febd@gmail.com Saif.febd@gmail.com Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh40" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 22, 2016 Tuesday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 22 -- World Bank (WB) President Jim Yong Kim, during his Dhaka trip on October 16-17, 2016 announced a major investment to help Bangladesh adapt to climate change. Under the plan, the bank would invest US$ 2 billion in the next three years in climate change projects. The WB pledge by was made in the run-up to the COP22 in Marrakech, Morocco during November 7-18, 2016. Heads of state and government from 80 countries and senior ministers from 115 countries participated in the event. Sea level rise, salinity, and extreme weather events have pushed the issue of climate change to the top of the agenda of most countries. As the Paris climate agreement enters into force, now is the time for actual action on the ground, as stressed by Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina at COP22 . Bangladesh is one of the most climate vulnerable countries in the world where climate change will affect a large section of the population. According to the Climate Risk Index 2015, Bangladesh was among the top six countries most affected by climate change during 1994-2013. Climate change is estimated to reduce the agricultural GDP of Bangladesh by more than 3 per cent during 2005-2050. The country is seeing an influx of climate refugees in the already overstretched capital city Dhaka. For countries like Bangladesh, adaptation rather than mitigation is the core issue. As prescribed by the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC), many countries have made national adaptation action plans and strategies to fight climate change. For its part, the Bangladesh government has taken climate change issue seriously. The country was among the first signatories in international protocols. Bangladesh made many rules, laws, plans, and policies to tackle climate change with support from international organisations like the UNFCCC and the World Bank. A National Adaptation Programme of Action (NAPA) was developed in 2005 focusing on immediate and urgent adaptation issues. The NAPA was further updated in 2009 and it identified 45 adaptation measures with 18 immediate and medium-term adaptation measures. In 2008, the Bangladesh Climate Change Strategy and Action Plan (BCCSAP) was developed and was updated in 2009. Many committees and units within the government and trust fund were created to take the issue seriously. Bangladesh mobilises its efforts to implement the BCCSAP through the twin funds: the Bangladesh Climate Change Resilience Fund (BCCRF) and the Bangladesh Climate Change Trust Fund (BCCTF). The former has a few hundred million US dollars from countries like the UK, Sweden, Australia, Denmark and others, while the latter has a few hundred million from own resources. Bangladesh is the first country to set up Climate Change Trust Fund of $400 million from its own resources. As of June 2016, 440 projects have been undertaken by the Bangladesh Climate Change Trust Fund. A core problem with mainstream adaptation thinking and action is that adaptation is often seen as a 'technical fix' to be embedded onto on-going development plans. Inderberg et al (2015) shows in book 'Climate Change Adaptation and Development' that the lens of community participation is often condoned in climate adaptation projects rolled out within the existing framework of top-down development planning and implementation. As of now, Bangladesh is generally perceived as a pioneer in the emerging developing field of Community-Based Adaptation (CBA). The tenth International CBA gathering was held in Bangladesh in April 2016 which highlighted the increasingly important issue of urban community adaptation. Bangladesh showcases success in disaster management programme including early warning system, construction of cyclone shelters and river weeds cultivation etc. As World Bank President Kim said, "Bangladesh has been a forerunner in adaptation and stronger disaster-coping mechanisms and these have reduced the impact of recent storms, cyclones, and floods." It needs to be stressed here that a core factor behind this success is the fact that the technical and infrastructural components of disaster management were complemented by a focus on community-based disaster response system. Although the BCCSAP time and again highlights the success of Bangladesh in community-based approach, the document itself focuses more on the technical and infrastructural aspects than the social and political aspects of community-based adaptation. Research and knowledge management envisioned in the BCCSAP does not clarify whether and how the advanced knowledge and know-how of the experts will blend with the local-level knowledge and know-how of ordinary community members. Creating, fostering and disseminating knowledge on climate change adaptation needs to be based on a trans-disciplinary and participatory approach. A salutary aspect of the strategy is the inclusion of gender lens in framing the adaptation programmes. The BCCSAP programme for awareness raising and public education as well as the programme for strengthening human capital may be expanded to ensure local capacity-building, stronger participation and two-way knowledge exchange for fruitful cooperation across international, national, and local scales on adaptation. For food security programme, the local coping strategies of most fragile groups need to be integrated with the adaptation strategy proffered by experts and stakeholders. In the same vein, the NAPA's priority list of 38 measures focuses more on the immediate, pressing issues. The immediate interventions need to synthesize with longer-term issues, such as submergence of the coastal area by 2050. Introduction of drought or flood-resistant crops and salinity-proof crops is an important step forward, but such steps need to be aligned with local realities such as shrimp and crab-firming, the landholding patterns, and local power relations. Climate change adaptation needs as much hardware (infrastructure and technology), software (knowledge and know-how), as it needs orgware (organisational and institutional aspects, networks, and so on). A core issue with the climate change adaptation strategy in Bangladesh is policy harmonisation. Different thematic, multi-sectoral and sectoral policies, plans and strategies often lack synchrony and coordination. Sectoral policies rather than national climate change strategies drive the preparation process. The Power Sector Master Plan 2010 of Bangladesh was planned after NAPA and BCCSAP. But reflection of these policies in making this master plan was inadequate. According to this plan, fuel composition ratio in electricity generation as of 2030 would be 50 per cent to coal. Coal-based power plant is anticipated to increase the amount of CO2 emission. The BCCSAP merely mentions that there would be clean coal technologies. Developed countries are shelving off coal-based power plants and replacing them by renewable energy. The Bangladesh government should also follow their footsteps and make plans and policies in transiting towards a more climate-friendly growth path. The world is closely keeping tabs on how Bangladesh as an adaptation pioneer goes forward handling environmental change. The pledge of the World Bank is certainly an important step in strengthening international financial support to help the South Asian country adapt to the all-too-real hazards of climate change. However, a number of analysts point out that Bangladesh should seek grant rather than loan as its legitimate claim from polluters. The message is: Bangladesh needs to secure its due share of support that the international community is bound to extend. Within itself, Bangladesh needs to ensure across-the-board commitment towards continuity of policy and strategies for climate change adaptation so that the future of our progeny are not held hostage to political vicissitudes. HYPERLINK mailto:nafiz@n9sports.com nafiz@n9sports.com Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh41" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 18, 2016 Friday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Rights groups have expressed their concern over the indecisions of the developed countries in respect to enhancing mitigation ambitions, saying their actions in Marrakech climate conference will lead to climate genocide in LDCs and MVCs. Several rights groups representing the least developed countries and most vulnerable countries expressed the dismay at a press conference in Marrakech in Morocco on Thursday, according to a message received here on Friday afternoon. Moderated by Rezaul Karim Chowdhury of EquityBD Bangladesh, other speakers of the press conference were Ziaul Haque Mukta of CSRL Bangladesh, Azeb Girmi from ENDA, Ethiopia and LDC Watch Brussels, and Justine Ginnetti of IDMC (International Displacement Monitoring Center), Geneva. In their group position paper, they said indecisions of the rich countries in respect to enhancing mitigation ambitions, very little or no financing commitment in respect to financing, especially for adaptation and loss and damages, and inaction about climate-induced displacement from this conference will lead to genocide in LDCs and MVCs. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh42" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="April 30, 2017 Sunday"source="Energy & Power" >
Tahzingdong, a non-governmental voluntary organization working on issues of the environment and socioeconomic development in the Chittagong Hill Tracts (CHT), has won the Energy Globe Award in Earth category at the COP22 . Tahzingdong has won the award for its project on the restoration and conservation of communitymanaged forest resources in the Bandarban hill district. The award was declared on November 10, 2016 in Marrakech, Morocco, at COP22 -the 22nd Conference of the Parties to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). Founder of Energy Globe Foundation Wolfgang Neumann handed over the award to the Tahzingdong authority at a program on March 17 this year. To inform people about winning of the award and the project, the organization held a press conference at a local hotel on Sunday with CHT Affairs Secretary Nabo Bikram Kishor Tripura as chief guest. Vice-Chairman of CHT Development Board Tarun Kumar Ghosh, Executive Director of Aranyak Foundation of Bangladesh Farid Uddin Ahmed and Executive Director of Tahzingdong Ching Shing Pru were present there. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh43" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 19, 2016 Saturday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 19 -- The next head of the UN global climate talks has appealed for the US to "save" Pacific islands from the impacts of global warming. Fijian Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama said that the islands needed the US now as much as they did during World War Two. He was speaking as global climate talks in Marrakech came to an end. Mr Bainimarama said that climate change was not a hoax, as US President-elect Donald Trump has claimed. Mr Trump has promised to pull the US out of the Paris Climate Agreement and scrap all payments for UN global warming projects. But as he accepted the role of president of the Conference of the Parties for the year ahead, the Fijian leader took the opportunity to call on the next US president to step away from his scepticism. "I again appeal to the President-elect of the US Donald Trump to show leadership on this issue by abandoning his position that man-made climate change is a hoax," said Mr Bainimarama. "On the contrary, the global scientific consensus is that it is very real and we must act more decisively to avoid catastrophe." He also made a direct call to the American people to come to their aid in the face of rising seas, driven by global warming. "We in the Pacific, in common with the whole world, look to America for the leadership and engagement and assistance on climate change just as we looked to America in the dark days of World War Two. "I say to the American people, you came to save us then, and it is time for you to help save us now." After two weeks of talks in Marrakech, participants arrived at a consensus on the next steps forward for the landmark climate treaty. This gathering saw the opening of CMA1, the Conference of the Parties meeting as the signatories of the Paris Agreement, which aims to limit global temperature rises. CMA1 will be the formal UN body that will run, manage and set the rules for the operation of the Paris treaty. The number of countries who have ratified the agreement jumped above 100 with the UK joining during the last few days of the conference. "Delegates in Marrakech made crucial progress in building the foundation to support the Paris agreement, which went into force just days before COP22 ," said Paula Caballero from the World Resources Institute. "Most importantly, negotiators agreed to finalise the rules of the Paris Agreement by 2018 and developed a clear roadmap to meet that deadline." US secretary of state John Kerry gave an impassioned speech in Marrakech, his last climate conference while in office The participants also agreed the Marrakech Proclamation, a statement re-affirming the intentions of all 197 signatories to the Paris deal. Seen as show of unity on the issue in the light a possible US withdrawal, countries stated they would live up to their promises to reduce emissions. The proclamation also called on all states to increase their carbon cutting ambitions, urgently. Some of the poorest nations in the world announced that they were moving towards 100 per cent green energy at this meeting. The Climate Vulnerable Forum said that the 47 member countries, including Bangladesh, Ethiopia and Yemen, would achieve this goal between 2030 and 2050. And they challenged richer countries to do the same. Despite these steps forward there were still some areas of significant difference between the parties, especially over money. The talks will continue in 2017 with a new the US delegation picked by the Trump administration. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh44" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 2, 2016 Wednesday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 2 -- Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina will join Conference of Parties 22 ( COP 22 ) to be held in Morocco this month. Foreign Minister AH Mahmood Ali, Environment and Forest Minister Anwar Hossain Manju and Water Resources Minister Anisul Islam Mahmud will accompany the PM. The world climate conference will be held in Marrakash city of Morocco on November 7-18. A letter, issued from Prime Minister's Office (PMO) on Tuesday, reached the Ministry of Foreign Affairs on Wednesday. The letter said that the prime minister will join the environment summit with three ministers and six government officials and attend its high-level segment on November 15 and 16, according to a news agency. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh45" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 17, 2016 Thursday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 17 -- Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina has returned home on Thursday morning wrapping up her three-day official visit to Marrakech, a former imperial city in western Morocco, to attend two high-level segments of the Conference of the Parties ( COP-22 ). On Tuesday, Sheikh Hasina delivered her statement at the high-level segments of COP-22 where she urged global leaders to fight together the perilous threats of climate change and share the burdens equally for fulfilling the promises to make the world a safer place for the future generation. COP-22 , which began on November 7 and to run through November 18 in Bab Ighli of Marrakech, is the first such meeting since the historic adoption of the Paris Agreement at COP 21 in December last year; according to a news agency. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh46" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 2, 2016 Wednesday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
The World Climate Summit, 22nd Session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP 22 ), will be held in Marrakech city of Morocco on November 7-18. The technical negotiation of the conference will be held on November 7-14 while the high-level segment on November 15-17. Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina will attend the high-level segment of the conference along with heads of governments, ministers or equivalent representatives from 191 countries. Environment and Forests Minister Anwar Hossain Manju came up with the information while speaking at a press briefing arranged ahead of the upcoming COP 22 at the Secretariat on Wednesday. The COP 22 is also known as 'Implementation COP', the minister said, adding that the main objective of this year's conference is to fix strategies for implementing the Paris Climate Agreement. Bangladesh delegation will place their action plan at the conference. Besides, an exhibit booth will be set up for showcasing success of Bangladesh in combating the climate change, he said. Manju said Bangladesh earlier signed the landmark Paris Agreement on April 22 and ratified it on September 21 last. The agreement was adopted in Paris in 2015. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh47" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="February 9, 2017 Thursday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Feb. 9 -- Bangladesh submitted its climate action plan called as Intended Nationally Determined Contribution (INDC) to the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) well in advance in September 2015. This was submitted for a new universal climate change agreement which is called "Paris Agreement" agreed upon by the participant countries, at the UN Climate Conference in Paris, in December 2015. The Paris agreement will come into effect in 2020, empowering all countries to act to prevent average global temperatures rising above 2 degrees Celsius and to reap the many opportunities that arise from a necessary global transformation to clean and sustainable development. Bangladesh signed the historic Paris Climate Agreement at the UN headquarters in New York on April 22, 2016, aiming to take multiple measures to save the world from disastrous consequences of climate change. During the signing ceremony, Bangladesh highlighted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's personal commitment to combating climate change, and reaffirmed her government's readiness to continue to work towards mobilising greater international efforts in support of comprehensively implementing the Paris Climate Agreement, where collective wisdom and commitments are essential. Bangladesh requested the world leaders to consider the urgency of acting immediately. Bangladesh also flagged the various initiatives taken by the government to adapt to climate change in a pro-active manner through its own resources and international cooperation. It emphasised on the need to prepare the roadmap for implementing INDC. Bangladesh pointed out that all the countries need to be united in this collective journey, keeping in mind that one's non-compliance may threaten the existence of all. We have also urged the developed countries to take the lead in implementing Paris Agreement. Bangladesh also agreed to work together with Turkey during the lead-up to UNFCCC COP22 in Morocco until November 2016 to promote the issues of common interests, with focus on climate vulnerable LDCs. MAJOR INITIATIVES TO FIGHT CLIMATE CHANGE: In addition to Bangladesh Climate Change Trust Fund (BCCTF), Bangladesh has formulated Climate Change Strategy and Action Plan (BCCSAP) in 2009. The BCCSAP is currently being updated by Ministry of Environment and Forests to make the strategies and actions more compatible to the changing scenarios of Climate Change impacts for Bangladesh. The Ministry of Environment and Forests also formulated Country Investment Plan (CIP) for the next five years in the field of Forestry, Environment and Climate Change. This will provide investment guidelines to the areas for next five years keeping the adaptation, mitigation in mind. Bangladesh recognises climate change as a long-term development challenge and has made significant efforts in adapting to climate change through its long-term strategy, the National Sustainable Development Strategy (NSDS), 2010-2021 and medium-term plans i.e., 6th and 7th Five Year Plans. Climate Change impacts will perhaps be most crucial for water, agriculture and food security issues and will ultimately affect the livelihoods of the people in a quite significant way than they affect other sectors. It is envisaged that more concerted efforts are needed to mainstream adaptation in development planning. While adaptation is a priority, Bangladesh should also continue its efforts on Green Growth by embracing environment-friendly practices which brings considerable co-benefits. Adaptation and environment-friendly water management and agricultural production require a long-term comprehensive policy framework with incentives for private sector action and provision of optimum financial resources. Keeping these in mind, General Economics Division (GED), Bangladesh Planning Commission is formulating "Bangladesh Delta Plan 2100" to ensure long-term water and food security, economic growth and environmental sustainability while effectively coping with natural disasters, addressing climate change and other delta issues through robust, adaptive and integrated strategies, and equitable water governance. Bangladesh Delta Plan 2100 would be an instrument to address the long term impacts of uncertainty of climate change and would contribute to sustained economic growth of the country. INVOLVEMENT OF BUSINESS COMMUNITY: It is understood that the Paris Agreement on climate change is very wide in its scope and will define the global economy of the 21st century, and has immediate impact on businesses around the world. This is also true for Bangladesh. Previous attempts to negotiate a universal agreement on climate change have either failed or resulted in a limited set of countries taking on modest greenhouse gas emissions reductions without a clear process for improving them over time. In contrast, the global community is now acting in unison and agreeing to do so for decades to come. The Paris Agreement provides for universal climate action by all countries including all major emitters, the industrialised nations, major emerging economies and the community of developing countries. The Paris Agreement has implications for the global environment and for the global economy. Just a few years ago, up to 4.80C of global warming was projected for the end of the century, which might create an "uninsurable world". The emissions reductions agreed in Paris now draw projected warming down to 2.70C, still dangerous for nature and humankind but a genuine commitment to safeguard the global environment. Crucially, a thriving clean economy is created in that space between 4.80C and 2.70C. Collectively, the national climate plans under the Paris Agreement represent at least a USD 13.5 trillion market for the energy sector alone through 2030. Low carbon investment in energy supply, infrastructure, buildings, manufacturing, transport and land use to implement the national climate plans brought under the Paris Agreement runs into trillions of dollars. Paris is also immediate in its impact on businesses and investors. The national climate plans are now being translated into domestic regulations. China recently integrated its climate targets into its 13th Five-Year Plan. The marketplace is also responding to the signals from Paris. Before governments return in 2020 to update or submit new national climate plans, climate action by businesses and investors has the potential to course-correct global emissions and help put the world on track to well below 20C of warming. Paris now calls to businesses and investors to accelerate the transition to a thriving clean economy by leveraging policy certainty and seizing trillions of dollars in investment opportunities. It is time to respond to this call. For Bangladesh, following are the areas where business communities and investors could invest for combating the climate change impacts as well as help the government to implement the Paris Agreement: (a) Energy Fuel Combustion (Energy industries, Manufacturing industries and Construction, Transport, Commercial/ Institutional, Residential, Agriculture/ Forestry/Fishing, and Other) Fugitive emissions from fuels (b) Industrial processes and product use (c) Agriculture with green growth practices (d) Land Use, Land-Use Change and Forestry (LULUCF) (e) Waste Gases:CO2, CH4, N2O, HFCs, PFCs, SF6 and NF3 Coverage: 100 per cent Side by side, Public-Private Partnership potentialities could be explored in the above areas where government and business community can work together locally or internationally to achieve the target set under Paris Agreement. Dr. Shamsul Alam is Member (Senior Secretary), General Economics Division, Bangladesh Planning Commission. HYPERLINK sabau47@yahoo.com Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh48" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 16, 2016 Wednesday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 16 -- Bangladesh has formally joined the International Solar Alliance (ISA) through signing up the Framework Agreement on ISA on Tuesday. Deputy Minister for Environment and Forests Abdullah Al Islam Jakob signed the agreement on behalf of the government in a ceremonial programme held during the Conference of Parties 22 ( COP 22 ) in Marrakech, Morocco. Signing of the ISA Framework Agreement has reiterated the firm commitment of the government towards further promoting renewable energy, more particularly solar energy, said a statement of the Foreign Ministry received in Dhaka on Wednesday. This also reflects the visionary leadership and strong determination of Prime Minister in tackling adversities of climate change and its resultant impacts, it added. Joining the ISA will widen the opportunities for Bangladesh to collaborate with other member of this Alliance in the areas of solar technology, finance, research, innovation and development as well as capacity building. International Solar Alliance is a global platform for cooperation among solar-rich countries, which was launched at the Climate Summit in Paris on 30th November 2015, according to UNB. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh49" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 24, 2016 Thursday"source="Dhaka Courier" >
Dhaka, Nov. 24 -- The Industrial Revolution is largely blamed for climate change that is almost self-evident in today's world. However, it is revealed that pre-industrial deforestation caused about 9 percent of today's global warming. Humans started this change long before the Industrial Revolution, when machines changed our ancestors' way of life, in the beginning of the fossil fuel era. A study shows that these emissions are still present in the atmosphere. Deforestation started as the world's population grew. Today the world is coming to a consensus on a "polluter pays" model, that means the biggest emitters take on the biggest role to mitigate the effects of climate change. Some people want to put the burden on China for developments that date as far back as the ninth century. Some point fingers at some other Asian countries too. In Bangladesh we lost our best rain forests either for tea or for timber. Our northeastern part, greater Sylhet area, is well known as the humid tropics. The best part of these humid tropics has been cleared for tea plantation. Our southeastern part, greater Chittagong and the Chittagong Hill Tracts area, has 'rain' forests, which were cleared mainly for teak plantation. These two valuable commodities were mainly used by non-natives! Once I was told that a 12-year-old British boy, Durrel, wrote to Mahathir Muhammad, the then premier of Malaysia, requesting him not to clear the rainforests, so that he (Durrel) could enjoy greater biodiversity and wildlife once he grew up. I understand that Mahathir reacted sharply and wrote: "The people, who asked you to write this letter - request them to pay more for our timber so that we don't cut more trees and grow more palms!" If we need to deal with responsibility, we have to keep per capita emissions in mind. The 'rich' have to pay for their oversized contributions to global warming. If we consider the data from 1900-2004: the US has contributed by far the lion's share, in the form of 314,772 m metric tonnes of carbon dioxide. That is well over four times the top European contributor, Germany (73,625 mt). Some other countries that may be of interest to us include the UK on 55,163mt, India 25,054mt, Brazil 9,136mt, Indonesia 6,167mt and China 89,243mt. Bangladesh's historical contribution stands at an almost negligible 562mt. One has to bear in mind that emissions started before this data was calculated. UK, having spawned the Industrial Revolution, may be held chiefly responsible for the emissions in the 19th century. As 2015 drew to a close, the international family of nations gathered in Paris, and against the odds, managed to agree a deal finally to deal with greenhouse gases emissions, through a program of mitigation and adaptation. The finance will start to flow in 2020. The Paris deal, as it came to be known, is regarded as the world's first comprehensive climate agreement. The following are its principal aims: Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina attended the Conference of Parties ( COP22 ) of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC), held in Marrakech, Morocco this year. There she rightly mentioned that the Paris Agreement created a solid ground for meaningful cooperation in combating climate change impacts. She felt that this is the time to move forward and implement the decisions with action. She called upon all the countries of the world to throw in their lot, in order "to share equitably the burden to fulfill our promises of making the world a safe and better place for our future generations." Under the prime minister's able leadership, Bangladesh has already taken a few initiatives by spending our own resources through the Bangladesh Climate Change Resilience Fund (BCCRF). She communicated this to the world leaders during her stay at the summit, and it would have acted as a powerful message to world leaders that the country most affected by climate change can no longer wait around for their issues to play out. The time to act is now. Published by HT Syndication with permission from Dhaka Courier. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh50" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 15, 2016 Tuesday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 15 -- Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina was given red carpet reception as she arrived there yesterday afternoon on a three-day official visit to Morocco. The Prime Minister left Dhaka to join the climate summit attending by 197 country Parties including more than 50 head of governments and states. COP-22 of the United Nation Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) is being held at Morocco's former imperial city Marrakech. Biman flight carrying the premier and her entourage members landed at Menara Airport at 4:45 pm local time yesterday. Minister of National Education and Vocational Training of Morocco Rachid Belmokhtar Benabdellah, Bangladesh Ambassador in Morocco Sultana Laila Hossain and senior officials of Bangladesh embassy and Morocco government received the Prime Minister at the airport. The Prime Minister was given a static guard of honour. Foreign Minister AH Mahmood Ali, Environment and Forest Minister Anwar Hossain Manju, Water Resources Minister Anisul Islam Mahmud and Deputy Minister of Environment and Forest Abdullah Al Islam Jacob, among others, will accompany the prime minister during her visit to Morocco. Sheikh Hasina is scheduled to return home on November 16, according to a news agency report. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh51" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="September 24, 2016 Saturday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Bangladesh has become the Chair of the Delta Coalition as the Netherlands formally handed over the chairmanship to it. The chairmanship was handed over to Bangladesh Foreign Minister AH Mahmood Ali by the Special Envoy for International Water Affairs of the Netherlands Henk Ovink at a simple ceremony at UNHQ in New York recently. COP 22 It is a government-to-government partnership of currently 12 countries: Bangladesh, Colombia, Egypt, France, Indonesia, Japan, Mozambique, Myanmar, the Netherlands, the Philippines, South Korea and Vietnam, said the Foreign Ministry here on Saturday. The Foreign Minister thanked the government of the Netherlands for this landmark initiative and their active contributions towards giving a concrete shape to the Coalition. Henk Ovink shared the outcomes of the first-ever Ministerial Conference of the Delta Coalition held on May 9-10 in Rotterdam, and expressed the hope that the partnership among the Coalition members will further be strengthened under Bangladesh's chairmanship. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh52" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 30, 2016 Wednesday"source="Energy & Power" >
UN Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon marked the entry into force of the Paris Agreement on November 4 with a call for strong action on climate change to realize the potential of the landmark agreement. Meeting with civil society representatives, the Secretary General said, "I ask each and every one of you to keep up the fight. Hold governments accountable and press for action." "Today we make history in humankind's efforts to combat climate change," he said. "Now is the time to strengthen global resolve, do what science demands and seize the opportunity to build a safer, more sustainable world for all." Members of civil society, representing a range of organizations working around the world, including in Egypt, Bangladesh, Nepal, and Guatemala, told the Secretary General that they were committed to carrying on efforts to reduce emissions and to focus on the needs of people. The Agreement provides that it shall enter into force 30 days after 55 countries, representing 55 percent of global emissions, have deposited their instruments of ratification, acceptance or accession with the Secretary-General. Those conditions were met on 5 October, triggering the entry into force. The Agreement will now enter into force in time for the Marrakech Climate Conference ( COP 22 ) that begins in Morocco on November 7, where the first Meeting of the Parties to the Agreement was opened on November 15. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh53" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 12, 2016 Saturday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
National governments should take a closer look at the ways in which trade can help spread the use of green technologies and therefore to tackle climate change, said Unctad Secretary-General Mukhisa Kituyi. International trade is traditionally seen as the purchase and sale of finished goods, but in fact the vast majority of it involves intermediate and unfinished goods, brought together from different countries for assembly in a single, final location. 'If our goal is to spread the use of green technology, then we have to ease trade within value chains, boost innovation, and help transfer green technology into the developing world,' Mukhisa Kituyi was quoted as saying in a statement received here from Geneva. 'But we have to use trade policy in such a way that we move away from protectionism towards sharing the benefits of a cleaner, greener global economy,' he said. Unctad, the ITC, WTO and IFAD will host a panel discussion at COP 22 in Marrakesh, Morocco on Saturday to discuss the Paris Agreement and the linkages to trade. 'We may come from different nations, but we are one, single global community, and on both climate change and trade, we sink or swim together,' Mukhisa Kituyi said. Liberalising the trade of green goods - by dropping tariffs and addressing non-tariff measures - would facilitate access to these goods, and therefore their use. Mukhisa Kituyi said developing countries, which aim to produce more green goods, may wish to explore ways to enter the relevant value chains. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh54" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 15, 2016 Tuesday"source="Energy & Power" >
Climate experts here recently called for strengthening bargaining capacity of Least Developed Countries (LDCs) like Bangladesh through acquiring knowledge on different aspects of climate change issue to avert its possible harmful impacts. LDCs must be united by developing strong leadership to pile up pressure on industrialized nations to take action to stem the planet's rising temperatures, they told a press conference on " COP 22 Climate Change Conference: Expectation of civil society" at the Jatiya Press Club. Different organizations including Forum of Environmental Journalists of Bangladesh (FEJB), Equity Justice Working GroupBangladesh (EquityBD) and Centre for Sustainable Rural Livelihood (CSRL) organized the press conference. General Secretary of Jatiya Press Club and Chairman of FEJB Quamrul Islam Chowdhury, Chief Moderator of EquityBD M Rezaul Karim Chowdhry and CSRL Secretary Sharmind Neelormi, among others, addressed the press conference. Bangladesh alone cannot face climate change issue as it is a global phenomenon, Quamrul Islam said, adding it should move bilaterally as well as multilaterally along with strong bargaining capacity to pile up pressure on rich nations to extend their financial and technical supports to climate vulnerable countries. Bangladesh is already facing adverse impact of global climate change and it is urgent to raise it voice to get adequate financing supports from green climate fund to make it climate resilient country, she added. A total of 62 countries accounting for almost 52 percent of emissions have now ratified the agreement to commit to take action to stem the planet's rising temperatures. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh55" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="October 7, 2016 Friday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
The UN Environment has said the countries need to move quickly to implement commitments to reducing emissions in their nationally determined contributions submissions. 'The work has just begun,' acting Regional Director, United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP) Regional Office for Asia and the Pacific Isabelle Louis said in a statement. It said the UN Environment will continue to work with Asia-Pacific countries to develop solutions for climate change and stands ready to support countries in realizing their nationally determined contributions, according to a message received here from UNEP on Friday. 'The Asia and the Pacific region made significant contribution towards this milestone, with half the countries in the region, among them major global emitters, having ratified the Paris Agreement,' Louis said. The Paris Agreement, coming into force on November 4, is an important moment in history, Louis said. On October 5, the threshold for entry into force of the Paris Agreement was achieved. The first session of the Conference of the Parties serving as the Meeting of the Parties to the Paris Agreement (CMA1) will take place in Marrakech in conjunction with COP 22 and CMP 12. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh56" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="June 3, 2016 Friday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, June 3 -- Climate change is a much-discussed global topic and has received increased focus after the Paris Agreement scaling up climate action and adaptation activities. COP 21 has brought a new dimension of accommodating different issues in which a significant role has to be played by the private sector where developing and small countries have also obliged themselves to undertake responsibilities. COP 21 is most remarkable as it brings to us the 31-page Paris agreement containing 140 decisions and 29 Articles. There are differences of opinion and political clouts throughout the whole negotiation period, but finally an agreement was reached, full implementation of which will take a year. So far about 200 countries signed the agreement and some of them have already ratified. A significant number of countries including Bangladesh is in the process of ratification. The 22nd session of the COP 22 to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCC) is scheduled to take place on November 7-18, 2016. During COP 22 , parties will, inter alia, begin preparations for entry into force of the Paris Agreement. Now the discussion is going on to have COP 22 as a follow-up of the Paris Agreement signed in December 2015 which is going to be held in Marrakesh, Morocco. It is of course true that achieving an agreement in Paris was no small feat; everyone seems to agree on this that it was difficult to come to an agreement, and what led to an agreement being reached has got a different dimension in which political agenda played a big role. The agreement is non-binding, but everyone is bound to save the planet. Undeveloped or poorer developing countries are also signatories because it promised them money and the main aim was saving the planet or universe. Financial commitment was almost absent but the countries felt there was nothing to be lost in signing it. The agreement, seen as a mark of positive wisdom and containing a long wish list, needs extensive follow-up and stock taking. The developing countries have obligated themselves by agreeing on Intended Nationally Determined Contributions (INDCs). For Bangladesh, it is 5 per cent unconditional by 2030 (Transport, Industry and Energy) and 15 per cent conditional. Bangladesh is one of the highly climate change vulnerable countries and has a natural dependency on agriculture, the main source of employment and it has little to contribute to the global GHG emission reduction. Analysts say although the per capita annual emission in Bangladesh is lower than that of developed countries, it has contributed for INDC and if financial and technological support is available from the international community, the reduction can be up to 15 per cent. Bangladesh has created an example in having these obligations but for showing scientific proof of emission and taking care of the issues of sustainability, it would definitely need support. The national strategy of Bangladesh in the context of INDC has highlighted the importance of adaptation and indicated certain key aspects of its adaptation are needed along with financial implications. Appropriate technology development and deployment are critical in this context. By and large, the state of technology regime remains well below the required levels. Political clout behind the Agreement was present. Big and powerful countries were always on the frontline to advocate their issues. The deal was crafted very intelligently- excluding emission reduction targets and finance in the legally binding part. The deal was a bit disappointment for low- lying small islands which need to bear the fallout of climate change in terms of land loss and migration. As of May 20, 2016, there were 177 signatories to the Paris Agreement. Of these, 17 countries also deposited their instruments of ratification, acceptance or approval accounting in total for 0.04 per cent of the total global greenhouse gas emissions. These are some of the achievements in terms of legal obligation. Fifty five parties to the convention account for 55 per cent of the total green house gas emission. Global average temperature limit to well below 2 degree Celsius and pursuance of 1.5 degree are important. Special priority for LDCs, financing and transparency is also very important for the countries that signed the agreement pledging to 'reach global peaking of greenhouse gas emissions as soon as possible without any specific date. Adaptation, strengthening scientific knowledge on climate change, research and systematic observation would be difficult for LDCs without strong commitment. Adaptation and loss and damage have been left in the dark and no legal actions can be taken. Although the Agreement for the first time recognises the concept of 'loss and damage', it makes it clear that developed countries will not accept liability for climate compensation. There is no mention of non-economic losses although technology transfer is one of the crucial areas for LDCs. Capacity building would require a country- driven approach. Climate-induced displacement was not included in the agreement. LDCs' climate finance was not ensured, external finance mechanism was stringent and ensuring climate justice was left out. Specific measures for parties to de-carbonise their economies are not clear. Finally, how the poor countries will survive remains a big question. Reach the target of 1.5 degrees is not possible through national commitments; many countries and their people need to survive the assaults of a changing climate. Governments, the international community and others need to encourage producers and consumers to drastically contribute to lower emissions. Strong follow-up actions are needed. In the new trade and investment policies, these issues need to be integrated and emphasised. The Bangladesh Climate Change Adaptation Action Plan -2009 would need to be revised in tune with COP 21 agreement. The Bangladesh government has already formed three important committees on Adaptation, INDC and Capacity Building. More private sector representatives should be included in these committees. The country is in the process of ratification and consultation with the private sector consultation is important. The private sector is connected mostly with mitigation (energy efficiency and solar panel), rather than adaptation. In case of emission reduction, mass awareness would need to be created to reduce wastages. If an individual wastage reduction is 0 .01 per cent how much we can reduce nationally need to be calculated. The Ministry of Environment and Forests should have more concerns in this regard. Institutionalisation of public-private collaboration and conceptualisation of private sector involvement are very important. The writer is CEO, BUILD. HYPERLINK mailto:ceo_build@outlook.com ceo_build@outlook.com Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh57" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 1, 2016 Tuesday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Over 8,500 children die every year in Bangladesh from diseases caused by household air pollution (HAP) and 89 percent of households use solid fuels - mostly wood, agricultural waste and cow dung - for cooking and space heating. Bangladesh has one of the largest burdens of child mortality associated with indoor air pollution, according to a new Unicef report titled 'Clear the air for children: The impact of air pollution on children.' Seeking to overcome these barriers, the Bangladesh Country Action Plan for Clean Cookstoves is a governmental strategy to achieve the goal of 100 percent clean cooking solutions by 2030. The target is to disseminate improved cookstoves to more than 30 million households by 2030. If this goal is reached, it will significantly reduce the direct and indirect health effects of children's exposure to air pollutants. It will also have a positive impact on women's health and time spent in the kitchen as Bangladeshi women on average spend four to five hours a day on cooking, and six to eight hours a day in the kitchen. Almost one in seven of the world's children, 300 million, live in areas with the most toxic levels of outdoor air pollution - six or more times higher than international guidelines - reveals the new report. Clear the Air for Children uses satellite imagery to show for the first time how many children are exposed to outdoor pollution that exceeds global guidelines set by the World Health Organization (WHO), and where they live across the globe. The findings come a week ahead of the COP 22 in Marrakesh, Morocco, where Unicef is calling on world leaders to take urgent action to cut air pollution in their countries. 'Air pollution is a major contributing factor in the deaths of around 600,000 children under five every year - and it threatens the lives and futures of millions more every day,' said Unicef Executive Director Anthony Lake. 'Pollutants don't only harm children's developing lungs - they can actually cross the blood-brain barrier and permanently damage their developing brains - and, thus, their futures. No society can afford to ignore air pollution.' The satellite imagery confirms that around 2 billion children live in areas where outdoor air pollution, caused by factors such as vehicle emissions, heavy use of fossil fuels, dust and burning of waste, exceeds minimum air quality guidelines set by the World Health Organization. South Asia has the largest number of children living in these areas, at 620 million, with Africa following at 520 million children. The East Asia and Pacific region has 450 million children living in areas that exceed guideline limits. The study also examines the heavy toll of indoor pollution, commonly caused by use of fuels like coal and wood for cooking and heating, which mostly affects children of the low-income groups, in rural areas. Together, outdoor and indoor air pollution are directly linked to pneumonia and other respiratory diseases that account for almost one in 10 under-five deaths, making air pollution one of the leading dangers to children's health. Unicef is asking world leaders attending COP 22 to take four urgent steps in their countries to protect children from air pollution. 'We protect our children when we protect the quality of our air. Both are central to our future,' Lake said. One study on Bangladesh found that children under age 5, regardless of gender, spend an hour a day in cooking areas because of their reliance on their mothers, said the Unicef report. From age 5 to 60, women's hours in cooking areas steadily rise from 1 hour a day to 3.8 hours a day, while men's hours in cooking areas decline from 1 hour a day to 0.2 hours a day. After age 60, women's hours in cooking areas rapidly fall, averaging at 1.5 hours a day. However, women's time in cooking areas beyond the age of 60 still remains higher than men's (averaging at 0.2 hours per day). \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh58" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 29, 2016 Tuesday"source="The New Nation (Bangladesh)" >
Dhaka, Nov. 29 -- The Director of Centre for Energy Research of United International University Shahriar Ahmed Chowdhury achieved the "UN Momentum for Change 2016" award. He was awarded for the project "PV DC Peer-to-Peer Smart Village Grid" at CoP 22 in Marakkesh, Morocco. The research pilot project (ShakibAli Matabbor Kandi village of Jajira Upazilla of Shariatpur district) is the world's first peer-to-peer network to allow energy to be shared between private solar installations. The research project was Co-funded by World Bank and IDCOL, A Bangladesh-German start-up company SOLshare provided the technology and implemented the project and NGO UBOMUS is operating the research pilot project at Shakimali Matborkandi village of Shener Char Union of Jajira upazilla of Shariatpur district. (GPS Co-ordinates of the implemented project site: 23.33180, 90.26893). Published by HT Syndication with permission from The New Nation. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh59" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 22, 2016 Tuesday"source="The New Nation (Bangladesh)" >
Dhaka, Nov. 22 -- The Paris Climate Agreement was hailed around the world as a historic achievement last December. Whether or not it makes history, however, depends on its successful implementation. This is the focus of the 22nd Conference of the Parties ( COP22 ) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) in Marrakesh, which began on Monday (7 November) and runs until 18 November. Being the first COP after the Paris summit in December 2015, the Marrakesh climate conference provides the first serious litmus test for the decisions reached in Paris. The record time in which the Paris Agreement was ratified is an encouraging sign that the international community is serious about climate policy. As such, the accord has come into effect in international law even before the Marrakesh conference. Yet, this does not make the implementation of its content a foregone conclusion. Its transformative ambitions entail a radical departure from business as usual - not least in key policies like energy, agriculture, transport and construction. If we are still to avert the gravest consequences of anthropogenic climate change, then incremental steps will be insufficient. Climate change and climate policy have far-reaching implications affecting virtually all areas of human development, from agriculture and energy supply to the protection of species and migration. Consequently, the Paris Agreement must be implemented in accordance with the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development. And this applies not least with regard to the need to adapt to climate change impacts, which is essential if we are to achieve goals on water supply (SDG 6), infrastructure (SDG 9) and the protection of ecosystems (SDG 15), among others. In accordance with the common but differentiated responsibilities of states for global climate change mitigation and the nationally determined contributions (NDCs) laid out at the Paris summit, each country must now determine its own combination of policies and technologies for effectively integrating the SDGs with its own national development objectives. This requires cool-headed calculation and technocratic planning, but most of all the moderation of political conflicts of interest, especially with regard to national implementation. The current debate on the German NDC is a case for that. In order to provide national and local actors with impetus for the way ahead in successfully implementing the Paris deal, the signatory countries should focus on achieving three things in Marrakesh. First, they should devise binding, long-term strategies for implementing the different issue areas of the Paris Agreement, not least with regard to financing, technology transfer and the promotion of a climate-sensitive global investment policy. Second, they should formulate the mechanisms through which they intend to regularly ratchet up their NDCs in order to achieve the overarching objective of stabilising average global warming at 1.5degC or a maximum of 2degC. Third, they should use the financing roadmap adopted a few weeks ago as a basis for further fleshing out how the pledge already made to provide developing countries with $100 billion annually from 2020 on can be honoured. In particular, they should spell out how sufficient finance will be mobilised for adaptation purposes and how global financial flows can be brought into line with climate-compatible development. Under these conditions, the Paris Agreement can be implemented in a way that truly promotes fundamental global transformation. If, at the same time, the SDGs are implemented in a climate-compatible way, then it will be feasible to decarbonise the world economy in a manner conducive to sustainable global development. Consequently, a particularly promising approach would be to systematically combine ambitious, multilaterally-negotiated goals with a long-term vision, as represented by the Paris Agreement and Agenda 2030 on the one hand, and the numerous initiatives of non-governmental actors on the other. Many companies and NGOs, as well as local actors such as cities, are forging ahead when it comes to innovative climate actions. If this bottom-up dynamic could be better integrated in Marrakesh with the cumbersome processes of UN climate policy and harnessed in the interests of the SDGs, then this would be instrumental for accelerating the transformation towards climate-compatible sustainable development. The obligation here clearly rests with the signatory states, though they are keen to present non-governmental achievements as accomplishments of national implementation. As host of this year's climate summit, Moroccan Environment Minister Hakima El Haite emphasised back in summer at the Petersberg Climate Dialogue that Marrakesh would be the "conference for implementation and support". The time has come to follow up on words with actions. (Steffen Bauer is a political scientist and Clara Brandi is a political scientist and economist at the German Development Institute/Deutsches Institut fur Entwicklungspolitik (DIE), a leading research institution and think tank for global development and international development policy worldwide. This piece was first published on their website). Published by HT Syndication with permission from The New Nation. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh60" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 22, 2016 Tuesday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 22 -- Local Government Initiative on Climate Change (LoGIC), a project aiming to make 0.2 million of the most vulnerable houses in Bangladesh better prepared to adapt to climate change, was launched in Dhaka on Tuesday. Started initially with a budget of US $ 20 million, the project will be implemented in the next four years in 7 most climate vulnerable districts of Bangladesh. Sweden, European Union (EU), United Nations Development Programme (UNDP), United Nations Capital Development Fund (UNCDF) and the Government of Bangladesh will provide the initial US $ 20m fund which will be spent in four years for reducing risks of damages caused by disasters and climate change in the 7 most vulnerable southern districts and prepare them to recover readily from adversity. Speaking at the programme, Senior Secretary of ERD Mohammad Mejbahuddin said, the government of Bangladesh is aware of the severity of the effects of climate change. "When the global leaders have concluded the UN Climate Change Conference ( COP 22 ) in Morocco, here in Bangladesh the UN, the EU and Sweden, joined with the government of Bangladesh to address the country's key climate change priorities set out in the Seventh Five Year Plan," he noted. He hoped that the LoGIC project, using and improving governmental structures, will set a mechanism to allow the local government institutions and vulnerable households direct access to the knowledge, technology and financing necessary to adapt to climate change. "Therefore, projects like LoGIC could be tremendously useful to harness the potential of local community through engaging them in developing the local development plan," he added. Of the initial $ 20m fund, Sweden will provide around $ 9.25m, the EU approximately $ 8,57m, the UNDP and the UNCDF will give $200,000 each, the Bangladesh government to provide BDT 60 million (6 crore. - Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh61" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 10, 2016 Thursday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Rights groups representing Most Vulnerable Countries (MVC) and Least Developed Countries (LDC) urged country delegates to decide the Temperature Peaking Year set out in the Paris Agreement £s soon as possible' to save the planet. Present trend of NDC (nationally determined contribution) will lead to the global temperature of 3.5 degree Celsius and above, which is much above the set temperature of '2 degree Celsius or well below toward 1.5 degree Celsius', as agreed in the Paris Agreement, they said in a press conference on UNFCCC (United Nation Framework on Climate Change Convention) CoP 22 (Conference of Parties), Media Centre in Marrakech of Morocco on Tuesday, according to message received here on Wednesday afternoon. Moderated by Ziaul Haque Mukta of Campaign for Sustainable Rural Livelihood (CSRL), Shamind Neelormi of the same organisation readout the keynote position in the press conference where Sanjay Vahsist of Climate Action Network (CAN) South Asia and Rezaul Karim Chowdhury of Equity and Justice Working Group Bangladesh (EquityBD) also spoke. Sharmind Neelormi said that the term in respect of peaking year which was stated in Paris Agreement £s soon as possible' should be specified in view of common but differentiated responsibilities and respective capacities (CBDRC). He said the 'Temperature Peaking Year' should be set for developed countries will be on 2020; Developing high emitting countries (like for China and India) should be on 2025 and for Developing countries which includes MVCs and LDCs should be 2035. Rezaul Karim Chowdhury said that the Marrakech climate conference has to deliver in respect of Loss and Damage discourse. In particular there should be a work plan from Warsaw Implementation Mechanism (WIM). He said that to recuperate loss and damage due to climate change there should be additional financing in this regard. There must be scope of integration of work on climate induced displacement in WIM process, he added. Ziaul Haque Mukta said that Marrakech must deliver a predictable road map in respect of much committed $100 billion climate finance from 2020 and also financing road map until 2020, which must be additional to other development assistance to the developing countries. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh62" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="October 16, 2016 Sunday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Oct. 16 -- The World Food Day is being observed on Sunday in the country as elsewhere in the world putting emphasis on more investment in rural development. The theme of World Food Day is "Climate is changing. Food and agriculture must too." Different government and non-government organisations have chalked out various programmes, including seminar and colorful rallies to observe the day, reports UNB. Marking the day, Ministry of Agriculture brought out a colourful rally from city's Khamarbari BRC premises this morning and also kicked off a three-day food festival at the BRC premises. Additionally, a seminar was scheduled to be held at BRC auditorium around 10:00am. On the eve of the day, President Abdul Hamid and Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina in separate messages wished success for the Day and its programs. In his message, the President said it is essential to ensure sustainable environment to attain food security for increasing populations from limited lands. "The coordination of sustainable technology is essential in agriculture for building a safe food security for all under changing climate atmosphere." The premier, in her messages, has said climate change and excessive production of food can have variety negative impacts on farm lands. So Bangladesh has to produce more crops through ensuring sustainable agricultural environment. According to Food and Agricultural Organization of the UN, the global population is growing steadily and is expected to reach 9.6 billion by 2050. To meet such a heavy demand, agriculture and food systems will need to adapt to the adverse effects of climate change and become more resilient, productive and sustainable. This is the only way that we can ensure the wellbeing of ecosystems and rural populations and reduce emissions. It resonates with the crucial time in which the day is being observed, just before the next UN Climate Change Conference, COP 22 , from 7-18 November 2016 in Marrakech, Morocco. FAO asked countries to address food and agriculture in their climate action plans and invest more in rural development. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh63" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="April 30, 2017 Sunday"source="Energy & Power" >
The world stood in shock as President Trump signed executive orders rolling back the Clean Power Plan and promoting outdated fossil fuels. While more than 190 countries are moving forward, as they agreed in Paris, towards a clean energy future, President Trump is taking America backwards by signing executive orders that attempt to revive the dirty coal industry that has been lagging since 2010. Grassroots movements and market forces have unleashed the clean energy revolution making it the cheaper, healthier option with the promise to generate the jobs of the future. CAN members and partners, including former US Vice President Al Gore and former UNFCCC Executive Secretary Christiana Figueres react. WWF\' s global Climate and Energy Practice Leader, Manuel-Pulgar Vidal, said:  Hampering the US\' ability to deliver on its international climate commitments will impact the world\' s climate trajectory, but it will not define its outcome.  Our ability to achieve the promise of the Paris Agreement does not rest on the actions of one government alone. At COP22 held in Marrakech last year, French President Holland said the Paris Agreement is an \' irreversible\' process. We agree. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh64" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="December 20, 2016 Tuesday"source="The New Nation (Bangladesh)" >
Dhaka, Dec. 20 -- The poor people in rural areas, particularly in geo-physically hard to reach areas, do not have access to basic and affordable energy for lighting, cooking and livelihood activities, said speakers. Lack of access to sustainable, clean and affordable energy hinders the economic development and livelihoods of the millions, particularly in the rural areas and urban slums, they said. They made the remarks while addressing a sharing workshop on Energy for All, jointly organized by Bangladesh Centre for Advanced Studies (BCAS) and Christian Aid, at Riggs Inn Hotel in the Capital on Monday. The speakers said: "The Goal-7 of the SDGs aims at increasing access to affordable, reliable and sustainable-clean energy for all. To achieve this global goal at country and community level, Bangladesh has to invest on renewable and community based energy system as well as to develop a sustainable energy system considering the needs and priorities of the poor, women and marginal communities". BCAS with support from Christian Aid (CAid) has undertaken an initiative with CAid partners and Actors to popularize and localize SDGs with particular focus on Clean Energy (SDG-7) for effective implementation in the country. As a part of this process, they organized a Civil Society Dialogue on SDG Challenges in Bangladesh in early 2016 and several regional consultations (in coastal zone, haor basin, barind upland and hilly area) and capacity building workshops in the last seven months with Local Government Institutions, NGOs and local Actors to seek the local perspectives, needs and priorities of SDGs and energy as well as raise the voice of the grassroots communities to influence the policies and practices. Christian Aid Acting Country Director Sanjib Biswas attended the programme as a Special Guest. Director of BCAS Khandaker Mainuddin chaired the inaugural session. Three keynote papers were presented at the function. Executive Director of BCAS Dr. Atiq Rahman presented one of the papers. Research Fellow of BCAS Omar Tarek Chowdhury shared people's perspectives, needs and priorities of SDG-7, stressing the need for clean energy for all. Another Research Fellow of BCAS Golam Rabbani shared the updates of CoP 22 (UN Climate Change Conference) held at Marrakech this year with focus on access to clean energy and mitigation to climate change. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The New Nation. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh65" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="May 3, 2017 Wednesday"source="The News Today (Bangladesh.)" >
From the cropless farmer to the beleaguered first responder to the person forced to evacuate their flooded home, we all have our reasons for caring about climate change. As an Indonesian-born Muslim living in California, it is my faith that compels me to protect our earth. For many people like me who cherish tolerance and clean air, the first 100 days of the Trump presidency have not been easy. As a Muslim immigrant to America, it has been painfully frustrating to witness the Trump administration reinforce xenophobia against both immigrants and Muslims. As someone whose faith is bound up with combating climate change, it hurt to see Trump impose an executive order that effectively denies the impacts of climate change I have seen with my own eyes. Frustration must never lead to resignation, however: that is why, on Saturday, I and many other Muslims will be marching in Washington, D.C. in solidarity with thousands of others for our climate and the protection of the vulnerable. Prophet Mohammed (peace and blessings be upon him) leaves Muslims like me in no doubt as to the duty we humans share: 'God has made the Earth green and beautiful, and He has appointed you as stewards over it,' he said. There is no greater threat to our 'green and beautiful' Earth than the more frequent and intense droughts, floods and storms brought by climate change. Muslim-majority countries around the world are some of the most severely affected by climate change impacts like heat waves, floods, droughts and extreme weather events like the recent famine in Somalia, which has led to more than 16 million people facing food shortages and death. Many Muslims live in parts of the world that are particularly vulnerable to climate change, such as Bangladesh and parts of sub-Saharan Africa. Pakistan is another country that is extremely short of freshwater resources. With a continuously increasing of climate crisis, the water availability has decreased severely, which then placed the country as water scarce nation and in turn it will have an adverse influence on poverty. Maldives is another Muslim-majority country that could become the first in history to be completely erased by the sea level rise at the turn of the century. And with last year's COP 22 taking place in Morocco, the responsibility has shifted to the governments of Muslim majority countries and their religious leaders to step up and play their role in the growing grassroots movement accross Muslim communities around the globe, to reverse the effects of climate change. That means phasing out greenhouse gas emissions as soon as possible, shifting away from fossil fuels to clean sources of energy, including urging the Muslim petropowers and oil-producing nations to take the lead in the transition toward renewable energy based development. (Rich and oil states should phase out their emissions by the middle of the century and provide generous support to help the poor nations to combat climate change). The consequences of climate change are already having significant and costly affects on our communities, our health and our ecosystem. Globally, 2014, 2015 and 2016 were the three hottest years on record. From January to March 2017, the US experienced five billion-dollar weather and climate disasters, a national record that killed 37 people. Climate change likely worsened the impact of Colorado's deadly 2013 floods and has exacerbated droughts in California. Of course, it is always the poor and vulnerable who are impacted most. These facts and figures are no abstractions for me. In February 2007 I was in Jakarta, Indonesia's capital, as the city was paralyzed by severe flooding - the worst in its history - that inundated about 70 percent of the city, killed a number of people, cut off the highway connecting to the country's major airport and sent about 450,000 fleeing their homes. In January 2014, a couple years after I moved to the US, California Gov. Jerry Brown declared a 'drought state of emergency' due to ongoing water shortfalls following the driest calendar year in state history. He asked Californians to cut their water usage by at least a fifth. As a California resident, I witnessed first hand firefighters battling a wildfire in San Diego County during the severe Santa Ana Wind and heat wave in 2016. I am not alone. Muslims - and indeed the majority of Americans outside the White House - are united on the urgency of the issue of climate change. In August 2015, I witnessed over 80 global Muslim leaders from over 20 countries release the Islamic Declaration on Global Climate Change in Istanbul, urging world governments to phase out fossil fuels and make a transition to renewable energy to tackle climate change. In December of that year, by signing the Paris Agreement on Climate Change, almost 200 governments set a path to do just that. The Global Muslim Climate Network, of which I am chair, is also doing its part to encourage more Muslims to focus on solutions and take concrete actions, such as running their local mosques on solar energy. By seeking to undermine the Paris Agreement, which the Trump administration could do if it decides to formally withdraw or which arguably it is already doing by seeking to eradicate climate regulations and funding for climate science research - Donald Trump and his administration are reneging on a promise to have the interests of the vulnerable and forgotten at heart. Together with his divisive rhetoric against Muslims and immigrants, Trump represents a potentially disastrous departure from the inclusive and multicultural American society that I love. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh66" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="May 7, 2016 Saturday"source="The New Nation (Bangladesh)" >
Dhaka, May 7 -- The diplomats have done their job, concluding the Paris climate agreement in December. And political leaders gathered last week at the United Nations to sign the new accord. But implementation is surely the tough part. Governments need a new approach to an issue that is highly complex, long term, and global in scale.At its core, the climate challenge is an energy challenge. About 80% of the world's primary energy comes from carbon-based sources: coal, oil, and gas. When burned, they emit the carbon dioxide that causes global warming. By 2070, we need a world economy that is nearly 100% carbon-free to prevent global warming from running dangerously out of control.The Paris agreement recognizes these basic facts. It calls on the world to cut greenhouse-gas emissions (especially CO2) to net-zero levels in the second half of the century. To this end, governments are to prepare plans not only to the year 2030 (the so-called Nationally Determined Contributions, or NDCs), but also to mid-century (the so-called Low-Emission Development Strategies, or LEDS).The world's governments have never before attempted to remake a core sector of the world economy on a global scale with such an aggressive timeline. The fossil-fuel energy system was created step by step over two centuries. Now it must be comprehensively overhauled in just 50 years, and not in a few countries, but everywhere. Governments will need new approaches to develop and implement their LEDS.There are four reasons why politics as usual will not be sufficient. First, the energy system is just that: a system of many interconnected parts and technologies. Power plants, pipelines, ocean transport, transmission lines, dams, land use, rail, highways, buildings, vehicles, appliances, and much more must all fit together into a working whole.Such a system cannot be overhauled through small incremental steps. A deep overhaul requires system-wide re-engineering to ensure that all parts continue to work effectively together.Second, there are still many large technological uncertainties in moving to a low-carbon energy system. Should vehicles be decarbonized through battery-electric power, hydrogen fuel cells, or advanced biofuels? Can coal-fired power plants be made safe through carbon capture and storage (CCS)? Will nuclear energy be politically acceptable, safe, and low cost? We must plan investments in research and development to resolve these uncertainties and improve our technological options.Third, sensible solutions require international energy cooperation. One key fact about low-carbon energy (just like fossil fuels) is that it is not generally located where it will ultimately be used. Just as coal, oil, and gas must be transported long distances, so wind, solar, geothermal, and hydropower must be moved long distances through transmission lines and through synthetic liquid fuels made with wind and solar power.Fourth, there are of course powerful vested interests in the fossil-fuel industry that are resisting change. This is abundantly clear in the US, for example, where the Republican Party denies climate change for the sole reason that it is heavily funded by the US oil industry. This is certainly a species of intellectual corruption, if not political corruption (it's probably both).The fact that the energy system involves so many complex interconnections leads to tremendous inertia. Shifting to a low-carbon energy system will therefore require considerable planning, long lead times, dedicated financing, and coordinated action across many parts of the economy, including energy producers, distributors, and residential, commercial, and industrial consumers. Policy measures such as a tax on carbon emissions can help to address some - but only some - challenges of the energy transition.Here is another problem. If governments plan only 10-15 years ahead, as is typical in energy policy, rather than 30-50 years, they will tend to make poor system-related choices. For example, energy planners will move from coal to lower-carbon natural gas; but they will tend to underinvest in the much more decisive shift to renewable energy.Similarly, they may opt to raise fuel standards for internal-combustion automobiles rather than to push the needed shift to electric vehicles. In this sense, planning 30-50 years ahead is vital not only to make the correct long-run choices, but also to inform the correct short-term choices. The UN's Deep Decarbonization Pathways Project has shown how long-term plans can be designed and evaluated.None of these challenges sits easily with elected politicians. The decarbonization challenge requires consistent policies over 30-50 years, while politicians' time horizon is perhaps a tenth of that. Nor are politicians very comfortable with a problem that requires large-scale public and private financing, highly coordinated action across many parts of the economy, and decision-making in the face of ongoing technological uncertainties. Small wonder, then, that most politicians have shied away from this challenge, and that far too little practical progress has been made since the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change was signed in 1992.One key step, I believe, is to remove these issues from short-term electoral politics. Countries should consider establishing politically independent energy agencies with high technical expertise. Of course, key energy decisions (such as whether to deploy nuclear energy or to build a new transmission grid) will require deep public participation, but planning and implementation should be free of excessive partisan politics and lobbying. Just as governments have successfully given their central banks some political independence, they should give their energy agencies enough leeway to enable them think and act for the long term.At the next global climate meeting ( COP22 in Marrakesh in November), Morocco's government and my team at the UN Sustainable Development Solutions Network will join with other partners to co-host a "Low-Emissions Solutions Conference." This conference will bring together energy experts from UN member countries, businesses, and cities to work on highly practical approaches to deep decarbonization. With the Paris climate agreement now in force, we must move urgently to effective implementation.(Jeffrey D. Sachs, Professor of Sustainable Development, Professor of Health Policy and Management, and Director of the Earth Institute at Columbia University, is also Director of the UN Sustainable Development Solutions Network). Published by HT Syndication with permission from The New Nation. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh67" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="February 3, 2017 Friday"source="The New Nation (Bangladesh)" >
Dhaka, Feb. 3 -- 2016 is on course to be not just the hottest on record, but also probably the dirtiest and most hazardous too. "The climate has broken records in 2016" says World Meteorological Organization chief Petteri Taalas. Smog once again returned to haunt many of the world's cities notably in China, Europe and India, with the primary cause the same as climate change: the burning of fossil fuels. Worldwide, around 18,000 people now die every day as a result of air pollution. Some 26 million people are also forced into poverty each year by the impact of natural disasters, with climate shocks reversing hard-won development gains. The year of green finance Yet before you get too downhearted, we need to celebrate the fact that 2016 was also the best year ever for green finance. Simply put, green finance covers the financing of investments that generate environmental benefits as part of the broader strategy to achieve inclusive, resilient and sustainable development. In 2016, G20 heads of state for the first time recognised the need to 'scale up green finance' setting out a series of steps to make this happen. Key countries issued strategies for greening their financial systems, with China in the vanguard launching a 35-point programme. Leading insurance regulators also decided to work together on how to respond to sustainability challenges, such as climate change. In all, UN Environment estimates that the number of policy measures to green the financial system has more than doubled to over 200 measures across 60 countries. Importantly, these policy moves were closely connected with the rapid growth of green finance in the marketplace. The green bond market went from strength to strength, with over US$81 billion in issuance, almost double the 2015 tally. Financial centres from Casablanca to London, Hong Kong to Paris set out their plans to seize the green finance opportunity, notably by mobilising the capital required for the low-carbon transition. And the transformational potential of fintech for sustainable development began to be appreciated, from crowdfunding and mobile payments to artificial intelligence. With global carbon emissions stalling and clean tech costs plummeting, the task ahead for green finance in 2017 is to step up the pace. Financial institutions with assets worth tens of trillions of dollars are now committed to aligning their portfolios with the low-carbon transition and sustainable development more broadly. Yet the actual reallocation of capital still remains insufficient. Amongst the blizzard of opportunities that exist, three practical steps stand out to shift the trillions of private capital: first, rolling out sustainable finance roadmaps at the national level; second, targeting public effort where market forces cannot reach; and third, encouraging a real convergence at the international level in terms of the 'rules of the game' that shape financial markets, such as market standards and financial regulations. Roadmaps for green and sustainable finance One of the key insights from the G20's work on green finance on 2016 was that governments need to be clearer about the policy signals they send to financiers about their plans for climate action and sustainable development. With the Paris Agreement now in force, the focus in 2017 will shift to how the Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) that set out each country's goals can be turned into clear investment pipelines. Insurance giant Aviva calls these 'capital raising plans', covering both climate and broader sustainability goals; others call them 'climate investment plans'. Whatever the precise terminology, what is key to these roadmaps is making the bridge between high-level national targets and the technical details of how money actually flows across banking, capital markets, insurance and investment. To do this requires an open and sustained conversation in each country to work through the opportunities, the bottlenecks and the priorities for national action. A number of countries are already moving ahead. At COP22 , Morocco's central bank launched its roadmap for the finance sector, pinpointing five priority areas: innovative financial instruments, better risk governance, stronger financial inclusion, capacity building and improved transparency. Throughout 2016, Italy has engaged in a national dialogue on sustainable finance; the results will be released in early February. The European Union is also drawing up a comprehensive strategy on sustainable finance as part of its Capital Markets Union, supported by a high-level expert group. And Mexico is also moving ahead with the design of a green finance strategy to implement its NDC. What needs to happen now is to ensure that the mobilisation of green finance becomes a core part not just of the wider implementation of the NDCs - through initiatives such as the NDC Partnership - but also part of mainstream plans for financial sector development. If we are successful, then we could have a critical mass of countries, both developed and developing, with roadmaps in place by the time of the next global climate conference (COP23), which takes place in November 2017. This would signal to the world of finance that the goal of the Paris Agreement to make financial flows 'climate consistent' had become both practical and bankable. Crowding in private capital We know that the vast bulk of green and climate finance will come from the private sector. But experience has also shown that without a combination of public finance and policy frameworks, capital will often not flow. This is especially the case in developing countries, where many key financial markets are still missing and where governments shape a large share of capital deployment through state-owned financial institutions, development banks and policy-directed lending. This leads to the second priority for 2017: targeting public effort where market forces cannot reach. The lessons flowing from the ramp-up in renewables shows what now needs to happen with other green finance priorities, notably energy efficiency and adaptation. Temporary and targeted incentives (such as feed-in tariffs) along with focused risk mitigation tools can help to overcome investor concerns with these new sectors and themes. International flows of public finance are critical here. Industrialised countries have extended their commitment to mobilise US$100 billion of climate finance each year for developing countries by 2020. Latest estimates suggest that actual flows of climate finance into developing countries rose from US$52 billion in 2013 to US$62 billion in 2014, with pledges made in 2015 set to take public flows alone to US$67 billion in 2020. As well as using scarce public money to pump-prime the investment shift, the public sector can also help to make markets not just by issuing green assets, as leading development finance institutions have done in the case of bonds, but also by buying them, so that they form a standard part of central bank balance sheets, for example. International cooperation on rules of the game What is striking about the breakthroughs made in 2016 was how countries observed what others were doing, and then put in place measures to boost national action that were aligned with international best practice. China and India's regulations to drive their green bond markets are prime examples, building on international norms in the Green Bond Principles and Climate Bond Standards. Insurance is another area where both financial institutions and financial regulators are moving ahead with common approaches. Closing the growing protection gap between the economic and insured losses from natural hazards is a growing concern, a gap that will be widened with climate change. On the back of the long-standing Principles for Sustainable Insurance for firms, the new Sustainable Insurance Forum is designed to promote cooperation on critical challenges facing supervisors, such as climate change. Co-hosted by the California Department of Insurance and UN Environment, the Forum's first meeting in December included insurance supervisors and regulators from Brazil, California, France, Ghana, Jamaica, Morocco, the Netherlands, Singapore and the UK, as well as the International Association of Insurance Supervisors. Heading into 2017, the Forum will focus on disclosure, access to insurance, sustainable insurance roadmaps, climate risk, disaster risk reduction and capacity building for supervisors. Again and again, measurement emerges as a core priority for international convergence. Here, the Financial Stability Board's Task Force on Climate-related Financial Disclosures (TCFD) shows how an industry-led process can provide in short order globally relevant guidance for consistent reporting by both corporations and financial institutions. Significantly, the recommendations of the TCFD broke new ground by underscoring the critical importance of forward-looking disclosures as well as reporting on past performance. In addition, the Task Force put disclosure by financial institutions squarely on the table alongside reporting by business and industry. Better reporting by banks, investors and insurance firms on the risks and opportunities they face will help close the information loop and improve the quality of data across the system. The TCFD's recommendations are still open for consultation until 12 February, with an updated report delivered to the FSB in June. Effective disclosure rests on clear and credible analytical tools, which is why making the financial risks flowing from environmental factors more transparent - and presenting options to reduce them - will be a priority theme of the G20 Green Finance Study Group under Germany's Presidency in 2017. Getting critical mass on measuring green finance flows across sectors and asset classes is also vital to market expansion. The mix of principles and standards in the green bond market has shown what can be done to build a clear and trusted approach. This now needs to be extended upstream into bank balance sheets through tagging loans with environmental markers, starting with housing and project finance. It also needs to move sideways into the world's equity markets, where some institutions such as FTSE in London are already tracking the green revenues of listed companies. Making sure we have a joined-up map of green finance flows will be critical both to avoid 'greenwashing' and also to target extra policy action where it is needed. Improved disclosure and measurement are a means to achieve the ultimate goal of capital allocation aligned to climate and sustainability goals. Already more and more financial institutions are taking action to reduce the carbon footprints of their portfolios and assign more capital to green assets. Launched in 2014, the Portfolio Decarbonization Coalition, for example, now brings together 27 international investors with more than US$3 trillion in assets. The key lesson from its experience to date is that "portfolio decarbonisation offers real benefits, both in terms of reducing a portfolio's carbon impact but also in terms of financial performance". As a result, 2017 will see more and more investors taking measurable action. The linkages between fintech and green finance are at an even earlier phase of evolution but with digitisation now revolutionising the way that financial services are delivered, it perhaps has even greater potential. As yet, the core standards have not been set. This is why the ANT Financial Services Group and UN Environment are launching a new international partnership during World Economic Forum's Annual Meeting in Davos. The Green Digital Finance Alliance will bring together financial institutions committed to using digital technology to advance green finance in lending, investment and insurance. These new financial services can shape citizens' behaviour in ways that positively impact the environment. A case in point is ANT's early experimentation in linking financial transaction and carbon footprint data, and then providing social media and carbon offset incentives to encourage carbon-light living. There is no doubt that considerable uncertainty clouds the year ahead. But one thing is clear, the shift to climate-consistent, green and, ultimately, more sustainable finance now looks unstoppable. (Nick Robins Co-Director, UNEP Inquiry into a Sustainable Financial System). Published by HT Syndication with permission from The New Nation. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh68" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 14, 2016 Monday"source="The New Nation (Bangladesh)" >
Dhaka, Nov. 14 -- With COP22 just around the corner, we continue to confront the challenge of implementing a reliable system for evaluating, overseeing and taxing carbon dioxide emissions and other GHGs. One of the major limitations lies in the difficulty of identifying and controlling all emissions on a global scale and determining the cost of "emissions permits". Without first knowing this cost, it is impossible to fix a price for these permits on a (single) carbon market. Unfortunately, the various efforts to implement such a system for regulating carbon emissions have proven to have serious limitations, even at national or regional level. In Europe, for example, carbon emission quotas were set in a relatively arbitrary manner and were not readily scaled up to a global level or applied to a wide range of carbon emitting activities (e.g., heating buildings). Emilie Alberola, director of the carbon and energy market research unit at CDC Climat (France), has stressed that, due to these weaknesses in the quota system, economic agents lack incentives to make the long-term investments (30 to 50 years) necessary to reduce CO2 and other GHG emissions. And such limitations are especially pronounced in times of economic crisis. Therefore, is it not critical that we pause to reevaluate our current strategies and recognise that the moment has come for a true paradigm shift? The current model for controlling carbon emissions relies on penalties, not incentives, and is unlikely to meet the ambitious goals - requiring swift action on a large scale - that we so urgently need to achieve. An alternative approach to managing carbon emissions The alternative approach proposed here seeks to replace taxes on carbon and other GHG emissions with an inherently dynamic, incentive-based strategy. This alternative proposal includes two interlocking components: 1) the first component consists of an excise duty applied on the extraction of fossil fuels and primary production of products with global warming potential (GWP) both synthetic and non-synthetic, including fluorocarbons and methane; 2) The second component involves a scalable refund that would make it possible to reclaim the excise duty levied upstream, in whole or in part. Refunds would be granted in exchange for a reduction in, or complete elimination of, emissions linked to the use of substances with a global- warming potential. Compared to the immediate sources of GHG emissions that are innumerable, there are indeed much fewer sources of extraction/production of GHG-emitting materials. Once adopted, the excise duty principle would be intrinsic in all participating countries and therefore more readily implemented. The great advantage of this combination is that it provides inherent incentives to promote compliance: could there be a more effective strategy? Examples of activities eligible for refunds would include demonstrated development of more energy-efficient processes or installations (agriculture, housing, and transport); cogeneration of energy, including renewable energy sources; production of long-lasting insulating materials and other non-emissive products as well as recycling, fixation, or long-term storage of GHGs. The excise duty would be levied on the basis of the quantity of material extracted. Suppose that the excise duty on petroleum is fixed at $10 ($25 per tonne) and with a barrel price ranging from $40 to $110, this would not constitute an insurmountable financial barrier for immediate "professional" uses and for consumers. As some 30 gigabarrels of oil are extracted each year, the excise duty on oil alone would generate at least $300 billion. And this does not take into account the revenues from excise duties on coal, traditional or other sources of natural gas (bituminous sands, shale gas) or, possibly, industrial non-recycled biomass (wood and pellet forms). This combination of duties and refunds has thus four critical advantages: 1) there are innumerable sources of GHG emissions, but relatively fewer sources of GHG extraction/production; so, it will be simpler and more straightforward to tax/regulate the latter; 2) the plan incorporates inherent incentives to promote compliance and meet emission reduction targets; 3) it avoids the uncertainties of the carbon stock market, which is inevitably speculative in nature; 4) it would not require direct funding from the producers or from states already struggling with limited resources or saddled with heavy debts. It is interesting to note that the proposal is supported by Christian de Perthuis in France and, somehow, Barack Obama also took over this idea although probably a little bit late in his second term. The process is also similar in some ways to the process described by the Nobel laureate Jean Tirole, who has urged that a carbon tax be levied in conjunction with a system of "green funds." though in this case, the duty would be levied not on GHG emissions, but on their extraction/production. How to manage a tax system based on carbon extractions After signing a treaty pledging its participation, each country would be obliged to levy the duty regardless of whether the GHGs (or other products associated with climate externalities) were extracted within the country or were imported from elsewhere. States choosing not to participate would be penalised by excise duties imposed at the borders by the WTO, the ECB, or an institution specifically created to fill this role. To ensure compliance, a source-tracing system (similar to those adopted in some food industry sectors) would be instituted. This is particularly important to trace the imports. In order to provide full or partial refunds of the excise duty levied upstream, we propose the implementation of a tax system incorporating environmental externalities (here the climate impact) of any product or activity and aligned with the traditional tax schemes like the European VAT. There already exists an operational strategy for quantifying and implementing excise duty refunds, based on models for monetisation of environmental and social externalities which draw distinctions between products or services according to their overall carbon profile. With such a system, the tax burden would thus not rise for those producers or consumers who adopt strategies that selectively reduce their climate externalities. Examples include the issues discussed in the UN's list of Millennium Development Goals. The tax would be calculated using methods (e.g., Life Cycle Analysis [LCA]) already in place for monetising some externalities. The main challenge? Probably the resistance to paradigm shifts Despite its potential benefits, such a proposal must first confront the "resistance to change" that characterises most stakeholders in our "advanced" societies: economists, the political world and even scientists. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The New Nation. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh69" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="June 21, 2016 Tuesday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, June 21 -- Dialogue is the only means to resolve complex issues peacefully. Climate dialogue has so far seen heated debates on contentious issues. World leaders have been spending a significant proportion of their time to have dialogues and discuss about global warming and responsibilities of the most pollutant countries. The Paris agreement was reached in December 2015 after a lengthy dialogue. The largest annual conference of parties ( COP22 ) -the sustainable innovation forum 2016-- is scheduled to take place during the second week of November in Marrakech, Morocco. In this climate dialogue and conference, the private sector is getting more and more importance as a significant proportion of funding is expected from it. Bangladesh, as a least developed country, has also contributed a lot. The government is seriously concerned over climate change and is taking full care of its capabilities, commitment for Intended Nationally Determined Contribution (INDC) at 5.0 per cent without external support and 15 per cent if external support is available as business-as-usual case. This has been appreciated by the world community. The last conference was held in Bonn, Germany in May 2016 where the LDC issues were discussed with a special focus on a good quality national adaptation plan. In the COP21 discussion, the political agenda of the large countries to take recourse to safe position were visible while LDC issues are sometimes bypassed. A number of 'shall' has been substituted at the last stage by 'should'. In some very pertinent areas, say finance, loss and damage, no decision was taken and in this respect ratification of the Paris agreement by the big polluter countries would be very important. It is expected that Bangladesh would lead a large delegation to the upcoming COP but private sector representatives and representatives from all other related sectors of water, energy and agriculture would probably need to be engaged to get benefits of climate change dialogue. The areas important for making the dialogue successful are many among which confidence on dialogue partners is one of the most important issues. So far it is seen that a sort of inertia has worked in the private sector in case of climate change issues; efficiency of natural resources with adaptation of new technologies is being treated from the point of view of cost issues. Both existing and upcoming state and non-state actors should have a clear idea and need to know the potential areas to exploit to accrue benefits out of it. A slew of measures can be initiated by having effective dialogue among public and private sectors both at domestic and international levels. It is clear that there is a gap of understanding of climate change issues and cost minimisation among different actors. BUILD, as a public-private dialogue platform, has identified seven gaps so far which need to be bridged to get better results from dialogue. There is confidence gap among public and private sectors. In order to bridge the gap, there is a serious need to have more and more platforms for structured dialogues inviting all relevant actors. There is an understanding gap between buyers and sellers; some corporate bodies have taken voluntary steps to reduce costs by implementing energy-efficient technology and procedures and have been able to bring in efficiency but are facing buyers' pressure to further reduce prices because of reduced cost of production which is discouraging for the private sector. Importers of products from Bangladesh should also encourage entrepreneurs to use more and more resource -efficient technology so that others are also interested to participate in these processes and educate themselves to maintain the full eco-system. There is information gap. Nobody knows who is doing what. Information disclosure is important. The private sector is a bit confused and does not also like to disclose information. All related information and steps taken by the government are not appropriately or timely communicated to the private sector. Projects are being implemented by the government, NGOs, stakeholders and the private sector are not closely involved and coordinated and no database of projects is being prepared. Policy gaps, mainstream policies and benefits for the private sector and tax policies are not always aligned with climate change strategies. Policy mix-in favour of climate responsible production processes is important. Tax policies would also need to be aligned with climate strategies so that gradually private sector becomes ready to be climate-responsible entrepreneurs. Another important issue is the issue of land which is not disciplined yet. After much efforts of the government, this issue cannot still be streamlined. Bangladesh is planning to go for at least 10 per cent of its energy consumption from solar power. There are some policies, say, agricultural land will not be used for a solar plant but a solar plant requires more land (per MW 4 acres while 50-100 MW can be generated from 4 acres from other sources). But Bangladesh is a land-scarce country. There should also not be any discrimination of policies between local and foreign entrepreneurs. Not only that, tariff negotiation is difficult in these areas. Price should be at a reasonable rate for sustenance of these types of entrepreneurship. Large corporate bodies are to some extent aware of the issues of climate change and environment management and are taking steps to grab opportunities by having some new and innovative ways of investment. But problems are with SMEs (90 per cent) of limited knowledge and flexibilities. The Bangladesh Bank (BB) recently established the Green Transformation Fund (GTF). The loan will be offered in US dollars and provided through authorised dealers. The areas of funding are water use efficiency in wet processing, water conservation and management, waste management, resource efficiency and recycling, renewable energy, energy efficiency, heat and temperature management, air ventilation and circulation efficiency, work environment improvement initiatives and other fields as identified by the BB from time to time. These are all very important and supportive initiatives, but how SMEs would be benefited from these schemes is not clear. There could be initiatives for SMEs also. There are project initiative gaps. While the government is giving emphasis on adaptation, the private sector is rather interested in mitigation (energy-efficient projects like solar energy etc). Projects would need to be identified which could provide benefits of both adaptation and mitigation-e.g., energy-efficient boiler, power generation, ETP plant etc.) It is of course true that mitigation can reduce the need of adaptation, but the priority of the government is to pledge more adaptation mechanisms. Another important gap is project return gaps. Waiting cost is huge and the private sector is unaware about return which requires time to wait for long. Water use efficiency in wet processing for a single industry may not be that much visible if a group initiative is taken. Thus a single enterprise has to wait for long to get visible benefit out of it. There are a number of examples in this respect; waste management and water conservation management are some of the few. In Bangladesh, there are a number of rice mills using indigenous boilers. In North Bengal people use rice husk for generating heat for boilers. Ashes of the rice mills are creating pollution and ponds and rivers are getting dust that obstructs human breathing. There is a technology for controlling ashes. BUILD initiated a small study on simplification of boiler policy and had a detailed discussion with the Ministry of Industries and suggested for a separate policy for small boilers used for rice mills, poultry and feed factories etc. In addition to the above mentioned gaps, institutional development and coordination are other major issues. People still believe climate change and other related issues are a part of the CSR and thus voluntary. But it is of course true that CSR activities can be an integral part of increasing resilience and sustainability and for this policy framework again play a very central role . Private-public dialogue would be instrumental for the climate agenda. A set of climate principles have been agreed in the recent dialogue for climate action held in Vienna. One of the principles is inclusion. In this respect, divisional stakeholders' consultation can be arranged while urgency is another principle. Prioritisation of issues is very important and in respect of pin-pointing the issues of COP21 decisions and agreements along with follow-up is needed. In respect of awareness, more demonstration of climate issues in schools and places of religion (mosques, temples etc) could give some better results. The architecture of climate dialogue needs involvement of scientists, meteorologists, environmentalists, academicians, stakeholders, university teachers, students and many others. In order to bring more transparency, climate dialogue should be informative, based on facts, and outcome must be consistent. Accountability must be there to build trust and confidence among dialogue partners. The writer is CEO, Business Initiative Leading Development (BUILD) HYPERLINK mailto:ceo_build@outlook.com ceo_build@outlook.com Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh70" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="January 31, 2017 Tuesday"source="Energy & Power" >
The Parliamentary Standing Committee on Environment and Forest Ministry recently recommended bringing amendment to the Brick Manufacturing and Brick Kilns Establishment (Control) Act 2013 as complexities arose during execution of the law. The committee said the amendment to some provisions of the law is needed to make it more applicable, realistic and implementable. The parliamentary watchdog came up with the recommendation at its 29th meeting held at the Jatiya Sangsad Bhaban with the committee's chairman Mohammad Hasan Mahmud in the chair. At the meeting, the parliamentary body discussed the brick kiln law, successes of the recently-held COP-22 and what should be the next courses of action for Bangladesh regarding climate change. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh71" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 14, 2016 Monday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
The World Bank will provide US$2 billion to Bangladesh in the next three years to fight climate change impacts, its Climate Change Group Senior Economist Stephane Hallegatte said on Monday. The World Bank will provide the fund to assist Bangladeshis people who were affected by climate change, and protect their property from natural disasters, he said. Stephane Hallegatte made the announcement at a press conference following a report published by the World Bank on 'Natural Disasters and Global Poverty' at the conference hall room at the 22nd Session of the Conference of Parties (COP) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change held here on Monday. The WB report said nearly US$ 520 billion goes down the drain every year due to the climate change. It also renders some 2.60 crore people poor each year. Meanwhile, World Bank has released names of 17 climate change vulnerable countries where Bangladesh has found its place. The summit of COP22 , which began on November 7, will focus on implementing the climate change agreement adopted at COP21 in Paris in 2015. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh72" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 17, 2016 Thursday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina returned home on Thursday morning wrapping up her three-day official visit to Marrakech, a former imperial city in western Morocco, to attend two high-level segments of the Conference of the Parties ( COP-22 ). On Tuesday, Sheikh Hasina delivered her statement at the high-level segments of COP-22 where she urged global leaders to fight together the perilous threats of climate change and share the burdens equally for fulfilling the promises to make the world a safer place for the future generation. COP-22 , which began on November 7 and to run through November 18 in Bab Ighli of Marrakech, is the first such meeting since the historic adoption of the Paris Agreement at COP-21 in December last year. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh73" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="September 28, 2016 Wednesday"source="The New Nation (Bangladesh)" >
Dhaka, Sept. 28 -- Fossil fuels are fuels formed by natural processes such as anaerobic decomposition of buried dead organisms, containing energy originating in ancient photosynthesis. Fossil fuels contain high percentages of carbon and include petroleum, coal, and natural gas and are used as an energy source in the electricity and transportation sectors. They are also a leading source of the world's global warming resulting in pollution. Burning fossil fuels negatively affects the environment because they release carbon dioxide and other gases that trap heat in the earth's atmosphere, which contributes to global climate change. According to the Union of Concerned Scientists, the burning of fossil fuels during the last 150 years has increased atmospheric carbon dioxide levels by 25 percent. Levels of methane and nitrous oxide have also increased . In addition to contributing to global climate change, burning fossil fuels also pollutes the air, leading to negative health effects for animals. Exposure to the carbon dioxide produced by burning fossil fuels can cause headaches and increase the risk of heart disease. According to GreenEnergyChoice.com, more than 2.5 million metric tons of carbon dioxide are produced just by power plants each year. Sulphur oxides produced burning fossil fuels form sulphuric acid when they combine with water vapor. As this acid accumulates in lakes and streams, it makes the habitats uninhabitable for plants and animals. Burning fossil fuels also results in thermal pollution. The process of burning any substance generates heat, and this heat is often released into lakes and streams when the water that they contain is used as a coolant. The increased temperatures in these lakes and streams upsets the ecosystem, causing some species' populations to increase and others to decrease. The wide scale use of fossil fuels, coal at first and petroleum later, to fire steam engines enabled the Industrial Revolution. At the same time, gas lights using natural gas or coal gas were coming into wide use. Fossil fuels lobby is the umbrella term used to name the paid representatives of large fossil fuel (oil, gas, coal) and electric utilities corporations who attempt to influence governmental policy. This energy lobby is criticized for using its influence to block or dilute legislation regarding global climate change. Many of the most influential members of the energy lobby are among the top polluters in the United States. According to the Environmental Integrity Project, a nonpartisan, nonprofit organization established in March 2002 by former attorneys at the Environmental Protection Agency, "Companies like ExxonMobil and Sunoco keep reporting record profits while increasing emissions or more cancer causing chemicals from their refineries. In the 2006 US election cycle, oil and gas companies contributed over $19 million to political campaigns. 82% of that money went to Republican candidates, while the remaining 18% went to Democrats. In 2004, oil and gas companies contributed over $25 million to political campaigns, donating 80% of that money to Republicans. In the 2000 elections, over $34 million was contributed, with 78% of that money going to Republicans. The energy lobby has a history of conflict with international interests and democratic global governance. According to the International Sustainable Energy Organization for Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency the second World Climate Conference was sabotaged by the USA and oil lobbieswhereupon UNISEO proceeded to set up a Global Energy Charter which protects life, health, climate and the biosphere from emissions. According to the organization, these same "reactionary energy lobby groups tried to boycott this Charter with the help from oil- and coal-producing nations and succeeded to keep energy out of the Rio Conference on Environment & Development (Earth Summit) in 1992, to continue this game in all Climate Conferences in Berlin, Kyoto, The Hague and Marrakech, where the USA boycotted the Kyoto protocol and still ignores the Charter. The financial conflict of interest behind the Cop 21-Paris summit-with about 20 percent of the budget brought corporations-is basically an open secret. Corporate Accountability International (CAI) has mapped out the connections between energy corporations sponsoring the event, policymakers, and international bodies to show exactly how well choreographed the conference has become: back-channel diplomatic horse trading, showcases for "business innovation," a perfunctory nod to "civil society groups" and a tightly controlled smattering of protesters. CAI analyzes four major COP21 sponsors that have seized Paris as a prime business opportunity. These companies have lately eschewed historical associations with polluting fuels and proclaimed their commitment to progressive investment in clean energy. But CAI argues sponsorship deals let "corporations responsible for causing the climate crisis green-wash their brands while continuing to make no meaningful changes to their polluting operations." Ahead of ( COP 22 If the ruling elite can't imagine climate talks without the influence of polluters' money, how can we imagine a world without dirty fuels? Yes, polluters should pay, but they shouldn't govern or give guidelines. The fossil-fuel industry's stake is tied to its environmental debt to society; they can't demand influence when they owe restitution. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The New Nation. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh74" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="December 31, 2016 Saturday"source="Energy & Power" >
Director of the Centre for Energy Research of United International University (UIU) Shahriar Ahmed Chowdhury received 'UN Momentum for Change 2016' award at CoP 22 in Marakkech, Morocco recently, says a press release. He is the team leader of the award-winning research pilot project 'PV DC Peer-toPeer Smart Village Grid'. The research project was co-funded by World Bank and IDCOL. A BangladeshGerman start-up company SOLshare provided the technology and implemented the project. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh75" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="December 4, 2016 Sunday"source="United News of Bangladesh" >
Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina will make a courtesy call on President Abdul Hamid at Bangabhaban this evening. The meeting will begin at 7pm, according to the programme schedule of the President. Generally, the Prime Minister meets President after foreign visits. Sheikh Hasina went to Hungary on November 28 on a four-day visit at the invitation of Hungarian President Dr Janos Ader to attend the Budapest Water Summit 2016. She also went to Morocco on November 14 on a three-day official visit to attend two high-level segments of the Conference of the Parties ( COP-22 ). \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh76" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="December 8, 2016 Thursday"source="The News Today (Bangladesh.)" >
It is time perhaps that the government authorities made a pause in the drive to push through the most widely objected project in Bangladesh for a rethink. The government should at least try for clearing a thickening mist surrounding the project. Such an imperative is created by a United Nations (UN) agency United Nations Organization for Education, Science and Culture (UNESCO)'s call for a halt, and a broad union in a body or mass at home as its corroborator. The UNESCO pull came at an advanced stage of the spadework on the Rampal thermal power plant in the vicinity of the Sundarbans. The spadework on the Rampal so far has been done brushing aside consistent protests by environmental experts and concerned civic groups as well as politicians in opposition and even in the broad ruling coalition. The anti-Rampal mass demonstrations particularly by the left-leaning fronts of politicians and conscious and concerned environmentalists as well and national interest-preservation volunteers have often turned into police-protester clashes. But these turned into little avail in deterring the government from its resolve for executing the ruinous coal-fired power plant under joint venture with an Indian company. When the former ruling party Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) took a public stand in opposition to the thermal power plant near the world-heritage-site Sundarbans, the ruling prime minister (PM) herself appeared on the media in an address to the nation to defend the government stand. "It'll go as planned", the ruling PM had said, apparently as a rebutter to former PM and BNP chief and other opponents' contentions over the 1320-megawatt harmful power project. The government was all set to strike a deal with India on the financing of the plant at the stage of project processing. But the campaigners in protest fear that it would be detrimental to the world's largest contiguous mangrove forest Sundabans. The joint-venture Bangladesh-India Friendship Power Company Ltd (BIFCL) has signed the loan agreement in July 2016 with the state-run Exim Bank of India, and the physical work on the power plant was started shortly afterwards. The red signal came from the UNESCO, setting off squalls of brainstorming talk over the possible boon and bane that may be packed in the project, wittingly or unwittingly. The government side logically has to go on the back-foot as the state minister for power said the government would give an analytical reply to a latest UNESCO letter carrying its concerns and call for a halt. Core contents of the UNESCO report titled, "Report on the mission to the Sundarbans World Heritage Site, Bangladesh", were recently published in newspapers. The three-member mission visiting Bangladesh from March 22-28, 2016 prepared the report based on consultations with different parties. Subsequently it was sent to the government in time. The UNESCO called for the government to relocate the plant to a "more suitable location" where it would not have a negative impact on the Sundarbans. It noted that the human-heritage forest along the Bay of Bengal was already facing serious shortage of freshwater flows as the sweet-water flows dropped alarmingly following construction of the Farakka barrage by India. It led to the rise in salinity and siltation in the Sundarbans - the precious gift of Almighty Allah. Salt-tolerant species are expanding replacing other natural varieties. The UN mission identified four core potential threats to the Sundarbans from the construction and operation of the Rampal thermal power plant in the vicinity of Sundarbans. They are (i) pollution from coal ash through air; (ii) pollution from wastewater and waste ash; (iii) increased shipping and dredging; and (iv) the cumulative impact of industrial and related development infrastructures. The report also said associated activities which are already going on around the Rampal power-plant site will also harm the world's largest mangrove forest. It also warned against unplanned development in coastal area. The World Heritage Site Sundarbans has Outstanding Universal Value (OUV) and the government should introduce a system that allows management of the forest in a more integrated manner. The UNESCO in 1997 declared the Sundarbans a World Heritage Site. The UN mission also recommended the government to halt the site development for the Orion power plant in Khulna and any similar proposed development until independent, comprehensive and scientifically sound environmental impact assessment (EIA) is conducted. The state minister for power, energy and mineral resources, after inaugurating a workshop on research in power and energy sector at Bidyut Bhaban in Dhaka, told inquisitive reporters that the government would respond to the UNESCO letter, "stating our position over its concern on the Rampal power plant". He hoped that getting the government response, the UN body would understand that there is no actual reason for concern - thereby dropping an indication that the process could continue. Some other Awami League (AL) senior politicians - apart from the junior minister - and associated intellectuals as well as energy journalists went on narrating the merits of the project and playing down the demerits being focused by the protesters. They viewed such UN body sanctions are not binding. An AL lawmaker in a TV talk- show went to the extent of questioning: "Does any UN agency feed the teeming millions in Bangladesh?" The campaigners, he quipped, want people to go back to the times of lighting with lanterns. An opposition politician from the international affairs wing of the BNP put up a tooth-and-nail fight against the logic pressed by a government-side politician, who presides over the parliamentary standing committee on food ministry, in favour of going ahead with the Rampal power project. The state minister for power, energy and mineral resources, in support of the project under his ministry, mentioned that the government had planned the power plant as part of its effort to ensure electricity to every household within 2018. The protesters, on the other hand, made it clear that they do appreciate the government recipe for electricity augmentation, but not at the cost of the Sundarbans that cannot be replicated while the plant can be relocated to any other site. The National Committee on Protection of oil, gas, power and ports in a latest development virtually toned down their stance as they pleaded for building a plant, even if there, based on bio-fuels instead of coal that needs to be imported through the Sundarbans water channels. The UNESCO stand, however, looks yet tougher. It requested the government to conduct a revised EIA before going ahead with the Rampal power plant. Also, the government has been requested to submit a revised EIA report with the advice note of the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN). Earlier in Bonn, Germany, in the 39th annual meeting held in 2015 the UNESCO had requested the government to undertake a comprehensive Strategic Environmental Assessment (SEA) in order to assess the indirect and cumulative impact from power plants and other developments in the vicinity of the Sundarbans. The latest and third representation to the government, the UN body's stance is being propped up by a wider coalition of campaigners, including one of the largest political parties of the country. The UNESCO's last word puts Rampal thermal power plant project at a crossroads, leaving two options for the Bangladesh government: ditch it or lose the World Heritage Site status of the Sundarbans. The first is dispensable, not the second in common consent. So, the choice is crucial. In its latest opinionated report, the UNESCO virtually has served an ultimatum like this: roll back the coal-fired power project from the vicinity of the one-of-its-kind of mangrove forest or it (UNESCO) will take back Sundarbans' crown of universal glory. The 41st session of the World Heritage Committee in 2017 in Istanbul will take a decision as to whether the Sundarbans will be put on the list of "World Heritage in Danger". Meanwhile, the authorities in India also apparently face a test of their wisdom over the power project as the campaigners have submitted an "open letter" to Prime Minister Narendra Modi through the country's mission in Dhaka for reconsidering the joint venture. Those who did it, interestingly, are not the ones from traditional India-bashing camps. Rather many of them, especially the leftwing political elements, might have party-to-party or people-to-people contacts in India. And their like-minded quarters and media across the border are also reported to have taken a stand on this issue that corroborates the views of the campaigners in Bangladesh. There have been many an environmentalist movements in India against projects, including coal-fired ones, which they deemed would harm the ecology. In some cases, the entrepreneurs had to take recourse to a retreat. On the home front, the anti-Rampal thermal power plant demonstrations have long been carried on particularly by a left-leaning front of politicians and national interest-preservation volunteers, sometimes erupting into police-protester clashes. A heavy extra weight has been added to the relentless campaign from the political front with a former ruling party, BNP, announcing its plan for leading a long march towards Rampal. The latest stance of the BNP, which had led a violent boycott movement against the last general election, on agitation against the Indo-Bangladesh joint-venture power plant, came as its demand in support of the greens fell flat. Thus what had started off as a protest by some left-leaning political groups has by now grew into a broader coalition cutting across varied political ideologies with a spontaneous alignment with the UN systems' cultural organ UNESCO. The opposition political front the BNP in a press conference fully supported the UNESCO position and demanded relocation of the plant. Activists of the leftwing allies of the AL also join in street protests and the Workers Party, a part of the ruling government, also called for relocation of the project. Many argue that the government would be ill advised to stand as an ivory tower alienated from all else with its prudent agenda of enhancing power generation to meet fast-growing needs. True, power is considered a vital development matrix in the modern times. It is evident that a country which consumes the highest amount of electricity is the most developed one of nations in economic terms. On this count, it is still the United States (US) that tops the development pyramid. But power development should not be at the cost of a World Heritage Site like the Sundarbans. Meanwhile, the government side, seemingly left with support from only the ruling party and a few energy journalists, has scaled up media campaign emphatically by involving young faces against what is being described as follies of old-school campaigners. They are calling for support to the government development strides through carrying on the power-generation mega-plan. In reply to repeated representation to the government for rethinking the setting up of thermal power plant because of its impact on the flora and fauna of the World Heritage Site, the government has also come up with clarification that the project has been undertaken following proper environmental impact assessment and ultra super-critical technology is being used to ensure that the plant does not have any adverse effect on the mangrove forest. Following governmental disagreement with the recommendation, UNESCO reaffirmed its stand. Experts, environmentalists and researchers have also listed hard facts and figures to highlight the damage the 1320-megawatt coal-fired power plant might do to the forest. They say the ultra-super-critical technology being talked about will not make the project pollution-free. The focus is on what technology can be used to prevent the air pollution, water pollution and solid waste pollution. But the government swept aside all reasoning as "unfounded, untrue and anti-development". This unique forest the Sundarbans, replete with its rare biodiversity, has been a matter of great pride to Bangladesh. But now UNESCO forewarns an action in reversal which analysts forecast would have other major collateral damage to national interest. What are those like? The nation loses the glory of possessing a unique UN recognition - World Heritage Site - along with a package of upkeep funds for its maintenance. It also risks being classed as a contributor to global warming and climate change and, hence, may lose the claim to climate-change compensation funds due as a worst victim of global climate change caused by rich country's by way of spewing excessive greenhouse gases into the atmosphere. It will prove a heavily losing tradeoff in the end, the critics say only about the monetary aspects. And with the Sundarbans, there cannot be any tradeoff whatsoever - you cannot create another Sundarbans. A journalist leader reminded that UNESCO is an important organization, a universal cultural body, so its "views should be considered with due importance". Despite all the considerations crediting the government's power agenda, a consensus is building up on the need for the government high-ups to get down to weighing the latest developments. The wise words of a senior journalist, who otherwise is associated with the pro-ruling camp of journalists amid divisions among the professionals, hold some substance. He told a televised talk on the raging controversies that "I don't agree, I'm not obliged to comply - this type of intransigence cannot be judicious now". But on the prime minister's return from the US after attending the United Nations General Assembly (UNGA) session she again came up with government stand for the last. Everyone desires that she should give a rethink to the issue to preserve the Sundarbans as she is now back from the High Level Segment of the 22nd Session of the Conference of the Parties ( COP22 ) at Marrakech, a former imperial city in western Morocco, where she urged global leaders to fight together the perilous threats of climate change. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh77" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="December 4, 2016 Sunday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Dec. 4 -- Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina will make a courtesy call on President Abdul Hamid at Bangabhaban on Sunday evening. The meeting will begin at 7pm, according to the programme schedule of the President, reports UNB. Generally, the Prime Minister meets President after foreign visits. Sheikh Hasina went to Hungary on November 28 on a four-day visit at the invitation of Hungarian President Dr Janos Ader to attend the Budapest Water Summit 2016. She also went to Morocco on November 14 on a three-day official visit to attend two high-level segments of the Conference of the Parties ( COP-22 ). Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh78" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="October 21, 2016 Friday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Oct. 21 -- Climate experts on Friday called for strengthening bargaining capacity of Least Developed Countries (LDCs) like Bangladesh through acquiring knowledge on different aspects of climate change issues. LDCs must be united by developing strong leadership to pressurise developed countries to take actions against planet's rising temperatures, they said. Speakers said it at a press conference on " COP 22 Climate Change Conference: Expectation of civil society" at the National Press Club, Dhaka. Different organisations including Forum of Environmental Journalists of Bangladesh (FEJB), Equity Justice Working Group-Bangladesh (EquityBD) and Centre for Sustainable Rural Livelihood(CSRL) organised the press conference, reports BSS. General Secretary of National Press Club and Chairman of FEJB Quamrul Islam Chowdhury, Chief Moderator of EquityBD M Rezaul Karim Chowdhry and CSRL Secretary Sharmind Neelormi, among others, addressed the press conference. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh79" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="November 17, 2016 Thursday"source="The Financial Express (Bangladesh)" >
Bangladesh, Nov. 17 -- Finance Minister Abul Maal Abdul Muhith indicated that the government is going to reduce fuel oil prices soon in order to strengthen the country's economy. A decision in principle in this regard will be finalised soon, the minister said, reports bdnews24.com. "The issue of cutting down on oil prices was discussed at a coordination council meeting. Now we will prepare the papers and send those to the energy ministry," Muhith said on Thursday. "The matter will be finalised after discussions with the prime minister.," he told reporters after a delegation of the International Monetary Fund met him at the Secretariat on Thursday. Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina returned home earlier in the day after attending the COP 22 UN Climate Change Conference at Marrakesh in Morocco. On Monday, the Fiscal Coordination Council decided in principle to reduce fuel oil prices. The decision, according to media reports, will come into effect next month. Published by HT Syndication with permission from The Financial Express. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:htsyndication@hindustantimes.com htsyndication@hindustantimes.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP22_Bangladesh80" COP="COP22" country="Bangladesh" date="October 31, 2016 Monday"source="Energy & Power" >
The world leaders have set an ambitious target to reach a zero CO2 emission era by the end of this century and already adopted a roadmap to reach there. And now they are struggling to find ways how the path could be implemented. They all know they will have to arrest the CO2 emission mostly created by the energy sector. On the other hand, many of the leaders as well as the energy sector leaders have come up with the challenges in mitigating the emission level. The leaders in the just concluded 23rd World Energy Congress in Turkey have opined that fossil fuel would still dominate the energy sector - to be specific, comparatively cleaner gas to dominate for at least next 40 years till 2060 while notorious coal and petroleum oil consumption to decline. Unfortunately, they predict, the renewable energy alone is unlikely to be able to make up for the demand to reach by then. The global energy policymakers have long been struggling to devise a strategy on how to overcome the difficulties, but so far ended up in finding only an Energy Trilemma - energy security, energy equity and environmental sustainability. UN added with it a nexus of Food, Energy and Water Resources (FEW). This, in fact, pushed the policymakers in a deeper crisis. Now the experts at the WEC started saying about a need for balancing between the trilemma and the FEW, some of them would prefer to integrate the two aspects. Addressing the congress, UN Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon commended the WEC for emphasizing the "Energy Trilemma," the World Energy Council's definition of energy sustainability based on the three core dimensions: energy security, energy equity, and environmental sustainability. According to Energy Ministers gathered at the Energy Congress, the private sector has a role to play in pushing for a bigger share of renewables in the energy mix. Energy and Environment ministers from UAE, Switzerland, Sudan, Ecuador and Afghanistan were joined by senior industry players from around the world to consider what is needed to achieve a smooth, quick transition to sustainable, affordable and low-carbon energy. They looked at the requirements for political and economic collaboration as well as the conundrum of striving for innovation while maintaining stable investment frameworks to keep the trilemma balanced and avoid political impact. While they agreed governments should be encouraged to enter into public-private partnerships to facilitate and accelerate this energy transition, the key global energy leaders cautioned against too big an involvement. The 2016 Energy Trilemma Index ranking shows global energy sector shifting priorities towards more balanced energy mix - Denmark, Switzerland and Sweden achieve AAA score and lead the 125 countries' index ranking. Nine out of top 10 countries are from Europe showing that EU cooperation on long-term policy for energy and climate to 2020 contributes to regional trilemma success. This signals that countries are building more energy systems by concurrently addressing the three dimensions of the Energy Trilemma - energy security, energy equity and environmental sustainability - finds the new Energy Trilemma Index report launched at the Congress. The Energy Trilemma Index 2016: Benchmarking the sustainability of national energy systems prepared by the World Energy Council, in partnership with Oliver Wyman along with its parent Marsh and McLennan Companies' Global Risk Center, provides a comparative ranking of 125 countries in terms of their ability to provide secure, affordable and environmentally sustainable energy systems. The 6th annual edition presents a new methodology based on a comprehensive set of 35 indicators with enhanced focus on diversity, quality and affordability of supply as well as the resilience of a country's system. But with only 13 of 125 countries achieving a triple A score for their progress on the trilemma goals, our work continues to offer valuable lessons for policymakers on how to create the frameworks which will incentivize investment and innovation to deliver secure energy for all while meeting the climate challenge." Key findings from the top performing countries and regional analysis show that: - 9 out of 10 countries are European showing that cooperation on long term policy for energy and climate can contribute to regional success even though Europe still has to manage its energy transition focusing on new market designs, demand management and establish an effective carbon price. - New Zealand makes the top 10 as the leading country in the East and the Philippines rank at the top of the environmental sustainability dimension whilst the Asian region overall faces the challenge of fast increasing energy demand and highly energy intensive future. - With around 50% of global resources in oil and gas, Middle East and North Africa countries are facing a real diversification and reduction of energy intensity challenge in order to improve their lower environmental performance. UAE leads the region with its diversification efforts positioning the country on the Index's "positive watch" list. - In Latin America, policies need to focus on system's resilience to extreme weather events and improving energy equity, building on the example of Uruguay, which ranks the highest in the region after operating a successful energy transition. - In Sub-Saharan Africa, Mauritius (49), Gabon (67) and South Africa (84) form the top three of a region that still register lowest levels of energy access despite a rich endowment in resources and high renewables potential. - Several G7 countries are flagged on the negative watch list including Germany, USA and the UK highlighting the challenges facing the more traditional leading industrialized countries to operate their energy transformation. A Call to Action Under the circumstances and marking the event of the Congress, the World Energy Council (WEC) issued a call to action. It says the transition is unstoppable and requires a global response and careful management, building on the principles of the Energy Trilemma. A successful energy transformation calls for worldwide political and economic collaboration at an unprecedented scale. There will be intense pressure on the three dimensions of the trilemma as individual countries aspire to improve energy security, expand energy equity and reduce carbon emissions. Novel approaches will be needed to keep the three dimensions balanced. Governments, business leaders, investors, and society will have to rethink the energy contract and find new ways to avoid deadlocks, allowing for timely decisions and delivery of integrated, effective and efficient infrastructure. Innovative urban planning solutions, adequate resilience response, as well as enabling policies and trade frameworks will all be required. Solutions will not solely come from within energy, but energy has a historic opportunity to provide leadership to power the broader industrial revolution. With the attendance of 250 ministers and CEOs as well as participation of key figures in policy making and 265 speakers from 82 countries in more than 60 meetings, the main focus of the remarks made by the world leaders have stressed on the energy supply security as well as diversification of energy. Chairman and CEO of WEC Younghoon David Kim, who expressed his thanks to Turkey's President Erdogan for his leadership and personal support for the event, urged the energy sector leaders to embrace new frontiers. Despite the instability and insecurity not only in the region but also throughout the world caused by crises, conflicts and terror, energy remains as major component in global relations. With this respect, the World Energy Congress in which is described as an event of "World's Energy Olympics" by President Erdogan aims to reach people worldwide with the motto of "share for peace." "Our goal through the congress is to not only establish platform to exchange ideas regarding energy's vision and scenarios towards future but also to make energy a tool for peace and justice," said President Erdogan. Also speaking at the Congress, Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro urged for new mechanisms to be put into place to drive up oil prices saying, "Prices are not sustainable anymore and have fallen to their lowest levels in the last 40 years.... We are seeing them fall to below the cost of production. Prices must be fairer and more realistic....for investment we need fair prices." Turkey's Prime Minister Binali Yildirim said: "New actors are coming to the energy sector every day. The global energy community needs to address [this] transformation process accordingly." He went on to say, "Countries should make sure that energy prices are not too high. Let's keep prices stable; this is a common expectation." Ahead of the event, the WEC has issued a statement calling on the energy sector to embrace a historic opportunity to redefine the energy contract. The reality that per capita demand for energy will peak before 2030, the reality that we haven't done enough to decarbonize our economies and the realities for national and private balance sheets are some of the 7 realities highlighted in the statement. Speaking ahead of the Congress, Marie-Jose Nadeau, Chair, World Energy Council, said: "The grand energy transition is an unstoppable phenomenon. Adapting to this new reality with innovative technologies and different business models will require a massive effort and our ability to respond rapidly will define both winners and losers." Christoph Frei, Secretary General, World Energy Council, added: "Slower global growth and shifting demographics define a new normal. The main driving forces are increasing political pressure to decarbonize, innovation fuelled by an unstoppable digital revolution, as well as emerging risks for which yesterday's unlikely has become today's reality. The full statement was shared with the WEC membership of ministers and energy leaders in nearly 100 countries along with the delegates to the 23rd World Energy Congress in Istanbul, Turkey. It says the next decade will begin to define the winners and losers of the energy transformation, making it crucial to understand seven new realities for the energy sector. The New Realities Energy 1. From Peak Oil to Peak Demand The peak oil debate belongs to the past: the reality is that per capita demand for energy will peak before 2030. Energy intensity reductions supported by primary energy substitution effects are set to increase at a faster rate than the demand increase from a growing global middle class. This therefore shifts the discussion from peak oil to peak demand with anticipated growth limited to only a 20% increase over the next 45 years. This will have significant implications for energy companies in terms of their ability to achieve their growth expectations, which will need to be factored into investment strategies. 2. Spending the Carbon Budget We haven't done enough to decarbonize our economies: the world will have to accelerate the decarbonization of the global GDP to a rate of 6%/yr to remain within the carbon budget associated with 2oC global warming. This will take considerable effort since with current trends could be reached and surpass the carbon budget between 2045 and 2055, even with optimistic assumptions on energy intensity reductions. The Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) agreed at COP21 provide about 1/3rd of the required ambition level. Rapid and successful transitioning of global transport to low carbon solutions presents the biggest obstacle or opportunity in achieving climate goals. Current market signals alone are not enough to improve critical areas such as energy efficiency, improved electrical storage, penetration of clean transport and much needed adoption of Carbon Capture, Utilization and Storage (CCUS). Clear, focused and unambiguous policies and institutional frameworks are required to reinforce a wider deployment of solutions that accelerate the transition and drive consumer choice towards the most carbon and cost effective solutions. 3. From Stranded Assets to Stranded Resources With stagnating growth potential in the oil sector and with coal likely to be of little importance by 2060, there will be a shift in the discussion from stranded assets (predominantly enterprise owned) to stranded resources in oil and coal (predominantly state owned). This has the potential to cause significant stress to the current global economic and geopolitical equilibrium and will need to be part of a broadened carbon and climate dialogue. 4. Shifting System Resilience We have seen a fourfold increase in extreme weather events over the past 30 years, increasing pressure on use of water in energy production and increasing levels of cyber threat that are all contributing to a new reality for the energy sector. With increasing systems integration, resilience is no longer just about building systems stronger and returning single assets to full operation after a disruptive event. When interdependent systems are blacked out, by extreme weather or cyber-attack, the system as a whole is at risk of being deadlocked. Black-starting capability, decentralized decision autonomy and local empowerment have become key concepts of a new "soft resilience" approach as opposed to the traditional "hard resilience" practice of simply building systems stronger. Operating in this new landscape requires different tools and new approaches to manage risk. 5. A Path of Innovation We are beyond the tipping point of a technology revolution in the energy sector. Energy markets are further increasing in complexity, accelerated by fragmented energy policy, fast moving technological innovation, and shifting consumer expectations. New realities are increasingly characterized by growing zero marginal cost supply, low entry barriers, greater focus on decentralization and local empowerment, digitalization and commoditization of technology, more flexible and rapid pay back solutions, increasingly active investors and servicing of emancipated consumers. Solar and wind power will continue their rapid growth with the electrification of energy use an unstoppable trend. As a percentage of total final production, electricity could reach penetration levels by 2060 as high as 30%, with up to 98% coming from non CO2 emitting technologies, a 3-fold increase over the current share with 40% coming from solar and wind technologies alone, representing a 10-fold increase over current share. Current market designs and business models are unable to cope with these new realities and will require entirely new skills-sets, business models and financing solutions. Meanwhile, we will still depend on up to 45% of our generated electricity being provided from fossil fuels supplemented by CCUS. To truly realize the potential, we need more focused Research, Development and Demonstration (RDandD). Coordinated innovation initiatives will be critical to the credibility of the decarbonization agenda. 6. Changing Global Governance The center of gravity in energy has moved outside OECD countries: China, India and Africa define tomorrow's agenda for energy and must take their due place in global energy governance. The world is witnessing a trend to more inclusive global energy governance with more global governance tools available than even five years ago: The United Nations have agreed a sustainable development goal on energy (SDG7), the Conference of the Parties (COP) process has achieved a deal in Paris, and organizations such as the IEA have been reaching out to new key energy players, including China. The G20 has energy security on the agenda and the Clean Energy Ministerial is including countries beyond the G20. Meanwhile, many of the substantive agendas remain a work in progress: minimizing international tariff and non-tariff trade barriers for clean energy goods and services to enable clean energy deployment; introducing carbon pricing mechanisms to ensure adequate investment signals; reinforcing regional infrastructure integration and market harmonization measures to ensure effective resources sharing. Focus will be required in this area, along with improved capability to respond sympathetically to increasing public activism, if we are to enable the energy transformation. 7. Entrepreneurship Driving Access for All Progress has been made, but we still have 1.1 billion people without access to energy. The recognition of energy as the 7th development goal by the United Nations has provided additional focus on high impact opportunities as well as the rapid deployment of best technology solutions. The recent rise of innovative and disruptive business models for rural off-grid power solutions is providing a formidable opportunity to places with greatest need in Sub-Saharan Africa or South Asia. The rollout of these solutions will define key entry points into tomorrow's markets and are a great contribution to keep equity gaps from increasing. Empowered trade and climate policy will be important for technology transfer to ensure the mistakes of the past are not repeated. Robust policy and institutional frameworks are urgently needed to de-risk and support entrepreneurial approaches and enable them to access large scale investors. Meanwhile, a session of the Congress was told that the balancing of supply and demand, and not the price of a barrel of oil, is the key concern for oil-producing nations. "My eyes aren't on the price, my eyes are on supply and demand," said Saudi Arabia's Minister of Energy, Industry and Mines, Khalid al Falih, after making the opening keynote address at the 23rd World Energy Congress. He said the world need to continue investing in all energy sources. While the industry must be ambitious, its approach must be "pragmatic considering the potentially bumpy road ahead," he said. "Energy transformation will not be linear. There will be setbacks," he said, adding that the international community would have to "skillfully navigate the uncharted waters of the energy transition." He said that Saudi Arabia would be stepping up investment in unconventional oil and gas, targeting 18 bcf by 2020. Determined to ratify the Paris Agreement on climate change before COP22 , the Minister also said that the Kingdom was targeting 10 GW in power-generation capacity from renewable resources, mainly solar and wind power, over the next five years. In her introductory remarks, Marie-Jose Nadeau, Chair of the World Energy Council, said: "No company, no country, no consumer will be unaffected by the changes we are set to witness. We call this the grand energy transition. None of us can continue business as usual," Nadeau said, adding that the future looked challenging for oil-producing countries. "Those we do not adapt will eventually lose," she said. FEW Must Not Look in Isolation Energy is inextricably linked to water and food, and all three are crucial to human existence however, the debate in the global energy business often overlooks this nexus, agreed panelists at the Congress. Water is a critical component of not only agriculture but also electricity production. Ninety-eight percent of electricity directly depends on water, from the extraction of primary energy sources such as oil and gas, to hydroelectric dams and river run-offs. "The world is on the wrong track with water use and we need to get back to a holistic appreciation of water and its interaction with energy and life," said Jason Drew, CEO, AgriProtein, a South African company that turns organic food waste into reusable proteins in a process that uses almost no water. "The cost of not doing something about water is unimaginable. Unfortunately, there is not a regular and clear policy around the world. There is no decision taken seriously," said Matar Al Neyadi, the UAE's Undersecretary at the Ministry of Energy and Vice Chair for the Gulf States/Middle East at the World Energy Council. Maria Neira, Director of Public Health, Environmental and Social Determinants, WHO, said, "We need to work on these essential pillars of clean energy, clean water and clean air. Clean air is the next human disaster on the horizon." A World Energy Council report called "The road to resilience - managing the risks of the energy-water-food nexus," prepared in collaboration with Swiss Re Corporate Solutions and Marsh and McLennan, is the first in a series that addresses the need for more investment and system change to combat the new emerging risks, including extreme weather, the energy-water-food nexus and cyber risks. Key findings of the report: 1. Energy is the second-largest freshwater user after agriculture. It is used all along the energy value chain from primary energy production to power generation. 3. Alongside growing demand, increasing uncertainty about water availability and quality will further increase the significance of risks posed by the nexus. 4. From 2014 to 2069, reductions in usable water capacity could impact 60% of the 24,515 hydropower plants analyzed and more than 80% of the 1,427 thermoelectric plants. 5. In many cases, location-specific knowledge on water issues and modeling tools to adequately reflect risks posed by the nexus in energy infrastructure investment decisions are lacking. 6. The risks posed by the nexus are often made worse by the lack of sound water governance such as well-defined water rights for competing users, water pricing and trading arrangements. 7. Cross-border cooperation is the key. Consumers to Drive Transition to Smart Grids Electricity grids need a new model, one that puts power in the hands of consumers. A panel discussing smart electricity transmission grids emphasized the importance of two driving forces behind their wide scale implementation: data and consumers. With its potential to promote efficiency and transform the way companies and consumers interact with electricity, data was highlighted as a central benefit of the smart grid. Electrical grids collect huge amounts of data, which is frequently lost to both utilities and consumers. But while consumers will be key in the transition to smart grids, bringing them on board with the change may not be easy. Julian Hardy, CEO, Eseye, said, "Consumers have an apathy to data. They focus on cost, on environmental footprint and access to energy in emerging markets." Panelists stressed the importance of the security of the system. With Hardy saying, "At the end of the day, you're dealing with consumers' lives." Digitization and Efficiency Keys to Energy Future Panelists offered insights on potential directions for the energy industry. At issue are three key goals: achieving the COP 21 targets from the 2015 Paris Agreement on climate change, pursuing and deploying technological breakthroughs and digital transformation of the industry. Fatih Birol, Executive Director of the International Energy Agency, stressed efficiency as key to meeting rising demand, comparing it to an untapped fuel: "All countries have energy efficiency resources. Unfortunately we are not making enough use of this." He pointed to slowed growth in China's oil demand as an example of steps made due to increases in efficiency. Gerald Davis, Executive Chair of Scenarios, World Energy Council, said, "The world is undergoing a grand transition, which will create a fundamentally new world for the energy industry," adding, "historically, people have talked about peak oil but now disruptive trends are leading energy experts to consider the implications of peak demand." Underscoring that rise of solar and wind energy will continue, the report says growth in non-fossil energy sources will dominate electricity generation to 2060. Solar and wind energy accounted for only 4% of power generation in 2014, but the number will likely rise up to 39% by 2060. Stable Tariffs to Boost Renewables Stable tariffs and policy support are needed to boost the growth of the renewable energy sector according to industry leaders at the Congress. 2015 saw record-breaking investment in renewable energy. At more than $348 billion, funding for clean energy is twice as high as spending on fossil fuels. More than half of that investment came from developing economies. While investment in the first half of 2016 was lower, this was at least partially due to the lower cost of solar panels and the increased number large-scale, lower-capex projects. Cheaper technology and financing are also causing the cost of power generation by renewable technologies to fall while the prices of coal and gas-fired electricity generation are rising, although clean energy remains more expensive. The daily cycle of output at solar and constant fluctuation of wind power generation presents storage challenges. The World Energy Council predicts that the cost of energy storage will fall 70% over the next 15 years. Carbon capture and storage (CCS) has an essential role to play in reaching global emissions reduction targets, despite slow development. CCS projects are often small, with capacity <1 million tonnes of CO2. There are 22 large-scale CCS projects currently in operation or under construction around the world, with capacity to capture up to 40 million tonnes of carbon dioxide per year. These projects cover a range of industries including gas processing, power generation, fertilizers, steel, hydrogen production and chemicals. Cement, chemicals, iron, refining and steel plants contribute to 20% of global carbon emissions. The World Energy Council's energy scenario expects the technology to play an important role in emissions mitigation after 2030. Meanwhile, the IEA estimates CCS will contribute to about a sixth of total CO2 emissions reduction required in 2050 and 14% of cumulative emissions reduction through 2050, against a business-as-usual scenario. Tipping Point for Electric Vehicles in 2020s The price of electric cars is expected to drop far enough by the 2020s to allow for direct competition with their combustion-engine counterparts. Advances in energy storage technology are fundamental to the future of the electric vehicle market as the cost of batteries currently keeps vehicle prices high. However, recent declines in the price of batteries could make the electric car an affordable option within the next two decades. Christina Bu, Secretary General, Norwegian Electric Vehicle Association predicted: "After 2020 electric car prices will go down and will be able to compete with traditional cars without additional incentives." Bu pointed to the rapid orders of the Tesla Model 3 car as evidence of the potential in future electric vehicle sales. Steven Young, Regional President of Turkey and the Middle East, Bosch said: "The cost of manufacturing electric cars will catch traditional production costs in seven to eight years." He said that 2025 would be the tipping point and the shift would, "have a domino effect on the production and consumption sides." Time of Convergence and Collaboration A time of challenging oil prices has coincided with unprecedented cooperation among actors in the global energy industry, the secretary-general of OPEC said in the closing session of the Congress. Secretary-General Mohammad Barkindo, joined onstage by SOCAR President Rovnag Ibrahim Abdullayev, spoke of seeing a "convergence of views between net producers and net consuming countries." Consuming countries, he said, were showing equal concern with the current period of low oil prices as their producing counterparts. Barkindo and Abdullayev spoke on key issues affecting the global energy industry. Abdullayev discussed Azerbaijan's approach to the prolonged period of low oil prices, saying that while many countries halted investments, Baku has implemented a different strategy. "We decided to undertake large projects. We didn't look at it only from a commercial point of view. With projects such as Shah Deniz, we wanted to provide long-term energy security," Abdullayev said. Barkindo stressed the unexpected longevity of the slump in prices. "We've had this severe contraction in investments and next year, it's still looking bleak." In light of the drop in upstream investments, he said, this "poses a serious threat" to the security of the supply. Gas, Power and Growth Sustainable development and projected growth in energy use were highlighted in keynote speeches of the Congress. Alexander Medvedev, Deputy Chairman of the Management Committee, Gazprom, echoed President Vladimir Putin's stance in relation to the ongoing production talks between OPEC and non-OPEC petroleum producers, said: "We will support a freeze [on production]." Guler Sabanci, Chairman, Sabanci Holding highlighted strides made by Turkey in its power sector, citing a tripling of the country's power generation capacity in the past 15 years and improvements to security of supply. Role of Nuclear Power at Cost The development of nuclear power today is concentrated with a small group of nations. China, India, Korea and Russia accounted for 40 of the 65 reactors under construction at the end of 2015. There are 446 operating nuclear reactors globally, which produce 11% of the world's electricity. Obstacles to more widespread nuclear power are public opposition, especially after the Fukushima reactor accident in 2011, the increasing price tag of reactor construction, and the falling costs of gas feedstock and renewables technology. Meanwhile, technological development continues in areas such as fast neutron reactors, high-temperature reactors, and small modular reactors. Kirill Komarov, First Deputy CEO for Corporate Development and International Business, Rosatom, was confident in the future success of nuclear energy. "It is possible to repeat the success of the previous century in the field of nuclear energy." Natural Gas to be Key to Energy Mix Natural gas will be the most likely substitute for coal as a future power generation feedstock according to BP's CEO Bob Dudley. During his keynote address at the Congress, Dudley said that current major projects in BP's portfolio are natural gas including the Khazzan project in Oman, Tangguh in Indonesia, Shah Deniz in Azerbaijan as well as projects in Trinidad and Egypt. He predicted that natural gas projects would comprise 60% of the company's portfolio by the end of the decade: "This is an important shift. This is the age of big gas." The BP chief said that renewable energy, even though it would exceed the growth rate of any other fuel it history, would not reach 15% of the overall future energy mix by 2025, up from the current 2%. Electricity Actors Enter New Frontiers Addressing market specifics and customer needs is a priority, and new technologies, particularly big data and smart solutions, have a prime role to play, representatives from global utilities companies agreed during a roundtable discussion at the Congress. New smart energy technologies and consumer behavior are changing conventional wisdom in the electricity supply sector. Decentralized systems can accommodate multiple generation sources closer to end users, optimize renewables input, and encourage increased efficiency. But there is no one-size-fits-all solution. Michael Bell, President and CEO, Silver Spring Network, emphasized the importance of technology that "creates new industries and disrupts old ones." Bell underlined the importance of smart technologies and of making more information available to consumers. He said, "It is possible to distil big data down to something that is quite tangible for consumers." Risks of Cyber Attacks in Energy Industry When it comes to dealing with cyber threats to energy systems, companies not only struggle to assess the risk but also often fail to develop the in-house tools to understand their own response. This point was underscored by Michael Bell, President, CEO and Member of the Board of Directors, Silver Spring Network, at a session that outlined the key challenges facing companies, contending with the risk of cyber-attacks. Bell said: "Everyone is rushing to adopt technologies but standards need to be used and best practices need to be implemented. It's important to make sure you have the expertise in-house and not farm it out to someone else. You need to understand it." A consensus among cyber security experts holds that cyber attacks on energy infrastructure are growing in number, scope and sophistication. A Symantec Corporation study reported that 43% of global mining, oil and gas companies experienced attacks in 2014. Such attacks can disrupt operations, causing blackouts, oil spills, data leaks, losses in production and physical damage, as well as impacting shareholder confidence. Regulations to Encourage Renewables The development of regulatory frameworks is key to boosting renewables, according to industry leaders. "Regulation is key from the investor point of view in renewables," Carlo Pignoloni, head of Europe and North Africa, Enel Green Power, told a session. Renewable energy makes up nearly around 30% of the world's installed generation capacity, and almost a quarter of electricity production. However, wind and solar, in part because of the challenges their variability poses to integration into the power grid, make up <5% of generated power. A 2016 study by the WEC found that countries need to increase the capacity of both their transmission and distribution grids to accommodate renewables, especially due to the distance of renewable power sources from high-consumption areas. Developing New Dynamic with Gas and LNG As global energy demand rises and with the pressure to transition towards a lower-carbon energy supply, the market for natural gas and liquefied natural gas (LNG) continues to expand. According to a World Energy Council study, unconventionals have now become a global phenomenon, transforming LNG markets through supply diversity and increased competition. Growing supplies of unconventional gas, led by US shale gas and Australian coal-bed methane (CBM), are emerging on the global market as LNG, transforming the market with dramatic price developments in Asia and beyond. Commodity Prices to be Highly Volatile At the Congress, a high-level discussion took place about OPEC's new production ceiling, the motives behind it and the potential OPEC/non-OPEC collaborative effort in this direction. Public and private actors discussed the role of OPEC, the fundamentals of supply and demand, the acceleration of cycles and the need to invest in new projects. Mohammad Barkindo, OPEC Secretary General, said: "There is a convergence of views both inside and outside OPEC towards market and price stabilization. Even OECD countries are now struggling, some of them facing deflation." Replace Coal with Gas for Cleaner Energy The world must wean itself off coal to generate electricity according to industry and government leaders at the World Energy Congress in Istanbul. Natural gas could play an important role as a "bridging fuel" to a low-carbon global economy. Substituting coal for gas as a feedstock for power plants will cut greenhouse gas emissions by half. Gas is also touted as an ideal backup for intermittent renewable energy supply, at least in areas with established infrastructure. The resource is also growing in popularity as a vehicle fuel, particularly in North America, because of its large volumes of unconventional reserves. Maros Sefcovic, Vice President in Charge of Energy Union, European Commission said: "Gas is a very important transitional fuel." The EU wants to keep gas consumption steady through 2030 and phase out coal. Trade Agreements Vital to Meeting Paris Goals The deal, which will come into force in 2020, requires signatories to submit Intended Nationally Determined Contributions (INDCs) every five years. Wide in scope and ambition, there are still many questions about how this will be implemented and the impact on economies. "The treaty is based on decentralized, uncoordinated action which will affect the terms of trade," said Ricardo Melendez-Ortiz, CEO, International Centre for Trade and Sustainable Development. "We need changes in the current frameworks we have for trade. For wind energy, we use 2,000 components that will change borders several times. If you have tariffs, the system is more difficult." Conclusion The five-day World Energy Congress that concluded with a closing ceremony on October 13 emphasized that the world would have to look for new technologies to create alternative energies in the future and look to balancing energy security, sustainability and affordability at the same time. Upcoming WEC chair Younghoon David Kim said it did not look possible to meet energy demands in the near future without fossil fuels and emphasized about 59 percent of global energy mix by 2050 would still consist of fossil fuels. "We have to search for efficient ways of creating and using fossil fuels as they will still continue to play an important role. We have to keep on searching for the new generation of sustainable technologies and keep on sharing the spirit of COP21 [Paris Climate Conference]," he said. Current WEC President Marie-Jose Nadeau said environmental issues would play an "increasingly important element of future global energy policy". "It is a positive development that major hard carbon producers look committed to decreasing their own carbon emissions," she added. United Arab Emirates Energy Minister Suhail Mohamed Faraj Al Mazrouei said he felt sure the world would be a greener place in the future. "The future of energy would have to be more innovative to make sure the commitments made by all nations in COP21 are met. "But they cannot be met only by governments. The collaboration of the private sector and young generations is also needed," he said. The 24th World Energy Congress will be held in 2019 in Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates. \</doc>
