<doc ID="COP25_Hong.Kong1" COP="COP25" country="Hong.Kong" date="December 9, 2019 Monday"source="EJ Insight" >
Tighter government climate regulations by 2025 could wipe up to US$2.3 trillion off the value of companies in industries ranging from fossil fuel producers to agriculture and car makers, an investor group warned, Reuters reports. Any abrupt policy shifts risk severely disrupting current investment strategies, Principles of Responsible Investing (PRI), a group representing investors with US$86 trillion of assets under management, was quoted as saying in a report.\~ "As the realities of climate change catch up, social pressure mounts, and low carbon solutions get cheaper, it's highly improbable that governments will be allowed to let the world sleep-walk into greater rises in temperature without being compelled into forceful action sooner," PRI Chief Executive Fiona Reynolds said.\~ "This poses huge threats for assets and for the wider system."\~ Most exposed is the fossil fuel sector which could lose one third of its current value, the PRI report said. Fossil fuels account for around two thirds of global greenhouse gas emissions.\~ Coal firms could lose as much as 44 percent in value, while the world's top oil and gas companies risk losing up to 31 percent of their current market share, according the report which forecasts oil demand peaking around 2027.\~ The analysis showed that broad index-based funds such as the iShares MSCI ACWI ETF could lose up to 4.5 percent or US$2.3 trillion in its value under the most extreme scenario.\~ The shift would nevertheless also lead to winners.\~ Auto makers heavily invested in electric vehicles and electric utility firms using low-carbon power could more than double their values, the report said.\~ The PRI report came out as world leaders meet in Madrid for the 2019 United Nations climate change conference , known as COP25 . HYPERLINK mailto:english@hkej.com english@hkej.com RC \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_Hong.Kong2" COP="COP25" country="Hong.Kong" date="December 5, 2019 Thursday 6:30 AM EST"source="Hong Kong Government News" >
Dec. 5 -- Hong Kong SAR Government issued the following news release: Following is the speech by the Secretary for Financial Services and the Treasury, Mr James Lau, at the Best Corporate Governance Awards 2019 Awards Presentation Luncheon this afternoon (December 5): Patrick (President of the Hong Kong Institute of Certified Public Accountants (HKICPA), Mr Patrick Law), ladies and gentlemen, Good afternoon. I had to miss your annual dinner last Monday but I am glad to be here today for the ceremony for the Best Corporate Governance Awards organised by the HKICPA. The different categories of 26 awards are witnesses of many corporates striving very hard to achieve excellence in corporate governance. We are here to congratulate the winning companies but we do recognise the efforts and commitments of all participants. Today I'd like to touch briefly on one aspect of global corporate governance, and that is sustainability and social responsibility. The United Nations Climate Change Conference , COP25 , is meeting these two weeks in Madrid. They just issued a carbon tracking report yesterday that pointed to a rise in global carbon emission, notwithstanding commitments in previous conferences. Sustainable development requires global efforts, and that includes us in Hong Kong. We are today in the 20th anniversary of the Awards and it is coincidental that it is called china anniversary, with a lowercase "c". China, with a capital "C", actually accords very high priority to sustainable development and social responsibility. When China was the G20 chair in 2016, it pushed very hard for the ratification of the COP21 Paris Agreement. But, on the contrary, a major G20 member has very recently started the process to withdraw from the Paris Agreement. Against this tide, Hong Kong still needs to play our role and our part for the greater global good. As the premier international financial centre in Asia, we have to shape our role as a regional hub for green finance through three different avenues. First, we have issued guidance for environmental, social and governance (ESG) investment products as well as ESG reporting. In April, the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) published guidance on enhanced disclosures for ESG investment funds in order to enhance transparency, comparability and credibility for their product offerings. As for ESG reporting for listed companies, the Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited published ESG guidance materials in May to improve issuers' disclosure of ESG activities and metrics. In September, the Hong Kong Green Finance Association published guidelines on impact assessment for green bonds. Secondly, the Hong Kong Monetary Authority (HKMA) set up in May the Centre for Green Finance under the Infrastructure Financing Facilitation Office as a platform for technical support for industry players in banking and finance. The HKMhas also decided in its management of the Exchange Fund to accord priority to green and ESG investments. The HKMwill continue to organise workshops to enhance green awareness and capacity building in Hong Kong. The third point is about multilateral collaboration. In June, the HKMjoined the Network of Central Banks and Supervisors for Greening the Financial System to explore how to incorporate climate risk and other related factors in supervisory framework and macro surveillance work. The SFC will also be leading a working group for member regulators of the IOSCO (International Organization of Securities Commissions) in Asia-Pacific to consider recommendations for redirecting capital towards green and sustainable investments. Let me close by just citing an example why Hong Kong, for its own sake, should champion sustainable development. Hong Kong is a low-lying coastal city and is susceptible to flooding from the rising sea level. The super typhoon Mangkhut that we saw in September last year caused serious and extensive damage to Hong Kong. The severe flooding we saw in Hong Kong and Macao is a dire reminder for all of us on the importance of sustainable development and, in this particular case, climate change. So, let us join hands and make this world a better and more sustainable one. Thank you very much. Source: Hong Kong SAR Government \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_Hong.Kong3" COP="COP25" country="Hong.Kong" date="December 11, 2019 Wednesday"source="Hong Kong Free Press" >
Delegates at this week\' s UN Climate Change Conference ( COP25 ) will once again try to implement measures to halt our march towards disastrous global warming. And as new plans and goals are announced at the end of these conferences, the rest of us will continue with our daily routines, making only piecemeal changes in our lifestyles and feeling a bit helpless given the size of the problem. This thought occurred to me as HYPERLINK https://www.nationalgeographic.com/culture/food/the-plate/2016/02/09/the-surprisingly-big-carbon-shadow-cast-by-slender-asparagus/ asparagus from \~ HYPERLINK https://www.cfiperishables.com/asparagus-from-mexico/ Mexico caught my eye while I was strolling through the vegetable section of the supermarket. Asparagus in the autumn, of course, is actually no longer so eye-catching. Nor is any type of out-of-season produce. A few steps away from the asparagus was yet another out-of-season food, this time from \~ HYPERLINK https://www.asparagus-lover.com/should-we-buy-peruvian-asparagus.html Peru \- blueberries. Out-of-season fruit and vegetables were generally not available a couple of generations ago, although some produce that keeps well, such as apples, cabbage, carrots, potatoes and onions have been eaten year-round for centuries. But as far as out-of-season fruit and vegetables go, that was about it. Asparagus. Photo: Wikimedia Commons/Muffet. Today, we have grown accustomed to having all sorts of fruit and vegetables at all times of year. No doubt, anyone under about 40 years old finds it completely normal to be able to buy blueberries and asparagus at any time of year. However, until fairly recently, asparagus and blueberries were available only in the spring and summer respectively, if at all. These two fruits and vegetables deserve a closer look because unless they are eaten when they are in season, they must have come from far away, which explains their Mexican and Peruvian origin at this time of year. This manipulation, in the case of asparagus, is carried out by growers who plant it in the desert. By timing the irrigation, the plants can be triggered to reach harvest-ready maturity to meet demand in export markets in the fall and winter. Asparagus, unlike blueberries, however, is especially sensitive. Under ideal temperatures and atmospheric conditions, blueberries can be HYPERLINK shipped by sea as far as Asia, which takes several weeks, and arrive in palatable condition. Not so with asparagus, which quickly loses flavour and becomes woody as time passes after it is harvested. Anyone who has personally harvested an asparagus spear and immediately fried it with a bit of salt and garlic will know what I mean. It\' s succulence and texture bear little resemblance to the supermarket variety. A cargo ship. Photo: Alexander Bobrov/Pexels. By one estimate, the carbon footprint of air-freighted food is 50 times greater than that of produce shipped by sea. Among vegetables, out of season asparagus has a greenhouse gas emissions rating of 8.9 kilograms, by far the highest of any vegetable. Compared with pumpkins, which are hardly ever shipped by air, and have the lowest footprint among vegetables at 0.3 kilograms, eating asparagus in the fall and winter has to be viewed as an egregious affront to the planet. However, when typical shoppers notice asparagus in the supermarket and casually toss a bundle into the basket, notions of the associated carbon footprint probably never enter their minds. They can be forgiven because most food packaging does not state the means of transport used, and even if our air-freighted fruit and vegetables were required to have a little airplane icon sticker, the average consumer would view it positively, likely thinking the food was fresher. One bundle of airfreighted asparagus, which weighs perhaps half a pound, obviously has a negligible effect on the environment. But when multiplied by millions of consumers, the amount of asparagus quickly increases from kilos to the hundreds of thousands of tons. And when other types of air-freighted fruits and vegetables are added to the list, the tonnage mounts to the millions. A cargo plane. Photo: Wikimedia Commons. Because most air-freighted produce comes from warm countries, an argument could be made that by purchasing this food here in Hong Kong, we are making a positive contribution to workers in a poor country, which in some sense is like development aid. On the other hand, it is generally acknowledged that the developing world will suffer most from climate change. The solution to our unsustainable eating practices is clear: having a better-informed public that is willing to act. In order to reduce the heavy carbon load of our present diet, the public needs to be educated via labeling on food packaging. Just as all food packaging now requires labels indicating nutritional values such as calories, likewise, as a first step, there should be labels indicating the carbon load that a food item has. Obviously such a step will not change everyone\' s food purchasing behaviour, but raising the awareness of consumers\' food choices and how they have an impact on the environment, and the unsustainability of our present eating habits, would be a step in the right direction. The delegates at COP25 not only need to agree on country-level policies, but also strategies on how to get individual members of society involved. Weaning us off air-freighted food should be high on the agenda. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_Hong.Kong4" COP="COP25" country="Hong.Kong" date="November 6, 2019 Wednesday"source="EJ Insight" >
Amid the deepening political crisis, our city has to cancel a number of high-profile annual international events such as the Hong Kong Wine & Dine Festival and the 2020 Hong Kong Formula E-Prix. Halfway across the world in South America, Chile has also been engulfed by nationwide anti-government protests in recent weeks. Chilean President Sebastian Pi\'f1era had no choice but to announce on Oct. 30 that the country would have to cancel the hosting of the APEC summit this month and the COP25 climate summit in December. If the Hong Kong government had not expected the now-withdrawn extradition bill to cause such turmoil, it would also be fair to say that\~the Chilean government was caught equally off guard by the nationwide riots triggered by a mere US$0.04 subway fare hike. The proposed fare hike, no matter how mild, provoked a huge public backlash across Chile, not least because the country has been riddled with "deep-rooted" social conflicts such as wealth inequality and blocked social mobility over the years. Different aspects of their daily living involving food, accommodation and transport are also deteriorating under existing policies. The subway fare hike was the last straw, prompting Chileans to give vent to their anger and rise up against their government. Pi\'f1era was quick in meeting protesters' demands. He immediately scrapped the fare hike, pledged to increase the national minimum wage, raised taxes on high-income citizens and overhauled his cabinet. Things might look bad for Chile for now, but as long as Pi\'f1era stays the course in delivering his promises and answers mounting public calls for amending the constitution in order to enhance state commitment to social welfare, he still stands a pretty good chance of being able to defuse the crisis. Things in Hong Kong are a lot more complicated, not least because our government only has very limited room for political maneuver. It has to meet the central government's directive to make the task of stopping violence and chaos a top priority, and it has to throw its weight behind the police despite its escalating brutality. As a consequence, the SAR administration has often found itself hamstrung when it comes to answering the demands of protesters ever since the protests broke out in June. Suffice it to say that the outlook for Hong Kong looks less promising than that of Chile. This article appeared in the Hong Kong Economic Journal on Nov 2 Translation by Alan Lee [Chinese version    ] - Contact us at mailto:english@hkej.com english@hkej.com JC/CG \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_Hong.Kong5" COP="COP25" country="Hong.Kong" date="December 16, 2019 Monday"source="EJ Insight" >
A handful of major states resisted pressure on Sunday to ramp up efforts to combat global warming as a UN climate summit ground to a close, angering smaller countries and a growing protest movement that is pushing for emergency action. The COP25 Many developing countries and campaigners had wanted to see much more explicit language spelling out the importance of countries submitting bolder pledges on emissions as the Paris process enters a crucial implementation phase next year. Brazil, China, Australia, Saudi Arabia and the United States had led resistance to bolder action, delegates said. "These talks reflect how disconnected country leaders are from the urgency of the science and the demands of their citizens in the streets," said Helen Mountford, Vice President for Climate and Economics, at the World Resources Institute think-tank. "They need to wake up in 2020." The lack of a strong outcome to reinforce the Paris accord raises the stakes for the next big climate summit, in Glasgow in November next year. As hosts, British Prime Minister Boris Johnson's government faces the task of persuading countries to submit more ambitious plans to cut carbon emissions. The Madrid summit had been due to end at the two-week mark on Friday but ran on for two extra days - a long delay even by the standards of often torturous climate summits. After final decisions were made, Chile's environment minister Carolina Schmidt - who served as president of the talks - said she was "of mixed emotions". The country had earlier triggered outrage after drafting a version of the text that campaigners complained was so weak it betrayed the spirit of the Paris Agreement. The process set out in the Paris deal hinges on countries ratcheting up emissions cuts next year. The final draft did acknowledge the "significant gap" between existing pledges and the temperature goals adopted in 2015. Nevertheless, it was still seen as a weak response to the sense of urgency felt by communities around the world afflicted by floods, droughts, wildfires and cyclones that scientists say have become more intense as the Earth rapidly warms. Guterres, who opened the talks on Dec 2., said he was "disappointed". "The international community lost an important opportunity to show increased ambition on mitigation, adaptation and finance to tackle the climate crisis," he said in a statement. "We must not give up and I will not give up." Delegates drew some consolation from an agreement reached in Brussels last week by the European Union's 28 member states, bar Poland, to reach net zero carbon emissions by 2050, under a "Green Deal" to wean the continent off fossil fuels. "It seems that EU now needs to be the leader and we want to be and we are going to be and that is what we are doing," said Krista Mikkonen, Finland's environment minister and the EU's representative at the talks. Brazil and Australia were among the main holdouts, delegates said, and the summit deferred big decisions on carbon markets. Smaller nations had also hoped to win guarantees of financial aid to cope with climate change. The Pacific island of Tuvalu accused the United States, which began withdrawing from the Paris process last month, of blocking progress. "There are millions of people all around the world who are already suffering from the impacts of climate change," Ian Fry, Tuvalu's representative, told delegates. "Denying this fact could be interpreted by some to be a crime against humanity." Reuters \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_Hong.Kong6" COP="COP25" country="Hong.Kong" date="February 16, 2020 (LOAD-DATE)"source="Asia Times-English" >
It remains to be seen if this will actually happen, but UK Prime Minister Boris Johnson is taking a green stand, albeit one that will benefit his party, HYPERLINK China Daily reported. Johnson announced that Britain will ban the sale of new petrol, diesel and hybrid cars from 2035, five years earlier than planned  a decision that could herald the end of over a century of reliance on the internal combustion engine, the report said. Johnson is seeking to use the announcement to elevate the United Kingdom's environmental credentials after he sacked the head of a Glasgow United Nations Climate Change Conference planned for November known as COP 26, the report said. "We have to deal with our CO2 emissions, and that is why the UK is calling for us to get to net zero as soon as possible, to get every country to announce credible targets to get there. That's what we want from Glasgow," Johnson said at a launch event for COP 26 at London's Science Museum, alongside famed naturalist David Attenborough. "We know as a country, as a society, as a planet, as a species, we must now act." The two-week COP 26 summit is seen as a moment of truth for the 2015 Paris Agreement to combat global warming with responsibility for persuading big polluting countries to agree more ambitious emissions cuts falling on the British hosts, the report said. Britain has pledged to reach net zero by 2050, but Greenpeace UK Head of Politics Rebecca Newsom said Johnson needed to take broader action than cleaning up transport, the report said. "We need a complete rethink of the way we power our economy, build homes, move around and grow our food," she said. Britain's step amounts to a victory for electric cars that if copied globally could hit the wealth of oil producers, as well as transform the car industry and one of the icons of 20th Century capitalism: the automobile itself. Countries and cities around the world have announced plans to crack down on diesel vehicles following the 2015 Volkswagen emissions scandal and the European Union is introducing tougher carbon dioxide rules, the report said. The mayors of Paris, Madrid, Mexico City and Athens have said they plan to ban diesel vehicles from city centers by 2025, the report said. France is preparing to ban the sale of fossil fuel-powered cars by 2040 and Norway's parliament has set a non-binding goal that by 2025 all cars should be zero emissions. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_Hong.Kong7" COP="COP25" country="Hong.Kong" date="December 22, 2019 Sunday"source="Orient Aviation" >
Hong Kong, Dec. 22 -- Despite trade wars, fragile global economic conditions and political unrest in several cities across the globe, the International Air Transport Association (IATA) has forecast airlines worldwide will turn in a collective net profit of US$29.3 billion in 2020, up from $25.9 billion in 2019. If correct, it will be the industry's 11th consecutive year in the black. IATA also forecast the struggling air freight sector would grow by 2% in the next 12 months. IATA said airlines were expected to earn a return on invested capital of 6%, up from 5.7% last year and also report a lift in net profit margins to 3.4%, from 3.1%. Average net profit per passenger was predicted to increase to $6.20, from $5.70, with overall performance boosted by a decline in the average price of fuel. "Slower than expected global economic growth in 2019 contributed to lower energy demand, with crude oil prices averaging around $65 per barrel (Brent), compared with $71.60 in 2018. Oil supply also is plentiful, which boosted inventories. As a result, oil prices are expected to dip in 2020 to $63 (Brent) per barrel," said IATA's chief economist Brian Pearce. "The forecast industry fuel bill of $182 billion will represent 22.1% of expenses, down from $188 billion, or 23.7% of expenses, in 2019." Speaking at IATA's Global Media Days in Geneva in early December, Pearce said Asia-Pacific carriers would experience a modest recovery in world trade and air cargo. The association forecasts the region's airlines would produce a $6 billion net profit in 2020, compared with $4.9 billion in 2019, and earn a 2.2% net margin for the coming year. Asia remains the manufacturing centre of the world and revenues from transporting much of those goods are a significant proportion of sales for many of the region's airlines, IATA said. "But the trade war is assumed just to be on hold. Trade tariffs are not reversed. Consequently, the rise in trade and cargo volumes is moderate. The net profit per passenger is anticipated at $3.34," it said. IATA director general and CEO, Alexandre de Juniac, said a combination of various global factors had created a tougher than anticipated business environment for airlines. "Yet the industry managed to achieve a decade in the black, as restructuring and cost-cutting continued to pay dividends. It appears 2019 will be the bottom of the current economic cycle and the forecast for 2020 is somewhat brighter," he said. "The big question for 2020 is how capacity will develop, particularly when, as expected, grounded 737 MAX aircraft return to service and delayed deliveries arrive." Given the state of the market, the modest optimistic projections for 2020 may come as a surprise to the industry, but Pearce said IATA's working assumption for the forecast is similar to those of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the Word Trade Organization (WTO). The prediction is that ahead of the U.S. elections in November 2020, there will be "a truce" in the U.S./Sino trade war, with no reduction in existing tariffs but with no additional tariffs implemented. "If so, then stronger economic growth in 2020 will produce a modest rise in international trade growth, from 0.9% in 2019 to 3.3% in 2020," said Pearce. This trend, he said, would be moderately supportive for the air cargo business. Pearce delivered other news that was not quite as welcome as the 2020 profit forecast. He said only a relatively small number of airlines had driven an improvement in aggregate industry level profitability. Remarkably, while IATA has nearly 300 members, ranking carriers by economic profit showed only around 30 carriers had been responsible for improvements in profits in the last ten years. "There is a long tail of airlines barely breaking even and a group making significant losses," he said. "For this long tail of airlines, performance has not improved in the past decade. This is why there has been a series of airline failures in the past two years, despite relatively good financial results at the aggregate industry level. There is work to be done to move the industry into a more financially sustainable position." IATA did not identify individual airlines that are struggling, but examples in the Asia-Pacific include Malaysia Airlines, Thai Airways International, Garuda Indonesia and Air India. IATA said air traffic growth would continue but at a slower pace than the historical average in the short-term. Passenger numbers are expected to reach 4.72 billion in 2020, up 4.0% or 4.54 billion, from 2019. Freight tonnes carried will recover to 62.4 million, a 2.0% increase over the 61.2 million tonnes carried in 2019 - the lowest result in three years. Stronger economic growth should support passenger traffic (RPKs) growth of 4.1%, similar to 2019 at 4.2%, but below historical trends. At the annual Global Media Days, it was clear IATA is putting a renewed focus on environmental issues. De Juniac said airlines had done a good job with their sustainability achievements but repeated his belief they had not done so well in getting the good news out to the general public. IATA has asked the European Union to support aviation's energy transition to sustainable aviation fuels (SAF) as part of the bloc's recently launched Green Deal. "Aviation has high hopes for the European Commission's Green Deal. We want to be part of Europe's building of a new energy economy. We will do everything we can to make sustainable aviation fuels a priority for aviation in Europe and around the world," said de Juniac, who recently took part in a Sustainable Innovation Forum that ran alongside the UN COP25 Climate Talks in Madrid. Since SAF were certified for commercial use in 2009, more than 215,000 flights have taken off using some blend of this low carbon fuel. The industry believed achieving 2% of global jet fuel from non-fossil sources by 2025 could create a tipping point for production and cost of SAF. The 14 production facilities operating, under construction or in the final stages of financing and planning would take the industry a long way towards the 2% goal, IATA said. "More progress is needed. Aviation should be a policy priority because it does not have a near-term electrification option. Traditional energy suppliers must prioritize investment in SAF," de Juniac said. IATA emphasised SAF were critical to the industry's long-term efforts to cut its emissions to half 2005 levels by 2050. The industry's strategy to achieve this goal includes significant investment in new technology aircraft, research into electric and hybrid propulsion, programs to improve operational efficiency, and the world's first global sectoral climate mechanism, CORSIA (Carbon Offsetting Reduction Scheme for International Aviation). Published by HT Digital Content Services with permission from Orient Aviation. For any query with respect to this article or any other content requirement, please contact Editor at HYPERLINK mailto:contentservices@htlive.com contentservices@htlive.com \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_Hong.Kong8" COP="COP25" country="Hong.Kong" date="January 20, 2020 Monday"source="Hong Kong Free Press" >
As horrific as the recent bush fires in Australia have been, a satellite image HYPERLINK attributed to NASA shared recently on social media made me gasp . It showed the entire continent of Australia literally on fire. On further inquiry, it turned out to be a composite image of all the forest fires (or bush fires as they are called in Australia) that the continent had suffered in the last one month or so. The brightest spots were on the east coast in the most populous states of New South Wales and Victoria where the two largest cities of Australia \- Sydney and Melbourne \- are located. HYPERLINK //imgur.com/a/9oiePhO 3D  visualisation of the fires in Australia, made from NASA satellite data. The latest report puts the toll at more than 2,000 houses destroyed, 26 deaths, and six million hectares burnt \- an area bigger than the size of Ireland. Heart-breaking scenes of wild animals such as the cuddly koalas and innocent kangaroos perishing in large numbers have made it to social media worldwide. The total loss of species is estimated to be in the hundreds of millions and many of them face extinction. The emotional trauma suffered by house owners, firefighters and survivors is harrowing to say the least. While landing in Sydney, I was immediately struck by the clear blue of the skies meeting the blue of a deeper hue in the Pacific Ocean on an unusually bright day. Sydney was to become our second home for the next five years.\~ We spent some wonderful time exploring the beauty of the Blue Mountains, and the pristine beaches of Bondi and Manly. File photo: Wikicommons. Even during those days and for decades and centuries before, bush fires have always been part of Australia, as much as the aboriginals in the outback and the kangaroos and koalas. However, the current fires are something else altogether in their scale, magnitude, ferocity and damage. More importantly, they are the clearest evidence yet that manmade climate crisis is now well and truly on our doorsteps. The Australian bushfire season is not at its peak.\~ The summer months are just starting, with the driest and hottest period historically occurring towards the end of February. Most experts believe that the worst is yet to come. Australia has been a climate change hotspot, with fragile eco-systems such as the Great Barrier Reef off the coast of Queensland already showing signs of major stress from global warming and ocean acidification. The climate policy of successive governments in Australia has favoured promotion of a fossil fuel-driven energy-intensive economic growth model, in spite of having vast untapped reserves of renewable energy such as solar and wind. The controversial Adani coal mine project (promoted by an Indian tycoon) has become a deeply contentious issue in the last few years. Australia like most developed countries has a very high per capita carbon footprint. Thanks to the conservative government led by Scott Morrison, it was at the forefront of a small group of fossil fuel-driven countries that ensured the unfortunate failure of COP 25 climate summit in Madrid. It blocked progress towards goals set by the Paris agreement by scuttling all action to limit global warming below 1.5 deg above pre-industrial levels. These urgent actions have now been delayed by another year. Australia\' s bush fire catastrophe is truly apocalyptic in magnitude without any historic precedent. Years of drought stemming from long stretches of dry weather in a continent with little rain to start with, and ever-increasing summer temperatures, have prepared the grounds for these cataclysmic events. The effect can be seen from space in satellite images. The smoke is predicted to circle the globe, polluting the air and causing health problems for millions in Australian cities and elsewhere. The massive fires earlier in Amazon forests in Brazil, California and elsewhere are now dwarfed by this disaster. As we watch climate crisis unfold in different parts of the world in the form of more frequent disasters of ever-increasing intensity, the prospects in places like Hong Kong are not much brighter either. It is reliably predicted that future typhoons will be more frequent and ferocious. A rise in seawater level is likely to be faster than predicted and could drown precious real estate in the most valuable coastal plains. Unpredictable weather patterns such as unseasonal rains, and unusually warm winters interspersed with record cold temperatures would cause major new public health issues. Hong Kong will also suffer from the major impact of the climate crisis in the Chinese mainland. The unsustainably high carbon footprint of Hong Kong \- dependent as it is on imports and extremely high consumption of meat \- sets a very bad example for the rest of the world. A major re-think and change in policy towards dealing with the climate crisis is urgently needed. Photo: PH Yang. Australia is experiencing a climate emergency predicted by scientists well in advance. It\' s a lesson for Australians as well as humanity at large. Unless fossil fuel use is drastically reined in and use of alternative renewable energy promoted on a massive scale, red meat consumption curtailed and afforestation taken up on a war footing, the future of our race is uncertain at best and doomed at worst. \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_Hong.Kong9" COP="COP25" country="Hong.Kong" date="February 28, 2020 (LOAD-DATE)"source="Asia Times-English" >
Chile has pulled out of hosting two major international summits as it struggles to restore order after more than 10 days of civil unrest that left at least 23 dead. President Sebastian Pinera said "common sense" dictated the decision to withdraw from the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation, or APEC, summit and the Cop 25 climate change conference. US President Donald Trump was planning to meet Chinese counterpart Xi Jinping to lock down a "phase one" agreement at next month\' s APEC forum that would partially have ended an 18-month trade war between the world's two biggest economies. The White House confirmed it was looking forward to finalizing an agreement "within the same timeframe," although analysts Eurasia Group said that may not happen until the end of the year. APEC reported that it had supported Chile's decision but gave no indication there would be a replacement summit this year, saying only that Malaysia would host the 2020 event. Russian leader Vladimir Putin had also been due to attend the forum, while teenage Swedish activist Greta Thunberg was among 25,000 delegates expected for COP 25 . After more than 10 days of street protests, Pinera said Chile was not in a position to host either the APEC summit or December\' s climate convention. The pullout is seen as a blow to Chile's tourism industry, and the Santiago stock exchange dropped 2.8 points while the peso fell to its lowest rate against the dollar since 2003. "This has been a very difficult decision, a decision that has been deeply painful because we know exactly how important APEC and COP are for Chile and the world," Pinera said. Demonstrators have demanded that the 69-year-old right-wing leader, whose personal fortune is estimated by Forbes at US$2.8 billion, step down. "When a father has problems, he must always prioritize his family over other options. The same goes for a president, he must always put his own compatriots first, ahead of any other considerations," he added. Chile is grappling with its worst social crisis in decades, one that shows little sign of abating, despite Pinera announcing a raft of measures aimed at placating protesters. Demonstrators have demanded that the 69-year-old right-wing leader, whose personal fortune is estimated by Forbes at US$2.8 billion, step down. They have been angered by low salaries and pensions, poor public health care and education, and a yawning gap between rich and poor. Last week, Pinera announced an increase in the minimum wage and pensions as well as measures to alleviate sky-high health care costs and a streamlining of public offices. "I'm not rejecting any structural reform," Pinera said earlier this week. "This is the time to listen to the people." On Monday, he reshuffled his cabinet for the third time since coming to power in March 2018, but the street movement continues. Protests began on October 18 and during the first few days there was widespread destruction, arson and looting. Demonstrations have been largely calm over the last week but there were violent clashes between demonstrators and security services on Monday, when shops were looted and a building set on fire. Huge numbers took to the streets on Wednesday, with the country semi-paralyzed as numerous shops and businesses remained closed. Canceling the two major international events is more likely to backfire than to placate the demonstrators, University of Chile analyst Octavio Avendano said.  It is a sign of weakness and a sharpening of the conflict, Avendano added. \- AFP \</doc>
<doc ID="COP25_Hong.Kong10" COP="COP25" country="Hong.Kong" date="January 12, 2020 Sunday 06:46 AM GMT"source="Asia Times-English" >
Of all the things Shinzo Abe thought might undo his legacy as economic savior, Iran may well have been the furthest risk from the Japanese Prime Minister\' s mind. But less than two weeks into 2020, the specter of renewed chaos in the Middle East is\~ HYPERLINK https://www.asiatimes.com/2020/01/article/how-us-iran-tensions-may-still-torpedo-oil-markets/ upending the calculus Now, Tokyo confronts the risk of skyrocketing oil prices as US President Donald Trump ratchets up tensions with Iran. Energy prices are surprisingly stable following the Trump-ordered assassination of Qasem Soleimani, the de facto commander of Iranian expansionist efforts in the Middle East. It is unclear if this stability will last. These are the dynamics wrecking Abe\' s 2020. The first \- the shadow of recession \- can be addressed with government stimulus moves. The $121 billion spending jolt that Abe unveiled last month will paper over many a crack. It is the second that presents a two-pronged challenge, and an unpredictable one at that. Energy vulnerabilities On the one hand, Japan\' s economy is uniquely vulnerable to a surge in oil prices, particularly in the Middle East. Oil stands at the center of Japan\' s energy mix, accounting for 76% of all sources. And\~ HYPERLINK https://nam12.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.reuters.com%2Farticle%2Fus-mideast-iran-japan%2Fjapan-to-send-warship-aircraft-to-middle-east-to-protect-vessels-idUSKBN1YV00W&data=02%7C01%7C%7C683714461d3e491cb15b08d795f0d164%7C84df9e7fe9f640afb435aaaaaaaaaaaa%7C1%7C0%7C637142733840944852&sdata=6YFkv4YYo73bg5HI8qjR7kaB1tIa88v6nd9m2CWU%2Fhc%3D&reserved=0 nearly 90% \~of Japan\' s oil imports come from the Persian Gulf. This leaves Japan over a proverbial barrel should Middle Eastern hostilities escalate and unleash fresh energy-market chaos. Energy has become an increasingly complicated \- and contentious \- topic for Japan. Since the 2011 Fukushima nuclear crisis, the majority of its 54 nuclear power plants have been idled. That has left Tokyo importing more and more coal, increasing its carbon footprint. At present, coal accounts for 17% of the mix. The next largest source is hydroelectric at 4.4%, followed by liquified natural gas at 1.6%, renewables at 1% and nuclear at 0.6%. Japan, in other words, is about 94% dependent on fossil fuels. That puts the country in a ticklish spot. No wonder organizers of the COP25 United Nations conference on climate change in Madrid last month\~ https://www.japantimes.co.jp/news/2019/12/01/national/united-nations-climate-conference-madrid-japan-shinjiro-koizumi-coal/#.Xhj_QsgzZPY rejected Abe\' s request Fossil fuel dependency makes Japan\' s economy increasingly sensitive to oil spikes. The World Bank sees Japan growing\~ HYPERLINK 0.7% this year , which doesn\' t leave much of a cushion should Trump intensify his trade war. Odds are, he will amid anger over impeachment and election-year wrangling. What better way to change the headlines than slapping new taxes on China or auto imports? Then there\' s the  HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/jan/05/impeachment-warren-trump-wag-the-dog-qassem-suleimani-iran wag the dog  risk clouding 2020. Washington pundits and Trump's legion of critics have long speculated Trump might start a war to get re-elected. In part, because he spent years, in his pre-White House days, arguing that predecessor\~ \~ HYPERLINK https://edition.cnn.com/2020/01/03/politics/kfile-trump-obama-2012-iran-war-reelection/index.html Barack Obama \~would do just that. Trump\' s Iran gamble could be the start of an increasing bet on poking Persian Gulf powers to cheer his base, but that could go bad quickly. His calls for additional sanctions on Iran alone raise the possibility of confrontation. Even without military action in the Gulf, Japan is vulnerable to energy-price swings for two reasons. One: They reduce demand both for businesses and households. Two: the yen tends to rally sharply in times of global turmoil. This safe-haven dynamic would slam Japan\' s biggest exporters and, ultimately, top-down growth. Moreover, rising oil costs would generate  bad inflation at a moment when the\~ HYPERLINK https://www.asiatimes.com/2019/06/article/time-for-bank-of-japan-to-get-aggressive/ Bank of Japan \~is struggling to put growth on a stable, self-reinforcing path. Inflation rose just 0.5% in November year-on-year, a far cry from Tokyo\' s 2% target.\~Higher oil prices act like a stealth tax increase, denting the economy. The costs would surge exponentially if a full-blown military clash occurred. Japan\' s oil reserves, it\' s worth noting, are a source of secret\~ HYPERLINK concern in Tokyo . As of October,\~total oil reserves were 81.98 million kiloliters, or 515.64 million barrels. On paper, that\' s supply enough to meet domestic demand for 234 days. But recent inspections found that one-fifth of those stockpiled may be inaccessible in winter, causing alarm and chatter about an energy crunch. The problem: tankers, thanks to rough winter seas, may have trouble reaching four of Japan\' s 10 major storage facilities this year. The finding emerged from inspections following a June attack on a\~ HYPERLINK https://www.reuters.com/article/us-mideast-tanker-japan-damage/flying-objects-damaged-japanese-tanker-during-attack-in-gulf-of-oman-idUSKCN1TF0M9 Japanese tanker \~near the Strait of Hormuz. Regulations prohibit tankers to dock for loading when waves exceed 1.5 meters or when wind exceeds 15 meters per second. That could put sites in Akita, Fukui, Fukuoka and Nagasaki prefectures, housing in total about 18 million kiloliters of oil, largely off-limits. Diplomacy stress test\~ The Trump era presents another big challenge\~for Abe. Japan\' s pacifist post-war constitution bars it from fielding a conventional offensive military. Since 2012, Abe has pursued a controversial policy of  reinterpreting the document. Come February, Abe plans to test constitutional limits further by\~ HYPERLINK https://www.reuters.com/article/us-mideast-iran-japan/japan-to-send-warship-aircraft-to-middle-east-to-protect-vessels-idUSKBN1YV00W sending a warship \~and patrol airplanes to the Gulf. The planned mission has got a hell of a lot riskier since the US assassinated Soleimani. Abe is a cagey politician, and at present, he claims the deployment is a go even as public opinion swings against. Making the destroyer particularly vulnerable is that the Japanese vessel will reportedly deploy independently, rather than as part of a bigger, beefier US or international naval force. In a\~ HYPERLINK http://www.asahi.com/ajw/articles/AJ202001100027.html Jan. 10 editorial , the Asahi newspaper concluded that the  government should suspend the plan and reconsider whether the deployment is necessary. Iran-US tensions are unwelcome developments given that Abe \- ever the diplomatic pragmatist \- has spent considerable energy wooing Iran. In June, he became the first sitting prime minister to visit Tehran in 40 years. It was meant to rekindle a Japan-Iran relationship that has been shaky since the 1979 Iranian Revolution. Iranian President Hassan Rouhani has been planning a visit to Japan \- to coincide with the destroyer deployment next month. It is these close ties that had Trump enlisting\~ HYPERLINK https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/jun/14/shinzo-abe-iran-ayatollah-talks-analysis-trump Abe as an emissary \~of sorts last June, for Japan still has the benefit of a constructive relationship with Rouhani\' s government. Once Japan\' s destroyer is in the Gulf, its mission will be explicitly separate from American interests. Even so, the vessel could well be caught in not just diplomatic, but actual military crossfire. Abe and South Korea\' s Moon Jae-in are under pressure to aid the US in the Gulf. It\' s a safe bet that US officials upped the pressure at last week\' s trilateral confab in Washington. For Abe, though, there\' s every reason at present to put some distance between Japan and Trump\' s America. That will not be easy as Trump turns the screws on Iran \- a situation that puts pressure on Tokyo\' s diplomatic relations at the same time as it lays bare Japan\' s addiction to Persian Gulf oil supplies. \</doc>
